<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maria_Elena 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maria_Elena</songId>
   <title>Maria Elena</title>
   <weeks>
      <week>1941-06-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"María Elena" is a 1932 popular song written by Lorenzo
    Barcelata (Spanish words and music). It was published by Peer
    International Corporation of Mexico. The English words by Bob
    Russell.</p>
      <p>The song was dedicated to María Elena, the wife of Mexican
    President Emilio Portes Gil.</p>
      <p>An instrumental version of the song was used for the
    background theme of the film 
    <i>Bordertown</i>, starring Paul Muni and Bette Davis, in 1935.
    The next year the words and music were used in the Mexican film
    
    <i>María Elena</i>.</p>
      <p>Lawrence Welk later introduced the tune in the United States
    on his radio program, then in 1941 on the Okeh Records
    label.</p>
      <p>The song was a hit for the Jimmy Dorsey orchestra with Bob
    Eberly doing the vocals. The recording was made on March 19,
    1941 by Decca Records as catalog number 3698. The flip side was
    "Green Eyes." The record first reached the Billboard magazine
    charts on May 16, 1941 and lasted 17 weeks on the chart,
    peaking at #1 on June 14, 1941. Since "Green Eyes" was also a
    #1 hit, this was a major double-sided hit recording. In the
    same year the Wayne King Orchestra also had a #2 hit with
    "Maria Elena".</p>
      <p>An instrumental version was recorded in 1958 and released in
    the United States in 1962 by Natalico and Antenor Lima, better
    known as Los Indios Tabajaras. This popular revival hit #6 pop,
    #3 easy listening in 1963.</p>
      <p>Ry Cooder performed an instrumental version of this song on
    his 1972 album 
    <i>Boomer's Story</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
