<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Candy_Shop 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Candy_Shop</songId>
   <title>Candy Shop</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/50_Cent</artistId>
      <artistName>50 Cent featuring Olivia</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2005-03-05</week>
      <week>2005-03-12</week>
      <week>2005-03-19</week>
      <week>2005-03-26</week>
      <week>2005-04-02</week>
      <week>2005-04-09</week>
      <week>2005-04-16</week>
      <week>2005-04-23</week>
      <week>2005-04-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/ac/50_Cent_-_Candy_Shop.jpg/200px-50_Cent_-_Candy_Shop.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/50-Cent-featuring-Olivia+Candy-Shop.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Massacre</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 1, 2005</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2004</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
      <genre>Dirty Rap</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:29</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Aftermath , Interscope , Shady</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>50 Cent</writer>
      <writer>Scott Storch</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Scott Storch</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Candy Shop" is the second single by rapper 50 Cent
    featuring R&amp;B singer Olivia. The song was written by 50
    Cent and Scott Storch for 50 Cent's second commercial album 
    <i>The Massacre</i>(2005). Scott Storch, who also produced the
    track, took influence from Middle Eastern music.</p>
      <p>The song was released as the album's second U.S. single, and
    first international single. It was one of the year's most
    popular songs, peaking inside the top ten on the majority of
    the charts it entered. "Candy Shop" received mixed reviews from
    critics, with some calling it a retread of 50 Cent's previous
    collaboration with Lil' Kim on "Magic Stick".</p>
      <p>In an interview with 
    <i>XXL</i>magazine, rapper Fat Joe claimed that he helped
    produce the track while working with Scott Storch. He stated:
    "I'm pretty sure the world don't know we actually produced
    Candy Shop together. I produced it with him (Storch)... Scott
    called me like 50 times, 100 times: 'Yo, you sure you don't
    want to use it? 50 Cent called me. 50 Cent want it.' I never
    had a problem with this dude. I was like, 'Go ahead.'" When
    writing the song, 50 Cent stated: "I attempted to be as sexual
    as possible, from a male perspective, without being vulgar or
    obscene".</p>
      <p>In the intro, 50 said, "so seductive". This alluded to Tony
    Yayo's hit single "So Seductive", due to the fact Yayo wrote
    the track before 50 wrote "Candy Shop".</p>
      <p>"Candy Shop" is a mid-tempo dancefloor track. The song,
    which was officially produced by Scott Storch, samples The
    Salsoul Orchestra's "Love Break". The production was described
    by IGN as having a "Middle Eastern tinge" with synthesized
    strings that "unleash a darkly atonal whirl that sounds too
    much like something either Timbaland or The Neptunes or Mannie
    Fresh have concocted". 
    <i>The Guardian</i>also wrote that the production contains
    "wan-sounding imitations of the Neptunes' sparse, breathy
    funk". PopMatters described the chorus as being "relaxed yet
    faintly ominous" with 50 Cent and Olivia crooning: "Girl what
    we do (what we do) / And where we do (and where we do) / The
    things we do (things we do) / Are just between me and you (oh
    yeah)." 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>also noted the chorus for 50 Cent's
    "amateur-sounding tenor croon".</p>
      <p>The song received mixed reviews from critics. PopMatters
    described it as a track "dripping with sexual energy and cool"
    and is "sexy as hell, but contains a pretty unmistakable edge
    of hostility, macho swagger, and thunderous chest thumping." 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>wrote that the song was an
    "appealing throwaway single" and lyrics such as "after you work
    up a sweat, you can play with the stick" are not seductions;
    "they're orders". MusicOMH's Azeem Ahmad wrote that the
    chemistry between 50 Cent and Olivia "is almost as explicit as
    the lyrics... the bass line is made for grinding to". Author
    Ethan Brown, in a review of 
    <i>The Massacre</i>, called the song "uninspiring" and "nearly
    identical" to his previous collaboration with Lil' Kim on
    "Magic Stick". He further stated that 50 Cent seemed too
    content with his "hypersexual image" among other things and
    "not inspired enough to work beyond the same old
    attention-getting schemes." Pitchfork Media also listed "Candy
    Shop" as a reprise of "Magic Stick" both "in beats and in
    timbre" and 
    <i>Stylus magazine</i>said it was "more of the same" as his
    previous collaboration. Similarly, 
    <i>Billboard</i>wrote that 50 Cent "shows little growth
    lyrically" with the song being "typical playa-friendly
    fodder".</p>
      <p>Fat Joe responded to the song after 50 Cent targeted him in
    "Piggy Bank", a "diss" track aimed towards several rappers. Fat
    Joe released a song, "My Fo, Fo", in which he raps "Is it me or
    does 'Candy Shop' sound like 'Magic Stick'?/ In the video, this
    nigga 50 'bout to strip/ Shaking his ass. What the fuck is
    wrong with this nigger/50 don't make me shiver."</p>
      <p>"Candy Shop" performed well in the United States, becoming
    50 Cent's third number one single. The song debuted at number
    eighty-two on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100, peaked at number one for nine weeks,
    and remained on the chart for twenty-three weeks. The track
    reached number one on the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs, Hot Rap
    Tracks, and Rhythmic Top 40 charts. The song also did well on
    pop-oriented charts, reaching number two on the Pop 100 and
    number five on the Top 40 Mainstream. "Candy Shop" was helped
    on the Hot 100 and Pop 100 by its strong digital downloads,
    peaking at number one on the Hot Digital Songs. The track was
    certified Gold by the RIAA and was nominated at the 2006 Grammy
    Awards for Best Rap Song, but lost to Kanye West's "Diamonds
    from Sierra Leone".</p>
      <p>Across Europe, the song reached number one in Austria,
    Belgium, Germany, and Switzerland and the top five in Ireland,
    Norway, the Netherlands, and the UK. In Australia, the song
    peaked at number three, was certified Platinum by the ARIA, and
    on the 2005 year-end chart, it was listed at number
    twenty-four. It also reached number two in New Zealand.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by Jessy Terrero on January 11
    – January 12, 2005 and filmed in Hollywood, California. Due to
    rapper Trick Daddy's music video for "Sugar (Gimme Some)"
    already having candy references, 50 Cent said "we tried to do
    something a little different" and not follow the same route.
    The video features Olivia as the lead dancer and several models
    including Chessika Cartwright (as a dominatrix), "Lyric" (as a
    nurse), and Erica Mena (as the girl in bed). It also features
    cameo appearances from Lil Scrappy and G-Unit member Lloyd
    Banks and former member Young Buck. The video was nominated for
    Best Male Video at the 2005 MTV Video Music Awards, but lost to
    Kanye West's "Jesus Walks".</p>
      <p>On February 2, 2005, the video debuted on MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>at number nine and stayed on the chart
    for forty-six days. It also reached number one on the 
    <i>MuchMusic</i>video charts.</p>
      <p>There is a remix featuring Marques Houston.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
