<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_Da_Club 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_Da_Club</songId>
   <title>In Da Club</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/50_Cent</artistId>
      <artistName>50 Cent</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2003-03-08</week>
      <week>2003-03-15</week>
      <week>2003-03-22</week>
      <week>2003-03-29</week>
      <week>2003-04-05</week>
      <week>2003-04-12</week>
      <week>2003-04-19</week>
      <week>2003-04-26</week>
      <week>2003-05-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/12/50_Cent_-_In_Da_Club_-_CD_cover.jpg/200px-50_Cent_-_In_Da_Club_-_CD_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/50-Cent+In-Da-Club.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Get Rich or Die Tryin'</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 4, 2003</released>
   <formats>
      <format>12-inch single</format>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2002</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:10</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Aftermath , Interscope , Shady</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>50 Cent</writer>
      <writer>Dr. Dre</writer>
      <writer>Mike Elizondo</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Dr. Dre</producer>
      <producer>Mike Elizondo</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"In da Club" is a hip-hop song performed by rapper 50 Cent
    from his commercial debut album 
    <i>Get Rich or Die Tryin'</i>. The song was produced by Dr. Dre
    with co-production from Mike Elizondo. 50 Cent, Dr. Dre, and
    Elizondo wrote the song. The track was released in 2003 as the
    album's lead single and it was positively received by music
    critics.</p>
      <p>"In da Club" became 50 Cent's first number one single and
    was one of 2003's most popular songs after reaching number one
    in the United States and peaking in the top five on the
    majority of the European record charts it entered. At the 46th
    Grammy Awards, it was nominated for Best Male Rap Solo
    Performance and Best Rap Song. The song's music video won Best
    Rap Video and Best New Artist at the 2003 MTV Video Music
    Awards. In 2009 the single was named the 24th most successful
    song of the 2000s, on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade.</p>
      <p>After 50 Cent was discovered by rapper Eminem in 2002, he
    flew to Los Angeles where he was introduced to record producer
    Dr. Dre. "In da Club" was the first of seven tracks he recorded
    in five days with Dr. Dre. 50 Cent described the studio
    sessions, saying:</p>
      <p>The production was originally given to the hip hop group
    D12, but was passed on to 50 Cent. He recorded the track with
    only the drum beat present. Since much of the content on 
    <i>Get Rich or Die Tryin'</i>was "dark", he wanted to write
    material that was "the exact opposite". He called the song a
    "celebration of life. Every day it's relevant all over 'cause
    every day is someone's birthday."</p>
      <p>"In da Club" was positively received from music critics.
    Allmusic described it as "a tailor-made mass-market good-time
    single". 
    <i>The Source</i>called the song a "guaranteed party starter"
    with its "blaring horns, funky organs, guitar riffs and sparse
    hand claps". The BBC also wrote that the song is "a spectacular
    party anthem" that "highlights 50 Cent's ability to twist his
    words effortlessly". 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>noted that 50 Cent "boasts
    unashamedly of his career objectives and newly flush bank
    account" with lyrics such as "I'm feelin' focus, man, my money
    on my mind/Got a mil out the deal and I'm still on the grind." 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>wrote that the song sports "a spare yet
    irresistible synth hook augmented by a tongue-twisting
    refrain". 
    <i>The Guardian</i>called the track "irresistible" due to its
    "sparse orchestral samples and snaking chorus" and Pitchfork
    Media also said "the bounce on 'In Da Club' is straight-up
    irresistible, Dre at both his minimalist best and most
    deceptively infectious." 
    <i>Splendid</i>magazine called the song an "insanely catchy"
    single with its "stanky, horn-addled thump". The track was
    listed at number ten on 
    <i>Blender</i>magazine's "The 500 Greatest Songs Since You Were
    Born". In 2008, it was ranked at number 18 on VH1's "100
    Greatest Hip Hop Songs".</p>
      <p>"In da Club" charted well in the United States, becoming 50
    Cent's first number one single. The song peaked at number one
    for nine weeks on the Hot 100 (starting on February 27, 2003)
    and remained on the chart for twenty-two weeks. The track also
    reached number one on the Top 40 Tracks, Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop
    Songs, and Hot Rap Tracks charts. In March 2003, it broke a 
    <i>Billboard</i>record as the "most listened-to" song in radio
    history within a week. "In da Club" was certified Gold by the
    Recording Industry Association of America and was nominated for
    Best Male Rap Solo Performance and Best Rap Song at the 2004
    Grammy Awards, but lost to Eminem's "Lose Yourself". Across
    Europe, the song reached number one in Denmark, Germany,
    Ireland, and Switzerland and the top five in Austria, Belgium,
    Finland, Greece, Norway, Sweden, the Netherlands, and the
    United Kingdom. In Australia, the single peaked at number one,
    was certified two times Platinum by the Australian Recording
    Industry Association, and on the 2003 year-end chart, it was
    listed at number five.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by Phillip Atwell on December
    10 – December 11, 2002. Almost all the film footage was
    used in the video except for a scene where 50 Cent raps in a
    glass box. The video is set in a fictional hip hop boot camp
    known as the Shady/Aftermath Artist Development Center. It
    begins with a black Hummer driving to the facility at an
    unknown location. 50 Cent is introduced by hanging upside down
    from the roof of a gym. Atwell commented, "I think I could have
    done better with it, but I really liked the way that it turned
    out". The video also contains a shooting range, which Atwell
    felt was appropriate because 50 Cent had been shot nine times.
    He said, "creatively, I felt like we were able to put guns in a
    video and have it play. And I like it when you are able to play
    within the standards and still give the artist something
    symbolic of what they are going for."</p>
      <p>The video ends with the camera zooming out of the club to
    reveal a two-way mirror with Eminem and Dr. Dre in white lab
    uniforms, observing 50 Cent and taking notes. Atwell stated
    that "seeing 50 with Dre and Em having his back is as big a
    visual statement as it is a musical statement" and the shot was
    significant because it made clear the club was inside the
    center and not unrelated performance footage. On January 27,
    2003, the video debuted on MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>at number nine and stayed on the chart
    for fifty days. It also reached number one on the 
    <i>MuchMusic</i>video charts. At the 2003 MTV Video Music
    Awards, the video was awarded Best Rap Video and Best New
    Artist and was nominated for Video of the Year, Best Male
    Video, and Viewer's Choice.</p>
      <p>In January 2006, 50 Cent was sued for copyright infringement
    by former 2 Live Crew manager Joseph Weinberger, who owns the
    rights to the rap group's catalog. He claimed that 50 Cent
    plagiarized the lines "it's your birthday" from former 2 Live
    Crew frontman Luther Campbell on his 1994 album 
    <i>Still a Freak for Life</i>. The lawsuit was dismissed by
    U.S. District Judge Paul Huck, who ruled that the phrase was a
    "common, unoriginal and noncopyrightable element of the
    song".</p>
      <p>Information taken from the liner notes of 
    <i>Get Rich or Die Tryin'</i>.</p>
      <p>Beyoncé Knowles released a remix cover version of the song
    titled "Sexy Lil Thug" that is sung from a girls perspective.
    The song follows the same instrumentals and melody as the
    original and cuts in at 3:13. Her version was often merged with
    the original in the clubs and on radio play. The remix of the
    song featuring 50 Cent, Lil Boosie, &amp; Max Manelli was found
    in the mixtape "Speak My Mind". There is another version of
    this song that has 50 Cent's intro (the dropping coin being
    inserted to a slot) from the album, and the intro &amp; 2nd
    verse from "In Da Club", it was found the 1st promotional CD of
    "Dangerously In Love", it's the official remix to "In Da
    Club".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
