<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Take_on_Me 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Take_on_Me</songId>
   <title>Take on Me</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A-ha</artistId>
      <artistName>a-ha</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1985-10-19</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e1/Take_On_Me_cover.jpg/200px-Take_On_Me_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/a-ha+Take-on-Me.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Hunting High and Low</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>16 September 1985</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1984-1985</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Synthpop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:46</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Warner Bros. Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Magne Furuholmen</writer>
      <writer>Morten Harket</writer>
      <writer>Pål Waaktaar</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Alan Tarney</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Take on Me" is a song by Norwegian pop band a-ha. Written
    by the band members, the song was produced by Alan Tarney for
    the group's first studio album 
    <i>Hunting High and Low</i>, released in 1985. The song
    combines synthpop with a varied instrumentation, which includes
    acoustic guitars, keyboards, drums and synthesizers.</p>
      <p>The original "Take on Me" was recorded in 1984, and took
    three releases to chart in the United Kingdom, reaching number
    two on the UK Singles Chart in November 1985. In the United
    States the song reached the top position of the Hot 100 in
    October 1985, due in no small part to the wide exposure of its
    memorable and cutting-edge music video on MTV, directed by
    Steve Barron. The video features the band in a pencil-sketch
    animation/live-action combination called rotoscoping. The video
    won six awards, and was nominated for two others at the 1986
    MTV Video Music Awards.</p>
      <p>Pål Waaktaar and Magne Furuholmen began their music careers
    playing in a band called Bridges, together with Viggo Bondi and
    Øystein Jevanord. In 1981 the band produced 
    <i>Fakkeltog</i>, an LP for which all of the music was composed
    by the group themselves, most of it being written by Waaktaar.
    Soon after, Bridges disbanded. Waaktaar and Furuholmen
    relocated to London to try their hand in the music industry
    there, but after six months of disappointment they returned to
    Norway. The duo decided to try to get Morten Harket to join
    them as lead singer. At the time, Harket was singing in a band
    called Souldier Blue, but he felt that his band was stagnating,
    and decided to join Waaktaar and Furuholmen. They stayed
    together for six months, writing some songs and working on demo
    tapes, including "Lesson One," the song that eventually became
    "Take on Me." In January 1983 the trio returned to London in
    search of a recording a contract.</p>
      <p>The band moved into a flat in London and began calling on
    record companies and publishing houses. After a few meetings
    with various A&amp;R personnel, the band signed with a
    publishing house called Lionheart. a-ha then returned to Norway
    to earn some money. When they returned to London, they left
    Lionheart out of frustration. They decided to record new demos,
    and chose the studio of musician and producer John Ratcliff,
    intending to re-record five songs. The band signed with
    Ratcliff, who in return introduced them to his manager, Terry
    Slater. With this encouragement, the band managed to complete
    some songs, including "Take on Me." After a few meetings,
    Slater signed them with Warner Bros. Records.</p>
      <p>The band met with Tony Mansfield, an expert in the use of
    computerized synthesizers, who mixed the demos with electronic
    instrumentation. The sound was not what a-ha had hoped to
    achieve, and the album was remixed again. The band rushed to
    release "Take on Me" as a single in the United Kingdom but
    failed to make an impact. After this, Warner Brothers' main
    office in the United States decided to invest in the band, and
    gave them the opportunity to re-record the song. Terry Slater
    convinced Alan Tarney to produce the new version. The song was
    soon completed and re-released in the United Kingdom, but the
    record label's office in London gave them little support, and
    the single flopped for the second time.</p>
      <p>In the United States, Warner Brothers put the group on high
    priority, and made the move to invest serious money in a
    revolutionary video for "Take on Me" using the version produced
    by Tarney. The single was released in the United States a month
    after the music video, and immediately appeared in the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100.</p>
      <p>"Take on Me" is a synthpop song, written in the key of A
    major, and includes instrumentation from acoustic guitars,
    keyboards, and synthesizers. Like the majority of pop music,
    the song is set in common time. It moves at a very quick tempo
    of 170 beats per minute. The lyrics are a plea for love, and
    are constructed in a verse-chorus form with a bridge before the
    third and final chorus. In the song, Harket demonstrates a
    vocal range of over two and a half octaves. He sings the lowest
    pitch in the song, A
    <sub>2</sub>, at the beginning of the chorus, on the first
    syllable of the phrase "Take on me." As the chorus progresses,
    Harket's voice hits ever higher notes, reaching a falsetto and
    hitting the song's highest note (E
    <sub>5</sub>) at the end (note values specified in this article
    using scientific pitch notation). One should also note the
    temporary change of markings in the drum pattern in the chorus,
    where for two bars the drums play in half time, only to pick up
    the same rhythm as before for the climax of the vocal line. A
    mix of drums, acoustic guitars and electronic instrumentation
    serves as the song's backing track.</p>
      <p>Two videos were made for the song. The first release of
    "Take on Me" in 1984 includes a completely different recording,
    and was featured in the first video, which shows the band
    singing with a blue background. The second video was directed
    by Steve Barron, and filmed at Kim's Café and on a sound stage
    in London, in 1985. The video used a pencil-sketch
    animation/live-action combination called rotoscoping, in which
    the live-action footage is traced-over frame by frame to give
    the characters realistic movements.</p>
      <p>The video's main theme is a romantic fantasy narrative. It
    begins with a young woman, played by actress Bunty Bailey,
    drinking coffee and reading a comic book alone in a coffee
    shop. The comic contains a narrative about competitive
    motorcycle racing in which the hero is pursued by two villains.
    As the girl reads, her waitress writes out the bill for her to
    pay. The winner of the race, played by Morten Harket, winks at
    the girl from the page. Then a graphical representation of a
    hand reaches through the comic book, inviting the girl to enter
    his animated world. Through a creative effect they both view
    each other through a strange window which allows them to see
    each other in live action, while they each actually remain in
    pencilled comic book form.</p>
      <p>When the waitress comes back for the bill, she discovers the
    girl missing and believes that she has left without paying. She
    angrily crumples up the comic book and throws it into a garbage
    can. Then, since the comic book is crumpled, the pages overlap
    and touch, allowing the two motorcycle villains to cross over
    into the panels containing Harket and the girl. One, wielding a
    pipe wrench, smashes the window. Harket punches one of the
    thugs and retreats with the girl into a maze created by the
    crumpled paper. Harket tears a hole in one panel so the girl
    can escape as he faces the two thugs with his own monkey
    wrench. She reluctantly complies, and reappears on the floor in
    the coffee shop, to the surprise of the shop clientele and
    employees. The startled girl grabs the crumpled comic book and
    runs home, where she attempts to smoothe out the creases to
    learn what happens next.</p>
      <p>One of the panels shows Harket seemingly lying lifeless, and
    she begins to cry. Harket then wakes up and begins throwing
    himself against the edges of the panel of the comic book's
    page, attempting to break out into the real world. As he does
    this, he begins to flash between animation and live action. The
    live-action version of him appears in the hallway leading to
    the girl's room, throwing himself against the corridor walls.
    He finally escapes from the comic book by becoming human and
    embraces the girl. This final scene is based on the 1980 movie 
    <i>Altered States</i>.</p>
      <p>At the 1986 MTV Video Music Awards, the video for "Take on
    Me" won six awards—Best New Artist in a Video, Best Concept
    Video, Most Experimental Video, Best Direction, Best Special
    Effects, and Viewer's Choice—and was nominated for two others,
    Best Group Video and Video of the Year. It was also nominated
    for Favorite Pop/Rock Video at the 13th American Music Awards
    in 1986.</p>
      <p>"Take on Me" was originally released in 1984, and was mixed
    by Tony Mansfield, but failed to make an impact in the United
    Kingdom. The group re-recorded the song with the help of
    producer Alan Tarney, releasing it for the second time in late
    1984, peaking at number three in Norway but also failing to
    reach audiences abroad.</p>
      <p>In the United States, Warner Bros. invested in the
    revolutionary second video for "Take on Me," which used
    Tarney's version of the song. The new video was released to
    dance clubs and television a month before the record was
    available in stores or played on the radio. Wide exposure on
    MTV made the song quickly soar to the top position of the Hot
    100 on 19 October 1985. It remained on the chart for
    twenty-three weeks, and ended up at the tenth position of the
    1985 year-end chart.</p>
      <p>"Take on Me" was released for the third time in the United
    Kingdom in September 1985. The song debuted on the UK Singles
    Chart at number fifty-five, peaked at number two for three
    weeks, and received a gold certification by the British
    Phonographic Industry (BPI). In Norway, a-ha's native country,
    "Take on Me" reentered the VG-lista singles chart, reaching a
    new peak of number one, a year after it was first released. The
    single was largely successful across the rest of Europe,
    reaching the top of the Eurochart Hot 100 for nine weeks,
    topping the singles charts in Austria, Belgium, Germany, Italy,
    the Netherlands, Sweden, and Switzerland, and reaching the top
    three in France and Ireland.</p>
      <p>(On this record, Pål Waaktaar is miscredited as Päl
    Waktaar)</p>
      <p>In 1999, ska punk band Reel Big Fish covered "Take on Me"
    for the film 
    <i>BASEketball</i>. The song was later released on the
    soundtrack and the international version of their album 
    <i>Why Do They Rock So Hard?</i>. The band also performed the
    song at concerts. Reel Big Fish released a video clip for "Take
    On Me", directed by Jeff Moore, and features the band playing
    the song while walking down an aisle in the stadium, and
    playing a game of BASEketball interlaced with clips from the
    film. An alternative video for the song's international release
    that contained only the stadium aisle footage was also
    released. Reel Big Fish also included a live version of the
    song in their live album 
    <i>Our Live Album Is Better than Your Live Album</i>and live
    DVD's 
    <i>You're All In This Together</i>and 
    <i>Reel Big Fish Live! In Concert!</i>.</p>
      <p>In August 2000, British boy band a1 released a cover of
    "Take on Me" for their second studio album 
    <i>The A list</i>. Despite being panned by music critics, who
    called it a "lame cover version", and a "note for note copy"
    that seems like "a re-release of the original"; it was
    commercially successful, topping the charts in Norway and the
    United Kingdom, where it was certified silver by the BPI. The
    cover's music video was directed by Stuart Gosling, and
    features the band saving the world from a deadly computer
    virus, an inspiration from the 1982 science fiction film 
    <i>TRON</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
