<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dancing_Queen 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dancing_Queen</songId>
   <title>Dancing Queen</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ABBA</artistId>
      <artistName>ABBA</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1977-04-09</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/8d/Dancing_Queen_That%27s_Me.jpg/200px-Dancing_Queen_That%27s_Me.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/ABBA+Dancing-Queen.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Arrival</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>16 August 1976 (Sweden) , 21 August 1976 (UK) , 12 November 1976 (US)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1975</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco / Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:51</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Polar (Sweden) , Epic (UK) , Atlantic (US)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Björn Ulvaeus</writer>
      <writer>Benny Andersson</writer>
      <writer>Stig Anderson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Björn Ulvaeus</producer>
      <producer>Benny Andersson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Dancing Queen" is a pop song recorded by Swedish pop group
    ABBA, released in 1976. It was the follow-up single to the hit
    "Fernando" and is commonly regarded as one of the most
    successful singles of the 1970s. Dancing Queen was written by
    Benny Andersson, Björn Ulvaeus, and Stig Anderson and is
    considered by many to be ABBA's signature song as it reached
    the number 1 position on popular music charts in 13 countries.
    Recorded in 1975 for the group's album 
    <i>Arrival</i>, it was released as a single the following year
    with "That's Me" as the B-side.</p>
      <p>In May 2004, the British performing rights group
    Phonographic Performance Limited celebrated its 70th
    anniversary by listing the 70 songs that have played most in
    Great Britain on the radio, in clubs and on jukeboxes. On this
    list "Dancing Queen" featured at number 6.</p>
      <p>"Dancing Queen" features the shared lead vocal performance
    by Agnetha Fältskog and Anni-Frid Lyngstad. Its opening
    keyboard glissando is one of the most instantly recognizable
    intros in pop music.</p>
      <p>The recording sessions for "Dancing Queen" began on 4 August
    1975. The demo was called "Boogaloo" and as the sessions
    progressed, Andersson and Ulvaeus found inspiration to the
    dance rhythm in George McCrae's disco classic "Rock Your Baby",
    as well as the drumming on Dr. John's 1972 album 
    <i>Dr. John's Gumbo</i>. Fältskog and Lyngstad recorded the
    vocals on sessions in September, and the track was completed
    three months later.</p>
      <p>During the sessions, Benny Andersson brought a tape home
    with the backing track on it and played it to his then-fiancée
    and band member, singer Anni-Frid Lyngstad, who apparently
    started crying when listening. "I found the song so beautiful.
    It's one of those songs that goes straight to your heart."</p>
      <p>While working on the lyrics, half of the second verse was
    scrapped: "Baby, baby, you're out of sight/hey, you're looking
    alright tonight/when you come to the party/listen to the
    guys/they've got the look in their eyes...". It survives in
    footage from a recording session.</p>
      <p>The track was premiered on Swedish tv on June 18, 1976,
    during an all-star live gala in honour of King Carl XVI Gustaf
    of Sweden and his bride to be, Silvia Sommerlath, who were to
    be wedded on June 19. Benny Andersson has cited it as "one of
    those songs where you 
    <i>know</i>during the sessions that it's going to be a smash
    hit". Also Agnetha Fältskog has stated in a TV-programe: "It's
    often difficult to know what will be a hit. The exception was
    Dancing Queen. We all knew it was going to be massive".</p>
      <p>"Dancing Queen" was massive. It became ABBA's only #1 in the
    United States in April 1977. It also hit #1 in at least 13
    other countries worldwide: Australia, Belgium, Brazil, Germany,
    Great Britain, Ireland, Mexico, The Netherlands, New Zealand,
    Norway, South Africa, Sweden and Zimbabwe. "Dancing Queen" also
    reached the Top 5 in Austria, Canada, Finland, France and
    Switzerland. The track peaked at #14 in Italy, where ABBA never
    achieved the same degree of popularity as elsewhere.</p>
      <p>"Dancing Queen" was their last of 3 consecutive Number 1's
    they had in the UK in 1976, with "Mamma Mia" and "Fernando"
    being #1 earlier in the year.</p>
      <p>In 1993, in honor of Swedish Queen Silvia´s 50th birthday,
    Anni-Frid Lyngstad was asked to perform "Dancing Queen" on
    stage, repeating ABBA's 1976 performance of the song at the
    wedding reception of King Carl XVI Gustaf and Queen Silvia.
    Frida contacted The Real Group and together they did an a
    cappella version of the song on stage at the Royal Opera House
    in Stockholm, in front of the king and queen. The Swedish Prime
    Minister at that time, Ingvar Carlsson, was also in the
    audience that night and he said it was an ingenious step to do
    "Dancing Queen" a cappella. This performance with Lyngstad and
    The Real Group, was filmed by Swedish Television SVT and is
    included in Frida - The DVD.</p>
      <p>In 1992, the song was re-released in the UK, as Erasure
    sparked an ABBA revival after the success of their 
    <i>Abba-esque</i>EP topping the UK charts. The re-issued
    "Dancing Queen" reached #16 in the UK in September 1992.</p>
      <p>In 2000, "Dancing Queen" came fourth in a Channel 4
    television poll of "The 100 Best Number Ones" in 2001. It was
    chosen as number 148 as part of the 365 Songs of the Century
    list. It is also ranked #171 on Rolling Stone's list of The 500
    Greatest Songs of All Time, the only ABBA song on the list.
    That same year, it made VH1's 
    <i>100 Greatest Dance Songs in Rock &amp; Roll</i>at #97.</p>
      <p>On 9 November 2002, the results of a poll, "Top 50 Favorite
    UK #1's", was broadcast on Radio 2, celebrating the 50th
    anniversary of The Official UK Charts Company. 188,357
    listeners voted and "Dancing Queen" came out at #8.</p>
      <p>Former U.S. presidential candidate John McCain named
    "Dancing Queen" as his favorite song in a top 10 list submitted
    to Blender Magazine in August 2008.</p>
      <p>In August 2008, "Dancing Queen" surpassed the 500,000 mark
    for digital sales in the US (512,000).</p>
      <p>For their 1980 Spanish language album/compilation "Gracias
    Por La Música", ABBA recorded a Spanish version of "Dancing
    Queen", renamed "Reina Danzante", with Spanish lyrics provided
    by Buddy and Mary McCluskey.</p>
      <p>The first International Standard Musical Work Code was
    assigned in 1995 to "Dancing Queen"; the code is
    T-000.000.001-0.</p>
      <p>"Dancing Queen" was A*Teens' fourth and final single from
    their first album 
    <i>The ABBA Generation</i>. It is a cover of the ABBA song of
    the same name.</p>
      <p>When the single came out in the spring of 2000, it peaked at
    number-one in Mexico, becoming their first number-one hit in
    that country, the song was also a smash hit in South America
    peaking at number three in Argentina, number five in Chile,
    number six in Colombia and number fifteen in Brazil.</p>
      <p>This was the main single for the United States promotion,
    when the album was released in March 2000. "Dancing Queen"
    reached ninety-five on the Billboard Hot 100, thirty-six on
    Airplay and number thirteen on the Hot Single Sales Chart.</p>
      <p>"Dancing Queen" was released as a double A-side with "The
    Name of the Game" in Europe, where both the songs were promoted
    on radio at the same time, because Universal Music thought that
    "Dancing Queen", being the last single, needed a back-up to be
    successful. The video for "The Name of the Game" was an
    unofficial video, made especially for an A*Teens TV special in
    Sweden and it was never intended to be a promotional video. It
    was only aired by Channel 4.</p>
      <p>Directed by Patrick Kiely, it was the first A*Teens video to
    be filmed in the United States. It was filmed on 7 March 2000,
    the same day the song was released. The video was tribute to
    the movie 
    <i>The Breakfast Club</i>. Paul Gleason (now deceased), the
    actor who played the principal in the movie, plays the same
    role in the video. When the principal leaves the members of the
    band alone in the detention room (which was actually the
    library), the school turns into a 70s discotheque.</p>
      <p>European 2-Track CD single</p>
      <p>European/Mexican CD maxi</p>
      <p>U.S. CD single</p>
      <p>U.S. cassette</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
