<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Don%27t_Want_to_Miss_a_Thing 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Don%27t_Want_to_Miss_a_Thing</songId>
   <title>I Don't Want to Miss a Thing</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aerosmith</artistId>
      <artistName>Aerosmith</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1998-09-05</week>
      <week>1998-09-12</week>
      <week>1998-09-19</week>
      <week>1998-09-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/d2/Idontwanttomissathing.jpg/200px-Idontwanttomissathing.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Aerosmith+I-Don-t-Want-to-Miss-a-Thing.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Armageddon Soundtrack</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 18, 1998</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Cassette</format>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1998</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:56</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Diane Warren</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mark Wright</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Don't Want to Miss a Thing" is a power ballad by American
    rock band Aerosmith. It appeared on the soundtrack to the film 
    <i>Armageddon</i>and debuted at number one on the Billboard Hot
    100 (a first for the band after 28 years together). The song
    stayed at number one for four weeks from September 5 to
    September 26, 1998, introducing Aerosmith to a new generation
    of fans. The song also stayed at #1 for several weeks in
    several other countries. The song rose steadily up the charts
    in the United Kingdom, peaking at number four in November 1998
    and becoming Aerosmith's highest charting song in the UK to
    date.</p>
      <p>"I Don't Want to Miss a Thing" was written primarily by
    Diane Warren. She stated in her compilation album 
    <i>Diane Warren Presents Love Songs</i>that the song was
    originally meant for Celine Dion.</p>
      <p>The music video for this song was shot in the Minneapolis
    Armory in 1998. It features the band playing the song
    intertwined with scenes from 
    <i>Armageddon</i>. It features a cameo appearance by Steven
    Tyler's daughter Liv Tyler, who plays Grace Stamper in the
    film. Liv previously had a role in the music video for another
    of the band's songs, "Crazy".</p>
      <p>The video begins with shots of the moon and several
    meteorites passing by and then a view of earth before zooming
    in to show Steven Tyler singing. The shots interchange between
    the band and Mission Control viewing the band singing via their
    monitors. As the video progresses it reveals that the band is
    playing in front of what appears to be the fictional Space
    Shuttle 
    <i>Freedom</i>. Along with Aerosmith, a full hand orchestra
    plays in sync with the melody. Smoke surrounds the orchestra
    and Aerosmith as 
    <i>Freedom</i>takes off from the launch pad. Finally, the
    screen goes out as a tearful Grace touches one of the monitors
    to reach out to her father (real life father Steven Tyler in
    the video; on-screen father Harry Stamper, played by Bruce
    Willis, in the film).</p>
      <p>During the filming of the video for "I Don't Want to Miss a
    Thing", Steven Tyler was still recovering from a leg injury
    sustained during the Nine Lives Tour and thus he does not move
    much in the video.</p>
      <p>The song was Aerosmith's most successful single in their
    career, debuting at #1 on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100, where it
    stayed for four weeks in September, and became a huge hit for
    the band internationally, reaching #1 in many countries around
    the world, including Australia, Germany, Ireland, Austria,
    Norway, Italy, the Netherlands, and Switzerland. "I Don't Want
    to Miss a Thing" remains the only song by a rock band to debut
    at #1 on the Billboard Hot 100. It was a shift from the hard
    rock music Aerosmith was ordinarily known for, and being more
    of a pop-rock song, only reached #4 on Billboard's Mainstream
    Rock Tracks chart.</p>
      <p>The song was nominated for an Academy Award for Best Song in
    1999. The song was also nominated in the Worst "Original" Song
    category at the 19th Golden Raspberry Awards 1998.</p>
      <p>The song helped open Aerosmith up to a new generation and
    remains a slow dance staple. 
    <i>American Idol</i>judge Simon Cowell labeled the song "one of
    the great songs of all time" during the show's seventh season.
    It remains one of Aerosmith's most popular songs.</p>
      <p>CD Single</p>
      <p>The song appeared on the Argentine version of the album 
    <i>Nine Lives</i>. It also appeared on the Japanese version of 
    <i>Just Push Play</i>.</p>
      <p>CD Single 2</p>
      <p>Crash and the original Pink appeared as tracks 9 and 11,
    respectively, on all versions of the album Nine Lives.</p>
      <p>In late 1998, country music artist Mark Chesnutt recorded a
    cover version of the song. His rendition is the first single
    from, and title track to, his 1999 album 
    <i>I Don't Want to Miss a Thing</i>. Chesnutt's cover spent two
    weeks at number one on the U.S. 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Country Singles &amp; Tracks (now Hot
    Country Songs) charts in early 1999, and is the last of his
    eight Number Ones on that chart. It is also the first of only
    two singles in his career to reach the Billboard Hot 100, where
    it peaked at #17 in early 1999.</p>
      <p>Allison Iraheta performed "I Don't Want to Miss a Thing"
    during the Top 7 (Idol in the Movies) week on American Idol
    Season 8, and again in an appearance on Live with Regis and
    Kelly on May 11, 2009.</p>
      <p>American pop punk band New Found Glory recorded a cover
    version in 2000, which was released on their cover album 
    <i>From the Screen to Your Stereo</i>. It is available as an
    Easter egg on some DVD copies of the 2003 film 
    <i>I'll Be There</i>, where it can be heard playing over the
    end of the closing credits.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
