<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Matter 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Matter</songId>
   <title>Don't Matter</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Akon</artistId>
      <artistName>Akon</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2007-04-07</week>
      <week>2007-04-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f4/Akon_Don%27t_Matter.jpg/200px-Akon_Don%27t_Matter.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Akon+Don-t-Matter.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Konvicted</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 18, 2007  (2007-01-18) , (see Release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>Digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Reggae Fusion</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:52 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>4:22 (Radio Version)</length>
      <length>3:02 (UK Radio Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Konvict / UpFront / SRC / Universal</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Thiam</writer>
      <writer>A./ Lawson</writer>
      <writer>A.</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Akon</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Don't Matter" is a pop–R&amp;B song recorded by Akon for
    his second studio album 
    <i>Konvicted</i>(2006). The song was released as the album's
    third single in early 2007. In April 2007, it became Akon's
    first solo U.S. number-one single and second number-one
    overall. A crucial part of the chorus takes from Bob Marley's
    1979 classic "Zimbabwe". The bridge also borrows the melody
    from R. Kelly's song "Ignition (Remix)". This song was #31 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s list of the 100 Best Songs of 2007. This
    song was also #81 on 
    <i>MTV Asia</i>'s list of Top 100 Hits of 2007.</p>
      <p>"Don't Matter" was released in the U.S. in mid-January 2007.
    The song made its debut at number seventy-nine on the Hot 100
    and reached number one after ten weeks on the chart, in large
    part due to its substantial airplay, the song topping the Hot
    100 Airplay chart for two weeks. In the UK, it debuted on the
    singles chart at number forty-five, based solely upon
    downloads, and late peaking at number three following a
    physical release. Following the song's debut inside the top ten
    on the singles chart in Canada, it peaked at number one for a
    period of three weeks. As of January 2008, the song has been
    certified 3 times platinum for 3,000,000 digital sales. Bizzy
    Bone made a remix with this song.</p>
      <p>Fall Out Boy did a cover of "Don't Matter" for their live
    album, 
    <i>****: Live in Phoenix</i>. They also performed the song at
    their June 12, 2007 concert, the night after their bassist Pete
    Wentz got in a fight with a fan.</p>
      <p>The music video starts with Akon picking up his date at a
    location. As he leaves with this date, an old man (presumably a
    relative of the date) is shown both reading a magazine about
    Akon partying at local clubs and staring at the two with an
    angry look. The video continues with Akon singing "Don't
    Matter" throughout the course of his date. It is set in a
    Caribbean beach style community at social places such as the
    beach, village market, and a dance. A scene in the video where
    Akon photographs his date taking off her bra has led to some
    controversy. Notably, in the video's final scene, the music
    becomes much more lively, with a Caribbean style rhythm playing
    under the songs chorus. It has a cameo appearance by
    Cuban-American rapper Pitbull. The music video is one of the
    most viewed videos on YouTube, so far #9[1], with one "Don't
    Matter" video having over 60 million views, while others having
    over 11 million, 11 million and 4 million[2].</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
