<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Here_in_My_Heart 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Here_in_My_Heart</songId>
   <title>Here in My Heart</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Al_Martino</artistId>
      <artistName>Al Martino</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1952-06-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Here in My Heart" is a popular song, written by Pat Genaro,
    Lou Levinson, and Bill Borrelli, and published in 1952.</p>
      <p>A recording of the song by Al Martino was a #1 hit single on
    the United States pop chart. The Martino version also made
    history as the first number one on the UK Singles Chart, on 14
    November 1952. "Here in My Heart" remained in the top position
    for nine weeks in the United Kingdom, setting a record for the
    longest consecutive run at number one, a record which, over 50
    years on, has only been beaten by five other tracks -
    "(Everything I Do) I Do It for You" (16 weeks), the Wet Wet Wet
    version of "Love Is All Around" (15), "Cara Mia" (10 weeks),
    "Umbrella" (10 weeks) and Whitney Houston's version of I Will
    Always Love You (10 weeks). Frankie Laine's "I Believe" spent a
    total of 18 weeks at number one, but not consecutive weeks,
    instead totalling 18 weeks across several runs at the top.</p>
      <p>By staying at number one until 1953 in the UK, Martino
    secured for himself the record of being the only performer to
    have a number one hit in the entire year of 1952. Needless to
    say, no subsequent act has ever dominated the top spot so
    entirely in any later year.</p>
      <p>Other versions, recorded by Vic Damone (reaching #8 on the
    Billboard chart), and Tony Bennett (reaching #15 on the chart),
    were also recorded around the same time. A rhythm and blues
    version was also recorded that year, by Wini Brown and her Boy
    Friends. Mario Lanza had also planned to record this song, but
    changed his mind when asked to by Martino so his own recording
    would not be neglected.[1]</p>
      <p>In 1961, Martino re-recorded the song, although it only
    reached #86 on the Billboard Top 100 chart (Top 20 on their
    "Easy Listening" survey). He had previously rerecorded the song
    in an unsuccessful rockaballad version for MGM's Cub label.</p>
      <p>In 1963, Richard Harris performed this song in the film 
    <i>This Sporting Life</i>, although he would not release his
    first album until four years later, with 1967's 
    <i>Camelot</i>.</p>
      <p>The track was Al Martino's only UK number one hit; his
    subsequent releases failed to reach the top of the charts, and
    his final UK chart appearance was in 1973, when a reissue of
    "Spanish Eyes" reached the top five.</p>
      <p>The song Heart(Less) by Kanute samples the opening
    verse.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
