<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No_One_(Alicia_Keys_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No_One_(Alicia_Keys_song)</songId>
   <title>No One</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alicia_Keys</artistId>
      <artistName>Alicia Keys</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2007-12-01</week>
      <week>2007-12-08</week>
      <week>2007-12-15</week>
      <week>2007-12-22</week>
      <week>2007-12-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/c/cf/Alicia_Keys_-_No_One_single_cover.jpg/200px-Alicia_Keys_-_No_One_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Alicia-Keys+No-One.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>As I Am</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 11, 2007</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Glenwood Place Studios , ( Burbank , California ) , Oven Studios , ( Long Island , New York )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:13 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>4:06 (Radio Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>J</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Alicia Keys</writer>
      <writer>Kerry Brothers</writer>
      <writer>Jr.</writer>
      <writer>George D. Harry</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Alicia Keys</producer>
      <producer>Kerry "Krucial" Brothers</producer>
      <producer>Dirty Harry</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"No One" is a song by American R&amp;B and soul
    singer–songwriter Alicia Keys from her third studio album, 
    <i>As I Am</i>(2007). Written and produced by Keys, Kerry
    Brothers, Jr., and George D. Harry, and released as the album's
    lead single in September 2007, this is overall Keys' biggest
    hit to date, having topped several singles charts, including
    the Hot 100 for five consecutive weeks and the Hot
    R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs for ten consecutive weeks. "No One" was
    ranked at number forty-two on The 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 All-Time Top Songs and number fourteen
    on the Top 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs. It is her second
    solo number-one single in the United States after 2001's
    "Fallin'". In 2009 the song was named number six on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade.</p>
      <p>The song won Best Female R&amp;B Vocal Performance and Best
    R&amp;B Song at the 2008 Grammy Awards on February 10, 2008.
    During the ceremony, Keys performed it in a duet with John
    Mayer. "No One" was also the most listened song on U.S. radio
    of 2008 with 3.08 billion listeners.</p>
      <p>Keys told MTV News Canada that the song "is really talking
    about the way that in relationships, the way that so many
    things are around you all the time to try to distract you. And
    even though people may talk and say whatever they may want to
    say, but then no one can get in the way of this."</p>
      <p>The song was first heard in August 2007 after Keys included
    a clip of the song in a newsletter on her official website and
    fan club. It was released officially on September 10, 2007, and
    its radio premiere was on Atlanta's WVEE on August 29.</p>
      <p>Keys performed a medley of "No One" with George Michael's
    "Freedom! '90" at the 2007 MTV Video Music Awards on September
    9. Remixes of the song featuring Lil' Kim, Damian Marley,
    Junior Reid, Beenie Man, Barbee, and Kanye West exist. The
    official remix has a different but similar beat from the
    original version and features rapper Cassidy, it was produced
    by Swizz Beatz.</p>
      <p>It was ranked at number three on the recap of The 10 Best
    Songs of 2007 by 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>, while it was voted number
    twenty-three in 
    <i>The Village Voice</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s 2007 Pazz &amp; Jop
    critics' poll (tied with Modest Mouse's "Dashboard", R. Kelly's
    "I'm a Flirt" (Remix) featuring T.I. and T-Pain, and Avril
    Lavigne's "Girlfriend").</p>
      <p>With only one full day of airplay, "No One" debuted at
    number sixty-five on the U.S. 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs chart the week of
    September 8, 2007. Seven weeks later, it reached the top
    position for ten weeks—becoming Keys' fifth number-one single
    on the chart—before being knocked out by her own song "Like
    You'll Never See Me Again" the first charting week of 2008. The
    song initially debuted at number fifteen on the Bubbling Under
    Hot 100 Singles the week of September 15, 2007, and managed to
    jump to the Hot 100 at number seventy-one the following week
    without the benefit of download sales. The following week, it
    rose to number fifteen because of digital downloads, and
    reached the top spot the charting week of December 1, 2007,
    staying atop for five weeks, preventing Timbaland and
    OneRepublic's hit "Apologize" from reaching the summit. It is
    Keys' first solo single to reach number one on the Hot 100
    since her debut single 2001's "Fallin'" and her third single,
    to date, to top the chart. The song's success marked Keys'
    return to the top twenty of the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 in three years; her last appearance
    occurred with the number-twenty entry "Karma". Furthermore, "No
    One" went on to top eleven other charts: the Hot 100 Airplay
    (for fourteen weeks in a row, the longest run atop the chart
    since Mariah Carey's 2005 hit "We Belong Together" spent
    sixteen weeks at number one), the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Airplay,
    the Hot Adult R&amp;B Airplay, the Pop 100, the Pop 100
    Airplay, the Top 40 Mainstream, the Rhythmic Top 40, the Hot
    Digital Songs, the Hot Digital Tracks, the Hot RingMasters, and
    the Hot Videoclip Tracks. The song was ranked number three on
    the Top Hot 100 Hits of 2008.</p>
      <p>"No One" was a massive success in Europe, reaching number
    two on the composite European Hot 100 Singles as well as
    topping the singles chart in Switzerland and Hungary, while
    charting inside the top five in France, Germany, Italy,
    Portugal, the Netherlands, Belgium, Austria, Sweden, Slovakia,
    and Turkey, and the top ten in the United Kingdom (where the
    single became Keys' first solo top ten hit since "Fallin'",
    peaking at number six, and sold in excess of 200,000 copies),
    Ireland, Spain, Denmark, and Norway. "No One" has re-entered
    the UK Singles Chart twice since its official release, both
    times due television exposure (firstly after being performed by
    an auditionee on 
    <i>Britain's Got Talent</i>and secondly after Keys herself
    performed it within a medley on 
    <i>The X Factor</i>). In May 2009 it re-entered at number
    fifty-four and in December 2009 it re-entered at number
    fifty-one. In total "No One" has spent twenty-nine weeks inside
    the UK top one hundred singles, making it by far her
    longest-charting single in the UK. It also charted highly in
    Oceania, spending three consecutive weeks at number three in
    Australia and six non-consecutive weeks at number two in New
    Zealand.</p>
      <p>In the week between October 22–25, "No One" gained 14.3% in
    radio airplay and audience impressions which marks the single
    at number one. 
    <i>As I Am</i>was also at number one that week.</p>
      <p>The song's music video, directed by Justin Francis,
    premiered on BET on September 24, 2007; it debuted on 
    <i>106 and Park</i>at number ten the following day, and has
    since peaked at number one. It premiered on Yahoo! Music on
    September 25 at number five and peaked at number one, and it
    premiered on 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>on October 4 and peaked at number one.
    It debuted on VH1's 
    <i>VSpot Top 20 Countdown</i>at number three, peaking at number
    one. The video was ranked at number twenty-two on VH1's Top 40
    Videos of 2007 and at number two on BET's "Notarized: Top 100
    videos of 2007".</p>
      <p>The video for "No One" consists of four settings: the first
    one shows Keys lying on a chair in an empty room; the second
    one is a musical instrument-decorated room in which Keys sings
    accompanied by a keyboard; in the third one Keys is initially
    alone, playing the piano on a rainy street, and she later finds
    herself surrounded with dozens of people; in the fourth and
    final one Keys is in a blue-lit nightclub. The video ends with
    a gear divided into four fractions, each one featuring a
    previously shown setting, and with Keys lying on the chair in
    the same room shown at the very beginning of the video.</p>
      <p>As of October 2009, the official video alone has had over
    eighty-four million views on YouTube, and peaks at number five
    on the website's rank of all-time most viewed videos as well as
    number four on the rank of all-time most viewed videos in the
    music category.</p>
      <p>"No One" was used in the theatrical trailer for the 2008
    romantic comedy film 
    <i>27 Dresses</i>, as well as in the 
    <i>Ugly Betty</i>episode "Burning Questions", originally aired
    on May 1, 2008. Felicia Barton sang the song in the top 36
    night on the March 3 show of 
    <i>American Idol</i>. Ten-year-old Natalie Okri performed the
    song on 
    <i>Britain's Got Talent</i>in auditions 6 of the show, which
    aired on May 16, 2009, receiving rave reviews from the judges
    and a standing ovation from the audience. In the 2009 film 
    <i>Alvin and the Chipmunks: The Squeakquel</i>, The Chipettes
    sing the song with Filipina singer Charice Pempengco. This
    version was released on the film's soundtrack on December 1,
    2009.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
