<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fallin%27 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fallin%27</songId>
   <title>Fallin'</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alicia_Keys</artistId>
      <artistName>Alicia Keys</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2001-08-18</week>
      <week>2001-08-25</week>
      <week>2001-09-01</week>
      <week>2001-09-29</week>
      <week>2001-10-06</week>
      <week>2001-10-13</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/6d/Alicia-keys-fallin-single.jpg/200px-Alicia-keys-fallin-single.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Alicia-Keys+Fallin.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Songs in A Minor</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 5, 2001  (2001-06-05)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2001; KrucialKeys Studios , ( New York City , New York )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:30 (album version)</length>
      <length>3:16 (radio edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>J</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Alicia Keys</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Alicia Keys</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Fallin'" is a song recorded, written, and produced by
    American R&amp;B-soul singer–songwriter Alicia Keys for her
    debut album, 
    <i>Songs in A Minor</i>(2001). Released to radio and music
    video outlets in 2001, it is generally considered her signature
    song. "Fallin'" became Keys' first number-one single in the
    United States and her first top five hit in several countries.
    It is also Keys' second biggest single to date after 2007's "No
    One". "Fallin'" won three Grammy Awards in 2002, including Song
    of the Year, Best R&amp;B Song, and Best Female R&amp;B Vocal
    Performance. In 2009 the single was named the 29th most
    successful song of the 2000s, on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>ranked it number sixty-two on their Top 100
    Songs of the 2000s decade. The song charted at 413 in 
    <i>Blender</i>magazine's 500 Greatest Songs Since You Were
    Born.</p>
      <p>Keys described the song as being a strong representative of
    who she was as an artist. She explained that the song was about
    the "ins and outs" of being in a relationship. She went on to
    say, "Sometimes, you're completely head-over-heels in love with
    someone, and sometimes you can't stand that person. You fall in
    and out, sometimes it goes back and forth, and that's just what
    relationships are about."</p>
      <p>Although it is regarded as Keys' signature song, it almost
    did not become her single. Before she joined J Records, Keys
    had signed a recording contract with Sony's Columbia Records.
    Sony felt that Keys should sing more mainstream-accessible
    material written by others, while she insisted upon recording
    her own compositions. As a result, Keys' recording career
    remained in limbo for two years. Bored and with free time on
    her hands because of Sony's lack of interest in her, Keys
    decided to put her time to good use and began to write a song.
    Instantly, arpeggios hit her, and she became inspired with the
    chords that would define "Fallin'". She quickly composed lyrics
    basing the tune on the emotions she faced during one of her
    first serious romantic relationships.</p>
      <p>As Keys was still in artistic limbo, the song was originally
    not meant for her; Sony intended to have Kim Scott, a child
    prodigy signed to their label, record "Fallin'". Keys became
    uneasy over the matter, as she wanted to record the song
    herself, but could not because Sony was not focusing on her
    career. At first Keys had surrendered the piece to Scott
    willingly, but later changed her mind, and Scott did not record
    it. Clive Davis, a former Columbia executive then at Arista
    Records, heard about Keys and was impressed with her artistry.
    After Davis started a label of his own, J Records, he bought
    out Keys' Sony contract and signed her to his label.</p>
      <p>Once at J Records, Keys began working on her debut album, 
    <i>Songs in A Minor</i>. Unlike Sony, J Records did not mind
    Keys recording her own compositions, and encouraged her to do
    so. When it was time for a first single to be chosen,
    "Girlfriend", a song Keys had worked on with Jermaine Dupri
    while at Columbia, was considered, but Keys and other
    executives agreed that "Fallin'" would be the best choice.</p>
      <p>"Fallin'" is a gospel-influenced song. It begins with piano
    and basic drum programming, then proportionally builds up to a
    crescendo. The record also features a violin performance of the
    pizzicato and legato strings by Miri Ben-Ari. Keys'
    collaborator Kerry "Krucial" Brothers provides the song's
    digital programming. The song samples 1966's "It's a Man's
    Man's Man's World" by James Brown. The song is written in the
    key of E minor.</p>
      <p>The song was one of the most critically acclaimed songs of
    the year. Barry Walters of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>compared Keys performance in the song to an
    Aretha Franklin vibe. Sal Cinquemani of Slant Magazine
    complimented Keys' voice, saying it was a "restrained vocal
    that never permeates the track's tight arrangement". Christian
    Ward of 
    <i>NME</i>alluded to the song being emotional, saying it will
    make the listener "weep 'til you're a dribbling, snotty wreck".
    Simon Price of 
    <i>The Independent</i>called the song Keys' breakthrough song.
    Stephen Thomas Erlewine of Allmusic pointed out the lack of
    depth in the song, saying it "doesn't have much body to it",
    which he felt was "a testament to Keys' skills as a musician".
    The song was listed at number four hundred and thirteen on 
    <i>Blender</i>magazine's list of The 500 Greatest Songs Since
    You Were Born and at number four in 
    <i>The Village Voice</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s 2001 Pazz &amp; Jop
    critics' poll. "Fallin'" was banned from many 
    <i>Australian Idol</i>auditions due to its popularity.</p>
      <p>"Fallin'" was released in April 2001 as Keys' debut single,
    amidst considerable promotion and praise from Davis and J
    Records. "Fallin'" peaked at number one on the U.S. Hot 100 and
    Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs charts and remained there for six and
    four weeks, respectively. It also reached the top position in
    the Netherlands, Belgium, and New Zealand as well as the top
    five in the United Kingdom, France, Italy, Germany, Austria,
    Switzerland, Norway, and Ireland and the top ten in Sweden and
    Australia. A remix of the song, featuring Busta Rhymes and
    Rampage from the Flipmode Squad (also at that time signed to J
    Records), included on the British edition of her album,
    reimagines the song as a hip hop-flavored dance song. Since its
    release, "Fallin'" has become a popular standard for
    contestants in the reality television series 
    <i>American Idol</i>.</p>
      <p>As one of the most critically acclaimed singles of 2001,
    "Fallin'" was nominated for several awards. "Fallin'" connected
    well with NARAS as the song was nominated in 2002 for four
    Grammy Awards: Song of the Year, Record of the Year, Best
    Female R&amp;B Vocal Performance, and Best R&amp;B Song. It
    ended up winning Song of the Year, Best Female R&amp;B Vocal
    Performance, and Best R&amp;B Song (Record of the Year was
    awarded to U2's "Walk On").</p>
      <p>At the 2001 Billboard Music Awards, "Fallin'" was nominated
    for the Hot 100 Single of the Year; however, it lost the award
    to Lifehouse's "Hanging by a Moment". The song was also
    nominated for Outstanding Song and Outstanding Music Video at
    the 2002 NAACP Image Awards; it did not win in either
    category.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Fallin'", directed by Chris Robinson.
    Unlike most other contemporary R&amp;B videos, the video for
    "Fallin'" was a low-key clip with no dancing. The video opens
    with a radio playing "Girlfriend", where Keys is sitting at a
    piano. The plot has Keys traveling to a prison to visit her
    incarcerated boyfriend. The plot is continued in the video for
    Keys' next single, "A Woman's Worth", which explores what
    happens when Keys' boyfriend is released and, with her help,
    adjusts back to regular life. Keys said in an interview that
    she was supposed to be the one incarcerated, and her boyfriend
    was visiting her.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
