<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Horse_With_No_Name 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Horse_With_No_Name</songId>
   <title>A Horse With No Name</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/America_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>America</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1972-03-25</week>
      <week>1972-04-01</week>
      <week>1972-04-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/89/AmericaHorseWithNoNameCover.jpg/200px-AmericaHorseWithNoNameCover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/America+A-Horse-With-No-Name.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>America</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 31, 1972</released>
   <formats>
      <format>vinyl record</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1971</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Folk Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:08</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Warner Brothers</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Dewey Bunnell</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Ian Samwell</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"A Horse with No Name" is a song by the band America. It was
    their first and most successful single, released in early 1972,
    topping the charts in several countries. It was certified
    "gold" by the Recording Industry Association of America.</p>
      <p>America's self-titled debut album was released initially in
    Europe with only moderate success and without the song "A Horse
    with No Name". Trying to find a song that would be popular in
    both the United States and Europe, "A Horse with No Name" was
    originally called "Desert Song" and was written while the band
    was staying at the home studio of Arthur Brown, in Puddletown,
    Dorset. The first two demos were recorded there, by Jeff Dexter
    and Dennis Elliott, and was intended to capture the feel of the
    hot, dry desert, that had been depicted at the studio from
    Salvador Dalí painting, and the strange horse had ridden out of
    an M.C. Escher picture. Writer Dewey Bunnell also says he
    remembered his childhood travels through the Arizona and New
    Mexico desert when his family lived at Vandenberg Air Force
    Base.</p>
      <p>"A Horse with No Name" was recorded in the key of E minor
    with acoustic guitars, bass guitar, and bongo drums. The only
    other chord is a Dadd6add9, fretted on the low E and G strings,
    second fret. A 12 string plays an added F# (second fret, high E
    string) on the back beat of the Em. A noted feature of the song
    is the driving bass line with a hammer-hook in each chorus. A
    "waterfall" type solo completes the arrangement. Produced by
    Ian Samwell on the day of final recording at Morgan Studios, at
    first the group thought it too corny and took some convincing
    to actually play it. Gerry Beckley has explained in 
    <i>Acoustic Guitar</i>magazine (March 2007) that the correct
    tuning for the guitar is D E D G B D, low to high. The chord
    pattern that repeats throughout the entire song is: 202002
    (Em),then 020202 and 000202. The tuning is unique to this song;
    they did not use it on any other America song.</p>
      <p>Despite (or perhaps, because of) the song's being banned by
    some U.S. radio stations (including one in Kansas City) because
    of supposed drug references the song ascended to number one on
    the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 and the album quickly scored
    platinum. The song did chart earlier in the Netherlands
    (reaching number 11) and the UK (reaching number 3), than it
    actually did in the United States. The interpretation of the
    song as a drug reference comes from the fact that "horse" is a
    common slang term for heroin.</p>
      <p>The song's resemblance to some of Neil Young's work aroused
    some controversy. "I know that virtually everyone, on first
    hearing, assumed it was Neil," Bunnell says. "I never fully
    shied away from the fact that I was inspired by him. I think
    it's in the structure of the song as much as in the tone of his
    voice. It did hurt a little, because we got some pretty bad
    backlash. I've always attributed it more to people protecting
    their own heroes more than attacking me." By coincidence, it
    was "A Horse With No Name" that replaced Young's "Heart of
    Gold" at the #1 spot on the U.S. pop chart.</p>
      <p>The song has also been ridiculed for its banal, oddly
    phrased lyrics, including "The heat was hot"; "There were
    plants, and birds, and rocks, and things"; and "Cause there
    ain't no-one for to give you no pain." Randy Newman once
    described it as a song "about a kid who thinks he's taken
    acid". Comedian Richard Jeni mocked the song's title. "You're
    in the desert," he said. "You got nothing else to do. 
    <i>Name the freakin' horse!</i>"</p>
      <p>The song was one of many popular songs quoted and parodied
    on the 
    <i>The Third Reich 'n Roll</i>album by The Residents. In 1987
    the Danish rock band D-A-D made a cover version released on the
    album 
    <i>D.A.D. Draws a Circle</i>. Furthermore, the song has been
    covered by Larrikin Love with somewhat Celtic-sounding
    instrumentation and style for Magazine in 2006. The song is
    also featured in the movie 
    <i>The Trip.</i>In 2008, it was used in a Kohls TV commercial
    for Vera Wang. It can also be heard in season 2 of 
    <i>Millennium</i>, in the episode "Owls" and was featured in
    the videogame Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas on one of the
    in-game radio stations. The song bookends the third season
    episode of Breaking Bad, "Caballo Sin Nombre" (Spanish for
    "Horse With No Name"), where the song plays on a car radio as
    Walter White drives through the desert in the beginning, and is
    sung by the Walter in the shower at the end.</p>
      <p>"A Place With No Name" is the first known unreleased single
    of singer/songwriter Michael Jackson's posthumous career. It
    currently exists as a 25-second sound bite. The sound bite was
    released by news outlet TMZ.com on July 16, 2009 and closely
    resembles "A Horse with No Name". Jim Morey, both Jackson's and
    America's former band manager, has stated that "America was
    honored that Michael chose to do their song and they hope it
    becomes available for all Michael's fans to hear."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
