<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Respect_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Respect_(song)</songId>
   <title>Respect</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aretha_Franklin</artistId>
      <artistName>Aretha Franklin</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1967-06-03</week>
      <week>1967-06-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Otis Blue</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 15, 1965</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>July 1965 , Stax Recording Studios , ( Memphis, Tennessee )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:08</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Volt / Atco , V-128</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Otis Redding</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Steve Cropper</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Respect" is a song written and originally released by Stax
    recording artist Otis Redding in 1965. "Respect" became a 1967
    hit and signature song for R&amp;B singer Aretha Franklin.
    While Redding wrote the song as a man's plea for respect and
    recognition from a woman, the roles were reversed for
    Franklin's version. Franklin's cover was a landmark for the
    feminist movement, and is often considered as one of the best
    songs of the R&amp;B era, earning her two Grammy Awards in 1968
    for "Best Rhythm &amp; Blues Recording" and "Best Rhythm &amp;
    Blues Solo Vocal Performance, Female", and was inducted in the
    Grammy Hall of Fame in 1998. In 2002, the Library of Congress
    honored Franklin's version by adding it to the National
    Recording Registry. It is number five on Rolling Stone's list
    of The 500 Greatest Songs of All Time. It was also included in
    the list of 
    <i>Songs of the Century</i>, by the Recording Industry of
    America and the National Endowment for the Arts.</p>
      <p>Otis Redding wrote and recorded "Respect" as a blues tune in
    the studio while finishing his third album, 
    <i>Otis Blue</i>. The album became widely successful, even
    outside of his largely R&amp;B and blues fanbase. When released
    in the summer of 1965, the song reached the top five on
    Billboard's Black Singles Chart, and crossed over to pop
    radio's white audience, peaking at number thirty-five there. At
    the time, the song became Redding's second largest crossover
    hit (after "I've Been Loving You Too Long") and paved the way
    to future presence at American radio.</p>
      <p>Producer Jerry Wexler brought Redding's song to Franklin's
    attention. While Redding's version was popular among his core
    R&amp;B audience, Wexler thought the song had potential to be a
    crossover hit and to demonstrate Franklin's vocal ability.
    "Respect" was recorded on February 14, 1967 with Aretha's
    sisters, Carolyn and Erma, singing backup</p>
      <p>During the recording process, a bridge was added to
    Redding's original composition. Another addition was King
    Curtis' tenor saxophone and the slicker production of Wexler
    and co-producer Arif Mardin. The resulting song was featured on
    Franklin's Atlantic Records debut album, 
    <i>I Never Loved a Man the Way I Love You</i>. As the title
    track became a hit on both R&amp;B and pop radio, Atlantic
    Records arranged for the release of this new version of
    "Respect" as a single.</p>
      <p>Franklin's rendition found even greater success than the
    original, spending two weeks atop the Billboard Pop Singles
    chart, and for eight weeks on the Billboard Black Singles
    chart. It also became a hit internationally, reaching number
    ten in the United Kingdom, and helping to transform Franklin
    from a domestic star into an international one. Even Otis
    Redding himself was impressed with the performance of the song,
    and at the Monterey Pop Festival in the summer of the cover's
    release, he was quoted playfully describing "Respect" as the
    song "that little girl done stole from me".</p>
      <p>"Respect" is one of several songs considered to have defined
    the 1960s. It has appeared in dozens of films and still
    receives consistent play on oldies radio stations. In the
    1970s, Franklin's version of the song came to exemplify the
    feminist movement. Although she had numerous hits after
    "Respect", and several before its release, the song became
    Franklin's signature song and her best-known recording. 
    <i>I Never Loved a Man the Way I Love You</i>was ranked
    eighty-third in Rolling Stone's 500 Greatest Albums of All-Time
    in 2002. Two years later, "Respect" was fifth in the magazine's
    500 Greatest Songs of All-Time. The song "Respect" is part of
    the The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame's 500 Songs that Shaped Rock
    and Roll list.</p>
      <p>Despite being overshadowed, Redding's version is still
    considered a soul classic, and highly regarded by fans of
    Stax-Volt and southern soul recordings. The Vagrants, a Long
    Island, New York blue-eyed soul group recorded a version of
    Respect in 1967, which became a minor hit in the Eastern United
    States. Another regional band that had a hit with the song was
    the Michigan-based rock band The Rationals, whose 1966 release
    of the song received airplay on Detroit radio stations and
    predated the release of Aretha Franklin's version by a year.
    The Rotary Connection also have a version of the song, recorded
    in 1969 for Chess Records.</p>
      <p>Ike and Tina Turner released it on their 1971 double live
    album 
    <i>What You Hear Is What You Get (Live at Carnegie
    Hall)</i>.</p>
      <p>Janis Joplin also recorded the song. Joplin's version is
    similar to Redding's, although it was a September 1968 studio
    improvisation, and goes up only to 1st chorus, after which
    Janis stops, saying: "Another, another". This recording is
    released only on the unofficial album "Rarer Pearls", which
    contains various other Joplin studio and live cuts.</p>
      <p>Cass Elliot and Sammy Davis, Jr. performed it as a medley
    with I Dig Rock and Roll Music, Say It Loud - I'm Black and I'm
    Proud, What'd I Say and another Franklin's tune, Think. They
    sang it on variety show The Hollywood Palace, in 1969.</p>
      <p>Dexys Midnight Runners frequently included the song in their
    live set, and have issued at least two different live
    recordings of the song. A house music cover was released by
    singer Adeva in 1989, and reached #17 in the UK singles chart.
    The song was covered by the Basque fusion-rock band Negu
    Gorriak, translated as "Errespetua" (
    <i>respect</i>in euskara) for their 1996 cover album 
    <i>Salam, agur</i>. After the band's split, singer Fermin
    Muguruza continued to perform his version of the song in some
    of his solo projects' concerts, and it appeared as the final
    track on his live album 
    <i>Kontrabanda - Barcelona, Apolo 2004-I-21</i>.</p>
      <p>The phrase "what you want, baby I got it" was interpolated
    on Joss Stone's song "Headturner", from her 2007 album 
    <i>Introducing Joss Stone</i>and Kool Moe Dee's song "No
    Respect," from his 1987 album 
    <i>How Ya Like Me Now</i>. The song was featured on the game
    Karaoke Revolution Volume 3.</p>
      <p>Actress Jessica Biel sang the song during the season 1
    episode Say Good-bye of the hit series 7th Heaven.</p>
      <p>Amber Riley also sang the song in the pilot episode of the
    Fox series 
    <i>Glee</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
