<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Girlfriend_(Avril_Lavigne_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Girlfriend_(Avril_Lavigne_song)</songId>
   <title>Girlfriend</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Avril_Lavigne</artistId>
      <artistName>Avril Lavigne</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2007-05-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/75/AvrilLavigneGirlfriend.jpg/200px-AvrilLavigneGirlfriend.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Avril-Lavigne+Girlfriend.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Best Damn Thing</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 5, 2007  (2007-03-05) , (see release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2006</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Punk</genre>
      <genre>Powerpop</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:38</length>
   </lengths>
   <writers>
      <writer>Avril Lavigne</writer>
      <writer>Lukasz "Dr. Luke" Gottwald</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Lukasz "Dr. Luke" Gottwald</producer>
      <producer>Matt Beckley</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Girlfriend" is a song by Canadian pop-punk singer Avril
    Lavigne, released as the lead single from her third studio
    album, 
    <i>The Best Damn Thing</i>. It was produced by Lukasz Gottwald.
    "Girlfriend" became Lavigne's biggest hit in the United States,
    where it became her first number one single in the U.S. Hot
    100. It topped the chart in Australia for 6 weeks, and reached
    number two in the United Kingdom. A remix featuring rapper Lil
    Mama was released in June 2007. The song was recently named by 
    <i>Billboard Magazine</i>the #94 Top Single of the decade. It
    was also the top selling song in 2007 with sales of over 7.3
    million from 72 different countries.</p>
      <p>The song involves Lavigne proclaiming a crush on a boy who
    currently has a girlfriend already, and features the typical
    80's pop-punk influence and power pop of her earlier songs.
    Lavigne said on the DVD side of the deluxe edition of 
    <i>The Best Damn Thing</i>that in the bridge when the listener
    hears hand clapping, the accompanying giggling was created by
    Lavigne and Gottwald, despite it sounding like a girl.
    "Girlfriend" is in the video game 
    <i>Burnout Dominator</i>in English, Japanese, Spanish, and
    Chinese. It also appears in 
    <i>Burnout Paradise</i>but this time only in English. This song
    is recorded in 7 languages other than English. It is the theme
    song of Japanese talk show 
    <i>Cartoon KAT-TUN</i>- on which Lavigne appeared on May 2,
    2007 - as well as being the insert song for popular Japanese
    manga based drama Hanazakari no Kimitachi e. It is featured in
    the theatrical trailer for the 2007 live-action 
    <i>Bratz</i>film, and in a trailer for the film 
    <i>I Now Pronounce You Chuck and Larry</i>, and also for 
    <i>Bring It On: In It to Win It</i>. Lavigne performed the song
    on 
    <i>The Tonight Show with Jay Leno</i>on June 15, 2007.</p>
      <p>The song was #35 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s list of the 100 Best Songs of 2007. This
    song was also #77 on 
    <i>MTV Asia</i>'s list of Top 100 Hits of 2007. Also was listed
    as the number 1 hit of 2007 according to MTV Latin America. .
    Note, Girlfriend peaked as number one in the North/Central
    Latin American Version of "Los 100 Más Pedidos 2007" (The 100
    Top Hits of 2007), while in the South Latin American Version of
    "Los 100 Más Pedidos 2007" it peaked at number 3, losing the
    first place to "With Love" by Hilary Duff. "Girlfriend" also
    won the Best Song of the Year at the 2008 Kids' Choice Awards.
    It beat "Big Girls Don't Cry", "Don't Matter", and "Beautiful
    Girls".</p>
      <p>Critics have compared the middle section of the song with
    the bridge from Toni Basil's "Mickey".</p>
      <p>Reviewers have noted that the chorus bears a resemblance to
    The Rubinoos' 1979 single "I Wanna Be Your Boyfriend", in which
    they sing "Hey hey, you you, I wanna be your boyfriend" similar
    to "Hey hey, you you, I could be your girlfriend" in
    "Girlfriend". The song can be heard on the Rubinoos' MySpace
    page.</p>
      <p>On May 25, 2007, Lavigne, her songwriter Lukasz Gottwald,
    her record label, and Apple Inc. were sued by James Gangwer and
    Tommy Dunbar, songwriters for The Rubinoos, over claims that
    "Girlfriend" infringes their copyright on their 1979 song "I
    Wanna Be Your Boyfriend". Lavigne's manager, Terry McBride,
    denied that "Girlfriend" was copied from "I Wanna Be Your
    Boyfriend", and pointed out that "Boyfriend" itself is similar
    to The Rolling Stones' "Get off of My Cloud". McBride said he
    hired a musicologist to compare the songs; according to McBride
    the musicologist reported that the songs were totally
    dissimilar, even a different meter. Prominent music critics
    such as Stephen Thomas Erlewine of 
    <i>Allmusic</i>have publicly noted that the song is a "total
    lift from the Rubinoos' song". McBride said that Lavigne has no
    current plans to settle the case, but will consider the costs
    of defending the case against those of settling. In January
    2008, the lawsuit was settled and Gangwer and Dunbar released a
    statement saying that the similarities between the songs were
    based on "certain common and widely used lyrics" and that they
    "completely exonerate Avril and Luke from any wrongdoing of any
    kind in connection with the claims made by us in our
    lawsuit."</p>
      <p>The world premiere of the music video was announced to be on
    MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>and MuchMusic's 
    <i>MuchOnDemand</i>on February 26. However, it premiered in New
    Zealand on Music Station C4 on February 20. It was in heavy
    rotation on European music TV channel VIVA Polska on February
    23 as well.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by The Malloys and filmed at
    Golf 'n' Stuff in Norwalk, California. It features two girls:
    one with an innocent persona, glasses and red hair (Lavigne),
    and one with a rebellious persona and black hair (also
    Lavigne). The video begins inside the building where the
    red-haired girl and her boyfriend are walking together. Lavigne
    sees her and shows her an intimidating disposition. As the
    couple walk away, Lavigne begins to sing the song and tries her
    luck on the red-haired girl's boyfriend. Featured in the video
    are scenes of Lavigne fighting over the man with the red-haired
    girl and trying to outdo her repeatedly. Between the scenes
    show Lavigne singing with her band accompanying her at the
    back. The video also featured Lavigne and her friends dancing
    within the comfort room (restroom) background. After the
    starting scene, the video shows them at Li'l Indy, where they
    ride go-carts. Here, Lavigne is seen viciously bumping the car
    of the red-haired girl, causing her to spin around and lose
    control. Next, the red-haired girl and her boyfriend get inside
    a photo booth where Lavigne hears them and grabs the red-haired
    girl away before they take pictures. Lavigne's friends then
    block the red-haired girl's way to give her more time.</p>
      <p>The next scene shows the couple eating together, where
    Lavigne sees them, throws the food away and kisses the
    red-haired girl's boyfriend. It is nighttime when the next
    scene was shown. This scene takes place in a miniature golf
    course where the couple are playing, and the red-haired girl
    cheerfully wins.</p>
      <p>Unfortunately for her, Lavigne and her friends are also
    present at the scene. As soon as she and her friends see them,
    Lavigne hits her in the head with a golf ball, and the
    red-haired girl splashes down below and into the water. Her
    boyfriend tries to grab her hand but misses. Finally, the last
    scene shows Lavigne waiting for the man. As he comes toward
    her, they soon hold hands together, and the red-haired girl
    sees them and tries to seize Lavigne (at the same time trying
    to get her boyfriend back). But Lavigne ducks down and the man
    moves sideways as soon as the red-haired girl charges towards
    Lavigne. She then tumbles all the way down and falls into a
    Porta Potty ahead, where she gives a look of desperation
    towards the camera, showing that she has failed to win back her
    boyfriend. Lavigne then finally wins the youth's affections.
    The video ends when she takes her new boyfriend into a bathroom
    stall and slightly opens the door after a moment and gives a
    thumbs up. Lavigne's boyfriend in the video is played by
    American model Bryan McMullin and dresses similarly to the
    "rocker" Lavigne in the video. The video features Lavigne's
    previous guitarist Evan Taubenfeld, and Lavigne's brother Matt
    on bass.</p>
      <p>Lil Mama and Lavigne shot a video for the remix of
    "Girlfriend", which was directed by R. Malcolm Jones.</p>
      <p>The first 15 seconds of the video include an audio sampling
    of 
    <i>"Arcade Ambiance 1983"</i>.</p>
      <p>On July 18, 2008 "Girlfriend" became the most viewed video
    of all time on YouTube and in August of that year, surpassed
    100 million views, the first YouTube video to reach that
    milestone, overtaking "Evolution of Dance" by Judson Laipply.
    The YouTube video of the song was accused of having an
    exaggerated number of views due to the use of a web link posted
    by AvrilBandAids, a fansite devoted to Avril Lavigne. Clicking
    on the link would automatically reload the YouTube video of
    Girlfriend every fifteen seconds. Fans of Avril Lavigne were
    encouraged to: "Keep this page open while you browse the
    internet, study for exams, or even sleep. For extra viewing
    power, open up two or more browser windows at this page!" It is
    expected that Avril's YouTube video views have earned in excess
    of $2 million (U.S). In November 2009, RCA Records removed the
    video of the song from YouTube, by which time it had received
    around 130 million views. The official video is now hosted on
    Vevo, a premium music video site owned by Google and Sony.</p>
      <p>"Girlfriend" was premiered on Edmonton radio station 91.7
    The Bounce before the official date it was supposed to be
    aired; the two DJs who played it were taken off the air shortly
    after. The single appeared and was available for download on
    the U.S. iTunes Store on February 23, but was subsequently
    removed the following day. It was made available again on
    February 27.</p>
      <p>Because of digital download sales in excess of 122,000, the
    song debuted at number five on the U.S. Hot 100 chart, the
    highest debut of her career. Afterwards it became Lavigne's
    first song to reach number one on the Hot 100, in the issue
    dated May 5, 2007; her previous highest peak on the chart was
    with 2002's "Complicated", which reached number two. It
    remained in the top ten for eighteen weeks, and has since been
    downloaded over 3 million times.</p>
      <p>"Girlfriend" debuted on the Australian ARIA Singles Chart at
    number three. The following week it reached number-one, and it
    remained at the top for six non-consecutive weeks, equaling
    Lavigne's previous number-one single on the ARIA Charts,
    "Complicated". After three weeks on the charts, it was
    certified gold by ARIA, then platinum after seven weeks for
    sales in excess of 70,000 copies. It was then certified double
    platinum, sales in excess of 140,000. In 2008, it was certified
    quadruple platinum for sales of 280,000.</p>
      <p>On the UK Singles Chart, "Girlfriend" peaked at number two,
    surpassing "Complicated" as Lavigne's highest peaking single on
    the chart. The song ended 2007 as the years 20th
    biggest-selling single in the UK and spent 27 weeks inside the
    chart and is Lavigne's biggest hit in the UK to date.</p>
      <p>It won the Award for "Canción del Año" (Song Of The Year) in
    "Los Premios MTV Latinoamérica 2007" (The Latin American MTV
    Awards) and was nominated for "Monster Single" in the MTV Video
    Music Awards 2007. It won Most Addictive Track (Single Of The
    Year) at the MTV Europe Music Awards</p>
      <p>There is a live video version of the song, which was part of
    
    <i>The Best Damn Tour - Live in Toronto</i>, and was sent to
    Brazil Music Channels (such as MTV and Multi Show) and was
    released to promote the DVD release for The Best Damn Tour
    2008.</p>
      <p>Seven additional versions of the song are available to
    enhance its worldwide marketability with the chorus sung in
    French, German, Italian, Japanese, Mandarin, Portuguese and
    Spanish language. The other parts of the song are in English.
    According to Lavigne's label, a Hindi version was attempted but
    Lavigne found it too difficult to record because the correctly
    pronounced lyrics did not best match the meter of the song.</p>
      <p>There is also an edited version for radio, because of
    explicit lyrics. There are two official censored versions: one
    blanking the word "motherfucking" in the line "I'm the
    motherfucking princess" and the other replacing it with "I'm
    the one and only princess". It is played on Canadian and
    Malaysian radio stations, and on Z100 in New York City.
    However, on other radio stations the entire word is cut out or
    just the word "mother", as in the version on the clean edition
    of the album, is said.</p>
      <p>The official remix was leaked onto the Internet in May 2007
    and features rap verses from American hip-hop musician Lil
    Mama. Lavigne sings the chorus and bridge and Lil Mama's rap
    verses are substituted for the original verses.</p>
      <p>(4988017647615; Released March 21, 2007)</p>
      <p>A code included on the CD to download the ringtone
    online.</p>
      <p>In September 2009, punk rock American band Zebrahead
    released "Girlfriend" as the first single of their new album 
    <i>Panty Raid</i>, which was released on November 4, 2009, in
    Japan and December 8 in the rest of the world. The album is
    noticed to only have cover versions of women's famous pop songs
    of the past two decades. It runs 3:05 and is fast-paced, thanks
    to Ali rap sing style. It was peaked in the Hot Modern Rock
    Tracks in the first week in the #84 place.</p>
      <p>The music video of the song was released in mid October and
    is a parody of the original "Girlfriend" video, with Ali
    playing the "Bad Avril" and Matty playing the good one. It
    resembles numerous situations that occur in the original video,
    but with a more comic sense into the video.</p>
      <p>"Girlfriend" was released in a number of countries over a
    three-month period. The remix featuring Lil Mama was released
    on June 15 in Taiwan, and on July 25 in the United States.</p>
      <p>Reaching number-one on numerous music charts worldwide,
    "Girlfriend" is Lavigne's most successful charting single.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
