<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raindrops_Keep_Fallin%27_on_My_Head 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raindrops_Keep_Fallin%27_on_My_Head</songId>
   <title>Raindrops Keep Fallin' on My Head</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/B._J._Thomas</artistId>
      <artistName>B. J. Thomas</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1970-01-03</week>
      <week>1970-01-10</week>
      <week>1970-01-17</week>
      <week>1970-01-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1969</released>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:57</length>
   </lengths>
   <writers>
      <writer>Hal David and Burt Bacharach</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Raindrops Keep Fallin' on My Head" is a song written by Hal
    David and Burt Bacharach for the 1969 film 
    <i>Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid</i>, winning an Academy
    Award for Best Original Song. David and Bacharach also won Best
    Original Score. The version by B. J. Thomas was number one on
    the Billboard Hot 100 chart in the United States in January
    1970 for four weeks and the first number-one single of the
    1970s. It also spent seven weeks atop the U.S. adult
    contemporary chart.</p>
      <p>The song was recorded in seven takes, after Bacharach
    expressed dissatisfaction with the first six.</p>
      <p>Ray Stevens had been first offered the opportunity to record
    the song for the motion picture, but turned it down. He chose
    instead to record "Sunday Morning Coming Down," which was
    written by Kris Kristofferson. Bob Dylan is also supposed to
    have been approached for the song, but he too reportedly turned
    down the offer.</p>
      <p>The song is featured in the Leslie Nielsen movie 
    <i>Spy Hard</i>, which parodies the scene in 
    <i>Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid</i>where the song plays.
    It also is featured on the soundtracks of 
    <i>Forrest Gump</i>and the superhero film, 
    <i>Spider-Man 2</i>, in the latter accentuating Peter Parker's
    blissful mood after abandoning his Spider-Man identity and its
    responsibilities. Most recently it was used in the Kevin Smith
    film 
    <i>Clerks II</i>. It was also sung in 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>episode, "Duffless". Also, the first episode
    of the second season from 
    <i>Grey's Anatomy</i>is named after the song.</p>
      <p>B.J. Thomas's version was listed at #12 on 
    <i>Billboard's Greatest Songs of all time.</i>[1]</p>
      <p>The song has been covered numerous times, most notably by
    the Rat Pack. The Welsh rock band Manic Street Preachers
    maintain it in their repertoire of live songs, playing it as
    part of an acoustic set during concerts. The band recorded a
    version of the song complete with trumpet solo by their drummer
    Sean Moore. This was the first piece of music the band recorded
    after the disappearance of guitarist and lyricist Richey
    Edwards, and saw release on the 1995 charity album 
    <i>Help</i>. This version also appears on their 2003 B-sides
    and rarities compilation album 
    <i>Lipstick Traces (A Secret History of Manic Street
    Preachers)</i>. The Manics further referenced the film 
    <i>Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid</i>with a b-side song
    called "Sepia". It includes the lines: "And just like the
    moment in Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid / I'm perpetually
    stuck in a sepia film / But bleeding inside I manage to keep it
    all in".</p>
      <p>It has also been covered by French singer Sacha Distel
    (whose version was a hit in the United Kingdom as well as
    France).</p>
      <p>The song was a hit in Australia for Australian singer John
    Farnham in 1969. [2]</p>
      <p>Johnny Mathis covered this song in 1970 on his LP 
    <i>Raindrops Keep Fallin' On My Head.</i>
      </p>
      <p>The Four Tops featured a cover of the song on their album 
    <i>Changing Times</i>in 1970.</p>
      <p>Paul Mauriat recorded it by his Grand Orchestra it 1973.
    This version was only "Raindrops Keep Falling" cover known in
    USSR.</p>
      <p>Delroy Wilson recorded a reggae version for the song that
    doesn't appear on any of his official albums; the record can be
    found on 7" and is considered rare.</p>
      <p>Mute Beat also recorded a reggae version for their 1989
    album 
    <i>March</i>.</p>
      <p>The Flaming Lips covered this song on their 1996 
    <i>Brainville EP</i>. Ben Folds Five also covered the song for
    the 1998 Burt Bacharach tribute TV special and soundtrack 
    <i>One Amazing Night</i>. In 2005 Australian band Jebediah
    covered the song for Triple J's 
    <i>Like a Version</i>compilation.</p>
      <p>In 1998, Shonen Knife covered it as part of the 
    <i>Big Deal Recording Artists Perform The Songs Of Burt
    Bacharach</i>project.</p>
      <p>The former football player and actor David Ginola sang a
    rather memorable version of this on 
    <i>Stars in Their Eyes</i>.</p>
      <p>Dionne Warwick has collaborated with Kelis on a cover of
    this for her 2006 duets album.</p>
      <p>Barry Manilow covered this song on his 2006 album 
    <i>The Greatest Songs of the Sixties</i>.</p>
      <p>Perry Como recorded the song for his album, 
    <i>It's Impossible.</i>
      </p>
      <p>In 2008, Niki Chow &amp; Patrick Tang have sung a song with
    this melody. It's called "Believing in Fairy Stories", and it
    is the end-of-episode song for The King Of Snooker, a drama
    series that they have both starred in.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
