<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Ain%27t_Seen_Nothing_Yet 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Ain%27t_Seen_Nothing_Yet</songId>
   <title>You Ain't Seen Nothing Yet</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bachman-Turner_Overdrive</artistId>
      <artistName>Bachman-Turner Overdrive</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-11-09</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Not Fragile</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1974</released>
   <recorded>1974</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:54</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Mercury</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Randy Bachman</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Randy Bachman</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"You Ain't Seen Nothing Yet" is a rock song written by Randy
    Bachman and performed by Bachman–Turner Overdrive (BTO) on the
    album 
    <i>Not Fragile</i>. It was released as a single in 1974 with an
    instrumental track "Free Wheelin'" as the B-side. It reached
    the #1 position on the Billboard Hot 100 singles chart the week
    of November 9, 1974. The single won the Juno Award for
    best-selling single of 1974.</p>
      <p>The lyrics for the song tell of the singer meeting a "devil
    woman" and her giving him love. The chorus of the song includes
    the song's famous stutter and speaks of her looking at him with
    big brown eyes and [saying] 'You ain't seen nothin yet. B-, b-,
    b-, baby, you just ain't seen na, na, nothin yet. Here's
    somethin' that you're never gonna forget. B-, b-, b-, baby, you
    just ain't seen na, na, nothin yet.'</p>
      <p>The guitar riff heard throughout the song's chorus is
    proportionate to the riff from Baba O'Riley by The Who. The
    riff follows a main pattern of A5, E5, then a D5, while the
    riff in Baba O'Riley is F5, C5, Bb5.</p>
      <p>"You Ain't Seen Nothing Yet" was written by Randy Bachman.
    In 
    <i>The Rolling Stone Record Guide,</i>writer Dave Marsh called
    the song "a direct steal from The Who," but "an imaginative
    one." The chords of the chorus riff are very similar to the
    ones used by The Who in their song "Baba O'Riley," and also,
    the stuttering vocal is indeed reminiscent of "My Generation."
    Randy insists that the song was performed as a joke for his
    brother, Gary, with no intention of sounding like "My
    Generation." Gary had a stutter, and Randy only intended to
    record it once with the stutter and send the only recording to
    Gary.</p>
      <p>Randy developed the song while recording BTO's third album, 
    <i>Not Fragile</i>. It began as an instrumental piece inspired
    by the rhythm guitar of Dave Mason. Randy says "it was
    basically just an instrumental and I was fooling around... I
    wrote the lyrics, out of the blue, and stuttered them through."
    The band typically used the song as a "work track" in the
    studio to get the amplifiers and microphones set properly.</p>
      <p>But when winding up production for their third album,
    Charlie Fach of Mercury Records said the eight tracks they had
    lacked the "magic" that would make a hit single. Some band
    members asked Randy, "what about the work track?" Randy
    reluctantly mentioned that he had this ninth song, but didn't
    intend to use it on a record. He said, "We have this one song,
    but it's a joke. I'm laughing at the end. I sang it on the
    first take. It's sharp, it's flat, I'm stuttering to do this
    thing for my brother."</p>
      <p>Fach asked to hear it, and they played the recording for
    him. Fach smiled and said "That's the track. It's got a
    brightness to it. It kind of floats a foot higher than the
    other songs when you listen to it."</p>
      <p>Bachman agreed to include the song, but only if he could
    re-record the vocals first, without the stutter. Fach agreed,
    but Bachman says "I tried to sing it normal, but I sounded like
    Frank Sinatra. It didn't fit." Fach said to leave it as it was,
    with the stutter.</p>
      <p>It is said that Gary Bachman has since lost his stutter.</p>
      <p>The first single from the 
    <i>Not Fragile</i>album was "Roll on Down the Highway." It
    performed well, but eventually stalled at #14 on the U.S.
    charts. "You Ain't Seen Nothing Yet," meanwhile, was becoming a
    hit as an album cut. Radio stations all over the USA were
    giving it a great deal of airplay. So much so, Bachman was
    embarrassed because he thought it was a stupid song, just
    something that he wrote as a joke.</p>
      <p>Fach would regularly call him with airplay reports, asking
    for permission to release "You Ain't Seen Nothing Yet" as a
    single. Bachman says, "And I refused for three weeks... I was
    producer, so I had final say on what went out. I woke up one
    day and asked myself, 'Why am I stopping this? Some of my
    favorite records are really dumb things like 'Louie, Louie'...
    so I said to Charlie, 'O.K., release it. I bet it does
    nothing.'"</p>
      <p>"You Ain't Seen Nothing Yet" debuted at #65 on September 21,
    1974 and shot to the top of the Hot 100 seven weeks later. It
    was the only chart-topper for BTO. (While in The Guess Who,
    Randy had penned only one other chart-topper, "American Woman,"
    which hit #1 in 1970.)</p>
      <p>"You Ain't Seen Nothing Yet" also holds the record for
    falling farthest on the chart before returning to the Top 10.
    After falling to #34 two weeks after being in the #1 spot, it
    jumped back to #8 for two weeks, largely because of interest in
    the flip side, an instrumental called "Free Wheelin'".</p>
      <p>On the UK version of the single, the label credits the band
    as "
    <i>Bachmann</i>–Turner Overdrive". It was kept off the top in
    the UK charts by "Lonely This Christmas" by Mud.</p>
      <p>Bachman appears in the promo video for Bus Stop's 1998
    remake of the song.</p>
      <p>The song was always played at the end of the "Smashie and
    Nicey" sketch on the British sketch show, 
    <i>Harry Enfield's Television Programme</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was played in an episode of 
    <i>Ballykissangel</i>.</p>
      <p>It was also played on the third season premiere of
    Supernatural.</p>
      <p>The song is featured in 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>episode 
    <i>Saddlesore Galactica</i>. At a BTO concert, Homer demands
    that they play the song one second after finishing it. When the
    band reminds him of this fact, he replies, "Whatever!"</p>
      <p>A techno remix of the song was used as the theme song for
    ITV Sport's Formula One coverage from 2003 to 2005. The remix
    is by German group, The Disco Boys, titled "B-B-B-Baby."</p>
      <p>The song is played at the beginning of the movie Studio 54
    when the boys are going to club Studio 54 for the first
    time.</p>
      <p>The song appears on the soundtrack of the film "Joe
    Dirt".</p>
      <p>The song was, together with U2's "Beautiful Day", used as a
    theme song by the US Democratic Party following the US 2006
    midterm elections.</p>
      <p>During a trip to the US, Margaret Thatcher quoted the song
    when talking to an audience with Ronald Reagan. Telling the
    audience that "You ain't seen nothing yet". Appears in the CBC
    movie: Keep Your Head up kid: the Don Cherry Story, also shot
    in Winnipeg, Manitoba.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
