<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Venus_(Shocking_Blue_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Venus_(Shocking_Blue_song)</songId>
   <title>Venus</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bananarama</artistId>
      <artistName>Bananarama</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-09-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/4/45/Shocking_Blue_Venus.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bananarama+Venus.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>At Home</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1969</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1969</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop / Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:06</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Pink Elephant, Metronome, Colossus , Poplandia, Joker, Yugoton</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Robbie van Leeuwen</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Robbie van Leeuwen</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Venus" is a 1969 song by the Dutch band Shocking Blue which
    the group took to number one in the U.S. and five countries
    across Europe in 1970. Notably covered by girl group
    Bananarama, the song returned to number one in the U.S. and
    topped the charts in six other countries around the world in
    1986. The composition has been featured in numerous films,
    television shows and commercials, and covered dozens of times
    by artists around the world.</p>
      <p>Released in late 1969 as a single from the album 
    <i>At Home</i>, Shocking Blue's single reached number one on
    the Billboard Hot 100 on February 7, 1970. RIAA certification
    came on January 28, 1970 for selling over one million copies in
    the U.S., garnering a gold record.</p>
      <p>The song's lead vocals are performed by Mariska Veres. The
    song's music and lyrics are written by Robbie van Leeuwen, the
    band's guitarist, sitarist and background vocalist, who also
    produced. Van Leeuwen used "The Banjo Song" on 
    <i>Winkin', Blinkin' and Nod</i>, a 1963 album by The Big 3
    with Mama Cass Elliot on vocals, as main inspiration.</p>
      <p>A cover of Shocking Blues' song "Love Buzz" was featured on
    Nirvana's 1989 release "Bleach"</p>
      <p>"Venus" was remixed and re-released by dance producers The
    BHF (Bisiach Hornbostel Ferrucci) Team in May 1990, scoring the
    group a Top 10 hit in the UK and Australia 21 years after the
    release of the original. The remix featured a hip house rhythm
    and samples including an instrumental version mixed by Don
    Pablo's Animals. The single began with a sample from James
    Brown's 1988 hit "The Payback Mix (Part One)." This release of
    "Venus" peaked at #4 on the UK Singles Chart and #8 in
    Australia in 1990.</p>
      <p>"Venus" had been a part of Bananarama's repertoire for
    several years before they actually recorded it. The team's
    three members, Sara Dallin, Siobhan Fahey, and Keren Woodward,
    had the idea of turning the song into a dance music tune, but
    they met with resistance from their producers at the time,
    Steve Jolley and Tony Swain. Bananarama brought the idea to the
    production trio of Stock Aitken Waterman, and it became
    Bananarama's first collaboration with them.</p>
      <p>Dallin, Fahey, and Woodward had nearly completed recording
    their third album, titled 
    <i>True Confessions,</i>with Jolley and Swain. Stock, Aitken
    and Waterman also resisted the idea because they believed that
    "Venus" would not make a good dance record. After persistence
    by the women, SAW relented, and the result was a worldwide
    smash. Bananarama's "Venus" went to number one in the U.S.,
    Canada, Australia, New Zealand, Switzerland, Mexico, and South
    Africa. It hit number two in Germany and Hong Kong and was a
    top ten success in Italy, Austria, Belgium, Finland, France,
    Netherlands, Sweden, Venezuela, Norway, Portugal, Spain, and
    their native UK (#8 on UK Singles Chart). It also went to
    number one for two weeks on the U.S. Dance chart.</p>
      <p>The collaboration on "Venus" led Bananarama and SAW to work
    together on the group's follow-up album 
    <i>Wow!</i>the following year.</p>
      <p>A new mix of the track appeared as b-side to the 1989
    limited release "Megarama '89" in Germany and France.
    Bananarama has since re-recorded the track for their 2001 album
    
    <i>Exotica</i>and it was later remixed by Marc Almond, with
    re-recorded vocals, and included on their 2005 album 
    <i>Drama</i>.</p>
      <p>The music video for the song received extensive play on MTV
    and video channels across the world, and presented Bananarama
    in various costumes, including a she-devil, a French temptress,
    a vampiress, and several Grecian goddesses. In one sequence of
    the video, 
    <i>The Birth of Venus,</i>the painting by Sandro Botticelli,
    was reenacted. The video marked a pivotal shift towards a more
    glamorous and sexual image for the girls that contrasted with
    the tomboyish style in their earlier work. Choreography by
    Bruno Tonioli. Music video directed by Peter Care.</p>
      <p>Bananarama</p>
      <p>Additional personnel</p>
      <p>Despite the fact that the heavily controlled Soviet mass
    media totally ignored much of Western popular culture, the
    Shocking Blue song quickly become a popular hit in 1970s
    Russia, especially among street youth akin to Western hippie
    and "hooligan" subcultures. Due to the song's simple
    arrangement and danceable rhythm, "Venus" was adopted and
    performed by thousands of underground amateur performers, both
    those who accompanied themselves on acoustic guitar and full
    contemporary bands who performed it with electric guitar at
    dance parties. Thus, the English language song of a Dutch band
    become a prominent phenomenon of Russian urban folklore and was
    considered by many an unofficial "anthem of the
    generation".</p>
      <p>The English language in the song, however, was only very
    loosely approximated, and the song was not even known by its
    title, "Venus". A countless number of variants of Russian
    lyrics existed for this song, but traditionally it was
    performed using gibberish or scat singing phonetically inspired
    by the sounds of original English lyrics which had become
    hardly intelligible after being passed along via repeated
    duplicate copying on cheap, low-end tape recorders. In the
    Russian variant, the first line of the chorus, "She's got it",
    was usually pronounced as "Shizgarah" ("Шизгáра") [
    <i>sheez-ga'-rah</i>], and it was this word which became a
    commonly adopted name of the song in the U.S.S.R., even among
    those who could understand the original English text.</p>
      <p>The Canadian teenage drama series program 
    <i>Degrassi: The Next Generation,</i>which is known for naming
    each installment after an 1980s hit song, named a two-part
    installment after this song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
