<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Don%27t_Bring_Me_Flowers 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Don%27t_Bring_Me_Flowers</songId>
   <title>You Don't Bring Me Flowers</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barbra_Streisand</artistId>
      <artistName>Barbra Streisand and Neil Diamond</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1978-12-02</week>
      <week>1978-12-16</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/72/YDBMF_single.jpg/200px-YDBMF_single.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Barbra-Streisand-and-Neil-Diamond+You-Don-t-Bring-Me-Flowers.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>"Barbra Streisand's Greatest Hits Volume 2" Barbra Streisand / "You Don't Bring Me Flowers" Neil Diamond</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 1978</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Easy Listening</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:25</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Alan Bergman and Marilyn Bergman</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"You Don't Bring Me Flowers" is a song that hit the top of
    the Billboard Hot 100 charts in 1978. It is a song about two
    lovers who have drifted apart while they "go through the
    motions" and heartache of life together.</p>
      <p>The song was written by Alan Bergman and Marilyn Bergman for
    the ill-fated TV show 
    <i>All That Glitters</i>. The song was intended to be a theme
    song, but Norman Lear changed the concept of the show so that
    the song no longer fit. Eventually, Neil Diamond and several
    collaborators came upon the song (then only 45 seconds long)
    and expanded it with instrumental sections. The Bergmans
    expanded the song to full length with an additional verse, and
    the composition took form.</p>
      <p>In 1977, Diamond released the album 
    <i>I'm Glad You're Here With Me Tonight</i>, which included the
    track. "You Don't Bring Me Flowers" which was also covered by
    Barbra Streisand on her album 
    <i>Songbird</i>and sung in the same key (C major). This led
    Gary Guthrie, then Program Director at WAKY (an AM radio
    station in Louisville, Kentucky) to combine the two in a
    "virtual" duet.</p>
      <p>The popularity of the virtual duet motivated Diamond and
    Streisand to record the real thing, and it became a very large
    hit. The song reached number one on the Hot 100 chart for two
    non-consecutive weeks in December 1978; this was the third #1
    hit for both singers. Their performance of the song during the
    1980 Grammy Awards show has been featured on live music
    performance highlight reels ever since.</p>
      <p>Diamond and Streisand had planned to star in a motion
    picture based on the song, but such plans were cancelled when
    Diamond starred in a remake of 
    <i>The Jazz Singer</i>, which was less successful than hoped at
    the box office.</p>
      <p>Concurrent with the success of Diamond and Streisand's
    version of the song, country singers Jim Ed Brown and Helen
    Cornelius released a country version of the song which reached
    #10 on the Hot Country Singles chart in early 1979.</p>
      <p>In 1980, a cover version of the song was recorded by
    expatriate American singer Dean Reed and Hungarian vocalist
    Kati Kovács. [1]</p>
      <p>In 1996, the song was also sung by rappers Ice T and an
    embarrassed Tupac Shakur during a 
    <i>Saturday Night Live</i>show. It was also infamously covered
    in spoken-word form by pianist Liberace.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
