<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No_More_Tears_(Enough_is_Enough) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No_More_Tears_(Enough_is_Enough)</songId>
   <title>No More Tears (Enough is Enough)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barbra_Streisand</artistId>
      <artistName>Barbra Streisand and Donna Summer</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1979-11-24</week>
      <week>1979-12-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f7/Enoughisenough.JPG/200px-Enoughisenough.JPG</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Barbra-Streisand-and-Donna-Summer+No-More-Tears-Enough-is-Enough.JPG</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Wet &amp; On the Radio: Greatest Hits Volumes 1 &amp; 2</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 1979</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>14—28 August 1979 at Village Recorder studios in Los Angeles</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco   Pop</genre>
      <genre>Hi Nrg</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:48 (Casablanca 7")</length>
      <length>4:43 (Columbia 7")</length>
      <length>8:19 (Wet album mix)</length>
      <length>11:43 (12"/ On The Radio album mix)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Casablanca , CBS</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Paul Jabara</writer>
      <writer>Bruce Roberts</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Gary Klein</producer>
      <producer>Giorgio Moroder</producer>
      <producer>Harold Faltermeyer (Donna Summer 12" version)</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>4:43 (Columbia 7"), 8:19 (
    <i>Wet</i>album mix),</p>
      <p>"No More Tears (Enough Is Enough)" is a duet from 1979 by
    Donna Summer and Barbra Streisand. While Summer was famous for
    her disco material and Streisand for her more easy listening
    and soundtrack work (though both had crossed over into other
    genres before), this song fused both sounds with a slow
    beginning (lasting almost two minutes) which then evolved into
    a disco song. The song then becomes something of a feminist
    anthem with two women taking action against their men and
    throwing them out.</p>
      <p>The song was recorded for Streisand's 
    <i>Wet</i>album and also as a new track for Summer's
    compilation double album entitled 
    <i>On the Radio: Greatest Hits Volumes 1 &amp; 2</i>. The
    full-length version was found on Streisand's album, while a
    longer 11 minute plus version (the 12" version) was featured on
    Summer's album. The Summer version features additional
    production by frequent collaborator Harold Faltermeyer, and
    incorporates the harder rock edge symbolic of her work with
    him. The single was released on both Casablanca Records
    (Summer's label) and Columbia Records (Streisand's label) and
    sales of the two were amalgamated. The versions on the two 7"
    singles differed slightly however, with different mixes and
    slightly different background vocal arrangements. The formats
    differed between nations - in the UK for example, only the
    Casablanca version was released as a 12" and Columbia released
    the 7".</p>
      <p>Although the sales of the two labels' releases were
    amalgamated, both the 7" and the 12" were certified Gold by the
    RIAA in early 1980. The 7" single was eventually certified
    Platinum by 1997. The single spent two weeks at number one on
    the U.S. singles chart (making it both singers' fourth
    chart-topping single in the U.S.). It was also a big
    international hit, and made the top three in the UK.</p>
      <p>During the recording of the song, Summer is said to have
    passed out and fallen off her chair having been out partying
    the night before. Streisand supposedly carried on singing her
    long note and waited until she had finished it before stopping
    and asking Summer if she was okay. Another rumour regarding the
    song is that Streisand's son, Jason Gould, is the one who
    talked his mother into recording the duet as he was a fan of
    Summer's work.</p>
      <p>It has been said that "No More Tears (Enough Is Enough)"
    almost never made it on to the 
    <i>Wet</i>album. The song was originally entitled, "Enough Is
    Enough", where the ballad introduction was never recorded
    between the two women. When the final song selections were
    being made, it was said by the producers that "Enough Is
    Enough" was not to be included, for it had nothing in common
    with the other songs, since the track did not interpret water
    of any kind (which was the theme of the 
    <i>Wet</i>album). Barbra Streisand really wanted the song on
    the album and thus changed the title of the song to "No More
    Tears (Enough Is Enough)", upon which the ballad introduction
    was written, to give more of an explanation of water to the
    song..."It's raining, it's pouring, my love life is boring me
    to tears after all these years...", and so forth.</p>
      <p>The Swedish pressing of the Casablanca Records 7" single had
    a B-side called "No More Tears (Enough is Enough)" (Special
    Disco Version) - a truth with modification since it was the
    exact same version as on the A-side, only without the ballad
    intro ( - 3:04).</p>
      <p>To date Summer or Streisand have never performed the song
    together live since recording it, although Summer still sings
    the song live in concert with other female performers, most
    recently her sister Mary Gaines Bernard.</p>
      <p>Comedian Eddie Murphy recorded a parody version of the song
    as it would be performed by exercise guru Richard Simmons and
    Little Rascals star "Buckwheat." The song appears on his
    self-titled comedy album.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
