<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Way_We_Were_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Way_We_Were_(song)</songId>
   <title>The Way We Were</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barbra_Streisand</artistId>
      <artistName>Barbra Streisand</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-02-02</week>
      <week>1974-02-16</week>
      <week>1974-02-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>The Way We Were</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 1973</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1973</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:31</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Alan Bergman</writer>
      <writer>Marilyn Bergman</writer>
      <writer>Marvin Hamlisch</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Marty Paich</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Way We Were" is the title song to the 1973 movie 
    <i>The Way We Were</i>, starring Barbra Streisand and Robert
    Redford. The song was written by Alan Bergman and Marilyn
    Bergman, scored by Marvin Hamlisch and performed by Streisand.
    It won the Academy Award and Golden Globe for Best Song and
    also made AFI's list of Top 100 Songs from Film; it was ranked
    number eight.</p>
      <p>"The Way We Were" topped the Hot 100 chart for one week in
    1974 and was replaced by "Love's Theme" by Love Unlimited
    Orchestra. It then returned to number one for two additional
    weeks. The song also spent two weeks atop the easy listening
    chart, Streisand's second single to reach the top of this chart
    (following 1964's "People").</p>
      <p>The 45 version of the song is a different vocal take than
    the version which appeared on the original movie soundtrack and
    subsequent greatest hits compilations. Both versions use the
    same music track. The difference in the vocals can most easily
    be heard on the line "Smiles we gave to one another" at
    approximately 1:15 into the song. The true 45 RPM single
    version has never appeared on CD. The soundtrack version of the
    song, a completely different take with alternate music track,
    appears on "Just For the Record," Streisand's 4-CD box set
    collection released in 1991.</p>
      <p>A bootleg of the recording sessions exists featuring
    Streisand with composer Marvin Hamlisch in a recording studio
    as they perform various takes of the song. One segment reveals
    Streisand changing the first word of the song from "Daydreams"
    to "Memories."</p>
      <p>Streisand's version was listed at #90 on 
    <i>Billboard's Greatest Songs of All Time.</i>[1]</p>
      <p>A 1975 version by Gladys Knight &amp; the Pips featured the
    intro to the song "Try to Remember", and was credited as "The
    Way We Were/Try to Remember". Released as a single, it reached
    #11 on the Billboard Hot 100 and #6 on the Hot Soul Singles
    chart.</p>
      <p>In 1975 Shirley Bassey recorded the song on her album 
    <i>Good, Bad, But Beautiful</i>.</p>
      <p>José José recorded the song in Spanish titled "Nuestros
    Recuerdos", included in his 1975 album 
    <i>Tan Cerca...Tan Lejos</i>.</p>
      <p>In Australia from March 1977 the song was used in Australia
    in advertisements for international phone calls by the Overseas
    Telecommunications Commission.</p>
      <p>Donna Summer performed a cover on her 1978 live double album
    
    <i>Live and More</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1979, Gilda Radner recorded a somewhat humorous version
    of the song as character Lisa Lupner from her LP "Live from New
    York."</p>
      <p>In April 2006, Paris Bennett performed a cover in the style
    of Gladys Knight &amp; the Pips' 1975 version on 
    <i>American Idol</i>Season 5 while she was in the Top 6.</p>
      <p>In 2007, Barry Manilow included the song on his album 
    <i>The Greatest Songs of the Seventies</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2008, Girlicious did a remake of the song on their
    self-titled debut album, 
    <i>Girlicious</i>.</p>
      <p>On December 30, 2008, Beyoncé Knowles performed her cover of
    the song to Barbra Streisand at the 31st annual Kennedy Center
    Honors in Washington, D.C.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
