<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/One_Week_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/One_Week_(song)</songId>
   <title>One Week</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barenaked_Ladies</artistId>
      <artistName>Barenaked Ladies</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1998-10-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/1/1b/One_Week_BL.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Barenaked-Ladies+One-Week.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Stunt</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 22, 1998  (1998-09-22)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>cassette</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1998</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Alternative Rock</genre>
      <genre>Rap Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:52</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Reprise Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ed Robertson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Barenaked Ladies</producer>
      <producer>David Leonard</producer>
      <producer>Susan Rogers</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"One Week" is a 1998 hit single by Barenaked Ladies, the
    first single off their 1998 album 
    <i>Stunt</i>. It was written by Ed Robertson, who features on
    the lead vocal of the rapped verses. Steven Page sings lead on
    the song's choruses, while the two co-lead the prechoruses in
    harmony. The song is notable for its significant number of pop
    culture references. It is one of the band's signature
    songs.</p>
      <p>"One Week" is the band's best best-performing single on the
    charts in both the United States and UK, though it slightly
    under-performed several other singles in the band's native
    Canada. It was the band's first and, as of 2009, only number
    one single in the U.S. on both the Hot 100 (for one week) and
    the U.S. Modern Rock Tracks (for five non-consecutive weeks);
    The band had begun breaking in the there with "The Old
    Apartment" and "Brian Wilson", both barely breaking the top 100
    of the US chart, paving the way for "One Week" to become the
    band's breakout single. The band's US chart success has not
    been equalled, and was neared only by followup single "It's All
    Been Done", and "Pinch Me", the first single off followup album
    
    <i>Maroon</i>; Both broke the top 50 of the U.S. Hot 100.</p>
      <p>Ed Robertson wrote the ideas for the non-rap 'choruses' with
    the concept being the structure of a fight where the
    protagonist knows they are wrong and is just trying to save
    face. He wanted to come up with a rapping verse for the song
    but all attempts failed. Bandmate Steven Page suggested he
    simply improvise the rap as the two commonly did onstage every
    night. Robertson heeded the advice and set up a video camera.
    He improvised the song at a slower pace to make rhyming easier
    and arrived at about four minutes of rap. He sent it to Page
    who told him not to change a word. Two minutes of the
    improvising was almost directly compiled (with very little, if
    any, tweaking) into the verses of the song. As it is
    improvised, it is not intended to directly have any relation to
    the plot of the chorus sections. The lyrics in the liner notes
    from 
    <i>Stunt</i>contain some additional lines that did not make it
    into the recorded version.</p>
      <p>Band members have stated that the first live run-through of
    "One Week" did not go well, and that it took some time to get
    the song to sound good live. The instrumental parts are played
    by band members (notably Ed Robertson and Steven Page on
    guitar, and Kevin Hearn) sometimes on guitar and sometimes on
    keyboards; as well, while Hearn was away from touring shortly
    after the song's release, his place at shows was taken by one
    of two other musicians on keyboards who each added their own
    unique parts to the song, helping to shape its live sound
    early.</p>
      <p>The song gained renewed popularity when it was featured in
    an ad for the Mitsubishi Lancer, with groups of young people in
    the car seeming to sing along until they could not keep up with
    the rapid-fire lyrics. It was featured on the third installment
    of 
    <i>Big Shiny Tunes</i>.</p>
      <p>In performances starting in 2003, the band developed an
    acoustic, bluegrass version of the song. It is typically used
    in a new performance setting they developed on the Peepshow
    Tour that year, in which they play acoustically while they
    stand around and sing into one omni-directional microphone.</p>
      <p>With the departure of Page in early 2009, Robertson has
    taken over singing Page's lead chorus vocal, while Page's
    harmonies have been performed by drummer Tyler Stewart.</p>
      <p>Verse 1</p>
      <p>Verse 2</p>
      <p>Outro</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by McG and begins with them
    singing in a royal court, featuring a singing girl on a wind-up
    pedestal, similar to a scene from the movie 
    <i>Chitty Chitty Bang Bang</i>. During the interlude they make
    an escape and sing while driving a lookalike of The General Lee
    from 
    <i>The Dukes of Hazzard</i>(using the numbers 07 instead of 01
    and minus the Confederate flag on the roof) and Starsky &amp;
    Hutch's Ford Gran Torino. The band drives into a suburb, where
    they perform a concert in front of a trailer, with a female
    motorcyclist, dressed like Evel Knievel, performing stunts. The
    video ends with a shot of the cyclist stuck on a tree. The
    video features Carmit Bachar from the Pussycat Dolls, playing
    an angel.</p>
      <p>"One Week" is in the video game "KR: American Idol Encore"
    as downloadable content. It is also on the game Karaoke
    Revolution as a playable song.</p>
      <p>The song appeared in a 2002 commercial for the Mitsubishi
    Lancer.</p>
      <p>"Weird Al" Yankovic has parodied "One Week". His version,
    called "Jerry Springer", features lyrics about The Jerry
    Springer Show. ApologetiX has also parodied this song on their 
    <i>Biblical Graffiti</i>album. Their version is called "One
    Way", and claims that Jesus Christ is the one way to Heaven. In
    January 2009, Collegehumor also released their own parody of
    the song, using lyrics making fun of the song's
    mostly-meaningless lyrics.</p>
      <p>One Week also appeared in Digimon: The Movie, American Pie
    and 10 Things I Hate About You</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
