<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mandy_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mandy_(song)</songId>
   <title>Mandy</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barry_Manilow</artistId>
      <artistName>Barry Manilow</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1975-01-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f6/Barrysecondalbum.jpg/200px-Barrysecondalbum.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Barry-Manilow+Mandy.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Barry Manilow II</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1974</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1974</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Bell</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Scott English</writer>
      <writer>Richard Kerr</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Brandy" is a 1971 hit for songwriters Scott English and
    Richard Kerr. It reached number 12 in the UK Singles Charts,
    but the fast-tempo version was a flop in the United States. In
    1974, recorded by Barry Manilow as "Mandy", the song was
    Manilow's first number-one hit on the Billboard Hot 100 and
    Easy Listening charts, and his first gold single.</p>
      <p>The suggestion that Scott English wrote the song about a
    favorite dog is apparently an urban legend. English has said
    that a reporter called him early one morning asking who
    "Brandy" was, and an irritated English made up the "dog" story
    to get the reporter off his back.</p>
      <p>In the three years between English's 1971 recording and
    Manilow's, Looking Glass had a hit song with "Brandy (You're a
    Fine Girl)" in 1972. Therefore, to avoid confusion, when
    Manilow decided to make his record, he changed the title to
    "Mandy". It was Clive Davis who suggested that Manilow record
    the song. Manilow originally recorded it as an up-tempo
    bubblegum pop tune similar to English's original, but he and
    the producer reportedly hated the way it turned out; thus, he
    sang it as a ballad and was much more pleased with the results.
    It was Manilow's first hit single and the first song on Clive
    Davis' Arista Records label (formerly Bell Records) to hit the
    Billboard Hot 100.</p>
      <p>There have been several other notable cover versions,
    including Andy Williams (1975), Richard Clayderman (1994),
    Johnny Mathis (1997), Me First and the Gimme Gimmes (1997),
    Bradley Joseph (2005), Raymond Quinn (X Factor runner-up 2006),
    Donny Osmond (2007).</p>
      <p>The song was also a hit for the Irish group Westlife.
    "Mandy" was the second single released from their album
    Turnaround.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
