<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Write_the_Songs 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Write_the_Songs</songId>
   <title>I Write the Songs</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barry_Manilow</artistId>
      <artistName>Barry Manilow</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1976-01-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Tryin' to Get the Feeling</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 1975</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" (45 rpm)</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1975</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Adult Contemporary</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:51</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Arista 0157</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bruce Johnston</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Ron Dante</producer>
      <producer>Barry Manilow</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Write the Songs" is a popular song by Barry Manilow from
    1975 written by Bruce Johnston. Manilow's version reached #1 on
    the Hot 100 chart in early 1976 after spending two weeks atop
    the 
    <i>Billboard</i>adult contemporary chart in December 1975. It
    won a Grammy Award for Song of the Year and was nominated for
    Record of the Year in 1977 and became one of Manilow's
    signature songs.</p>
      <p>The title has been misunderstood to mean that the singer (or
    songwriter) "
    <i>writes the songs</i>," but the actual songwriter, The Beach
    Boys' Bruce Johnston, has stated that the "I" in the song is
    "music". He went on to say that songs come from the spirit of
    creativity in all of us.</p>
      <p>The first time the song was released on a single was from
    David Cassidy in 1975 from the album, 
    <i>The Higher They Climb</i>. The single reached #11 on the UK
    Singles Chart in August of that year.</p>
      <p>Manilow was initially reluctant to record the song, stating
    in his autobiography 
    <i>Sweet Life</i>: "The problem with the song was that if you
    didn't listen carefully to the lyric, you would think that the
    singer was singing about himself. It could be misinterpreted as
    a monumental ego trip." After persuasion by Clive Davis, then
    president of Arista Records, Manilow relented and recorded the
    song, and his version of "I Write the Songs" was the first
    single taken from the album 
    <i>Tryin' to Get the Feeling</i>. It first charted on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 on November 15, 1975, reaching the top
    of the chart nine weeks later, on January 17, 1976.</p>
      <p>This song was also recorded by Captain &amp; Tennille,
    Johnny Mathis, Tom Jones, Dinah Shore, David Osborne, as well
    as Bruce Johnston himself on his 1977 
    <i>Going Public</i>album. Frank Sinatra sang it as "I Sing The
    Songs". In 2008 Me First And The Gimme Gimmes recorded it on
    their album 
    <i>Have Another Ball</i>.</p>
      <p>Manilow once did a parody duet titled "I Write The Songs/I
    Wreck The Songs" with Rosie O'Donnell on her talk show on April
    18, 1997. A sample of the lyrics is:</p>
      <p>B: I write the songs that you sing in the shower, R: You
    write the songs I mutilate by the hour, B: You sing my songs
    and make your neighbors complain, B: I write the songs, R: I
    wreck the songs, B: I am music, R: And I wreck the songs!,</p>
      <p>Manilow did another shortened performance of this song with
    Stephen Colbert when he was a guest on 
    <i>The Colbert Report</i>on October 30, 2006.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
