<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eve_of_Destruction_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eve_of_Destruction_(song)</songId>
   <title>Eve of Destruction</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barry_McGuire</artistId>
      <artistName>Barry McGuire</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1965-09-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1965</released>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:38</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Dunhill</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>P. F. Sloan</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Eve of Destruction" is a protest song written by P. F.
    Sloan in 1965. Several artists have recorded it, but the
    best-known recording was by Barry McGuire. This recording was
    made between July 12 and July 15, 1965 and released by Dunhill
    Records. The accompanying musicians were top-tier LA session
    men: P.F. Sloan on guitar, Hal Blaine (of Phil Spector's
    "Wrecking Crew") on drums, and Larry Knechtel on bass. The
    vocal track was thrown on as a rough mix and was not intended
    to be the final version, but a copy of the recording "leaked"
    out to a DJ, who began playing it. The song was an instant hit
    and as a result the more polished vocal track that was at first
    envisioned was never recorded.</p>
      <p>In the first week of its release, the single was at number
    103 on the charts. By August 12, Dunhill released the LP, "Nick
    Featuring Eve of Destruction". The LP reached its peak of
    number thirty-seven on the Billboard album chart during the
    week ending September 25. That same day the single went to
    number one on the chart, and repeated the feat on the 
    <i>Cashbox</i>chart, where it had debuted at number thirty.
    McGuire was never again to break into the top forty of the
    Billboard Hot 100.</p>
      <p>The song had initially been presented to The Byrds as a
    Dylanesque potential single, but they rejected it. The Turtles,
    another LA group who often recorded The Byrds' discarded or
    rejected material, recorded a version instead. Their version
    was issued as an album track shortly before McGuire's version
    was cut. It eventually hit number 100 on the Billboard Hot 100
    in 1970.</p>
      <p>The song is a grave warning of imminent apocalypse, and
    considered by some to be the epitome of a protest song. It
    expressed the frustrations and fears of young people in the age
    of the Cold War, Vietnam, the nuclear arms race, and the civil
    rights movement.</p>
      <p>The American media helped popularize the song by using it as
    an example of everything that was wrong with the youth of that
    time. The song also drew flak from conservatives. A group
    called The Spokesmen released an answer record entitled "The
    Dawn of Correction". A few months later, Green Beret medic Sgt.
    Barry Sadler released the patriotic "Ballad of the Green
    Berets". Johnny Sea's spoken word recording, "Day For
    Decision", was also a response to the song. The Temptations'
    song "Ball of Confusion (That's What the World Is Today)"
    mentions the song title.</p>
      <p>In the late 1970s, Los Angeles punk band The Dickies
    recorded a cover of "Eve of Destruction". New Wave group Red
    Rockers covered the song in their 1984 album 
    <i>Schizoprenic Circus</i>. Johnny Thunders recorded it in the
    "Hurt Me" album and also frequently covered the song in
    concert, while veteran Canadian punk outfit D.O.A. also covered
    the song on their 2004 album 
    <i>Live Free Or Die</i>. The song has also been covered by
    Australian band Screaming Jets on their 1997 album 
    <i>World Gone Crazy</i>. Left-wing Christian punk band Crashdog
    also covered it on their album 
    <i>Cashists, Fascists, and Other Fungus</i>. Post-Industrial
    psychedelic rock outfit Psychic TV released "Eve Ov
    Destruction" as a limited edition single in the late 1980s. In
    2003, the reggae singer Luciano recorded a version of the song.
    The band Bishop Allen also released a song titled "Eve of
    Destruction" on their 2003 album, "Charm School" which takes
    it's chorus from this song.</p>
      <p>The song was briefly featured on Stephen King's 1994
    miniseries 
    <i>The Stand</i>. With a burning Des Moines, Iowa as a
    backdrop, Larry Underwood sits atop the hood of a car, belting
    out the song to amuse himself until interrupted by another
    survivor of the superflu. It also appeared in 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>episode GABF16, "The Girl Who Slept Too
    Little," and was also featured in Michael Winterbottom's 1997
    film 
    <i>Welcome to Sarajevo</i>. A Joey Scarbury cover was played
    repeatedly in the original airing of 
    <i>The Greatest American Hero</i>episode "Operation Spoil
    Sport" to encourage the hero to prevent an automated nuclear
    strike being triggered by a renegade U.S. general (the aliens
    who provided the hero's super-powers commandeered his car radio
    and tuned it to stations playing the song). Due to rights
    issues, the song does not appear in the DVD version of the
    episode. A French translation is used in the closing credits of
    Michael Moore's film 
    <i>Sicko</i>. An Italian version, "Questo vecchio pazzo mondo"
    ("This old crazy world"), was recorded by Gino Santercole in
    1967; a 1984 recording by Adriano Celentano was included in his
    album 
    <i>I miei americani</i>(a collection of US hits translated into
    Italian).This song also makes an appearance in "The
    Doors"(directed by Oliver Stone), as the opening act performs
    it before the Doors take the stage in Miami.</p>
      <p>Though he's now known primarily as a singer of contemporary
    Christian songs, Barry McGuire has continued to sing "Eve Of
    Destruction" in recent years, often updating the lyrics to
    refer to such events as the Columbine High School massacre.</p>
      <p>The song was banned by some radio stations in the USA as
    well as by the BBC and Radio Scotland.</p>
      <p>The song, like many other popular songs of the day, gave its
    name to a gun truck used by United States Army Transportation
    Corps forces during the Vietnam war. The truck is on display at
    the U.S. Army Transportation Museum and is believed to be the
    only surviving example of a Vietnam era gun truck.</p>
      <p>The song is featured in the fourth level of the Vietnam War
    Video game Men of Valor. While the song is playing, the main
    character's lieutenant is dying of his wound on the
    battlefield.</p>
      <p>Barry McGuire became a born-again Christian, and as a result
    renounced the song for many years, refusing to perform it.</p>
      <p>Barry McGuire updated the lyrics when he performed at a
    reunion of folksingers, with the line "Selma, Alabama",
    replaced by the words "Columbine Colorado", referring to the
    student massacre of 1999.</p>
      <p>On March 12, 2008, Barry McGuire appeared on the Australian
    Music Comedy/Game Show 
    <i>Spicks and Specks</i>, performing an updated version of "Eve
    of Destruction", with new lines such as "You're old enough to
    kill/ you just started voting" and "...can live for ten years
    in space". The reference to "Red China" was also removed.</p>
      <p>McGuire also mentioned that "Eve of Destruction" was
    recorded in one take on a Thursday morning (from words scrawled
    on a crumpled piece of paper), and he got a call from the
    record company at 7:00 the following Monday morning, telling
    him to turn on the radio - his song was playing. The recording
    includes an "ahhh" where McGuire couldn't read the words.</p>
      <p>ESPN sportscaster Chris Berman, famous for inventing
    nicknames for sports figures, and often bringing song titles
    into the play on words, dubbed slugger Mark McGwire as "Mark
    'Eve of Destruction' McGwire".</p>
      <p>The indie rock group Bishop Allen perform a song by the same
    name which borrows heavily from the original, but with an even
    more sharply apocalyptic theme. It includes the lyrics "And if
    this moment is gone in a flash/ And my hand in yours becomes
    ash in ash", followed in the next verse by an imagining of
    rejection from Heaven: "Then we'll have a dance, yeah a dance,
    on the head of a pin/ Then God will grin, and shoo us
    away".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
