<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saturday_Night_(Bay_City_Rollers_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saturday_Night_(Bay_City_Rollers_song)</songId>
   <title>Saturday Night</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bay_City_Rollers</artistId>
      <artistName>Bay City Rollers</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1976-01-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1975</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Arista</label>
   <descr>
      <p>"Saturday Night" is a 1976 pop hit by the Scottish band Bay
    City Rollers. It was written and produced by Bill Martin and
    Phil Coulter. The tune is an upbeat pop-rock number with a
    memorable hook: the word "Saturday" spelled out in a rhythmic
    chant.</p>
      <p>An early version of the song was recorded in the UK in 1973,
    but did not hit the charts. On the first version Gordon "Nobby"
    Clark was the lead singer of the band. The song was re-recorded
    for the Rollers' 1974 UK album 
    <i>Rollin'</i>, but never saw release as a single in their home
    country; by this time Clark had left the band for solo work and
    had been replaced by Les McKeown. The re-recording was issued
    as a US single in late 1975 and became a smash hit in early
    1976, becoming the first Billboard #1 of the US Bicentennial
    year. Despite a string of worldwide hit songs, and other US
    hits, "Saturday Night" was the group's only enduring American
    hit.</p>
      <p>Among the remakes of "Saturday Night" is a 1993 hit version
    by Ned's Atomic Dustbin, featured in the Mike Myers movie 
    <i>So I Married an Axe Murderer</i>along with the Bay City
    Rollers' original.</p>
      <p>Japanese comedian Gorie released a cover of "Saturday Night"
    called "Pecori Night" which was the 48th best-selling single in
    Japan for 2005, according to Oricon charts. Although the melody
    is the same, the lyrics are completely different from the
    original.</p>
      <p>Also, the Japanese producer Yoichiro Ito - Akakage released
    a groove disco cover.</p>
      <p>Japanese boyband Arashi borrows the chorus replacing the
    lyrics Saturday Night with Carnival Night, in their song
    Carnival Night Pt. 2</p>
      <p>Japanese band JAM Project uses the Saturday Night chant
    rhythm in its song "March of Rescue Hero."</p>
      <p>Japanese band Tokio uses elements from Saturday Night in
    their song "Kanpai!!"</p>
      <p>A local band from Ottawa, Ontario, Canada, Harpoon (formerly
    known as the Eric Eggleston Band) did a cover of the song in
    2008. It is commonly used during Saturday night Ottawa Senators
    games at Scotiabank Place.</p>
      <p>Drake Bell also did a live cover of this song at his concert
    at the Auditorio Nacional in his dvd "Drake Bell In
    Concert."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
