<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Too_Much_Heaven 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Too_Much_Heaven</songId>
   <title>Too Much Heaven</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bee_Gees</artistId>
      <artistName>Bee Gees</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1979-01-06</week>
      <week>1979-01-13</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/86/Toomuchheaven.jpg/200px-Toomuchheaven.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bee-Gees+Too-Much-Heaven.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Spirits Having Flown</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>24 October 1978 ( UK ) , 21 November 1978 , ( US , Canada )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>vinyl record (7" 45 RPM)</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Criteria Studios , , Miami, Florida , , June — July 1978</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:56</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RSO</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Barry Gibb</producer>
      <producer>Robin Gibb</producer>
      <producer>Maurice Gibb</producer>
      <producer>Albhy Galuten</producer>
      <producer>Karl Richardson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Too Much Heaven" is a song by the Bee Gees, which was the
    band's contribution to the "Music for UNICEF" fund. They
    performed it at the Music for UNICEF Concert on January 9,
    1979. The song later found its way to the group's thirteenth
    original album, 
    <i>Spirits Having Flown</i>. In the United States and Canada,
    it became the latest in a long line of chart-toppers, and rose
    to the top three in the United Kingdom, as well.</p>
      <p>Imbued with their falsetto style, it is also notable for
    being one of two songs on the album featuring the Chicago horn
    section (James Pankow, Walt Parazaider and Lee Loughnane)--the
    other track with the Chicago members being "Search, Find".</p>
      <p>The recording process was the longest of all the tracks on 
    <i>Spirits Having Flown</i>as there are nine layers of
    three-part harmony creating 27 voices, though the high falsetto
    voices are the most pronounced in the final mix:</p>
      <p>The horn section from the band Chicago play on the song, in
    return for the brothers’ appearance on the Chicago song "Little
    Miss Lovin".</p>
      <p>In the summer of 1978, the Gibb brothers announced their
    latest project at a news conference at the United Nations in
    New York City. All of the publishing royalties on their next
    single would go into UNICEF, to celebrate the International
    Year of the Child, which was designated to be 1979. The song
    earned over $7 million dollars in publishing royalties.
    Then-United Nations Secretary-General Kurt Waldheim heralded
    the move as "an outstanding and generous initiative."</p>
      <p>The Bee Gees were later invited to the White House, where
    President Jimmy Carter thanked the group for their donation. At
    the ceremony, the brothers presented Carter with one of their
    black satin tour jackets. Carter remarked that he was "not a
    disco fan" but knew enough about their music because his
    daughter Amy was a big fan.</p>
      <p>"Too Much Heaven" was released nine months after "Night
    Fever". At the time, this had been the longest gap in The Bee
    Gees' distribution of singles since 1975.</p>
      <p>The single "Too Much Heaven" was released in the late autumn
    of 1978 (it had originally been intended for use in the John
    Travolta movie 
    <i>Moment By Moment</i>, but was pulled before the film's
    release reportedly because Barry Gibb thought the movie was
    awful when he was shown a rough cut.), and started a slow
    ascent up the music charts. In the first week of 1979,
    preceding the Music for UNICEF Concert, the single first topped
    the charts in both the United States and Canada. In the United
    Kingdom, the single peaked at number three late in 1978. A slow
    ballad that was unlike the previous two singles off the 
    <i>Saturday Night Fever</i>soundtrack, Barry Gibb noted that
    the group wanted to "move in an R&amp;B direction, still
    maintaining our lyric power, and our melody power as well."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
