<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_Can_You_Mend_a_Broken_Heart 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_Can_You_Mend_a_Broken_Heart</songId>
   <title>How Can You Mend a Broken Heart</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bee_Gees</artistId>
      <artistName>Bee Gees</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1971-08-07</week>
      <week>1971-08-14</week>
      <week>1971-08-21</week>
      <week>1971-08-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a7/BrokenHeart.jpg/200px-BrokenHeart.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bee-Gees+How-Can-You-Mend-a-Broken-Heart.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Trafalgar</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 1971</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>28 January 1971 , IBC Studios , London</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:57</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Polydor (UK) , Atco (U.S., Canada)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Barry Gibb</writer>
      <writer>Robin Gibb</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Robert Stigwood</producer>
      <producer>Barry Gibb</producer>
      <producer>Robin Gibb</producer>
      <producer>Maurice Gibb</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Let's Stay Together</i>
      </p>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Sex and the City: Original Motion Picture Soundtrack</i>
      </p>
      <p>"How Can You Mend a Broken Heart" is a song released by the
    Bee Gees in 1971. The song had been written by Barry and Robin
    Gibb in August 1970, when the Gibb brothers had reconvened
    following a period of break-up and alienation. They said that
    they originally offered it to Andy Williams, but ultimately the
    Bee Gees recorded it themselves and included it on their 1971
    album, 
    <i>Trafalgar</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was recorded on 28 January 1971 in London. The
    instrumental track is: Barry Gibb (guitar), Maurice Gibb
    (guitar, piano, bass guitar), possibly Alan Kendall (guitar),
    and Geoff Bridgeford (drums), with strings and woodwinds
    arranged and conducted by Bill Shepherd. The vocals are by
    Robin (solo in the opening verse), Barry (solo in choruses and
    second verse), and Maurice (joins Barry and Robin in harmony on
    choruses). It was released as a single in May 1971 ahead of the
    album. The B side was a non-album song "Country Woman", written
    by Maurice Gibb, recorded on 6 April by Maurice (guitar, piano,
    bass guitar), Kendall (guitar), Bridgeford (drums), and
    Shepherd (string and horn arrangement).</p>
      <p>Although failing to chart on the UK Singles Chart, the song
    became the Bee Gees' first U.S. number one on the Hot 100 and
    also reached number four on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Adult Contemporary chart.</p>
      <p>Recently this song was featured on Denzel Washington's
    character's I-Pod in "The Book of Eli"</p>
      <p>An alternate version appeared on the first UK pressing of
    the 2001 compilation 
    <i>Their Greatest Hits: The Record</i>. It has different vocal,
    piano, and bass guitar tracks. It is very noticeable that
    Barry, not Robin, sings the first verse, and that Barry's sigh
    does not appear before each chorus. This was a tape library
    mistake, both this and the correct reel being marked as best.
    The differences illustrate how the Bee Gees built up a
    recording track by track. These unsatisfactory vocal, piano,
    and bass tracks would be re-done to make the officially
    released version.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
