<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jive_Talkin%27 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jive_Talkin%27</songId>
   <title>Jive Talkin'</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bee_Gees</artistId>
      <artistName>Bee Gees</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1975-08-09</week>
      <week>1975-08-16</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a7/Jive_Talkin.jpg/200px-Jive_Talkin.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bee-Gees+Jive-Talkin.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Main Course</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>31 May 1975</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl record (7" 45 RPM)</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Criteria Studios , , Miami, Florida , , 30 January — , 19 February 1975</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3 min 46 s</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RSO</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Barry</writer>
      <writer>Robin &amp; Maurice Gibb</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Arif Mardin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Jive Talkin'" is a song by the Bee Gees, which hit number
    one on the Billboard Hot 100 and reached the top-five on the UK
    singles chart in the summer of 1975. Largely recognized as the
    group's "comeback" song, it was their first U.S. top ten hit
    since "How Can You Mend a Broken Heart" in 1971.</p>
      <p>The song was originally called "Drive Talking". The song's
    rhythm was modeled after the sound a car would make crossing
    the bridge from Biscayne Bay into Miami. The sound of the car's
    tires were making a "Chicka, Chicka, Chicka," sound, which was
    used vocally before the group sings the title of the song.
    Producer Arif Mardin wished to market the song toward the teen
    market, and suggested the change to "Jive Talkin'" (the phrase
    "jive talkin'", slang for "telling lies", was a popular
    colloquialism at the time). Barry Gibb wrote the song and then
    had to fix the lyrics upon completion because he had assumed
    "jive talkin'" referred to "speaking in jive", a then-popular
    term for African-American Vernacular English. All actual
    "talking jive" references were fixed so they meant "lying".</p>
      <p>Upon its release to radio stations, the single was delivered
    in a plain white cover, with no immediate indication of what
    the song's name was or who sang it. The DJs would only find out
    what the song was and who played it when it was placed on the
    turntable; RSO did provide the song with a label on the record
    itself.</p>
      <p>The disco-oriented sound was a departure from the pop
    ballads the Bee Gees had become known for. With the new sound,
    the public had gained a newfound interest in the Bee Gees and
    their music. The single sold over a million copies in the
    United States alone, and sold in excess of a hundred thousand
    copies in Canada. While not a top seller in the United Kingdom,
    it did mark the first time in three years that a Bee Gees
    single had charted there.</p>
      <p>Two years after its release as a single the song was
    included on the Bee Gees-dominated soundtrack to Saturday Night
    Fever.</p>
      <p>In 1987 this song was covered by the Boogie Box High. Boogie
    Box High was a musical project by Andros Georgiou in the late
    1980s, that featured a range of vocal collaborations such as
    his relative George Michael (of Wham!) and Nick Heyward (of
    Haircut 100). A cover of the Bee Gees song Jive Talkin' was
    their biggest hit in 1987.</p>
      <p>On Iron Maiden's song "More Tea Vicar", towards the end,
    Bruce Dickinson sings a bit of the song in a voice imitating
    The Bee Gees as a joke, then follows it up with "No, no no! You
    got the wrong track, you have to go in the studio next door."
    Then sings "Okay" in a Bee Gees voice.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
