<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stayin%27_Alive 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stayin%27_Alive</songId>
   <title>Stayin' Alive</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bee_Gees</artistId>
      <artistName>Bee Gees</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1978-02-04</week>
      <week>1978-02-11</week>
      <week>1978-02-18</week>
      <week>1978-02-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/36/Bee_Gees_Stayin_Alive.jpg/200px-Bee_Gees_Stayin_Alive.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bee-Gees+Stayin-Alive.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Saturday Night Fever: The Original Movie Sound Track</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 13, 1977</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl record (7" 45 RPM)</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Château d'Hérouville , , Hérouville , France 1977</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:45</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RSO</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Robert Stigwood</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Stayin' Alive" is a disco song by the pop group Bee Gees
    from the Saturday Night Fever motion picture soundtrack. The
    song was written by the Bee Gees - Barry, Robin, and Maurice
    Gibb - and produced by the Bee Gees and Albhy Galuten and Karl
    Richardson. It was released on December 13, 1977, as the second
    single from the 
    <i>Saturday Night Fever</i>soundtrack.</p>
      <p>Upon release, Stayin' Alive climbed the charts, hitting the
    number one spot on the Billboard Hot 100 the week of February
    4, 1978, and staying there for four weeks. In the process, it
    became the band's most recognizable tune, in part because of
    its place at the beginning of 
    <i>Saturday Night Fever</i>.</p>
      <p>The producer of the soundtrack, Robert Stigwood (who doubled
    as the Bee Gees' manager) called them up and asked them to
    write a few songs for a soundtrack to a film he was planning.
    At this point, the film was in early stages and it didn't have
    a title yet. All Stigwood had to go on was a 
    <i>New York</i>cover story about discomania. He asked them to
    go on with the soundtrack anyway, and they wrote "Stayin'
    Alive" over the course of a few days while sprawled on the
    staircase at the Château d'Hérouville studio in Paris. As with
    Pink Floyd, a majority of the soundtrack was recorded in France
    for tax reasons.</p>
      <p>Due to the death of drummer Dennis Byron's mother in the
    middle of the song's sessions, the group first looked for a
    replacement. Oddly enough, the shortage of drummers in this
    area of France prompted the group to use a drum machine—yet it
    did not offer satisfactory results. After listening to the drum
    track of the already-recorded "Night Fever", the group (and
    engineer Albhy Galuten) selected two bars from the song,
    re-recorded them to a separate track, and proceeded with
    sessions for "Stayin' Alive". This accounts for the unchanging
    rhythm throughout the song.</p>
      <p>As a joke, the group listed the drummer as "Bernard Lupe" (a
    takeoff on session drummer Bernard Purdie). Mr. Lupe became a
    highly sought-after drummer - until it was discovered that he
    did not exist.</p>
      <p>The song was not originally supposed to be released as a
    single, but fans called radio stations and RSO Records
    immediately after seeing trailers for 
    <i>Saturday Night Fever</i>, in which the aforementioned
    introductory scene was played. The single was eventually
    released in mid-December, a month after the album, and moved to
    the top of the Billboard Hot 100 in the United States in
    February, where it would stay for four weeks. Soon after, it
    would slide to number two, locking in a solid one-two punch
    with the Bee Gees' other hit from the album, "Night Fever". In
    the United Kingdom, "Stayin' Alive" was a solid seller but not
    as popular as it was in the United States, topping out at
    number four.</p>
      <p>Further demonstrating the Bee Gees' U.S. chart domination in
    1978, "Stayin' Alive" was replaced at number one with the
    group's younger brother Andy Gibb's single, "Love Is Thicker
    Than Water", followed by the Bee Gees' own "Night Fever". This
    was then replaced by Yvonne Elliman's "If I Can't Have You".
    Since Barry Gibb had a hand in writing all four of these songs,
    he became the only person in history to write four consecutive
    U.S. number one singles.</p>
      <p>Besides the version that appeared on the soundtrack album
    (and subsequent CD release) and the edited single for the 45RPM
    and Top 40 radio release, there was yet another version, of the
    same basic mix, that was distributed to club DJs and radio
    stations that specialized in airing longer versions of hit
    songs. This "Special Disco Version" as it was called, featured
    all the same parts as the album version, but had a mysterious
    horn rhythm section part interjected twice, but turned out to
    be broadcast on very few U.S. radio stations. This version was
    finally released on CD when Reprise re-issued 
    <i>Bee Gees Greatest</i>in 2007 in an expanded &amp; remastered
    edition.</p>
      <p>As for the message of the song, Robin Gibb was quoted as
    saying, "Stayin' Alive" is about survival in the big city—any
    big city—but especially New York."</p>
      <p>The music video for the song is of a completely different
    concept to Saturday Night Fever. It depicts the group singing
    the song on an abandoned subway terminal set at MGM Studios,
    directly adjacent to the one where the boys were filming 
    <i>Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band</i>at the time. This
    set featured buildings, a train station, and other
    elements.</p>
      <p>The original three music videos for the movie 
    <i>Saturday Night Fever</i>were shot on the soundstages, and
    edited at the facilities of, Video City, Inc., in North Miami,
    Florida. The European video for "Stayin' Alive" as mentioned
    above (with Barry sans his beard) was one of these original
    three. These original music videos were scrapped and re-shot in
    California after Barry grew his beard.</p>
      <p>The song was prominently featured in the 1980 disaster spoof
    
    <i>Airplane!</i>during a memorable flashback scene in which
    Robert Hays' and Julie Hagerty's characters are shown meeting
    at a dive bar and engaging in an extremely exaggerated
    semblance of popular disco dancing. The music in the movie was
    however, sped up 10% over its usual speed, with permission.
    This parody might also have given rise to the misconception
    that "Stayin' Alive" is the song played during John Travolta's
    famous dancing scene in 
    <i>Saturday Night Fever</i>. The film Foul Play featured the
    song in a particular scene (Dudley Moore's apartment
    scene).</p>
      <p>The song has also been included on the soundtracks of over
    20 other films, and was featured in the films 
    <i>A Goofy Movie</i>, 
    <i>Bushwhacked</i>, 
    <i>A Night at the Roxbury</i>, 
    <i>Honey, I Blew Up the Kid</i>, 
    <i>Arthur and the Minimoys</i>, 
    <i>Young @ Heart</i>, 
    <i>Naked Gun 33⅓: The Final Insult</i>, 
    <i>Madagascar</i>, 
    <i>Chicken Little</i>, and 
    <i>Airplane!</i>.</p>
      <p>The song is also featured as the theme song for the movie
    Staying Alive, starring John Travolta.</p>
      <p>The Bee Gees won a Grammy Award for the song in 1977 for
    Best Vocal Arrangement for Two or More Voices.</p>
      <p>Over the years, "Stayin' Alive" has earned more critical
    acclaim. The song was ranked number 189 on the list of Rolling
    Stone's 500 Greatest Songs of All Time, and it was also on the
    list of the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame's 500 Songs that Shaped
    Rock and Roll.</p>
      <p>The song is also listed at #46 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top 100.</i>[1]</p>
      <p>A number of musicians have covered "Stayin Alive'":</p>
      <p>It featured twice on the HBO series, 
    <i>Entourage</i>, in the episodes "Aquamansion" and "The Dream
    Team". It is the only song to feature in more than one episode
    of the series.</p>
      <p>
         <i>The Simpsons</i>have made numerous references to the song,
    using it in scenes as the aforementioned "Table Five" parody
    Homer sang, during a scene in the episode "Two Bad Neighbors",
    and in a "Treehouse of Horror" scene. In "Bart's Girlfriend",
    the opening is featured.</p>
      <p>On 
    <i>Jeopardy!'</i>s 14 September 2006 episode, the last 3
    categories in the 
    <i>Jeopardy!</i>round referenced the opening lines of the
    song:</p>
      <p>U.S. ventriloquist Terry Fator uses "Stayin' Alive" in his
    stage show at The Mirage in Las Vegas, Nevada. One of Fator's
    puppets, Winston the Impersonating Turtle sings part of the
    song. The performance is included on the DVD "Terry Fator: Live
    from Las Vegas".</p>
      <p>"Stayin' Alive" was used in a study to train doctors to
    provide the correct number chest compressions per minute while
    performing CPR. The song has exactly 103 beats per minute, and
    100 chest compressions per minute are recommended for CPR. The
    study found that doctors who think about "Stayin' Alive" are
    much more likely to do CPR correctly.</p>
      <p>In the newspaper comic strip 'Fox Trot,' the older son Peter
    in one strip sings the opening lines as 'well you can tell be
    the way I view my clock, I'm at 0.9 C, less time to talk,' in a
    performance he humorously dubbed 'Saturday Night Physics', with
    other songs parodied, including 'More than a Woman' and 'Disco
    inferno' as 'More than a Photon' and 'Disc has Inertia.'</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
