<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_Deep_Is_Your_Love 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_Deep_Is_Your_Love</songId>
   <title>How Deep Is Your Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bee_Gees</artistId>
      <artistName>Bee Gees</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1977-12-24</week>
      <week>1977-12-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e1/How_Deep_Is_Your_Love.jpg/200px-How_Deep_Is_Your_Love.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bee-Gees+How-Deep-Is-Your-Love.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Saturday Night Fever</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1977</released>
   <formats>
      <format>vinyl record (7" 45 RPM)</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Château d'Hérouville , , Hérouville , 1977</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>RSO</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Barry</writer>
      <writer>Robin and Maurice Gibb</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Barry Gibb</producer>
      <producer>Robin Gibb</producer>
      <producer>Maurice Gibb</producer>
      <producer>Albhy Galuten</producer>
      <producer>and Karl Richardson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"How Deep Is Your Love" is a song recorded by the Bee Gees
    in 1977. Originally intended for Yvonne Elliman, it was
    ultimately used as part of the soundtrack to the film 
    <i>Saturday Night Fever</i>. It was a number three hit in the
    UK. In the U.S., it topped the Hot 100 on 24 December 1977 and
    stayed in the Top 10 for a then-record 17 weeks. The song also
    spent six weeks atop the U.S. adult contemporary chart. The
    song was ranked #366 on Rolling Stone's list of the 500
    Greatest Songs of All Time. Along with "Stayin' Alive", it is
    one of the group's two songs on the list. The song also lists
    at #20 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top 100.</i>It was famously covered by
    Take That for their 1996 
    <i>Greatest Hits</i>album, reaching number one on the UK
    Singles Chart for three weeks. In 1983, The Bee Gees were sued
    by a Chicago songwriter, Ronald Selle, who claimed that the
    Gibb brothers stole melodic material from one of his songs,
    "Let It End," and used it in "How Deep Is Your Love." At first,
    The Bee Gees lost the case; one juror said that a factor in the
    jury's decision was the Gibbs' failure to introduce expert
    testimony rebutting the plaintiff's expert testimony that it
    was "impossible" for the two songs to have been written
    independently. However, the verdict was overturned a few months
    later. Two music videos were made for this song. In one, the
    brothers are singing while an image of a woman shows throughout
    the video. Barry Gibb had his beard shaven off in this video,
    as in the "Night Fever" video. A second video was later made in
    which the brothers sing while passing by a stream of rainbow
    lights. In this video Barry Gibb is bearded.</p>
      <p>Take That's version was released as a single from their 
    <i>Greatest Hits</i>compilation in 1996. The single went on to
    become what was to be the band's final U.K. number one until
    their 2005 comeback a decade later. The song stayed at number
    one in the UK charts for three weeks. The single sold 670,000
    copies and has received a Platinum sales status certification
    in the UK.</p>
      <p>The video saw the four members of the band tied to chairs
    and in a basement. A blonde woman (actress and model Paula
    Hamilton) looking slightly deranged with smeared mascara walks
    into the basement and circles the four members individually
    pulling their hair. She then puts them all into her van and
    drives down the motorway. She stops by a reservoir and has the
    four members placed on the edge, she points at each member
    before grabbing Gary's rope and pushes him back still holding
    on. Her fingers slip through the rope and he falls backwards,
    the others look shocked as she does. She then smirks and it is
    unsure whether she meant to get rid of him or not.</p>
      <p>New Zealand RnB group Adeaze released the song as a single
    in 2004</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
