<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Take_My_Breath_Away 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Take_My_Breath_Away</songId>
   <title>Take My Breath Away</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Berlin_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Berlin</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-09-13</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/d4/Berlin_-_Take_My_Breath_Away_Single_Cover.jpg/200px-Berlin_-_Take_My_Breath_Away_Single_Cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Berlin+Take-My-Breath-Away.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Top Gun soundtrackCount Three &amp; Pray</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1986</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1986</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:15</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia , Geffen</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Giorgio Moroder</writer>
      <writer>Tom Whitlock</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Giorgio Moroder</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Take My Breath Away" is the name of a love song from the
    film 
    <i>Top Gun</i>(1986). The song was written by Giorgio Moroder
    and Tom Whitlock, performed by the band Berlin. It won the
    Academy Award for Best Original Song as well as the Golden
    Globe Award for Best Original Song in 1986.</p>
      <p>"Take My Breath Away" was the first single from the
    soundtrack album and was released in 1986 as a split single
    alongside the song "Radar Radio":</p>
      <p>The song reached number one on the Billboard Hot 100 on
    September 13, 1986 and became number 1 in the UK for four weeks
    in November 1986.</p>
      <p>"Take My Breath Away" is available on both the original 
    <i>Top Gun</i>soundtrack album and the expanded edition. The
    song was also featured in several of the band's best-of and
    remix albums: 
    <i>Best of Berlin 1979-1988</i>, 
    <i>Master Series</i>, 
    <i>Greatest Hits Remixed</i>(which includes a "Mission UK
    Remix" version), 
    <i>Live: Sacred &amp; Profane</i>and 
    <i>Metro Greatest Hits</i>. "Take My Breath Away" was one of
    the only songs not written by Berlin's John Crawford that they
    had performed on any album up to that point.</p>
      <p>"Take My Breath Away" was re-released in October 1990 to
    coincide with the first television showing of 
    <i>Top Gun</i>(by ITV, on the evening of October 6) as well as
    Peugeot's new television advertising campaign for the 405 model
    range. The re-release reached number three in the UK singles
    charts.</p>
      <p>The music video features scenes from the movie 
    <i>Top Gun</i>intermingled with Berlin's singer Terri Nunn
    performing the song in blue coveralls walking between pieces of
    planes in a windy aircraft boneyard (part of the Mojave Air
    &amp; Space Port) at night. Bandmates John Crawford and Rob
    Brill are shown relaxing in the yard and then following Terri.
    This video clip can be seen occasionally in VH1 Europe's Top 10
    Movie Soundtracks program. This video was re-released within
    the 2004 DVD Collector's Edition.</p>
      <p>In 1994 has The Flying Pickets released a Acapella-Version
    of this song on him Album The Original Flying Pickets: Volume 1
    and is 4:34 long. The B-Side of this cover is the cover of Road
    to Nowhere.</p>
      <p>American pop singer Jessica Simpson covered "Take My Breath
    Away" and released it as the third single from the album 
    <i>In This Skin</i>in 2004. Her version was produced by Billy
    Mann. Simpson chose to cover this song because she felt that it
    was the theme song of her relationship with her then husband,
    Nick Lachey. Simpson's version was also included on the
    compilation album 
    <i>Now That's What I Call Music! 16</i>(from the U.S. 
    <i>Now!</i>series). The remix is seen on 
    <i>Much Dance 2005</i>. It also received heavy airplay on
    Mainstream Urban stations.</p>
      <p>The video shows her driving through a southwestern desert.
    She stops to fill up with gas, and then arrives at a diner
    where she watches lovers in motion. The music video peaked at
    #5 on MTV's TRL and spent a total of 12 days on the
    countdown.</p>
      <p>"Take My Breath Away" became a number-twenty hit on the Hot
    100, as well as a top ten hit on the Top 40 Tracks and the Top
    40 Mainstream charts. The song also became another number-one
    hit for Simpson on the Hot 100 Singles Sales. Although the song
    did not break records of any sorts, it performed decently on
    the other tracks it charted on: the Adult Top 40, the Adult
    Contemporary, the Hot 100 Airplay, the Hot Dance Club Play, and
    the Hot Digital Tracks. In late 2005 it received a gold
    certification by the RIAA.</p>
      <p>The song has been performed by other artists; the band
    Copeland performed it on their album of cover songs, 
    <i>Know Nothing Stays the Same</i>, and it was translated into
    Cantonese and covered by Sandy Lam.</p>
      <p>The Christian rock band Relient K also covered it as part of
    their "Top Gun Medley" on a few of their tours.</p>
      <p>Originally Martha Davis of The Motels was asked by Giorgio
    Moroder to make a demo of the song. Her demo version is
    available on The Motels' 
    <i>Anthologyland</i>CD.</p>
      <p>Also to be found on YouTube under the listing for a Romanian
    band by the name of Activ, but unsure as to its validity due to
    not finding it on their website Activmusic.ro.</p>
      <p>Diana Ross covered the song in 2007 for her album 
    <i>I Love You</i>(US only; the song does not appear on the
    European edition).</p>
      <p>X Factor 2008 finalist Ruth Lorenzo covered the song for the
    first live shows, and secured a place in the second round.</p>
      <p>Though not strictly a cover, Swedish electro-pop band The
    Knife released a song called "You Take My Breath Away", a song
    that contains some melodic allusions to the Take My Breath
    Away, and a direct lyrical reference in the line "I wanted to
    get laid to 
    <i>'Take my breath away'</i>"</p>
      <p>My Morning Jacket has a rendition on one of its Early
    Recordings discs. It ends with a clip from the film Top
    Gun.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
