<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Check_on_It 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Check_on_It</songId>
   <title>Check on It</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beyonc%C3%A9_Knowles</artistId>
      <artistName>Beyoncé featuring Slim Thug</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2006-02-04</week>
      <week>2006-02-11</week>
      <week>2006-02-18</week>
      <week>2006-02-25</week>
      <week>2006-03-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/94/Checkonit.jpg/200px-Checkonit.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Beyonce-featuring-Slim-Thug+Check-on-It.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>#1's, The Pink Panther</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 13, 2005</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2005 , Sony Music Studios ( New York City , New York ) , Henson Recording Studios ( Hollywood , Los Angeles , California )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:31</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Beyoncé Knowles</writer>
      <writer>Kasseem Dean</writer>
      <writer>Sean Garrett</writer>
      <writer>Angela Beyincé</writer>
      <writer>Stayve Thomas</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Swizz Beatz</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Check on It" is a song by American R&amp;B singer Beyoncé
    Knowles, featuring American rapper Slim Thug. It was written by
    Knowles, Kasseem "Swizz Beatz" Dean, Sean Garrett, Angela
    Beyincé and Stayve Thomas, and produced by Knowles and Swizz
    Beatz for the 2006 film 
    <i>The Pink Panther</i>, in which Knowles co-stars. Although
    not included on its soundtrack album, the song is included on
    Destiny's Child's greatest hits album 
    <i>#1's</i>and on selected non-U.S. versions of Knowles' second
    solo studio album, 
    <i>B'Day</i>.</p>
      <p>Knowles said that the song started out as a joke, and that
    the title "Check on It" was jokingly used with her and her
    management before they decided to turn it into a song. However,
    the song's lyrics bluntly talks about a woman's booty.</p>
      <p>"Check on It" was released on Knowles' former group
    Destiny's Child's greatest hits, 
    <i>#1's'</i>. It was not originally intended for release as a
    single from the album 
    <i>#1's</i>. However, it received heavy rotation in US radio
    stations than the first single, "Stand Up for Love". Because of
    this, "Check on It" debuted on the Hot 100 in late 2005. A
    remix of the song was made, which features fellow Houston
    artist Bun B.</p>
      <p>"Check on It" reached number one on the Hot 100 in its
    twelfth week on the chart, becoming Knowles' third number-one
    as a solo artist and Slim Thug's first. The single remained at
    number-one for five consecutive weeks, tying Canadian singer
    Daniel Powter's 2005 single "Bad Day" for the longest-running
    number-one single in 2006. It was certified platinum by the
    RIAA for net shipment of 800,000 paid downloads. "Check on It"
    achieved crossover success, peaking at number one on the
    Rhythmic Top 40 and Hot Dance Club Play charts, and at number
    three on the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs chart. It also reached
    number one on the Pop 100, becoming Knowles' first entry on the
    chart. It was the eighth most played song of 2006 on the radio,
    being played 290,231 times.</p>
      <p>It became Knowles' fifth top-twenty hit in Canada in late
    2005, and in February 2006 the song climbed to number twenty on
    the Canadian BDS airplay chart for a second time. The song
    reached the top five in Norway and the Netherlands, the top ten
    in Europe, Switzerland, Austria and Brazil, and the top twenty
    in Germany and Sweden. In the UK the song debuted at number
    four before rising to number three the week later, selling
    122,500 copies.</p>
      <p>When demand was growing for the song, Knowles shot a music
    video serving as promotion for both 
    <i>#1's</i>and 
    <i>The Pink Panther</i>. The video was directed by Hype
    Williams, and was premiered on December 16, 2005. The remix of
    the song in the music video features a remix of "The Pink
    Panther Theme" and a rap from Bun B. "Check on It" won on
    August 31, 2006 the 2006 MTV Video Music Award for Best R&amp;B
    Video.</p>
      <p>The video has a pink theme to fit in with 
    <i>The Pink Panther</i>. Knowles is shown in mostly all pink,
    and the dancers wear PVC jackets and dance around rippling
    satin sheets. The video also features Knowles bending over and
    grabbing her behind. The video cuts to Knowles wearing a polka
    dot corset against a hot magenta polka dot wall, wearing a pink
    wig and pink lipstick. Where black bars normally appear on a
    4:3 (full screen) television showing a widescreen production,
    footage is displayed of curtains moving in the background. This
    was a trend in Hype Williams' videos during that year.</p>
      <p>The video was featured on the DVD of the film.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
