<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crazy_in_Love_(Beyonc%C3%A9_Knowles_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crazy_in_Love_(Beyonc%C3%A9_Knowles_song)</songId>
   <title>Crazy in Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beyonc%C3%A9_Knowles</artistId>
      <artistName>Beyoncé featuring Jay-Z</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2003-07-12</week>
      <week>2003-07-19</week>
      <week>2003-07-26</week>
      <week>2003-08-02</week>
      <week>2003-08-09</week>
      <week>2003-08-16</week>
      <week>2003-08-23</week>
      <week>2003-08-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/29/Beyonce_-_Crazy_In_Love_single_cover.jpg/200px-Beyonce_-_Crazy_In_Love_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Beyonce-featuring-Jay-Z+Crazy-in-Love.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Dangerously in Love</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 1, 2003</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>DVD single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2002, Sony Music Studios , ( New York City , New York )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:55</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Beyoncé Knowles</writer>
      <writer>Rich Harrison</writer>
      <writer>Shawn Carter</writer>
      <writer>Eugene Record</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Rich Harrison</producer>
      <producer>Beyonce Knowles</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Crazy in Love" is a song by American R&amp;B
    singer–songwriter Beyoncé Knowles, featuring American rapper
    Jay-Z. Knowles, Jay-Z, and producer Rich Harrison wrote the
    song for Knowles' debut solo album, 
    <i>Dangerously in Love</i>. The track features a sample from
    The Chi-Lites' 1970 song "Are You My Woman (Tell Me So)" that
    serves as the song's horn hook.</p>
      <p>Released on July 8, 2003 as the album's lead single, "Crazy
    in Love" has reached number one on the charts of United States
    and the United Kingdom, and the top ten of many charts
    worldwide. "Crazy in Love" was critically acclaimed and has
    earned Knowles several awards. In 2009, British magazine 
    <i>NME</i>voted the song as the best song of the decade. The
    song was also ranked at number three on 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s 100 Best Songs of the Decade, number
    four on Pitchfork Media's list of The Top 500 Tracks of the
    2000s, number seven on a list produced by 
    <i>The Daily Telegraph</i>and number six on Slant Magazine's
    list of the 100 Best Singles of the Decade. The song won Best
    R&amp;B Song and Best Rap/Sung Collaboration at the 46th Grammy
    Awards.</p>
      <p>In 2002, Knowles had already recorded numerous songs for 
    <i>Dangerously in Love</i>. Her management scheduled the album
    for an October 2002 release, however it was postponed several
    times to capitalize on the success of American rapper Nelly's
    single "Dilemma", which features Destiny's Child group mate
    Kelly Rowland. These delays allowed Knowles to go back to the
    studio and record more songs.</p>
      <p>Rich Harrison had already prepared a demo of "Crazy in Love"
    (originally called 'Crazy Right Now') before he met Knowles. He
    recalled: "Yeah, I had it in the chamber, I hadn't really
    shopped it much, because sometimes you don't want to come out
    of the bag before it's right. People don't really get it and
    you'll leave them with a foul taste in their mouth. So it was
    just something that I held on to until I got the call from
    B."</p>
      <p>Knowles was introduced to Harrison three months before the
    song was recorded. In the studio, Harrison played the demo for
    Knowles. After listening to the sample, Knowles asked Harrison
    to write the song, giving him two hours. The theme came from
    Knowles speaking of being conscious of her appearance. She kept
    saying "I'm looking crazy right now" and Harrison sang that
    back to her.</p>
      <p>Knowles' boyfriend, American rapper Jay-Z became involved
    late into the song's production. Around three in the morning,
    he came to the studio and recorded a rap verse, which he
    thought up in about ten minutes but had not written down.</p>
      <p>"Crazy in Love" is a love song composed in the key of D
    minor. The song's tempo is set at a moderate 100 beats per
    minute, in common time. Knowles' vocal range spans around one
    and a half octaves in the song, from A
    <sub>3</sub>to F
    <sub>5</sub>. "Crazy in Love" builds a song out of two major
    chords, B♭ and G, a third apart. One of the main vocal riffs
    uses the traditional cowbell rhythm that is often found in
    samba music and the like. Aside from its go-go vibe, "Crazy in
    Love" has also old soul influences that is derived from the
    horn hook. The hook is sampled by Harrison from the 1970 song
    "Are You My Woman? (Tell Me So)", originally recorded by the
    Chicago-based vocal group The Chi-Lites.</p>
      <p>The lyrics of "Crazy in Love" is composed in the traditional
    verse-chorus form. Jay-Z opens the song with a brief spoken
    lyrics. After Knowles sings "uh-oh, uh-oh", he continues the
    monologue. Knowles begins the first verse, followed with the
    chorus. She repeats the "uh-oh, uh-oh" phrase, leading to the
    second verse. The chorus follows, giving way to the second rap.
    The song continues to the bridge, chorus, then fades out with
    the horns.</p>
      <p>"Crazy in Love" was lauded by reviewers. Tim Sendra of
    Allmusic, an online music database, described the song as a
    "stunning pop masterpiece", while Stephen Thomas Erlewine of
    the same website called it "deliriously catchy". Darryl
    Sterdan, writing for the Canadian website Jam!, noted the
    song's "instantly addictive horn lines". Anthony DeCurtis for 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine also remarked to the horn sample,
    and noted the contribution of Jay-Z, writing: "'Crazy in
    Love' ... roars out of the speakers on the strength
    of a propulsive horn sample and the charged presence of her
    pal, Jay-Z." Marc Anthony Neal of the international webzine
    Popmatters complimented the "uh-oh, uh-oh" phrase as "catchy".
    MTV News considered the song the "proudest moment" of the
    album. "Crazy in Love" is ranked second in the list of
    biggest-selling singles since the year 2000 produced by
    Yahoo!.</p>
      <p>In 2004, Knowles received three Grammy Awards nominations
    for "Crazy in Love", in the categories of Record of the Year,
    Best R&amp;B Song, and Best Rap/Sung Collaboration, winning the
    last two. The award for Record of the Year was won by
    Coldplay's "Clocks". A remix of "Crazy in Love" known as "Krazy
    in Luv" (Maurice's Soul Nu Mix) won the award Best Remixed
    Recording, Non-Classical for its remixer, Maurice Joshua. It
    was also recognized at the 2004 ASCAP Awards as Most Performed
    Songs and its publisher, EMI, received the Publisher of the
    Year accolade. 
    <i>Vibe</i>magazine's VIBE Awards also recognized the song for
    Coolest Collabo in 2003. In Europe, "Crazy in Love" won the
    award for Best Song at the 2003 MTV Europe Music Awards. The
    song has also been recognized by Knowles' peers in the urban
    markets, and won the award for Best Collaboration at the BET
    Awards in 2004. 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>magazine ranked "Crazy in Love" 47
    in the list of The 100 Greatest Summer Songs.</p>
      <p>In 2002, Knowles signed with beverage company Pepsi.
    Subsequently, she appeared on various advertising campaigns of
    the company's product, and, in one of those promotional
    footages, the song "Crazy in Love" is being used as background
    music. "Crazy in Love" was included on the official soundtracks
    to the 2004 romantic comedy film 
    <i>Bridget Jones: The Edge of Reason</i>. In 2004, it was also
    featured in the soundtracks of American comedy film 
    <i>White Chicks</i>and 
    <i>Taxi</i>, the Hollywood remake of the French film. The 2007
    comedy film 
    <i>Good Luck Chuck</i>used "Crazy in Love" in its
    soundtrack.</p>
      <p>"Crazy in Love" was a commercial success in the United
    States. Although not yet served to retail stores, the single
    was already gaining massive attention. The single reached
    number one on the Hot 100, the official US singles chart, based
    on heavy rotation alone. The same week it reached number one, 
    <i>Dangerously in Love</i>debuted on the 200 at number one as
    well. The substantial airplay, and later in retail, gains of
    "Crazy in Love" facilitated it to dominate the chart,
    subsequently spending eight straight weeks atop the Hot 100,
    making it Knowles' first #1 single in her solo career. Beyonce
    quickly outdid herself with the release of the album's second
    single, "Baby Boy", which topped the chart one week longer than
    "Crazy in Love." The single charted for twenty-seven weeks on
    the Hot 100, spending fifteen of those weeks in the top ten,
    and twenty-six of those weeks in the top fifty. The song was
    certified gold by the Recording Industry Association of America
    in 2004 for 500,000 digital downloads. In 2006 its Mobile
    Mastertone was also certified gold. "Crazy in Love" eventually
    became the fourth biggest hit of 2003 in the United States.</p>
      <p>In international markets, "Crazy in Love" fared as well.
    Knowles made history being the second female artist to have a
    number-one single and a number-one album simultaneously in the
    UK. The first was Australian pop singer Kylie Minogue in 2001
    with her album 
    <i>Fever</i>and its single "Can't Get You out of My Head".
    Counting her career with former group Destiny's Child, this
    becomes her third number-one single in the UK and "Crazy in
    Love" was the only song to top the charts in both the UK and US
    in 2003. The single spent three weeks at number one in the
    UK,(370,000) and reached the top ten in many European
    countries. It reached number two in Australia; "Crazy in Love"
    was certified platinum by the Australian Recording Industry
    Association with sales in excess of 70,000 units, and emerged
    as the twenty-eighth best-selling single in Australia.</p>
      <p>The music video of "Crazy in Love", released in May 2003,
    was filmed by English director Jake Nava. The video showcases
    Knowles in various dance sequences. The opening scene begins
    with Knowles wearing a tank top, short shorts, and red
    high-heels. She performs an elaborate solo dance on a riser.
    The scene shifts to a gold set detailing a mock photo shoot,
    before moving into a scene with dancers detailing Knowles and
    dancing against a wall while wearing caps and full length
    pants. Jay-Z then appears and ignites a line of petrol leading
    to a car which then explodes into flames. He proceeds to
    perform his rap in front of the burning car, and Beyonce dances
    and gyrates beside him, wearing an exotic silk print over a fur
    coat, before kicking the valve off a fire hydrant. She
    continues to dance while the water is flying all over the
    place. The video ends with Knowles and her dancers in front of
    a giant fan in vibrant dresses in contrast to the more neutral
    colors of the background, the video also had Carmit Bachar (one
    of the former Pussycat Dolls) as one of the dancers.</p>
      <p>The music video received acclaim from critics, and won three
    awards at the 2003 MTV Video Music Awards in the categories of
    Best Female Video, Best R&amp;B Video, and Best
    Choreography.</p>
      <p>The song has various remixes, including the Rockwilder
    remix, Maurice's Nu Soul remix, and Juniors World remix. These
    versions appeared on the single releases of "Crazy in Love"
    under an altered spelling, "Krazy in Luv". British close
    harmony trio The Puppini Sisters have recorded a version of the
    song on their 'The Rise of Ruby Woo' album - a cover version
    further remixed by English electronica jazz outfit The Real
    Tuesday Weld. A version of the song included on Asian releases
    of 
    <i>Dangerously in Love</i>features a rap in Mandarin Chinese
    performed by American-Taiwanese singer Vanness Wu, in lieu of
    Jay-Z's performance.</p>
      <p>Since the song's release, many artists have recorded cover
    versions. In 2003, Irish singer-songwriter Mickey Joe Harte
    recorded an acoustic rendition of "Crazy In Love" for the
    charity album 
    <i>Even Better Than the Real Thing Vol. 1</i>. Alternative rock
    band Snow Patrol covered the song on a BBC session with Zane
    Lowe. The cover was released as a b-side to the single
    "Spitting Games" and was later included on the compilation 
    <i>Cosmosonica - Tom Middleton Presents Crazy Covers Vol.
    1</i>. David Byrne performed "Crazy in Love" live, at the
    Hollywood Bowl in 2005. In 2007, American alternative rock band
    Switchfoot produced a rock version released in part of Yahoo!'s
    CoverArt series. While maintaining the fundamental elements of
    the track, Switchfoot added their "rock flavor" in it. The band
    shot a video for the cover version and is available on the
    Yahoo! Pepsi Smash website. After performing the song on air on
    the Australian radio station Triple J, The Magic Numbers
    recorded a cover for the 2007 Starbucks (Hear Music)
    compilation album, 
    <i>Sounds Eclectic: The Covers Project</i>. British close
    harmony trio The Puppini Sisters covered the song for their
    2007 album 
    <i>The Rise and Fall of Ruby Woo</i>. Indie artist Dsico
    recorded an electronic music style cover of the song, which is
    available for download on the Internet. German group The
    Baseballs covered the song in rockabilly style for their debut
    album 
    <i>Strike!</i>in 2009. Antony and the Johnsons released an
    orchestral take of the song as the b-side to their 2009 "Aeon"
    single.</p>
      <p>This song was number three on 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s 2009 list of the 50 Best Songs of the
    Decade. And number one on NME's " Tracks Of The Decade"</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
