<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single_Ladies_(Put_a_Ring_on_It) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single_Ladies_(Put_a_Ring_on_It)</songId>
   <title>Single Ladies (Put a Ring on It)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beyonc%C3%A9_Knowles</artistId>
      <artistName>Beyoncé</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2009-01-03</week>
      <week>2009-01-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/aa/Singleladiesbk.jpg/200px-Singleladiesbk.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Beyonce+Single-Ladies-Put-a-Ring-on-It.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>I Am... Sasha Fierce</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 8, 2008  (2008-10-08) , February 16, 2009  (2009-02-16) ( UK , Germany )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2008</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:12</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Beyoncé Knowles</writer>
      <writer>Terius "The-Dream" Nash</writer>
      <writer>Thaddis "Kuk Harrell" Harrell</writer>
      <writer>Christopher "Tricky" Stewart</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Christopher "Tricky" Stewart</producer>
      <producer>The-Dream</producer>
      <producer>Beyoncé Knowles</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Single Ladies (Put a Ring on It)" is a song by American
    singer Beyoncé Knowles, composed by Christopher Stewart, Terius
    Nash, Kuk Harrell and Knowles for her third solo album, 
    <i>I Am... Sasha Fierce</i>. The song was released as the
    album's second single after her worldwide hit "If I Were a
    Boy". It was a critical and commercial success, becoming
    Knowles' fifth solo single to peak at number one on the Hot
    100, and peaking in the top 10 in various countries.</p>
      <p>The song gained popularity for its catchy hook and theme of
    female empowerment, and it was ranked #1 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's list of the Best 100 Singles of
    2008 and number two on MTV's list of the Best Songs of 2008.
    The choreography-driven video achieved great success, prompting
    a legion of imitations and parodies, and, according to the 
    <i>Toronto Star</i>, became known for starting the first major
    dance craze of the millennium and of the Internet.</p>
      <p>The song's music video was nominated in nine categories for
    the 2009 MTV Video Music Awards and won three, including Best
    Choreography and Video of the Year. It also won Video of the
    Year at the 2009 BET Awards, the 2009 MOBO awards, and the 2009
    MTV Europe Music Awards. It won the Song of the Year at the
    2009 Soul Train Awards, and won Song of the Year, Best R&amp;B
    Song, and Best Female R&amp;B Vocal Performance at the 52nd
    Grammy Awards ceremony.</p>
      <p>"Single Ladies" is ranked as the number two Best Song of the
    Decade in 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's Reader's Poll. The song appeared
    at number 50 on the magazine's critics' list of the 100 Best
    Songs of the Decade.</p>
      <p>"Single Ladies (Put a Ring on It)", alongside "If I Were a
    Boy", was initially targeted to debut on radio stations on
    October 7, 2008, with aims at rhythmic formats for the former.
    However, the song premiered the following day on the mainstream
    urban radio station Power 105.1.</p>
      <p>The song was performed on November 9, 2008 at the 2008 World
    Music Awards and at 
    <i>Saturday Night Live</i>on November 15, 2008; that night,
    Knowles was also featured in a parody of the "Single Ladies
    (Put a Ring On It)" music video, where the two female backup
    dancers from the video were replaced by three men. One of the
    three men was Justin Timberlake, who showed up unexpectedly at
    the dressing room in a leotard before filming. The other two
    were 
    <i>SNL</i>cast members Andy Samberg and Bobby Moynihan. On
    November 16, 2008, Knowles performed the song during the final
    episode of 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>. Knowles performed the song on
    November 18, 2008 at BET's 
    <i>106 &amp; Park</i>. She also performed "Single Ladies (Put a
    Ring on It)" during the 2008 AMA Awards on November 23, 2008.
    On November 25, 2008, she performed the song on 
    <i>The Ellen DeGeneres Show</i>. On November 26, 2008, she
    performed the song at Rockefeller Plaza on 
    <i>The Today Show</i>. Knowles also performed the song on 
    <i>The Tyra Banks Show</i>with two male dancers.</p>
      <p>This song has been included in many television shows,
    including J.J. Abrams' 
    <i>Fringe</i>, 
    <i>Cougar Town</i>, and was used at least three times in 
    <i>Glee</i>.</p>
      <p>The song received generally positive critical response. Bill
    Lamb of About.com, stated that: "Stylistically, the pair ['If I
    Were a Boy'/'Single Ladies'] are very distinctive from each
    other, but both are pure Beyoncé. To my ears, 'If I Were a Boy'
    sounds like an 'Irreplaceable' size smash. However, that is
    only if it doesn't get overshadowed by the power bounce of
    'Single Ladies,' an extension of the style of 'Get Me Bodied'
    from 
    <i>B'Day</i>." Allmusic had a negative view of the similarities
    between the two songs, saying the song is "a dire 'Get Me
    Bodied' retread". Leah Greenblatt of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>magazine said the song "is all
    bouncy hand claps and post-breakup sass, a giddy, high-stepping
    hybrid of lyrical kiss-off and fizzy jump-rope jam". Mariel
    Concepcion of 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine was not impressed with the song,
    calling it "standard screech-thump fare".</p>
      <p>
         <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine named "Single Ladies (Put a Ring
    On It)" the best song of 2008 writing, "The beat, courtesy of
    The-Dream and Tricky Stewart, is irresistible and exuberant,
    the vocal hook is stormy and virtuosic." The song also landed
    at number two on MTV's list of "The Best songs of 2008":
    "'Single Ladies' is hyperactive and supercharged in ways I
    never thought possible. It's epic and sexy and even a bit sad
    (because, you know, he didn't put a ring on it)...there is
    absolutely zero chance Beyoncé ever releases a single like this
    ever again." 
    <i>Time</i>magazine's critic Josh Tyrangiel, who called the
    song "ludicrously infectious", ranked it the seventh best song
    of 2008. "Single Ladies (Put A Ring On It)" has also been named
    Song of the Year by Fuse TV.</p>
      <p>"Single Ladies (Put a Ring on It)" debuted at number 78 on
    the Hot 100 and steadily ascended the charts, entering the top
    40 at number 28 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>issue date of November 29; the following week,
    "Single Ladies" surged to number two on the Hot 100. With
    strong digital sales of 204,000 "Single Ladies" topped the Hot
    Digital Songs chart, pushing Knowles' other single "If I Were a
    Boy" to number two with a tally of 160,000 copies sold. The
    song sold 228,000 downloads the following week, a twelve
    percent increase over the last week's tally of 204,000, and
    spent two weeks at number one on the Hot Digital Songs. "Single
    Ladies" fourth week at number one was prompted by a massive
    surge of 157% on downloads, which gave her 382,000 downloads
    for the week alone. The single's performance on the Hot 100 was
    also boosted by heavy rotation, as the song also topped the Hot
    100 Airplay chart for a number of weeks. "Single Ladies" became
    Knowles' fifth number one single on the Hot 100, eventually
    topping the chart for four non-consecutive weeks, interrupted
    at the top in its second week by T.I. and Rihanna's "Live Your
    Life". It was certified 2x Platinum by the RIAA on February 13,
    2009. As of September, 2009, this song has so far sold over
    3,000,000 digital downloads in the United States, becoming
    Knowles' highest-selling song in the U.S to date.</p>
      <p>As Knowles' fifth number one song, she is now second, behind
    R&amp;B singer Rihanna, for most number one singles this decade
    by a solo female artist (excluding three of her number one hits
    with Destiny's Child from this decade). The song spent four
    non-consecutive weeks atop the Hot 100, becoming Knowles'
    second Christmas and New Year number-one single, the first one
    being "Irreplaceable" in 2006-2007. "Single Ladies" was also a
    crossover success, topping both the Hot Dance Club Play and Hot
    Dance Airplay charts. It was well received by an R&amp;B
    audience, where it debuted at number 20 on the Hot
    R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs chart and spent twelve consecutive weeks
    at the summit. It is Knowles' fifth number-one R&amp;B single
    in her solo career.</p>
      <p>Internationally, the song performed well. It debuted at
    number 81 on the Canadian Hot 100 based on downloads alone, and
    jumped to number 17 the following week based on strong sales,
    eventually peaking at number two. In the UK. "Single Ladies"
    was not initially released as an independent single, and was
    released instead as the b-side to "If I Were A Boy". However,
    the song achieved great success, entering UK Singles Chart at
    number 67 on November 23, 2008, based on downloads alone, and
    slowly climbed to a peak of number seven (and number one on the
    UK R&amp;B Chart for three consecutive weeks), giving Knowles
    her twelfth UK top ten hit. To date "Single Ladies" has spent
    60 weeks on the UK Singles Chart (top 100) making it her
    longest charting single ever in the country, beating nine of
    her other higher charting singles (including every one of her
    #1 singles). As of March 2010, it still remains on the chart,
    well over a year after it was released. It's sales have
    exceeded 400,000 making it her third gold single in the UK. The
    song peaked at number 4 on the Irish Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>On November 24, 2008, "Single Ladies" debuted at number 15
    on the Australian ARIA Singles Chart and peaked at number 5.
    The song was certified 3x Platinum, selling over 210,000
    copies. In New Zealand, the song debuted at number thirty-two
    on November 24, 2008, and peaked at number two in its fourth
    week where it stayed for three weeks. It was certified
    Platinum, selling over 15,000 copies. The single began charting
    in 2008 and is only the second single to chart over three
    consecutive years, as it sat at number 36 in the top 40 going
    into 2010. In the Netherlands, "Single Ladies" became a top 10
    hit based on downloads and airplay, eventually peaking at
    number 8.</p>
      <p>On November 16, 2009, "Single Ladies" had spent 52 weeks (a
    year) in the Top 50 Australian ARIA Singles Chart, before
    dropping out the next week.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Single Ladies" was shot concurrently
    with "If I Were a Boy", as both singles were released together
    to emphasize the duality of the singer and her more aggressive
    alter ego Sasha Fierce. However, Knowles revealed that the
    budget for the videos was spent almost entirely on "If I Were a
    Boy", and the producers were forced to downgrade for "Single
    Ladies". Like "If I Were a Boy", "Single Ladies" is shot in
    black and white, and was directed by Jake Nava, with whom
    Knowles had worked on her previous music videos including
    "Crazy in Love" and "Beautiful Liar". According to Nava, the
    styling was inspired by a 
    <i>Vogue</i>photo shoot.</p>
      <p>Choreographed by Frank Gatson and JaQuel Knight, Knowles
    performs as her alter ego, Sasha Fierce. It shows her in
    asymmetrical leotard and high-heels, with two look-alike backup
    dancers (Ebony Williams and Ashley Everett). The video features
    Knowles dancing inside an infinity cove (which alternates
    between black and white), placing focus on the complex
    choreography. The dance routine incorporates various styles,
    including jazz, tap and hip hop, and is credited with
    popularizing J-Setting, a flamboyant lead-and-follow dance
    style prominent in many African American gay clubs across
    Atlanta (which in turn was borrowed from the moves of the
    all-female J-Sette dance troupe of Jackson State University).
    Towards the end of the video, Knowles flashes her $5 million
    Lorraine Schwartz wedding ring that camouflages with her
    titanium glove, also made by Schwartz.</p>
      <p>Knowles premiered the music video, alongside the video for
    "If I Were a Boy," also directed by Nava, on MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>show. The video was released to major
    outlets on October 13, 2008. Upon the video's release, many
    internet bloggers noticed similarities between the choreography
    of "Single Ladies" and that of a June 1969 performance by Gwen
    Verdon on 
    <i>The Ed Sullivan Show</i>entitled "Mexican Breakfast". The
    latter—choreographed by Broadway legend Bob Fosse—became an
    internet viral sensation when Unk's "Walk It Out" was dubbed
    over the original mix. While promoting the song on BET's 
    <i>106 &amp; Park</i>, Knowles stated that she was inspired by
    the video after viewing it on YouTube and wanted to see if she
    could attempt it. In an interview with 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>magazine, Knowles said she saw an
    old tape of Verdon and used it as an inspiration for the video
    to "Single Ladies". The choreography also borrows liberally
    from Fosse's "There's Gotta Be Something Better Than This"
    routine from the stage musical and subsequent film 
    <i>Sweet Charity</i>(Verdon played Charity on Broadway, and
    Shirley MacLaine, the role in the film).</p>
      <p>There are gospel and acoustic versions. Toddlers have
    tackled it. [So have] recreation centre dance classes, sorority
    sisters in their dorm rooms, suburban teenagers in their
    basements and high school cheerleaders... There are all-male
    tributes, an impromptu number in an airport lounge and even
    some "new 'n' improved" videos of dance teams taking a second
    try. As with every Internet trend, there are of course the
    requisite Facebook groups devoted to it ... a couple of
    years ago, Soulja Boy initiated a short-lived dance
    craze ... but it remained mainly a male hip-hop dance,
    whereas the 'Single Ladies' dance has crossed over to all age
    groups and genders.</p>
      <p>"Single Ladies" has gained widespread popularity for its
    catchy hook and theme of female empowerment, with critics
    comparing the song to Aretha Franklin's "Respect" or Gloria
    Gaynor's "I Will Survive". The music video has achieved fame
    for its intricate choreography, which has been credited as
    having started the "first major dance craze of both the new
    millennium and the Internet". It was parodied on 
    <i>Saturday Night Live</i>, where the two female backup dancers
    from the video were replaced by Justin Timberlake and 
    <i>SNL</i>castmembers Andy Samberg and Bobby Moynihan. On June
    3, 2009, Joe Jonas of the Jonas Brothers did the dance and
    posted it on their YouTube account for their album countdown.
    Also, the song and its choreography was used on the popular
    American TV show Glee, performed by the character Kurt, played
    by Chris Colfer, who also performed a watered down version of
    the dance.</p>
      <p>The music video has inspired a legion of imitators who have
    posted videos of themselves on to YouTube attempting to perform
    the choreography. One of the more popular viral videos is that
    of Shane Mercado, who appeared on The Bonnie Hunt Show to
    perform the choreography and later got the chance to meet
    Beyonce Knowles. In one of the videos on the internet, filmed
    by American singer John Legend, the American president Barack
    Obama can be seen doing a small part of the "Single ladies"
    dance, while talking to Knowles. In London, 100 dancers wearing
    leotards similar to the one worn by Knowles performed the
    choreography on April 20, 2009 to promote Trident Unwrapped, a
    gum company. The music video for "Single Ladies" is also
    parodied on a 2009 television commercial in the United Kingdom
    for the new Doner Kebab flavoured Pot Noodle.</p>
      <p>The video has generated interest in j-setting, the dance
    form that choreographer JaQuel Knight highlights in the video,
    and is credited as bringing the dance style to the mainstream.
    Like the histories of many popular dances, there are several
    versions of the development of J-setting (named after the
    "Prancing J-Settes" of Jackson State University in Jackson,
    MS). In a radio interview on NPR's 
    <i>All Things Considered</i>, Knight shared his excitement
    about the popularity of the video's one-take dance sequence as
    an inspiration for anyone to get up off the couch and try out
    the moves.</p>
      <p>The popularity of the video on YouTube has been in turn
    reflected by Knowles; during her concert tour, excerpts from
    many of the YouTube videos play on the video screens in the
    background. In the music video for "Dancin on Me" by DJ Webstar
    and Jim Jones, it features three females in the background
    imitating the "Single Ladies" dance.</p>
      <p>"Single Ladies" won the 2009 BET Awards Video of the Year.
    In addition, it was nominated for a total of nine awards at the
    2009 MTV Video Music Awards, and ultimately won the award for
    Video of the Year, and an additional two awards as well, though
    its loss in the Best Female Video category to Taylor Swift's
    "You Belong with Me" led to controversy during the ceremony;
    Swift's award acceptance speech was interrupted by
    singer/rapper Kanye West, who grabbed her microphone to declare
    the "Single Ladies" video as "one of the best videos of all
    time". When Knowles won the Video of the Year award, she
    stated, "I remember being 17 years old, up for my first MTV
    award with Destiny's Child, and it was one of the most exciting
    moments in my life" and that she would like for Swift to "come
    out and have her moment".</p>
      <p>The song is covered by The Chipettes, which also topped
    several charts, in the film 
    <i>Alvin and the Chipmunks: The Squeakquel</i>, and is
    available on the film's soundtrack.</p>
      <p>A Sunday edition of 
    <i>Stone Soup</i>features Val Stone watching the video on
    YouTube to learn the dance, with her daughter Holly stating
    that she will "never show her anything on YouTube again" in
    reaction to seeing her doing the dance. 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>put it on its end-of-the-decade,
    "best-of" list, saying, "Sorry, Taylor. Kanye was right. With
    choreography that had everyone flashing their bling-free ring
    fingers, Beyoncé's fierce female anthem really is "one of the
    best videos of all time."</p>
      <p>The music video was parodied on an SNL sketch, which
    included Beyonce herself.</p>
      <p>In Nov 2009, Australian Band 'The Pigs' released a country
    version with John Williamson (singer) on Jaw Harp. It is the
    first single off The Pigs’ second album, Horses. The music
    video; first aired on ABC's rage music program as Indie Video
    Of The Week;The pigs official website</p>
      <p>In the 2009 film, "
    <i>Alvin and the Chipmunks: The Squeakquel</i>", The Chipettes
    (Brittany, Jeanette, and Eleanor) sing the song, and this
    version was released on the film's soundtrack.</p>
      <p>The band - The Fray - also 'covered' the song "Single
    Ladies" and "Hips Don't Lie" for laughs at concerts.</p>
      <p>The band Pierce The Veil often starts their song "Yeah Boy
    and Doll Face" with "Single Ladies" when performing live.</p>
      <p>Naomi, the fictional Alter ego of romanian actor and singer
    Mihai Bendeac from satire TV show "Mondenii" (Prima TV)
    parodied the song, intitling it "Super Sexy &amp; Sensimbile" -
    
    <i>Super-Hot and Sensitive</i>.</p>
      <p>It was parodied on Australian sketch show Double Take as
    'It's Humiliating'. The lyrics are changed to make fun of
    Beyonce's outfit and dancing in the original video</p>
      <p>It is featured twice in the 'Preggers' episode of Glee, most
    notably when it is danced to by the school football team</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
