<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baby_Boy_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baby_Boy_(song)</songId>
   <title>Baby Boy</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>Beyoncé featuring Sean Paul</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2003-10-04</week>
      <week>2003-10-11</week>
      <week>2003-10-18</week>
      <week>2003-10-25</week>
      <week>2003-11-01</week>
      <week>2003-11-08</week>
      <week>2003-11-15</week>
      <week>2003-11-22</week>
      <week>2003-11-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/c/cd/BK-BabyBoy.jpg/200px-BK-BabyBoy.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Beyonce-featuring-Sean-Paul+Baby-Boy.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Dangerously in LoveDutty Rock</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 9, 2003</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2003, South Beach Studios, Miami, Florida</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Reggae Fusion</genre>
      <genre>Dancehall</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:04</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Beyoncé Knowles</writer>
      <writer>Scott Storch</writer>
      <writer>Sean Paul Henriques</writer>
      <writer>Robert Waller</writer>
      <writer>Shawn Carter</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Beyoncé Knowles</producer>
      <producer>Scott Storch</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Baby Boy" is a R&amp;B–reggae song by American singer
    Beyoncé Knowles and features Jamaican reggae rapper Sean Paul.
    The track was produced by Knowles and Scott Storch for her
    debut solo album 
    <i>Dangerously in Love</i>. "Baby Boy" was written by Knowles,
    Storch, Robert Waller, Jay-Z and Sean Paul.</p>
      <p>"Baby Boy" was released on October 14, 2003 in the United
    States as the second single from the album. The single was a
    commercial success, and topped the US Singles Chart for nine
    consecutive weeks. It was certified platinum in the US, and was
    Knowles' longest-running solo number-one single until
    Irreplaceable who topped for ten consecutive weeks . "Baby Boy"
    performed well internationally, reaching the top ten in many
    countries, and achieving platinum status in Australia. The song
    has been praised by both critics and music industry personnel.
    "Baby Boy" remains a staple of Knowles' concert set list. The
    American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers
    recognized it at the 2005 Pop Music Awards as one of the most
    performed songs of the year.</p>
      <p>In 2005, US singer-songwriter Jennifer Armour filed a
    copyright infringement lawsuit claiming that Knowles had used
    the primary musical hook from her song "Got a Little Bit of
    Love for You". It was settled in favor of Knowles.</p>
      <p>Knowles went to Miami, Florida in the United States to work
    with Canadian record producer Scott Storch for her debut solo
    album, 
    <i>Dangerously in Love</i>. She and Storch wrote "Baby Boy"
    with contributions from American songwriter Robert Waller and
    Knowles' long-time boyfriend rapper-hip hop artist Jay-Z. The
    song also contains a lyrical interpolation of "No Fear" by
    hip-hop group O.G.C. used towards the ending of the song: "We
    steppin' in hotter this year."</p>
      <p>Once the track was supposedly done, Knowles had the idea
    that it would be "perfect" if Jamaican dancehall-reggae artist
    Sean Paul contributed a vocal track. Knowles contacted Sean
    Paul about a possible collaboration. Sean Paul agreed and flew
    in from Jamaica to join the recording sessions of the song. He
    contributed a toast verse, and they finished recording "Baby
    Boy" in March 2003, during the latter stages of the album's
    recording.</p>
      <p>"Baby Boy" is a mid-tempo contemporary R&amp;B song
    performed with a moderate groove. It is in the key of C minor,
    and is set to ninety-two beats per minute in common time. "Baby
    Boy" is a hybrid of R&amp;B and dancehall and has a reggae
    influence. Storch's knowledge on Indian and Middle Eastern
    music contributes to its Eastern influences. According to Fox
    News, "Baby Boy" is based on the 1995 reggae song "Here Comes
    the Hotstepper" by Jamaican singer Ini Kamoze.</p>
      <p>"Baby Boy" is a sequel in ways to "'03 Bonnie &amp; Clyde";
    a 2002 Jay-Z song featuring Knowles. The lyrics detail a
    woman's fantasies, and in keeping with the album's overall
    theme, Knowles' deemed them as personal to her. Sean Paul
    remarked, "She's telling me about her fantasies and picturing
    me and her going here and there, all over the world ...
    I'm answering back, like, 'I'm wit it.'" The lyrics are
    constructed in the toast–chorus–verse form; Sean Paul performs
    the toasting while Knowles sings all other verses and choruses.
    The pattern is repeated twice; a further chorus and verse
    follow, resolving at the toasting and final verse.</p>
      <p>"Baby Boy" was released as the second single from the album 
    <i>Dangerously in Love</i>. It was released as a CD in Canada
    on May 4, 2003, in Australia on September 9, and in the United
    States on October 14, 2003 as a 12" single. The track appeared
    in the revamped version of Sean Paul's 2003 second album, 
    <i>Dutty Rock</i>.</p>
      <p>"Baby Boy" was well-received by critics. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine reviewer Anthony DeCurtis wrote
    that Knowles‎ sounded like she was "having fun" on the song,
    while Stephen Thomas Erlewine of Allmusic, an online music
    database, described Knowles' vocals as "assured and sexy". Mark
    Anthony Neal of the international webzine PopMatters, regarded
    the song as one of the "high-profile collaborations" from 
    <i>Dangerously in Love</i>. Lisa Verrico of the daily US
    newspaper 
    <i>The Times</i>described the song a "Latino-tinged
    collaboration ... set to clicky beats that sound like
    castanets". She concluded that "Paul does a reggae rap in the
    middle, but it's when he chats while Beyoncé half raps that the
    pair have real chemistry". Yancey Strickler of the 
    <i>Flak</i>magazine wrote that "'Baby Boy''s diwali stutter is
    enhanced by Sean Paul's dancehall monotone". 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>magazine's Neil Drumming said that
    "'Baby Boy' goes full-tilt Bollywood 'n da hood, with Sean Paul
    ripping a pulsing tabla raga".</p>
      <p>James Anthony of the British newspaper 
    <i>The Guardian</i>said the track "bridges the gap between the
    genres of R&amp;B and dancehall". British record label EMI was
    honored by the American Society of Composers, Authors and
    Publishers (ASCAP) during the 2005 Pop Music Awards as
    Publisher of the Year for publishing "Baby Boy", among other
    songs. Scott Storch earned Songwriter of the Year at the same
    event.</p>
      <p>"Baby Boy" attained a positioning on the commercial charts
    before its physical release in the US. The track led to a
    higher 200 chart placing for 
    <i>Dangerously in Love</i>, and helped the album to attain
    multi-platinum certification in the US. The single debuted on
    the Hot 100, the US' official singles chart, at number
    fifty-seven while "Crazy in Love" was still in the top spot.
    "Baby Boy" dominated the US airplays, charting atop the
    Hot 100. It reached the chart's top spot eight weeks after
    its debut, and stayed there for nine consecutive weeks. The
    single stayed number one for a week longer than "Crazy in Love"
    had, becoming Knowles' longest-charting number-one single. The
    feat was not broken until Knowles' 2006 single "Irreplaceable",
    from her second album 
    <i>B'Day</i>, spent ten weeks at the top spot in late 2006 to
    early 2007 due to heavy radio play. The single stayed on the
    Hot 100 for twenty-nine weeks, and was certified platinum
    on June 6, 2006 by the Recording Industry Association of
    America. "Baby Boy" achieved success on 
    <i>Billboard</i>crossover and mainstream radio charts,
    appearing on the Top 40 Tracks, Rhythmic Top 40 and Top 40
    Mainstream, as well as on the Hot 100 Airplay, Dance Radio
    Airplay and Hot Dance Music/Club Play.</p>
      <p>Internationally, "Baby Boy" performed just as well, peaking
    inside the top ten on most charts. The single debuted at number
    two in the United Kingdom, becoming the chart's highest debut
    and "Baby Boy"'s highest entry internationally. Though it spent
    eleven weeks on the chart, it failed to top it (being held off
    by "Where Is The Love?" by The Black Eyed Peas). In most
    European countries, the single entered the top ten. In
    Australia and New Zealand, "Baby Boy" peaked at number three
    and two, respectively. It was certified platinum by the
    Australian Recording Industry Association with sales in excess
    of 70,000 units.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Baby Boy" was filmed by English
    director Jake Nava, who also shot Knowles' "Crazy in Love"
    video. It was recorded in Miami, Florida on August 7–8, 2003.
    Parts of the video were captured in a house with different
    styles rooms: one in a Japanese style and one in an old English
    style.</p>
      <p>Scenes featuring Knowles and Sean Paul are shown separately.
    The video begins with Sean Paul sitting on a throne while
    toasting; Knowles is leaning against the wall dancing. In the
    following scene, Knowles is seen on a bed tossing herself. Sean
    Paul is shown with several women who are lying on the floor
    caressing each other. Knowles walks towards the beach; she
    spots a man, and the two touch and flirt. At a party, Knowles
    dances with a man. Water floods the floor as she sings "the
    dance floor becomes the sea". The original track is
    interpolated towards the end with an Arabic instrumental,
    designed for the music video. This section showcases Knowles
    vigorously dancing on the sand.</p>
      <p>Sal Cinquemani of the online publication Slant Magazine,
    described the video as a "baby-oil-logged follow-up" to "Crazy
    in Love"'s "bootylicous video". "Baby Boy" premiered on MTV's
    program 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>on August 25, 2003 at number ten and
    reached the top spot. It stayed on the show for forty-one days,
    the same chart run "Me, Myself &amp; I" earned.</p>
      <p>Knowles performed "Baby Boy" during the 2003 MTV Video Music
    Awards. She sang the song in a medley with the pre-recorded
    vocals of Sean Paul, and also performed "Crazy in Love" with
    Jay-Z. She later performed "Baby Boy" at the 2003 MTV Europe
    Music Awards together with Sean Paul. Her performance was
    panned by PopMatters' Jessica Hodges as a "letdown" compared
    with her applauded 2003 MTV VMA.</p>
      <p>"Baby Boy" has been included on the set list for most of
    Knowles' concert tours. The song was set as opening of her
    Dangerously in Love World Tour that began in late 2003. During
    the tour, she appeared suspended from the ceiling of the arena
    being lowered to a red lounger—a prop she also used during the
    2003 MTV VMA. The footage taken in London's Wembley Arena in
    the United Kingdom is included in the 
    <i>Live at Wembley</i>concert DVD that was released on April
    27, 2004. Knowles performed the song midway through the setlist
    of her former group Destiny's Child farewell tour Destiny
    Fulfilled ... And Lovin' It, and it subsequently appeared on
    the 
    <i>Destiny's Child: Live in Atlanta</i>concert DVD. During the
    2007 The Beyoncé Experience world concert tour, Knowles again
    performed "Baby Boy" in a version that incorporated a reggae
    song "Murder She Wrote". The footage taken at the Staples
    Center in Los Angeles on September 2, 2007 appeared on 
    <i>The Beyoncé Experience Live!</i>DVD. She performs the song
    while suspended in the air during her 
    <i>I Am... Tour</i>and then lowered to the B-Stage to where she
    finishes the "Baby Boy" number with an excerpt from Dawn Penn's
    "You Don't Love Me (No, No, No)".</p>
      <p>In the 2005 ASCAP Pop Music Awards, "Baby Boy", along with
    Knowles' songs "Me, Myself and I" and "Naughty Girl", was
    honored as one of the most performed songs of the year.</p>
      <p>In 2005, US singer-songwriter Jennifer Armour filed a
    copyright infringement lawsuit claiming that Knowles had used
    some lyrics and the musical hook from her song "Got a Little
    Bit of Love for You". In 2003, Armour's former label manager
    had submitted a demo recordings to record labels, including
    Knowles' Columbia Records and Sean Paul's Atlantic Records.
    According to the district court, an Expert witness (Chair,
    Dept. of Music Theory &amp; Composition, Shepherd School of
    Music, Rice University) determined the songs to be
    "substantially similar" (a requirement for an infringement
    finding). With regard to the musical hook the Expert stated in
    his report, "When the aural comparisons of the two songs are
    presented in the key of C Minor (for easy comparison) and
    presented back-to-back, in AB fashion, even the least musically
    inclined listener should immediately determine that the two
    songs are strikingly similar; I daresay that many listeners may
    even perceive them as being the same song! And again,
    transposing a song for this purpose does not alter any
    fundamental qualities or characteristics of the song but merely
    assists the ability of those unfamiliar with the technicalities
    of music in making a comparison." The district court judge
    nonetheless ruled that she, herself, could not hear the
    similarities between the two songs and dismissed the case,
    denying the motion for the songs or case to be heard by a
    jury.</p>
      <p>On appeal, the United States Court of Appeals for the Fifth
    Circuit affirmed the district court's ruling, but ruled with
    different reasoning. It held that there was no infringement
    based on Knowles' claim that Armour's demo tape was received
    shortly after the writing of Knowles' song had been
    substantially completed. However, the court did not address the
    issue of substantial similarity.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
