<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Irreplaceable 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Irreplaceable</songId>
   <title>Irreplaceable</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beyonc%C3%A9_Knowles</artistId>
      <artistName>Beyoncé</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2007-01-06</week>
      <week>2007-01-13</week>
      <week>2007-01-20</week>
      <week>2007-01-27</week>
      <week>2007-02-03</week>
      <week>2007-02-10</week>
      <week>2007-02-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/ef/Irreplaceable_Single_Cover.jpg/200px-Irreplaceable_Single_Cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Beyonce+Irreplaceable.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>B'Day</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 5, 2006 ( United States ) , October 23, 2006 ( United Kingdom ) , November 6, 2006 ( Australia )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
      <format>maxi single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2006 , Sony Music Studios , New York City, New York</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:47</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Shaffer "Ne-Yo" Smith</writer>
      <writer>Mikkel S. Eriksen</writer>
      <writer>Tor Erik Hermansen</writer>
      <writer>Espen Lind</writer>
      <writer>Amund Bjørklund</writer>
      <writer>Beyoncé Knowles</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Stargate</producer>
      <producer>Knowles</producer>
      <producer>Ne-Yo (co-producer)</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Irreplaceable" is a song by American R&amp;B singer Beyoncé
    Knowles. The song was written by Knowles, Ne-Yo, Tor Erik
    Hermansen, Mikkel S. Eriksen, Espen Lind, Amund Bjørklund, and
    produced by Stargate and Knowles for her second solo album, 
    <i>B'Day</i>(2006). Originally not created for Knowles, she
    re-arranged the demo presented by the producers—a
    country-turned-pop-contemporary R&amp;B song. The lyrics refer
    to breaking up with an unfaithful man, part of Knowles and
    Ne-Yo's vision of creating a record that people could relate
    to, and was considered an anthem to female empowerment.</p>
      <p>Following the less successful chart performances of "Déjà
    Vu" and "Ring the Alarm", "Irreplaceable" was released on
    December 5, 2006 in the United States as the album's third
    single, and the second single in most international music
    markets. "Irreplaceable" was a worldwide commercial and
    critical success, becoming Knowles' second best-selling single
    in her solo career after "Crazy in Love" and 
    <i>B'Day</i>'s most successful release. The single performed
    well on the US Hot 100, remaining at the top spot for ten
    consecutive weeks. Certified multi-platinum, "Irreplaceable" is
    the US' best-selling single in 2007 and the 25th most
    successful song of the 2000s, according to the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade.</p>
      <p>"Irreplaceable" was lauded by contemporary critics, citing
    its distinct production compared with most tracks featured on
    the album. The song won awards, including one during the 2007
    Soul Train Music Award. The single's music video, which
    features the debut performance of Knowles' all-female band Suga
    Mama, earned Knowles additional awards. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>ranked it number sixty on their list of 100
    Best Songs of the 2000s decade.</p>
      <p>"Irreplaceable" was originally not made for Knowles, but
    instead for Chrisette Michele. Norwegian production team
    Stargate and American R&amp;B-pop singer-songwriter Ne-Yo had
    been writing for her second solo album 
    <i>B'Day</i>; but Tor Erik Hermansen of Stargate stated that
    "they might not have gone in the direction they did on the
    song". The tune was originally not matched to Knowles' voice,
    and Ne-Yo wrote the lyrics from a male perspective, which he
    revealed not from his personal experiences. Written as country
    song, he was thinking of country-based singers Shania Twain and
    Faith Hill during the sessions. When Ne-Yo heard them playing
    the song with a guitar, he thought it sounded like country
    Western music. But when the drums were incorporated into the
    music, it was brought to R&amp;B vibe, and Ne-Yo considered
    making an R&amp;B-country western music song.</p>
      <p>When the team worked with him, they recorded the song with
    male on vocals. However, they thought of a female's vocal more
    suitable, and Ne-Yo also thought that it is empowering for a
    woman singing it. While Knowles was working on material for 
    <i>B'Day</i>after filming 
    <i>Dreamgirls</i>, she was pleased with the demo of the song
    that was presented to her. Knowles asked for changes in the
    track, including the addition of drums, vocal arrangements, and
    singing the song in higher note than the demo. Espen Lind and
    Amund Bjørklund, from the Norwegian production team Espionage,
    wrote the chord structure and came up with the guitar part. The
    recording was engineered by Jim Caruana and mixed by Jason
    Goldstein at Sony Music Studios in New York City.</p>
      <p>What happens sometimes, is you think about a specific artist
    and you put them in this box, the song has to be this way or
    that, and then you're usually confining yourself to the thing
    they did three years ago.</p>
      <p>After the sessions for "Irreplaceable" ended, Hermansen said
    that "everyone felt they had captured something special and
    that Beyoncé had done the track justice". In an interview,
    Ne-Yo said, "Beyoncé had some stuff that she wanted to get off
    her chest", while also aiming to make a record that women could
    relate to, in keeping with the theme of the album.</p>
      <p>"Irreplaceable" is a mid-tempo pop song, with ballad and
    R&amp;B influences. Written in the key of B♭ major, the beat is
    set in common time and moves at a moderate 88 bpm. Knowles
    vocal range spans nearly two and a half octaves, from B♭
    <sub>2</sub>to E♭
    <sub>5</sub>. While most of the songs in the album are
    aggressive and uptempo, her voice in "Irreplaceable" is toned
    down.</p>
      <p>"Irreplaceable" uses a gently strummed acoustic guitar,
    following the B♭
    <sub>5</sub>-F
    <sub>5</sub>-Cm
    <sub>7</sub>-E♭
    <sub>6/9</sub>chord series. Hermansen and Eriksen combined the
    classic chord progression on an acoustic guitar, a
    modern-sounding 808 drumbeat and cellos. Al Shipley of Stylus
    Magazine noted that the guitar strum was copied in Barbadian
    R&amp;B singer Rihanna's 2007 single "Hate That I Love You", a
    song co-produced by Stargate and Ne-Yo. A 2007
    Stargate-produced single "With You" performed by American
    R&amp;B-pop singer Chris Brown also features the same element,
    which Rob Sheffield of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine wrote that "Stargate was just
    trying to roll out 'Irreplaceable' one more time", while a
    review from 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine said that it "leans a bit too heavily"
    to the song.</p>
      <p>"Irreplaceable" refers to a woman breaking up with a
    boyfriend after she found him cheating, and the lyrics were
    considered a statement of independence. Hermansen quoted that
    "it's a song people from all walks of life can enjoy", while
    Knowles stated that it is "a little honest". When interviewed
    about the song, she replied: "Basically we can't forget our
    power and our worth. And sometimes ... you're so in
    love, you forget that. And sometimes you feel like you're not
    being ... appreciated. And ... sometimes
    they forget that they can be replaced." Bill Lamb of About
    noted that the female empowerment theme of "Irreplaceable" has
    similarities to the central concept of Terry McMillan's 1995
    novel 
    <i>Waiting to Exhale</i>.</p>
      <p>The song's lyrics are constructed in the
    verse-pre-chorus-chorus form. Starting with a guitar strum,
    Knowles sings the hook-intro "To the left, to the left",
    repeating for three times in alternating bars. In bar seven,
    she sings the first verse, arguing her boyfriend about the
    indifference of their relationship, and telling him to walk
    away. The pre-chorus and chorus follows, giving way to the
    second verse where she recollects the moment she found her
    boyfriend unfaithful to her. The same pattern occurs, leading
    to the second chorus. Towards the end, Knowles sings the
    bridge. She repeats the intro and the chorus, ending with an
    ad-libbed chorus.</p>
      <p>Following 
    <i>B'Day</i>'s lead single "Déjà Vu", "Irreplaceable" was
    released as the second single in international markets through
    Columbia Records. Two single versions were released in the
    United Kingdom on October 26, 2006: a standard CD single, which
    features the album version of the track and the Freemasons club
    mix radio edit of "Ring the Alarm"; and an enhanced CD,
    containing the album version, three "Ring the Alarm" remixes
    and "Ring the Alarm" music video. A 12" single was released in
    the same country the following week. In Australia, a maxi
    single was released on November 4, 2006, featuring the album
    version and two remixes of "Déjà Vu".</p>
      <p>In the United States, "Irreplaceable" served as 
    <i>B'Day</i>'s third single, following "Ring the Alarm". The
    single was released on December 5, 2006, featuring the album
    and instrumental version of the track. Knowles recorded a
    Spanish version of the song called "Irreemplazable", and was
    included in the second disc of the deluxe edition of 
    <i>B'Day</i>released on June 12, 2007. An 
    <i>Irreemplazable</i>EP was released in the United States on
    August 28, 2007 and on September 10 in the United Kingdom. The
    EP includes "Irreemplazable" and the Norteña Remix of
    "Irreplaceable", "Amor Gitano", three versions of "Beautiful
    Liar", the Timbaland remix of "Get Me Bodied" featuring Voltio,
    and "Oye", the Spanish version of "Listen".</p>
      <p>The song was performed in various public appearances of
    Knowles. She opened the 2006 American Music Awards performing
    "Irreplaceable". American country band Sugarland, who were
    known for covering Knowles' songs in their live performances,
    were joined by the singer for a performance of the country
    version of "Irreplaceable" at the 2007 American Music Awards.
    "Irreplaceable" was the closing song during her 2007 The
    Beyoncé Experience world tour. It was originally performed
    towards the end of the set in earlier tour dates, but was
    shifted when she embarked on the United States leg. The footage
    of the performance at the Staples Center, Los Angeles was
    included in 
    <i>The Beyoncé Experience Live!</i>DVD.</p>
      <p>In May 2007, the song was featured prominently in the
    crucial final scene of "When the Chickens Come Home to Roost",
    the first season finale of the CW comedy-drama television
    series 
    <i>The Game</i>.</p>
      <p>While most of the tracks featured in 
    <i>B'Day</i>are upbeat, "Irreplaceable" was well received by
    critics for its guitar-driven melody. Bill Lamb of the website
    About complimented Stargate for the "simple, pop-oriented
    production", and listed on the site as their fourth best
    R&amp;B song of 2006. For a review in 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>magazine, Jody Rosen said the track
    is "a lilting tune unlike anything Beyoncé has ever performed".
    Sarah Rodman of 
    <i>The Boston Globe</i>wrote that the song is "gentle but
    maddeningly hook-y", and Bill Lamb called it a "gorgeous,
    lightly swinging Stargate arrangement". Spence Abbott of the
    website IGN observed that "Irreplaceable", alongside
    "Resentment", "go for a much more traditional contemporary
    R&amp;B vibe" compared to the other tracks in the album, and
    stated that it made them "stand out as if they were recorded
    separately from the rest of the album". In 2009 Pitchfork
    ranked the song as the #183 song on list of The Top 500 Tracks
    of the decade.</p>
      <p>Lamb listed "Irreplaceable" on their site as one of the
    strongest tracks in the album, and noted it as "subject matter
    of female strength and independence". The indie-oriented
    website Pitchfork Media named the song Knowles' "most
    sophisticated" and her "most honest performance to date". Barry
    Schwartz of Stylus Magazine wrote that "Irreplaceable"
    recaptured Knowles' debut single "Crazy in Love"'s
    "near-perfection and features her most genuinely emotional
    vocal to date, equal parts vulnerable, upset, pissed off,
    vindictive, resigned, and apathetic".</p>
      <p>"Irreplaceable" won at the 2007 Soul Train Music Award for
    Best R&amp;B/Soul Single, Female, and the 2007 Nickelodeon
    Kid's Choice Award for Favorite Song. It was nominated for
    Record of the Year in the 2008 Grammy Awards, as well Song of
    the Year at the VH1 Soul Vibe awards show. The song was awarded
    among the top five most-performed songs in 2008 at the ASCAP
    Pop Music Awards.</p>
      <p>The song created controversy over the writing credits. Ne-Yo
    spoke to MTV to clarify any confusion: "Apparently Beyonce was
    at a show somewhere and right before the song came on she said,
    'I wrote this for my girls' and then the song came on. ...
    The song is a co-write. I wrote the lyrics, I wrote all the
    lyrics. Beyonce helped me with the melodies and the harmonies
    and the vocal arrangement and that makes it a co-write. Meaning
    my contribution and her contribution made that song what it
    is."</p>
      <p>During the production of "Irreplaceable", Hermansen thought
    that the track would not receive radio play because of its
    acoustic guitars, and deemed the song too pop-oriented.
    Hermansen did not expect "Irreplaceable" to conform to any
    genre. Despite his prediction, the song became successful on
    urban charts; it was played in New York- and country-based
    radio stations. "Irreplaceable" entered various charts
    worldwide, and became the most successful single released from 
    <i>B'Day</i>.</p>
      <p>The single debuted on the US Hot 100 on November 4, 2006 at
    number eighty-seven. It climbed the charts rapidly because of
    heavy airplay, and received the Greatest Airplay Gainer
    certification for six consecutive weeks in early December 2006.
    Three weeks after its release, it helped 
    <i>B'Day</i>re-enter the top ten on the 200. The single peaked
    at number one on December 16, becoming Knowles' fourth
    number-one single as solo artist, and her second in 2006,
    following "Check on It" featuring Slim Thug. The single spent
    ten consecutive weeks at the top spot, and was replaced by
    Canadian singer Nelly Furtado's 2006 single "Say It Right" on
    February 24, 2007. The feat was achieved since 2006 after Kanye
    West's 2005 single "Gold Digger" featuring Jamie Foxx took ten
    weeks at the top spot. "Irreplaceable" outperformed "Baby
    Boy"'s nine-week record; however, it failed to surpass her
    former group Destiny's Child's 2000 single "Independent Women
    Part I", which stayed on the top spot for eleven weeks late in
    2000 and early in 2001. On the list of most number-one singles
    by a female song-writer, "Irreplaceable" installed Knowles at
    the third place, beating American singers Janet Jackson and
    Carole King and tying Diane Warren for nine number-one singles.
    Knowles received three song-writing credits in a single year,
    the only woman to achieve since King in 1971 and Carey in 1991.
    The single remained on the chart for thirty weeks, and was
    certified 3x platinum by the Recording Industry Association of
    America on July 27, 2007. "Irreemplazable" charted equally
    well, peaking at number four on the Hot Latin Songs. The EP
    appeared on the Latin Pop Albums at number two, Top Latin
    Albums at number three, Top R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Albums at number
    forty-one and on the 
    <i>Billboard</i> 200 at number 105. "Irreplaceable" was
    the US' best-performing single of 2007, topping the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Top Hot 100 Hits. As of September 2009, the
    single has sold over 2,697,000 digital downloads in the United
    States.</p>
      <p>Internationally, "Irreplaceable" performed equally well. In
    Oceania, "Irreplaceable" debuted at number-eight on the
    Australian ARIA Singles Chart, and eventually peaked at
    number-one for three consecutive weeks becoming Knowles' first
    number-one hit in the country. "Irreplaceable" was certified
    Platinum by ARIA for sales in excess of 70,000 copies,
    "Irreplaceable" appeared twice on the ARIA Year-Ends charts
    ranked at number twenty-three in 2006, and number forty-two in
    2007. "Irreplaceable" debuted at number three on November 6 on
    the New Zealand Singles Chart, and was "Irreplaceable"'s
    highest entry; it peaked at number one, and charted for
    eighteen weeks. "Irreplaceable" reached number two for thirteen
    weeks in Indonesia. "Irreplaceable" peaked at number four in
    the United Kingdom, and generally inside the top fifteen across
    European music markets. Despite only reaching #4 in the UK,
    "Irreplaceable" spent 12 weeks inside the top 20 and with a
    total of 25 weeks on the UK Singles Chart the song is Beyoncé's
    third longest charting single (with more weeks on the chart
    than her #1 singles "Crazy in Love" and "Déjà Vu" but slightly
    less than her recent hits "If I Were a Boy" and "Single Ladies
    (Put a Ring on It)"). On the UK iTunes chart, "Irreplaceable"
    is currently Beyoncé's most downloaded non 
    <i>I Am... Sasha Fierce</i>single and still ranks in the top 30
    of R&amp;B/Soul songs.</p>
      <p>"Irreplaceable" was directed by Anthony Mandler, who
    co-directed the video of "Get Me Bodied". The video features
    the debut performance of Knowles' all-female band, Suga Mama,
    who also appeared in the "Green Light" music video. Her
    acting-then-ex-boyfriend in the video is model Bobby Roache,
    who played police officer for the "Ring the Alarm" music video
    and warrior during Jay-Z and Knowles' live performance at the
    2006 Fashion Rocks show. The video was included on the 2007 
    <i>B'Day Anthology Video Album</i>, and a video edit was
    produced for "Irreemplazable". Part of the video which shows
    Knowles dancing in silhouette in front of a glass door is
    inspired by a James Bond movie. Late in January 2008,
    "Irreemplazable" premiered on the MiTRL, a video countdown show
    on the bilingual channel MTV Tr3s.</p>
      <p>The music video follows the storyline of the song's lyrics.
    "She told me to pack up all my stuff, I'm getting kicked out —
    the video starts off like that", said Roache. Mid-way in the
    video, Knowles follows her then-ex boyfriend outside the house
    and leans on a 2007 Jaguar XK. She appears to be pretentiously
    caressing him; only to find out she would be collecting things
    she bought for him. He leaves her and the car, about to ride
    off in a taxi. Between cuts, Knowles manages herself in front
    of a mirror; putting on a lipstick, wearing huge curlers and a
    high-waisted skirt. Towards the end of the video, she sings
    with her all-female band, Suga Mama. It ends with Knowles
    greeting her new boyfriend at the front door.</p>
      <p>At the 2007 Black Entertainment Television (BET) Awards,
    Knowles won Video of the Year Award for "Irreplaceable", an
    award for which "Beautiful Liar" was nominated. It was
    nominated for Video of the Year during the 2007 MTV Video Music
    Awards, but was beaten by Rihanna's single "Umbrella". At the
    2007 Soul Train Music Awards, the video was nominated for the
    Michael Jackson Award for Best R&amp;B/Soul or Rap Music Video,
    but lost to rapper (and husband) Jay-Z's "Show Me What You Got"
    video.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
