<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mony_Mony 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mony_Mony</songId>
   <title>Mony Mony</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Billy_Idol</artistId>
      <artistName>Billy Idol</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-11-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/46/Mony_Mony_Live.jpg/200px-Mony_Mony_Live.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Billy-Idol+Mony-Mony.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Don't StopVital Idol</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1981 (original version) , 1987 (live version)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1980</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:01 (on Don't Stop )</length>
      <length>5:02 (on Vital Idol )</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Chrysalis</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Tommy James</writer>
      <writer>Bo Gentry</writer>
      <writer>Richie Cordell</writer>
      <writer>and Bobby Bloom</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Keith Forsey</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Mony Mony" was a 1968 single by the American rock band
    Tommy James &amp; The Shondells from their 1968 album of the
    same name. The song became a hit for Billy Idol in 1987.</p>
      <p>"Mony Mony" was credited to Tommy James, Bo Gentry, Richie
    Cordell, and Bobby Bloom. The hook in the song is said to have
    been inspired by James' view of a MONY sign atop the Mutual of
    New York Building in the New York City skyline from his
    Manhattan apartment. As Tommy James says in a 1995 interview in
    
    <i>Hitch</i>magazine:</p>
      <p>{}quote|True story: I had the track done before I had a
    title. I wanted something catchy like "Sloopy" or "Bony
    Maroney," but everything sounded so stupid. So Ritchie Cordell
    and I were writing it in New York City, and we were about to
    throw in the towel when I went out onto the terrace, looked up
    and saw the Mutual of New York building (which has its initials
    illuminated in red at its top). I said, "That's gotta be it!
    Ritchie, come here, you've gotta see this!" It's almost as if
    God Himself had said, "Here's the title." I've always thought
    that if I had looked the other way, it might have been called
    "Hotel Taft."|}}</p>
      <p>"Mony Mony" was the only song by the group to reach the top
    twenty in the United Kingdom; it reached #1 in the UK, and #3
    in the USA music video of it was made at the time, dated in
    showing love beads, but a decade and half later would receive
    some play on MTV.</p>
      <p>The song "Mony Mony" has been covered by many artists,
    including Billy Idol, Amazulu, Status Quo and The Beach Boys.
    Notably, Billy Idol's version replaced another Tommy James hit
    as the #1 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 single, "I Think We're Alone Now",
    covered by Tiffany.</p>
      <p>"Weird Al" Yankovic wrote a parody of this song from his
    album, 
    <i>Even Worse</i>, entitled "Alimony" (based on the Billy Idol
    version). It was about a recently divorced man complaining
    about his ex-wife taking everything he owns away from him in
    alimony payments.</p>
      <p>Billy Idol's version was recorded on two separate occasions.
    The original 1981 studio recording is the most common version
    heard on rock radio stations across the globe. However, Idol
    released a live version as a single in 1987, while promoting
    his forthcoming compilation Vital Idol. It was the live version
    that shot straight to #1, beating out Tiffany's cover of Tommy
    James I Think We're Alone Now.</p>
      <p>The live single version can be found on Idol's 
    <i>Greatest Hits</i>compilation.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
