<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Can_Help 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Can_Help</songId>
   <title>I Can Help</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Billy_Swan</artistId>
      <artistName>Billy Swan</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-11-23</week>
      <week>1974-11-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>I Can Help</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 1974</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1974</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Country</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:58 (single edit)</length>
      <length>4:01 (album version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Monument Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Billy Swan</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Chip Young and Billy Swan</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Can Help" is a song written and performed by Billy Swan.
    Released in September 1974, the song was a big crossover smash,
    reaching #1 on both the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 and Hot Country Singles charts late
    that fall.</p>
      <p>Although Swan had other charting singles on both the Hot 100
    and country charts, the song is generally recognized as being
    Swan's only major hit single release. However, Swan — later a
    member of the band Black Tie — had continued success as a
    songwriter for other artists and as a session musician.</p>
      <p>At the end of the song, the sound of applause by a small
    group of people is heard. During the second take of recording
    the song, a small dog wandered into the recording booth and
    started growling and tugging on Swan's pants with its teeth as
    he was playing and singing. The recording session was going so
    well that Swan refused to stop. After the song was finished,
    the people in the booth all applauded that Swan managed to
    finish.</p>
      <p>Two versions of the song exist:</p>
      <p>In addition to being a No. 1 country and pop hit, "I Can
    Help" reached No. 6 on 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Hot Adult Contemporary Singles chart and No.
    6 on the United Kingdom's 
    <i>Record Retailer</i>chart. In addition, the song was a hit
    throughout most of Europe and also reached #1 in Australia.</p>
      <p>"I Can Help" is certified gold for sales of 500,000 units by
    the Recording Industry Association of America. [1]</p>
      <p>Elvis Presley also recorded "I Can Help" on 10 March 1975 at
    RCA Studio C, Hollywood, California. Elvis gave Billy the socks
    that he wore during the recording of his version of "I Can
    Help". Billy Swan worked at Graceland during the mid 1970's as
    a gate guard. He still has the socks.</p>
      <p>Loretta Lynn covered the song in 1975.</p>
      <p>A cover version was recorded by Aaron Tippin on his 1995
    album 
    <i>Tool Box</i>, and by Steve Kolander on his 1995 album 
    <i>Pieces of a Puzzle</i>.</p>
      <p>Ringo Starr also covered this song in his Memphis sessions
    in 1987. The Memphis album remains unreleased.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
