<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gonna_Fly_Now 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gonna_Fly_Now</songId>
   <title>Gonna Fly Now (Theme From Rocky)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Conti</artistId>
      <artistName>Bill Conti</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1977-07-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/7/7a/GonnaFlyNow.gif</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bill-Conti+Gonna-Fly-Now-Theme-From-Rocky.gif</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Rocky - Original Motion Picture Score</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1976</released>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:48</length>
   </lengths>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bill Conti</writer>
      <writer>Carol Connors</writer>
      <writer>Ayn Robbins</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bill Conti</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Gonna Fly Now", also known as "Theme from Rocky", is the
    theme song from the movie 
    <i>Rocky</i>, composed by Bill Conti with lyrics by Carol
    Connors and Ayn Robbins, and performed by DeEtta Little (the
    sister of actor Cleavon Little) and Nelson Pigford. Released in
    1976 with the movie Rocky, the song became part of American
    popular culture after main character Rocky Balboa completed his
    daily training regimen while the song played. The song finishes
    as Rocky completes his famous run up the "Rocky Steps" of the
    Philadelphia Museum of Art and raises his arms in a victory
    pose. The song is also often played at sporting events,
    especially at sporting events in the city of Philadelphia or
    featuring sports teams from there.</p>
      <p>The song (whose lyrics have a total count of 30 words) was
    nominated for an Academy Award for Best Original Song in the
    49th Academy Awards. The version of the song from the movie,
    performed by Conti with an orchestra, hit number one on the
    Billboard Hot 100 chart in 1977, while a version by jazz
    trumpeter Maynard Ferguson (died in 2006) hit the top 30. Disco
    versions by Rhythm Heritage and Current were on the chart at
    the same time. Conti's single was certified gold by the RIAA.
    The American Film Institute placed it 58th on its AFI's 100
    Years... 100 Songs list.</p>
      <p>In 
    <i>Rocky II</i>, an alternate version of the song was used,
    with a children's choir singing the chorus. 
    <i>Rocky III</i>included an updated disco influenced
    arrangement during the training montage on the beach. This
    recording is however missing from the soundtrack album, the
    sleeve notes of which say "All music on this album selected by
    Sylvester Stallone", who instead opted to reprise the original
    versions of "Gonna Fly Now" and "Reflections" from the first
    film and "Conquest" from the second installment. Thus the album
    fails to present the actual score recorded for Rocky III.</p>
      <p>Rocky IV was scored by Vince DiCola who mainly introduced
    new themes of his own but "
    <i>Gonna Fly Now</i>" returned with its composer for later
    installments. In 
    <i>Rocky Balboa</i>, a slightly alternate version of the song
    used more trumpets and different vocal tones. The soundtrack
    for that film also includes a vocal remix performed by Natalie
    Wilde.</p>
      <p>Due to its original use, the song is used frequently in
    various forms of popular media where a main character is forced
    to train hard in order to defeat an opponent, often during a
    montage sequence.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
