<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/White_Christmas_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/White_Christmas_(song)</songId>
   <title>White Christmas</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bing_Crosby</artistId>
      <artistName>Bing Crosby</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1942-10-31</week>
      <week>1942-11-07</week>
      <week>1942-11-14</week>
      <week>1942-11-21</week>
      <week>1942-11-28</week>
      <week>1942-12-05</week>
      <week>1942-12-12</week>
      <week>1942-12-19</week>
      <week>1942-12-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"White Christmas" is an Irving Berlin song reminiscing about
    an old-fashioned Christmas setting. The version sung by Bing
    Crosby is the best selling single of all time.</p>
      <p>Accounts vary as to when and where Berlin wrote the song.
    One story is that he wrote it in 1940, poolside at the Biltmore
    hotel in Phoenix, Arizona. He often stayed up all night
    writing — he told his secretary, "Grab your pen and take
    down this song. I just wrote the best song I've ever
    written — heck, I just wrote the best song that anybody's
    ever written!"</p>
      <p>The first public performance of the song was also by Crosby,
    on his NBC radio show on Christmas Day, 1941 and the recording
    is not believed to have survived. He recorded the song with the
    John Scott Trotter Orchestra and the Ken Darby Singers for
    Decca Records in just 18 minutes on May 29, 1942, and it was
    released on July 30 as part of an album of six 78-rpm songs
    from the film . At first, Crosby did not see anything special
    about the song. He just said "I don't think we have any
    problems with that one, Irving."</p>
      <p>The song initially performed poorly and was overshadowed by
    the film's first hit song: "Be Careful, It's my Heart". By the
    end of October 1942, however, "White Christmas" topped the
    "Your Hit Parade" chart. It remained in that position until
    well into the new year. (It has often been noted that the mix
    of melancholy — "just like the ones I used to know" —
    with comforting images of home — "where the treetops
    glisten" — resonated especially strongly with listeners
    during World War II. The Armed Forces Network was flooded with
    requests for the song.)</p>
      <p>In 1942 alone, Crosby's recording spent eleven weeks on top
    of the Billboard charts. The original version also hit number
    one on the Harlem Hit Parade for three weeks, Crosby's
    first-ever appearance on the black-oriented chart. Re-released
    by Decca, the single returned to the #1 spot during the holiday
    seasons of 1945 and 1946 (on the chart dated January 4, 1947),
    thus becoming the only single with three separate runs at the
    top of the U.S. charts. The recording became a chart perennial,
    reappearing annually on the pop chart twenty separate times
    before Billboard Magazine created a distinct Christmas chart
    for seasonal releases.</p>
      <p>Following its prominence in in the musical 
    <i>Holiday Inn</i>, the composition won the Academy Award for
    Best Original Song. In the film, Bing Crosby sings "White
    Christmas" as a duet with actress Marjorie Reynolds, though her
    voice was dubbed by Martha Mears. This now-familiar scene was
    not the moviemakers' initial plan; in the script as originally
    conceived, Reynolds, not Crosby, was to sing the song.</p>
      <p>The familiar version of "White Christmas" most often heard
    today is not the one Crosby recorded in 1942. He was called to
    Decca studios on March 18, 1947, to re-record the track; the
    1942 master had become damaged due to its frequent use. Efforts
    were made to exactly reproduce the original recording session,
    and Crosby was again backed by the Trotter Orchestra and the
    Darby Singers. Even so, there are subtle differences in the
    orchestration, most notably the addition of a celesta and
    flutes to brighten up the introduction.</p>
      <p>Crosby was dismissive of his role in the song's success,
    saying later that "a jackdaw with a cleft palate could have
    sung it successfully." But Crosby was associated with it for
    the rest of his career. Another Crosby vehicle — the 1954
    musical 
    <i>White Christmas</i>— was the highest-grossing film of
    1954.</p>
      <p>Crosby's "White Christmas" single has been credited with
    selling 50 million copies, the most by any release. The 
    <i>Guinness Book of World Records</i>lists the song as a
    100-million seller, encompassing all versions of the song,
    including albums. Crosby's holiday collection 
    <i>Merry Christmas</i>was first released as an LP in 1949, and
    has never been out-of-print since. However, due to incomplete
    record keeping before 1958, "White Christmas" is officially
    listed as the second best-selling single worldwide.</p>
      <p>"ItsRanked" ranked Crosby's "White Christmas" as the number
    one Christmas song on its Top 40 Christmas Songs of all time.
    In 1999, National Public Radio included it in the "NPR 100",
    which sought to compile the one hundred most important American
    musical works of the 20th century. In 2002, the original 1942
    version was one of 50 historically significant recordings
    chosen that year by the Library of Congress to be added to the
    National Recording Registry.</p>
      <p>The recording was broadcast on the radio on April 30, 1975,
    as a secret, pre-arranged signal precipitating the U.S.
    evacuation of Saigon (see Fall of Saigon).</p>
      <p>Irving Berlin's opening bars are often dropped in many
    recordings, but are included on 
    <i>A Christmas Gift for You from Phil Spector</i>, sung by
    Darlene Love.</p>
      <p>There's never been such a day, in Beverly Hills, L.A., But
    it's December the twenty-fourth,—, And I am longing to be up
    North—</p>
      <p>Keane's version also did include the introduction, but
    changed lyrics to give the song a melancholic feeling:</p>
      <p>Seems everyone wears a frown, for Christmas in London town,
    It reminds me each time I roamed., I'm longing to be back
    home</p>
      <p>The Drifters' 1954 cover of "White Christmas" showcased the
    talents of lead singer Clyde McPhatter and the bass of Bill
    Pinkney. Their recording of the song peaked at #2 on
    Billboard’s R&amp;B chart in December 1954, and returned to the
    same chart in the next two years. In December 1955, "White
    Christmas" became the Drifters' first of 34 singles to register
    in the mainstream Hot 100 chart. For decades, the Drifters'
    version was primarily heard on R &amp; B radio stations,
    getting little exposure elsewhere. The song received a boost in
    the early 1990s, when it was prominently featured in the film 
    <i>Home Alone</i>during a scene in which the lead character
    Kevin is applying his father's aftershave while mouthing the
    lyrics. Radio stations formats as diverse as oldies, adult
    contemporary, Top 40, and country began playing the Drifters'
    version. The song was later featured in the film 
    <i>The Santa Clause</i>.</p>
      <p>Andy Williams charted on the Christmas Singles chart in 1963
    (#1) and 1967 (#22) with his version. The B-Side was his
    version of 
    <i>The Christmas Song</i>. In 1963, Jimmy McGriff recorded the
    song for his album "Christmas With McGriff".</p>
      <p>In 2006 was covered by Twisted Sister feat Doro Pesch and
    was released on their album A Twisted Christmas, with
    German/English lyrics.</p>
      <p>Andrea Bocelli recorded the song for his first holiday
    album, 
    <i>My Christmas</i>, in 2009. The song debuted at No. 30, on
    the 
    <i>Portuguese Singles Chart</i>, spent the 2 following weeks at
    No. 19, then rose to No. 18, on its forth week, before reaching
    No. 16 on its fifth. The song also debuted at No. 7 on the
    Hungarian Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>Stiff Little Fingers Covered the song as part of their Silly
    Encores B-Side and also appeared on their USA release album -
    Hanx!.</p>
      <p>Boy George did make a cover of the song in 2009 and released
    as a single in digital download format.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
