<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swinging_on_a_Star 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swinging_on_a_Star</songId>
   <title>Swinging on a Star</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bing_Crosby</artistId>
      <artistName>Bing Crosby</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1944-08-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Swinging on a Star" is an American pop standard with music
    composed by Jimmy Van Heusen and lyrics by Johnny Burke. It was
    sung by Bing Crosby in the 1944 film Going My Way, winning an
    Academy Award for best song, and has been recorded by numerous
    artist since then.</p>
      <p>Song writer Jimmy Van Heusen was at Crosby’s house one
    evening for dinner, and to discuss a song for the movie 
    <i>Going My Way</i>. During the meal one of the children began
    complaining about how he didn’t want to go to school the next
    day. The singer turned to his son and said to him, “If you
    don’t go to school, you might grow up to be a mule. Do you
    wanna do that?”</p>
      <p>Van Heusen thought this clever rebuke would make a good song
    for the movie. He pictured Bing, who played a priest, talking
    to a group of children acting much the same way as his own
    child had acted that night. Van Heusen took the idea to his
    partner lyricist Johnny Burke, who approved. They wrote the
    song.</p>
      <p>The first recording of 
    <i>Swinging on a Star</i>took place in Los Angeles on February
    7, 1944, released by Decca Records. The Williams Brothers
    quartet, including legendary crooner Andy Williams, sang backup
    vocals to Crosby.</p>
      <p>It was also featured in the Little Lulu cartoon, 
    <i>Bout with a Trout.</i>,</p>
      <p>Some additional recordings:</p>
      <p>The song was parodied in a 
    <i>The Far Side</i>cartoon, which depicted a man-turned-pig
    saying to his wife, "Hey, so I made the wrong decision!
    [referring to the part of the song which says "Or would you
    rather be a pig"] But I wasn't sure I 
    <i>wanted</i>to swing on a star, carry moonbeams home in a
    jar!"</p>
      <p>In 1969, Ray Stevens sang "Gitarzan", which featured the
    wrong notes from "Swinging on a Star". ("Carrying Moonbeams
    Home in a Jar").</p>
      <p>During his 2009 
    <i>Tour of Refusal</i>indie legend Morrissey occasionally sang
    the chorus over the chorus of his 2004 hit 'First of the Gang
    to Die'.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
