<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Fence_Me_In_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Fence_Me_In_(song)</songId>
   <title>Don't Fence Me In</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Andrews_Sisters</artistId>
      <artistName>Bing Crosby and The Andrews Sisters</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1944-12-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>Don't Fence Me In is a popular American song with music by
    Cole Porter and lyrics by Robert Fletcher and Cole Porter.</p>
      <p>Originally written in 1934 for 
    <i>Adios, Argentina,</i>an unproduced 20th Century Fox film
    musical, "Don't Fence Me In" was based on text by a poet and
    engineer with the Department of Highways in Helena, Montana,
    Robert (Bob) Fletcher. Cole Porter, who had been asked to write
    a cowboy song for the 20th Century Fox musical, bought the poem
    from Fletcher for $250. Porter reworked Fletcher's poem, and
    when the song was first published, Porter was credited with
    sole authorship. Porter had wanted to give Fletcher
    co-authorship credit, but his publishers did not allow that.
    After the song became popular, however, Fletcher hired
    attorneys who negotiated his being given co-authorship credit
    in subsequent publications. Although it was one of the most
    popular songs of its time, Porter claimed it was his least
    favorite of his own compositions.</p>
      <p>Ten years later, in 1944, Warner Bros. resurrected "Don't
    Fence Me In" for Roy Rogers to sing in the movie, 
    <i>Hollywood Canteen</i>. Many people heard the song for the
    first time when Kate Smith introduced it on her radio broadcast
    of October 8, 1944. "Don't Fence Me In" was also recorded by
    Bing Crosby and The Andrews Sisters in 1944. Crosby entered the
    studio on July 25, 1944, without having seen or heard the song.
    Within 30 minutes, he and The Andrews Sisters had made the
    recording, which later sold over a million copies and topped
    the 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts for eight weeks in 1944-45.</p>
      <p>Miss Ella Fitzgerald recorded this on her Verve Cole Porter
    Songbook album, it was also released on her Verve release "Ella
    Fitzgerald Sings More Cole Porter."</p>
      <p>Also made famous by the original "Singin' Cowboy" Gene
    Autry.</p>
      <p>The following year, the song was sung again as the title
    tune of another Roy Rogers film, 
    <i>Don't Fence Me In</i>(1945), in which Dale Evans plays a
    magazine reporter who comes to Roy Rogers' and George "Gabby"
    Hayes' ranch to research a story which she is writing about a
    legendary late gunslinger. When it's revealed that Gabby Hayes
    is actually the supposedly dead outlaw, Roy must clear his
    name. Rogers and The Sons of the Pioneers also find time to
    perform some songs, including the Cole Porter title tune.</p>
      <p>The next year (1946), a biopic about Cole Porter used a clip
    from 
    <i>Hollywood Canteen</i>of Rogers singing "Don't Fence Me
    In."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
