<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27ll_Be_Seeing_You_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27ll_Be_Seeing_You_(song)</songId>
   <title>I'll Be Seeing You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bing_Crosby</artistId>
      <artistName>Bing Crosby</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1944-07-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"I'll Be Seeing You" is a popular song from the Broadway
    musical 
    <i>Right This Way</i>, which closed after fifteen performances.
    Its music was written by Sammy Fain, the lyrics by Irving
    Kahal. The song was published in 1938.</p>
      <p>The musical theme has emotional power, and was much loved
    during World War II. The lyrics begin, in Ambrose's recorded
    version, with a preamble:,</p>
      <p>Cathedral bells were calling and our hearts sang on;, Was it
    the spell of Paris or the April dawn?, Who knows if we shall
    meet again,, But when the morning chimes ring sweet again,,
    I'll be seeing you in all the old familiar places...</p>
      <p>As the song develops, the words take a jaunty commonplace of
    casual farewell and transform it by degrees, to climax with</p>
      <p>"...and when the night is new,, I'll be looking at the
    moon,, But I'll be seeing you."</p>
      <p>The resemblance between the main tune's first four lines and
    a passage within the theme of the last movement of Gustav
    Mahler's Third Symphony (1896) was pointed out by Deryck Cooke
    in 1970</p>
      <p>Featured throughout the 1944 movie also titled 
    <i>I'll be Seeing You</i>, starring Ginger Rogers and Joseph
    Cotten, the recording by Bing Crosby became a hit that year,
    being number one for the week of July 8. Later, the song became
    notably associated with Liberace, as the theme to his
    television show of the 1950s. It has also been featured in the
    1989 Woody Allen film 
    <i>Crimes and Misdemeanors</i>; in the end credits of the 1990
    film ; in the 1992 movie 
    <i>Shining Through</i>; in a few episodes of 
    <i>Star Trek: Deep Space Nine'</i>s final season; and in the
    2004 film 
    <i>The Notebook</i>as the song for Noah and Allie. It was also
    featured in the closing credits for the final episode of 
    <i>Beavis and Butthead</i>. During the 2009 Academy Awards
    presentation, Queen Latifah sang the song during the 'In
    Memoriam' tribute to members of the motion picture industry who
    had died during the previous year, which was controversial
    because the In Memoriam tribute was previously traditionally
    unaccompanied.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by well known artists.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
