<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boom_Boom_Pow 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boom_Boom_Pow</songId>
   <title>Boom Boom Pow</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Eyed_Peas</artistId>
      <artistName>Black Eyed Peas</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2009-04-18</week>
      <week>2009-04-25</week>
      <week>2009-05-02</week>
      <week>2009-05-09</week>
      <week>2009-05-16</week>
      <week>2009-05-23</week>
      <week>2009-05-30</week>
      <week>2009-06-06</week>
      <week>2009-06-13</week>
      <week>2009-06-20</week>
      <week>2009-06-27</week>
      <week>2009-07-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/95/Bepbbp3008.jpg/200px-Bepbbp3008.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Black-Eyed-Peas+Boom-Boom-Pow.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The E.N.D.</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 10, 2009 , (see release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download cd single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2008</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Electro Hop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:11 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>5:08 (Album Version With Intro)</length>
      <length>3:38 (Radio Edit)</length>
      <length>3:27 (Video Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <writers>
      <writer>William Adams</writer>
      <writer>Allen Pineda</writer>
      <writer>Stacy Ferguson</writer>
      <writer>Jaime Gomez</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>will.i.am</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Boom Boom Pow" is a single by the Black Eyed Peas released
    as the lead single from their fifth studio album, 
    <i>The E.N.D.</i>The song uses the auto-tune vocal effect, and
    blends the genres of dance pop, electro-hop and hip hop.</p>
      <p>"Boom Boom Pow" topped the Hot 100, making it the group's
    first U.S. number-one single. It is the second longest-running
    single to stay atop the Hot 100 in 2009, beaten only by the
    Black Eyed Peas' second single from 
    <i>The E.N.D.</i>, "I Gotta Feeling", which held the top spot
    for 14 consecutive weeks. It has also topped the Australian,
    Canadian and UK singles charts as well as reaching the top 10
    in more than 20 countries. The song was named 7th on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade.</p>
      <p>The song sold over 4,295,000 digital downloads in the U.S,
    becoming the group's highest-selling song in the U.S. to date.
    It reached this threshold in just 23 weeks, faster than any
    other song in digital history. The old record was set by "Low"
    by Flo Rida, which topped the 4 million mark in its 35th week
    of release. The single has since sold 5,034,711 copies in the
    U.S.</p>
      <p>"Boom Boom Pow" was ranked as the No. 1 song and digital
    song at the Billboard Year End Chart of 2009.</p>
      <p>The song was nominated at the 52nd Grammy Awards for Best
    Dance Recording and won Best Short Form Music Video. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>ranked the song #14 on their Best 25 Songs
    of 2009 list.</p>
      <p>The song opens with Will.i.am meditating on and affirming a
    new, futuristic sound for himself and the rest of the Peas ("I
    got that rock-and-roll, that future flow"). Fergie, Taboo , and
    apl.de.ap each offer a variation on this theme, after which
    Will.i.am (introduced by Fergie) demonstrates the theme at work
    in a series of rapid-fire raps, punctuated with digital
    effects. The song concludes with Fergie repeating her initial
    verse, forming an outro of sorts and taking the listener more
    or less full-circle.</p>
      <p>Fergie has commented on the unusual structure of the song,
    stating</p>
      <p>The song also attempts a futuristic quality, with Fergie
    rapping the lyric "I'm so three thousand and eight, you so two
    thousand and late." The song's beat is influenced by 1980's
    electro song "Planet Rock". Will.i.am stated that the lyric
    helped inspire the futuristic concept of the video. Will.i.am
    also stated on the 
    <i>Merrick and Rosso</i>breakfast show (
    <i>Nova 96.9</i>) that the song was heavily influenced by the
    electro sounds he heard in the nightclubs in Sydney, Australia,
    during the filming of 
    <i>X-Men Origins: Wolverine</i>and his visit to Australia.</p>
      <p>Following the band's record breaking success with "Boom Boom
    Pow" and "I Gotta Feeling", Will.i.am commented in a video on 
    <i>Billboard</i>on the song's success, saying:</p>
      <p>"Boom Boom Pow" was released to U.S. mainstream radio on
    March 13, 2009. It was released officially on iTunes in the
    U.S. on March 30, 2009. It was scheduled to be released in the
    UK on May 25, 2009, however due to 3 alternative versions of
    the song entering the UK iTunes Top 50 songs, the Black Eyed
    Peas version was released 2 weeks early, on Sunday, May 10. One
    of their full performances took place at the American Idol
    Finale of 2009. This had also helped the single to become more
    well known to the public.</p>
      <p>As of June 2009, an unknown number of North American radio
    stations have elected to censor the song's reference to
    satellite radio. Most UK radio stations have also been found to
    distort the word satellite radio, and this is the version that
    appears on the UK CD single.</p>
      <p>The official remix is called, "Let the Beat Rock (Boys Noize
    Megamix)", and is produced by Boys Noize and there are 5
    versions of the song. The official remixed version features 50
    Cent of which there are 2 versions:</p>
      <p>The second version features Gucci Mane also in the EP, the
    third version features Flo Rida, the fourth version is a
    mash-up of the 50 Cent remix and the Gucci Mane remix, and the
    fifth version is known as "Ching, Chang, Chong", by Rucka Rucka
    Ali. There are other remixes using the original version of the
    song by Busta Rhymes and Fatman Scoop.</p>
      <p>A remix by DJ Ammo/A Poet Named Life is played in the ending
    credits of the 2009 Summer blockbuster film 
    <i>G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra</i>.</p>
      <p>At the 2009 American Music Awards, the guitar riff of
    "Smells Like Teen Spirit" by Nirvana was played after the
    performance of this song.</p>
      <p>On the fourth season of 
    <i>America's Best Dance Crew</i>, a District 78 remix of the
    song was used for the sudden death challenge on the first
    episode, in the dance-off between Beat Ya Feet Kings, Southern
    Movement, and Fr3sh. Fr3sh was eliminated.</p>
      <p>Nick Levine from 
    <i>Digital Spy</i>gave "Boom Boom Pow" four out of five stars,
    saying that "it's a fairly ridiculous robopop stomper featuring
    no real chorus, 
    <i>808s &amp; Heartbreaks</i>-style beats, lashings of
    Auto-Tune, techno synths that arrive half-way through and this
    vintage diss from Fergie: 'I'm so 3008, you're so 2000 and
    late.' It may well become grating, but frankly who cares? Right
    now this just sounds cracking." 
    <i>Billboard</i>gave the song a positive review, stating that
    the song "shows the Black Eyed Peas in fine form" and that it
    was "a knockout".</p>
      <p>In Australia, Boom Boom Pow was released on the 30th of
    March and debuted on the ARIA Charts on April 6, 2009. It has
    since reached number one, staying there 12 weeks and was
    certified 4x Platinum by the RIAA. It was the highest selling
    single of 2009 before being de-throned by Britney Spears's hit
    single "3". It spent 27 weeks in the Top 20. Australia is the
    first country in which the song was released.</p>
      <p>The song (as of the end of 2009) has sold 4,670,000 million
    downloads in the US. The U.S., the song debuted at number 71
    after garnering heavy airplay. In its second week, it rose to
    number 54. In the third week, it rose to 39, still surging in
    airplay. The song rocketed from 39 to 1 in its fourth week on
    the Hot 100. The single sold 465,000 downloads in its first
    week of digital release, the third-largest number of download
    sales in a single week overall, and the largest single-week and
    debut-download totals by a group in the history of
    digital-download sales tracking, reaching #1 on the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100 and Pop 100. It became the group's first U.S.
    #1, holding the spot for twelve consecutive weeks. Having been
    dethroned to #2 by the Black Eyed Peas' other song "I Gotta
    Feeling", it is the second longest running #1 song of 2009 to
    date on the chart, behind I Gotta Feeling, and the first song
    to spend at least twelve weeks at #1 since Mariah Carey's "We
    Belong Together" in 2005. "Boom Boom Pow"'s 12-week stay at #1
    ties the record held by Eminem's "Lose Yourself" as the longest
    running Rap/Hip Hop song to top the Billboard Hot 100 chart.
    The song was finally dethroned on the Hot 100 by the band's own
    follow up single "I Gotta Feeling." The chart week of May 30,
    2009 "Boom Boom Pow" became only the fifth song to top both 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Mainstream Top 40 and Rhythmic Top 40 charts
    in the same week, reaching an estimated audience of 99 million
    on U.S. radio that week. It was the fourth song of the decade
    of the 2000s to spend at least twelve weeks at #1, and only the
    twelfth song in the chart's history to spend at least twelve
    weeks at the top. It is the band's first Rhythmic number one,
    and their second Mainstream Top 40 number one. "Boom Boom Pow"
    became the first song in digital history to spend its first
    twelve weeks of release as the most-downloaded song in America,
    selling at least 200,000 copies a week for eleven straight
    weeks.</p>
      <p>It has also topped the charts on the Canadian Hot 100 the
    same week as on the Hot 100 and on the Australian ARIA Charts.
    On the New Zealand RIANZ chart, the song has so far peaked at
    number two. Moreover, it has charted within the top 10 in more
    than ten countries.</p>
      <p>On May 17, 2009, it entered the UK Singles Chart at #1 based
    on almost 75,000 downloads alone. It is the band's second
    number one in the UK (the other being "Where Is the Love?"
    which also reached the top of the chart six years prior). It
    has also reached #3 so far in Ireland.</p>
      <p>After being knocked off the number 1 spot in the United
    Kingdom on May 24, 2009 by "Bonkers" by Dizzee Rascal and
    Armand Van Helden, the song remained at the #2 slot for 2 weeks
    before returning to #1 on June 7, 2009. "Bonkers" had meanwhile
    swapped places with "Boom Boom Pow" and took the #2 slot. This
    subsequently marks the first time a song has had two separate
    runs at the summit of the chart since Shakira's "Hips Don't
    Lie" in July 2006. Their follow up single in the UK "I Gotta
    Feeling" also peaked at #1 and managed the same feat of having
    two separate runs at number one on the UK Singles Chart. With
    sales of over 600,000, the single is currently the sixth best
    selling of 2009 in the UK. "Boom Boom Pow" is also the 13th
    best selling R&amp;B song of the 21st century in the UK.</p>
      <p>Fergie had stated at an interview on 
    <i>The Insider</i>that the music video would be shooting the
    week of March 8, 2009. The making of the video was released by
    MTV on April 8.</p>
      <p>In an interview to MTV, it was said that "... the concept of
    the video is the Peas' birth into the digital afterlife,"
    Fergie said. "So the transformation is us going into a sort of
    birth or cocoon and coming out the other end as forms of
    energy. It's a parallel to the music industry. Now everything
    is downloaded." Group member will.i.am stated the video was
    inspired by how digital the world has become and hopes the
    video portrays "what it would be like if we were actually in
    the computer, if art was fused in it," he said. "[It's] analog
    life from a digital perspective. Becoming technology." The
    music video was directed by Mathew Cullen and Mark Cudsi. The
    video premiered on Dipdive on April 18, 2009 and was released
    on iTunes on April 24, 2009.</p>
      <p>The video is set in the year of 3008, portraying "how it
    would be like if we actually lived in computers". This concept
    was based in a line of the song, in which singer Fergie states
    "I'm so 3008 / You so 2000 and late". The video starts with
    Taboo flicking through pictures on a HP TouchSmart, he selects
    the image of a mushroom cloud. As the singing starts, images of
    computer icons and random computer code and some ASCII art of
    "THE END" are flashing in the background. The Black Eyed Peas
    are then seen singing their verses of the song. While this is
    happening, dancers are seen in striped zentai suits, dancing to
    the song, and negative images are turned into positive images.
    e.g. the mushroom cloud turns into a tree swing, the grenade
    into a microphone, a gun into a trumpet and a nuclear barrel
    played as a drum. The video also features the face used on the
    album cover miming along to various lyrics; the face was
    designed as an amalgam of all four band members' facial
    features. Much of the imagery in the video is a homage to
    Rebecca Allen's 1986 video for the Kraftwerk song 
    <i>Musique Non Stop</i>.</p>
      <p>The video was meant to go the full song but they cut it to
    3:29.</p>
      <p>The video won a Grammy at the 52nd Grammy Awards in the
    category of Best Short Form Music Video.</p>
      <p>In January 2010, it was announced that the song was
    allegedly copied from another. Chicago artist Ebony Latrice
    Batts, better known by her stage name Phoenix Phenom, asserted
    the song is simply a copy of her track, "Boom Dynamite". It was
    written by Manfred Mohr and conceived in a music studio in
    Chicago. The duo sent a demo tape to Interscope Records because
    the record company was interested in their material. Now, they
    are seeking indemnity from The Black Eyed Peas and
    Interscope.</p>
      <p>Promotional CD</p>
      <p>CD single - United Kingdom</p>
      <p>
         <i>Invasion of Boom Boom Pow - Megamix E.P.</i>, An E.P. of
    remixes entitled "Invasion of Boom Boom Pow - Megamix E.P." was
    released on May 5, 2009</p>
      <p>Common Versions</p>
      <p>Other Versions</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
