<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rapture_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rapture_(song)</songId>
   <title>Rapture</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blondie_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Blondie</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1981-03-28</week>
      <week>1981-04-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/73/Blondie_-_Rapture_%28US%29.jpg/200px-Blondie_-_Rapture_%28US%29.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Blondie+Rapture.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Autoamerican</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 1981</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1980</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Rap</genre>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>6:33 (US)</length>
      <length>4:57 (UK)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Chrysalis Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Deborah Harry</writer>
      <writer>Chris Stein</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mike Chapman</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Rapture" is a single by the American new wave band Blondie.
    It was released in January 1981 and became one of the first
    substantial hit singles to involve rap music, and the first
    rap-influenced single to reach number one on the US Billboard
    Chart. It was the second and final song to be released from the
    band's 1980 album 
    <i>Autoamerican</i>, the first being "The Tide Is High", which
    had topped the chart in the US and UK. "Rapture" went on to
    reach number one on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100, number one on
    the U.S. Hot Dance Music/Club Play chart, and number five in
    the UK singles chart. The B-side was "Walk Like Me", also from 
    <i>Autoamerican</i>. The song was the first #1 hit in the U.S.
    to feature rapping.</p>
      <p>It was Chic's track "Good Times" that inspired Debbie Harry
    and Chris Stein to write "Rapture".</p>
      <p>Rapture is a combination of New Wave pop, funk, jazz and rap
    music, with the rap section forming an extended coda. While it
    was not the first single involving rap to be successful, it was
    the first to top the charts. The Sugarhill Gang's 1979 hit
    "Rapper's Delight", a straightforward rap track based on the
    backing track of Chic's "Good Times", reached #36 on the U.S.
    Hot 100 chart and was certified Gold. Kurtis Blow's "The
    Breaks" was released in 1980, and became the second rap single
    to be certified Gold. The lyrics of "Rapture" included
    references to hip-hop pioneers Fab Five Freddy and Grandmaster
    Flash.</p>
      <p>Debuting in 1981, the music video was the first rap video
    ever broadcast on MTV. Set in the Upper East Side, the "Man
    from Mars" or "voodoo god" (dancer William Barnes in the white
    suit and top hat) is the introductory and central figure.
    Barnes also choreographed the piece. The final shot is a
    one-take scene of Debbie Harry dancing along the street,
    passing by graffiti artists, Uncle Sam, a Native American and a
    goat. Fab Five Freddy and graffiti artists Lee Quinones and
    Jean-Michel Basquiat make cameo appearances. Basquiat was hired
    when Grandmaster Flash did not show for the filming.</p>
      <p>The versions appearing on the U.S. and UK 7" and 12" singles
    were quite different. The US 7" single, also issued with a
    different cover picture, used the regular 
    <i>Autoamerican</i>album version, the US 12" single a version
    with an additional verse partly in French, making it just 40
    seconds longer. For the UK and international single releases,
    producer Mike Chapman remixed the track completely. The Special
    Disco Mix has a different intro and it was also given a longer
    instrumental break with new percussion overdubbed, making it
    ten minutes long. The UK 7" version (4:59) was an edit of this
    Special Disco Mix, and a slightly different edit (5:33)
    appeared on the band's first 'greatest hits' compilation 
    <i>The Best of Blondie</i>in 1981. The track "Live It Up" was
    also extended and remixed for the B-side of the international
    12" single, the 8 minute version was included on the deleted
    1994 UK CD edition of 
    <i>Autoamerican</i>but was re-issued as part of EMI's lavish 14
    disc 
    <i>Singles Box</i>in 2004.</p>
      <p>The picture of Debbie Harry used for the UK/international
    editions of the original 7" and 12" "Rapture" singles was later
    used for the cover of 1995 compilation 
    <i>Beautiful - The Remix Album</i>.</p>
      <p>Another official remix of "Rapture" can be found on the 1988
    compilation 
    <i>Once More into the Bleach</i>. The track was remixed again
    and re-issued as a single in both the UK and the US in 1994 and
    included on compilations 
    <i>The Platinum Collection</i>, 
    <i>Beautiful - The Remix Album</i>and 
    <i>Remixed Remade Remodeled - The Remix Project</i>.</p>
      <p>Grandmaster Flash scratch mixed "Rapture" on his single "The
    Adventures of Grandmaster Flash on the Wheels of Steel". In
    1996 Foxy Brown (featuring Jay-Z) used the song as the base for
    her hit, "I'll Be". It was also sampled by Won-G for his single
    "Caught up in the Rapture", and was interpolated by rapper
    KRS-One on his 1997 single "Step into a World (Rapture's
    Delight)". In 2000 it was sampled once more by Glamma Kid on
    his single "Bills 2 Pay". In that same year Destiny's Child
    sampled it on their single "Independent Women Part I". The song
    was also sampled by The Jungle Brothers in the song "In Days 2
    Come" from the album "Done by the Forces of Nature". Elements
    of "Rapture" were recreated for the Joe Pesci song "Wise Guy",
    in which he raps in-character as Vincent LaGuardia Gambini from
    the film 
    <i>My Cousin Vinny</i>.</p>
      <p>English synthpop duo Erasure covered "Rapture" on the US
    version of their 1997 album 
    <i>Cowboy</i>, with Vince Clarke providing the rap.</p>
      <p>In 2004 at VH1's annual Diva's Live concert, Debbie Harry
    performed "Rapture" with rapper Eve who performed her own
    original rap.</p>
      <p>At the 2003 Brit Awards Justin Timberlake performed part of
    the song with Kylie Minogue singing the rap, as the finale of a
    medley including his hit songs Cry Me a River and Like I Love
    You. During their raunchy routine Timberlake infamously touched
    Minogue’s behind. The performance reportedly caused a dispute
    between Minogue and her then-boyfriend, model James Gooding.
    The much-publicised bottom grope was later revealed to be a
    part of the sequence’s planned choreography.</p>
      <p>In 2005 "Rapture" was fused with The Doors' "Riders on the
    Storm" into "Rapture Riders" by Go Home Productions. This
    unofficial mashup remix was later approved to be included on
    Blondie's 
    <i>Greatest Hits: Sight + Sound</i>/
    <i>Greatest Hits: Sound &amp; Vision</i>. The song was a Top 40
    hit in Australia and made the top ten on the U.S. Hot Dance
    Club Play chart.</p>
      <p>Chilean musician Nicole also did a cover of this song in
    2006, included on her album 
    <i>APT</i>. Dub Pistols covered the song for their 2007 album 
    <i>Speakers and Tweeters</i>, featuring Terry Hall from The
    Specials at the vocals.</p>
      <p>US 7" (CHS 2485, January 1981),</p>
      <p>US 12" (12 CHS 2485, January 1981),</p>
      <p>UK 7" (CHS 2485, January 1981),</p>
      <p>UK 12" (CHS 12 2485, January 1981)</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
