<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heart_of_Glass_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heart_of_Glass_(song)</songId>
   <title>Heart of Glass</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blondie_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Blondie</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1979-04-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/40/Blondie_-_Heart_Of_Glass_%28UK%29.jpg/200px-Blondie_-_Heart_Of_Glass_%28UK%29.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Blondie+Heart-of-Glass.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Parallel Lines</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 3, 1979</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12" vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>June 1978</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:48 (album version)</length>
      <length>3:22 (US single version)</length>
      <length>3:54 (UK single version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Chrysalis</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Debbie Harry</writer>
      <writer>Chris Stein</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mike Chapman</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Heart of Glass" is a song by American New Wave band
    Blondie. Featured on the band's third studio album, 
    <i>Parallel Lines</i>, it was released as a single in 1979 and
    topped the charts in several countries, most notably in the
    United Kingdom and United States.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Rolling Stone</i>ranked the song number 255 on its list of
    the 500 greatest songs of all time.</p>
      <p>"Heart of Glass" was originally recorded in 1975 under the
    name "Once I Had a Love," and was much slower with a
    blues/reggae vibe to it. The song was frequently performed on
    tours, then was re-recorded with the same title in 1978, when
    the song was made a bit more rock-oriented. When Blondie
    recorded the album 
    <i>Parallel Lines</i>, disco was big on the music scene, and
    producer Mike Chapman decided to give the song the disco twist
    that made the song what it is today, and one of the best-known
    Blondie recordings. For the single release the track was
    remixed by Chapman with the double-tracked bass drum even more
    accentuated.</p>
      <p>The song was released in January 1979, and reached number
    one in both the US and the UK. The UK B-side was "Rifle Range",
    from Blondie's self titled debut album while the US single used
    the 
    <i>Parallel Lines</i>track "11:59". The accompanying music
    video for "Heart of Glass" was filmed at Studio 54 in New York
    City.</p>
      <p>The versions appearing on the 7" single issued in early 1979
    varied from country to country, some used the regular album
    version (UK, 3:54), others an edited album version (US, 3:22)
    and others an edited version of the 12" Disco Mix (4:10), which
    is the one usually found on current hits compilations like the
    1994 anthology 
    <i>The Platinum Collection</i>, 
    <i>Greatest Hits: Sight + Sound</i>(2005) and 
    <i>Greatest Hits: Sound &amp; Vision</i>(2006). For the band's
    very first hits compilation, 1981's 
    <i>The Best of Blondie</i>, producer Mike Chapman created a
    special mix including elements from both the 12" Disco Version
    and the 12" Instrumental (4:33). The 1981 version appears on
    2002's 
    <i>Greatest Hits</i>.</p>
      <p>Almost immediately after its release, "Heart of Glass"
    became the subject of controversy because of its disco sound.
    At the time, Blondie was one of the bands at the forefront of
    New York's growing New Wave musical scene and were accused of
    "selling out" for releasing a disco song. According to Blondie
    frontwoman Deborah Harry, "Heart of Glass" made the band
    pariahs in the eyes of many of their fellow musicians in the
    New York music scene. The band was accused of pandering to the
    mainstream that many punk/new wave bands at the time were
    actively rebelling against.</p>
      <p>There was also the issue of the use of the expression "pain
    in the ass" within the lyrics which, at the time, did not sit
    easily with the BBC. The radio version changed it to "heart of
    glass." In Australia, the song was banned from radio for its
    "strong language."</p>
      <p>Despite the controversy, the song was a huge hit and helped
    propel Blondie from cult group to mainstream icons. The band
    itself has acknowledged the success of the song in helping
    their careers and has downplayed criticism of the song,
    pointing out that Blondie always experimented with different
    styles of music and that "Heart of Glass" was their take on
    disco. The band itself has jokingly taken to referring to the
    song as "The Disco Song" in interviews.</p>
      <p>The "Heart of Glass" promotional video was filmed at the
    Studio 54 discothèque in New York City with director Stanley
    Dorfman. The video begins with footage of New York City in the
    night before joining Blondie perform at Studio 54. Then, the
    video alternates between close-ups of Harry's face as she
    lip-syncs, and mid-distance shots of the entire band. In the
    video Harry wears a silver dress designed by Stephen Sprouse.
    To create the dress, Sprouse photo-printed a picture of
    television scan lines onto a piece of fabric, and then,
    according to Harry, "put a layer of cotton fabric underneath
    and a layer of chiffon on top, and then the scan-lines would do
    this op-art thing". The popularity of the song helped Sprouse's
    work earn a lot of exposure from the media.</p>
      <p>"Draped in a sheer, silver Sprouse dress," Kris Needs
    summarized while writing for 
    <i>Mojo Classic</i>, "Debbie sang through gritted teeth, while
    the boys cavorted with mirror balls". Studying Harry's attitude
    in the "effortlessly cool" video, music writer Pat Kane felt
    she "exuded a steely confidence about her sexual impact ... The
    Marilyn [Monroe] do has artfully fallen over, and she's in the
    funkiest of dresses: one strap across her shoulder, swirling
    silks around about her. Her iconic face shows flickers of
    interest, amidst the boredom and ennui of the song's lyrics".
    Kane also noted that the band members fooling around with disco
    balls, "taking the mickey out of their own disco fixation".
    Reviewing the 
    <i>Greatest Hits: Sound &amp; Vision</i>DVD for Pitchfork
    Media, Jess Harvell wrote that while "owning your own copy of
    'Heart of Glass' may not seem as cool [anymore] ... there's the
    always luminous Deborah Harry, who would give boiling asparagus
    an erotic charge, all while looking too bored to live".</p>
      <p>The first official remix of "Heart of Glass", by Shep
    Pettibone, appeared on the Blondie/Debbie Harry remix
    compilation 
    <i>Once More into the Bleach</i>in 1988 and was also issued as
    a single in certain territories. The song was remixed by Diddy
    and re-released again in July 1995, reaching number 15 in the
    UK Singles Chart and was included on the 1995 remix compilation
    
    <i>Beautiful - The Remix Album</i>. In 2007, Positiva Records
    released a seven-track EP consisting of the original radio and
    album versions of the song, plus five new remixes by DJ Edison.
    Missy Elliott's 2003 hit "Work It" sampled the famous Roland
    CR-78 drum machine intro from the track. Natalie
    Bassingthwaighte sampled the song on her song "Supersensual",
    which is from her debut studio album, 1000 Stars.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
