<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tide_Is_High 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tide_Is_High</songId>
   <title>The Tide Is High</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blondie_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Blondie</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1981-01-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>On the Beach with the Paragons</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1967</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rocksteady</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:53</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Treasure Isle Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>John Holt</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Tide Is High" is a 1967 song written by John Holt and
    performed by The Paragons with John Holt as lead singer.
    Although originally released as an A-side in Jamaica on the
    Treasure Isle label it was relegated to the B-side of the "Only
    a Smile" single for UK release a few months later.</p>
      <p>The song features the violin of "White Rum" Raymond and was
    popular in Jamaica and became popular amongst West Indians and
    skinheads in the UK when a deejay version by U-Roy was released
    in 1971. The song went mainly unnoticed in the rest of the
    world until it was rediscovered in 1980 when it became a US/UK
    no.1 hit for the band Blondie. The British girl group Atomic
    Kitten also had a no.1 with their version of the song in
    2002.</p>
      <p>"The Tide Is High" was covered by US New Wave band Blondie
    in 1980, in a reggae/ska style that included horns and strings.
    It was released as a single, and appeared on the band's fifth
    album, 
    <i>Autoamerican</i>. It reached number one on the Billboard Hot
    100, and was popular outside the USA, reaching number one on
    the UK singles chart, number four in Australia, and number
    fifteen in the former West Germany. It was the last UK number
    one single for the band until "Maria" in 1999. The B-side of
    "The Tide is High" was "Suzie and Jeffrey", which appeared as a
    bonus track on the original 1980 cassette edition of the album 
    <i>Autoamerican</i>and was also included on EMI-Capitol's
    re-issue of 
    <i>Autoamerican</i>in 2001.</p>
      <p>Official remixes of the Blondie version have been issued
    twice. First by Coldcut in 1988 on the Blondie/Debbie Harry
    remix compilation 
    <i>Once More into the Bleach</i>and the second time in 1995 by
    Pete Arden and Vinny Vero on the album 
    <i>Remixed Remade Remodeled - The Remix Project</i>(UK edition:
    
    <i>Beautiful - The Remix Album</i>).</p>
      <p>In November 1980, the song was played on radio stations
    across the state of Alabama in anticipation of a football game
    between University of Alabama, whose nickname is the Crimson
    Tide, and the University of Notre Dame.</p>
      <p>In 1981, Swedish singer Siw Inger recorded a German language
    version of the song. Although the lyrics are not a direct
    translation, the vocal and instrumental arrangements are
    virtually identical.</p>
      <p>In 1984, Nigerian singer Onyeka Onwenu covered the song for
    the album 
    <i>In the Morning Light</i>. A year later, parts of this song
    were taken and used as a sample for Bryan Adams' "Reggae
    Christmas".</p>
      <p>In 2000, "The Tide Is High" was covered by
    singer-turned-actress Billie Piper for her second album, 
    <i>Walk of Life</i>. It was due for release in early 2001.
    However, according to Piper's autobiography, Growing Pains, she
    told Virgin Records (her record label), not to bother releasing
    "The Tide Is High" as a single because she was worn out and
    didn't want to sing anymore after appearing in court against a
    woman named Juliet Peters who had given Piper, her friends and
    her family numerous death threats.</p>
      <p>This time, the song was remade with keyboards to make it
    more pop-oriented. Their version of the song also added a new
    bridge, hence the subtitle "Get the Feeling". The song reached
    number one in the UK in September, 2002. The full song was
    played during the opening credits of The Lizzie McGuire Movie
    (the album version was used in the movie, however, the version
    on the soundtrack had slightly different lyrics), and was used
    for a TV commercial for Japanese beer company, Asahi Breweries.
    There are two versions of the single.</p>
      <p>Groove Brothers Radio Edit was also made. The mix clocks in
    at (3:20)</p>
      <p>"Numba 1 (Tide Is High)" is the latest version of "The Tide
    Is High", performed by Canadian rapper Kardinal Offishall
    featuring Keri Hilson. Produced by Supa Dups, the song – a
    percussive, dancehall-infused hip hop update – was released in
    September 2008 as the fourth single from his fourth album 
    <i>Not 4 Sale</i>. It was released on iTunes on October 14,
    2008.</p>
      <p>Aside from the album version, which features Rihanna, there
    are three other versions of "Numba 1 (Tide Is High)". The
    second is the original version, featuring Nicole Scherzinger.
    The third version features Rihanna and Nicole Scherzinger. The
    fourth version is the official single and features Keri Hilson.
    There is also a mash-up version which features Rihanna, Nicole
    Scherzinger and Keri Hilson.</p>
      <p>The music video premiered on October 24 at Yahoo! Music. The
    video is directed by Gil Green, and Akon makes a cameo
    appearance. The song "Nina" is featured at the end of the
    video.</p>
      <p>12" single</p>
      <p>7" single</p>
      <p>Rihanna and Nicole Scherzinger versions</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
