<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Call_Me_(Blondie_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Call_Me_(Blondie_song)</songId>
   <title>Call Me</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blondie_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Blondie</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1980-04-19</week>
      <week>1980-04-26</week>
      <week>1980-05-03</week>
      <week>1980-05-10</week>
      <week>1980-05-17</week>
      <week>1980-05-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/4a/Blondie_-_Call_Me_%28GER%29.jpg/200px-Blondie_-_Call_Me_%28GER%29.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Blondie+Call-Me.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>American Gigolo</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 1980 (US) , April 1980 (UK)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl 7" &amp; 12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>August 1979</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
      <genre>Hard Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:32 (7" version)</length>
      <length>8:04 (LP version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Polydor Records , Chrysalis Records , Salsoul Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Debbie Harry</writer>
      <writer>Giorgio Moroder</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Giorgio Moroder</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Call Me" is a song by the American new wave band Blondie.
    Released in 1980, "Call Me" topped the singles charts in both
    the US (where it became the band's biggest selling single) and
    the UK (where it became their fourth no.1 hit).</p>
      <p>The song was the main theme of the film 
    <i>American Gigolo</i>. European disco producer Giorgio Moroder
    originally asked Stevie Nicks from Fleetwood Mac to help
    compose and perform a song for the soundtrack, but she declined
    (as a recently signed contract with Modern Records prevented
    her from working with Moroder). It was at this time that
    Moroder turned to Debbie Harry and Blondie. Moroder presented
    Harry with a rough instrumental track called "Man Machine."
    Harry was asked to write the lyrics and melody, a process that
    Harry states took only a few hours . The completed song was
    then recorded by the band, with Moroder producing. The bridge
    of the original English language version also includes Harry
    singing "Call Me" in Italian ("Amore, chiamami") and French
    ("Appelle-moi, mon cheri").</p>
      <p>In the US the song was released by three different record
    companies: on the soundtrack album by Polydor, the 7" and 12"
    on Blondie's label Chrysalis, and a Spanish language 12"
    version, with lyrics by Buddy and Mary McCluskey, on disco
    label Salsoul Records. The Spanish version, titled "Llámame,"
    was meant for release in Mexico and some South American
    countries. This version was also released in the US and the UK
    and had its CD debut on Chrysalis/EMI's rarities compilation 
    <i>Blonde and Beyond</i>(1993). In 1988, a remixed version by
    Ben Liebrand taken from the Blondie remix album 
    <i>Once More into the Bleach</i>was issued as a single in the
    UK. In 2001 the "original long version" appeared as a bonus
    track on the 
    <i>Autoamerican</i>album re-issue.</p>
      <p>The single was released in the United States in February
    1980. It peaked at #1 for 6 weeks, and was certified Gold (for
    one million copies sold) by the RIAA. It also spent four weeks
    at number two on the U.S. dance chart. The single was also #1
    on 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine's 1980 year-end chart. It was released
    in the UK two months later, where it became Blondie's fourth UK
    no.1 single in little over a year. The song was also played on
    a British Telecom advert from the 1980s. Twenty-five years
    after its original release, "Call Me" was ranked at #283 on the
    list of Rolling Stone's 500 Greatest Songs of All Time.</p>
      <p>The song lists at #44 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top 100</i>.[1]</p>
      <p>There were two videos made:</p>
      <p>All tracks written by Deborah Harry and Giorgio Moroder.</p>
      <p>The song appeared in Quantum Leap: 
    <i>Another Mother</i>(credits)</p>
      <p>The song appeared in 1998 film 
    <i>Bride Of Chucky.</i>
      </p>
      <p>The song appeared in Deuce Bigalow: Male Gigolo</p>
      <p>The song appeared in 'The Business' (credits)</p>
      <p>In 1980, KMET DJ Chuck Taylor played the 12" version of this
    single at double speed and announced, in jest, that it was The
    Chipmunks' latest single. So many requests came for this "new"
    Chipmunks release, that Ross Bagdasarian, Jr. and his
    collaborator Steve Vining rushed to record what would be the
    Chipmunks' "comeback album," 
    <i>Chipmunk Punk</i>in 1980.</p>
      <p>The Swedish charts</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
