<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Honey_(Bobby_Goldsboro_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Honey_(Bobby_Goldsboro_song)</songId>
   <title>Honey</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bobby_Goldsboro</artistId>
      <artistName>Bobby Goldsboro</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1968-04-13</week>
      <week>1968-04-20</week>
      <week>1968-04-27</week>
      <week>1968-05-04</week>
      <week>1968-05-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/3e/Bobby_Goldsboro_Honey_single_cover.jpg/200px-Bobby_Goldsboro_Honey_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bobby-Goldsboro+Honey.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Honey</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1968</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Country</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>United Artists</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bobby Russell</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Honey", also known as "Honey (I Miss You)", is a song
    written by Bobby Russell. He first produced it with former
    Kingston Trio member Bob Shane. Then he gave it to American
    singer Bobby Goldsboro who recorded it for his tenth album 
    <i>Honey</i>. The song's protagonist mourns his deceased lover,
    beginning with him looking at a tree in their garden,
    remembering "it was just a twig" on the day that they planted
    it together, then reflecting on their relationship before
    turning to the day "the angels came."</p>
      <p>It was released as a single in the U.S. in 1968 (see 1968 in
    music) and spent five weeks at the top of the Billboard Pop
    Singles Chart, from April 7 to May 11, and three weeks atop
    Billboard's Hot Country Singles chart. It was preceded on the
    Billboard Hot 100 by "(Sittin' on) the Dock of the Bay" by Otis
    Redding, and was followed by Archie Bell &amp; the Drells'
    "Tighten Up". It was Goldsboro's first and only number-one hit
    on the Pop Singles and Country Singles charts, and it was his
    first song to top the Adult Contemporary chart. "Honey" reached
    number two on the UK Singles Chart, and a re-release of the
    single in England in 1975 (see 1975 in music) was also popular.
    In Australia it spent four weeks at #1 on the ARIA Charts,
    replacing The Beatles' "Lady Madonna", and was the sixth most
    popular song of 1968.</p>
      <p>One day in Spring 1968, Bobby Goldsboro was sitting at home
    in his apartment in Nashville, Tennessee, when Larry Henley
    (the falsetto singer from the group The Newbeats) walked in to
    talk to him. Larry Henley had said that he had just heard this
    nice new song that Bobby Russell had played for him. Bobby
    Russell's office at Acuff-Rose Music was right across the
    street from where Goldsboro lived. So they went over to Bobby
    Russell's office. Russell then played the song, Honey, for
    Larry Henley and Bobby Goldsboro, on a guitar. At the end of
    the song, Henley said "That's a great song. Wasn't that just
    beautiful" or words to that effect. Goldsboro just thought "If
    that's what makes you happy, then okay", but the song "didn't
    do anything for him", he later remembered. Goldsboro then
    walked back to his apartment, and that was that.</p>
      <p>A few weeks later, Goldsboro was sitting in the office of
    his new producer, Bob Montgomery (his producer up to that point
    had been Jack Gold, who produced "Little Things", "See The
    Funny Little Clown", and most of the pre-1968 songs that he
    did). Bob Montgomery and Bobby Goldsboro were sitting around
    and thinking about new songs that he could sing. Then, in an
    ironic twist of events, Bob Montgomery took him over to Bobby
    Russell's office again, and the three were all thinking
    together, and Goldsboro said "How about that other song you
    played for me the other day?". And Russell said "You mean
    "Honey"?? Goldsboro replied "Yes, I think so". So Russell
    played the song for Montgomery and Goldsboro, with another
    guitar, and it just "floored them both". Goldsboro was
    delighted. He asked Russell if he could try singing the song as
    a possibility of a new hit. However, Russell told him Bob
    Shane, from the group The Kingston Trio already had recorded
    the song. It was already getting a little bit of airplay on
    radio stations. Russell said to Bobby Goldsboro that it was in
    top 20 in the music charts down in Texas, where Shane was from.
    Russell told Goldsboro that he could have a try at the song if
    Shane's record flopped. Luckily nothing happened for Shane, so
    then Bobby Goldsboro recorded "Honey", and it became a number
    one hit song for 5 weeks in April 1968. (summarized from liner
    notes by Steve Kolanjian from "The Best Of Bobby Goldsboro:
    Honey by Bobby Goldsboro", September 1991, issued by
    Capitol-EMI Records, available on CD).</p>
      <p>Bobby Russell was married to Vicki Lawrence (who played Mama
    Thelma Harper on the TV sitcom Mama's Family in the 1980s) from
    June 1972 until November 1974. He wrote several other songs
    other than "Honey", including The Night The Lights Went Out In
    Georgia, which was sung by his then wife Vicki Lawrence (they
    got divorced in 1974), and the O.C. Smith song Little Green
    Apples, which was a big hit in 1969. Russell died of a heart
    attack on November 19, 1992, in Nicholasville, Kentucky, which
    is near Lexington. He was only 52 years old when he passed away
    in November 1992.</p>
      <p>Larry Henley later ended up writing the song The Wind
    Beneath My Wings, which was sung by Bette Midler in the movie
    Beaches, in 1989. He still lives in Nashville, Tennessee as of
    present, in 2010.</p>
      <p>
         <i>The Cincinnati Enquirer</i>reported that the song frequently
    appears on "worst songs of all-time" lists, and in April 2006,
    Todd Leopold of CNN named it the "Worst Song of All Time".
    Nonetheless, it remains heavily played on the radio and has
    been covered many times. In the 1970s when British radio DJ
    Tony Blackburn was going through his divorce with his wife
    Tessa Wyatt, he regularly played "Honey" and would comment live
    on air about how much he missed his wife.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
