<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ode_to_Billie_Joe 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ode_to_Billie_Joe</songId>
   <title>Ode to Billie Joe</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bobbie_Gentry</artistId>
      <artistName>Bobbie Gentry</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1967-08-26</week>
      <week>1967-09-02</week>
      <week>1967-09-09</week>
      <week>1967-09-16</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Ode to Billie Joe</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 1967</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>45rpm</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Country</genre>
      <genre>Blues</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:15</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol 5950</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bobbie Gentry</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Kelly Gordon</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Ode to Billie Joe" is a 1967 song written and recorded by
    Bobbie Gentry, a singer-songwriter from Chickasaw County,
    Mississippi. The single, released in late July, was a
    number-one hit in the United States, and became a big
    international seller. The song is ranked #412 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s list of "the 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time". The recording of "Ode to Billie Joe" generated eight
    Grammy nominations, including three wins for Gentry and one win
    for arranger Jimmie Haskell.</p>
      <p>This song is a first-person narrative that reveals a
    quasi-Southern Gothic tale in its verses by including the
    dialog of the narrator's family at dinnertime on the day that
    "Billie Joe McAllister jumped off the Tallahatchie Bridge."
    Throughout the song, the suicide and other tragedies are
    contrasted against the banality of everyday routine and polite
    conversation.</p>
      <p>The song begins with the narrator and her brother returning,
    after morning chores, to the family house for dinner. After
    cautioning them about tracking in dirt, "Mama" says that she
    "got some news this mornin' from Choctaw Ridge" that "Billie
    Joe McAllister jumped off the Tallahatchie Bridge," apparently
    to his death.</p>
      <p>At the dinner table, the narrator's father is unsurprised at
    the news and says, "Well, Billie Joe never had a lick o' sense;
    pass the biscuits, please" and mentions that there are "five
    more acres in the lower forty I got to plow." Although her
    brother seems to be taken aback ("I saw him at the sawmill
    yesterday.... And now you tell me Billie Joe has jumped off the
    Tallahatchie Bridge"), he's not shocked enough to keep him from
    having a second piece of pie. Late in the song, Mama questions
    the narrator's complete loss of appetite ("Child, what's
    happened to your appetite? I been cookin' all mornin' and you
    haven't touched a single bite,") yet earlier in the song
    recalled a visit earlier that morning by Brother Taylor, the
    local preacher, who mentioned that he had seen Billie Joe and a
    girl who looked very much like the narrator herself and they
    were "throwin' somethin' off the Tallahatchie Bridge."</p>
      <p>In the song's final verse, a year has passed, during which
    the narrator's brother has married and moved away. Also, her
    father died from a viral infection, which has left her mother
    despondent. The narrator herself now visits Choctaw Ridge
    often, picking flowers there to drop from the Tallahatchie
    Bridge onto the murky waters flowing beneath.</p>
      <p>The bridge mentioned in this song collapsed in June
    1972.</p>
      <p>In an interview with Bob Harris broadcast by BBC Radio 2 in 
    <i>Bob Harris Country</i>on 16 April 2009, singer Rachel
    Harrington claimed that Bobbie Gentry originally wrote 11
    verses but deleted six because a record producer thought it was
    too long.</p>
      <p>"Ode to Billy Joe" was originally intended as the "B side"
    of Gentry's first single recording, a blues number called "
    <i>Mississippi Delta</i>," on Capitol Records. It was
    originally a seven minute recording with only Gentry's guitar
    backing the lyrics which told more of the story of what
    happened to Billie Joe at the Tallahatchie Bridge. After the
    original version was finished, the label executives realized
    that this song was the better option for a single release.
    Thus, they went back into the studio with the string orchestra
    for backing and cut the song length almost in half. Cutting the
    length and lyrics provided the song with a mystical allure
    which left more to the listener's imagination about what really
    happened to Billie Joe. It also made it more suitable for radio
    airplay.</p>
      <p>Gentry continually dismissed speculation that the song was
    autobiographical. At the height of the song's popularity,
    numerous rumors circulated that she had been questioned by
    Mississippi police.</p>
      <p>The song's popularity proved so enduring that in 1976, nine
    years after its release, Warner Bros. commissioned author
    Herman Raucher to adapt it into a novel and screenplay, 
    <i>Ode to Billy Joe</i>. The poster's tagline, which treats the
    film as being based on actual events and even gives a date of
    death for Billy (June 3, 1953), led many to believe that the
    song was based on actual events. In fact, when Raucher met
    Bobbie Gentry in preparation for writing the novel and
    screenplay, she confessed that she herself had no idea why
    Billie Joe killed himself. In Raucher's novel and screenplay,
    Billy Joe kills himself after a drunken homosexual experience,
    and the object thrown from the bridge is the narrator's
    ragdoll.</p>
      <p>Billy Joe's story is analyzed in Professor John Howard's
    history of gay Mississippi entitled 
    <i>Men Like That: A Queer Southern History</i>as an archetype
    of what Howard calls the "gay suicide myth".</p>
      <p>Bob Dylan's 1967 "Clothesline Saga," (on the album 
    <i>The Basement Tapes</i>) is a parody of the song. It mimics
    the conversational style of "Ode to Billie Joe" with lyrics
    concentrating on routine household chores. The shocking event
    buried in all the mundane details is the revelation that "The
    Vice-President's gone mad!". Dylan's song was originally titled
    'Answer to "Ode"'</p>
      <p>The Austin Lounge Lizards' "Shallow End of the Gene Pool",
    from their 1995 album 
    <i>Small Minds</i>, is melodically similar to "Ode to Billie
    Joe", and ends with the line "and that's why Billie Joe
    McAllister jumped off the Tallahatchie Bridge".</p>
      <p>The November 15, 2008 
    <i>Saturday Night Live</i>featured Kristen Wiig and guest host
    Paul Rudd (with guitar) in a skit as a duo covering the song's
    melody, but with lyrics regarding a delivery man attempting to
    deliver a package, reading off the tracking numbers, etc.</p>
      <p>In 1967 American/French singer-songwriter Joe Dassin had
    much success with a French translation of the song, that tells
    exactly the same story almost word for word, only with the
    characters reversed. The narrator is one of the sons of the
    household, and the character who committed suicide is a girl
    named Marie-Jeanne Guillaume.</p>
      <p>A quick overview of the translated names and places:</p>
      <p>Besides the change in character names and locations, there
    are also obvious changes to various environments like the food,
    the crops, etc. For example, instead of "Pickin'cotton", the
    narrator took care of the vineyards. The setting is a
    fictitious small town in south west France. The river Garonne
    however is real.</p>
      <p>In 1968, a Swedish translation by Olle Adolphson titled "Jon
    Andreas visa" was recorded by Siw Malmkvist. It is faithful to
    the story in "Ode to Billie Joe", but has changed the setting
    to rural Sweden.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
