<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monster_Mash 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monster_Mash</songId>
   <title>Monster Mash</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bobby_%22Boris%22_Pickett</artistId>
      <artistName>Bobby "Boris" Pickett and the Crypt-Kickers</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1962-10-20</week>
      <week>1962-10-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/6d/Monster_Mash_cover.jpg/200px-Monster_Mash_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bobby-Boris-Pickett-and-the-Crypt-Kickers+Monster-Mash.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Original Monster Mash</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 1962</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Novelty</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bobby Pickett</writer>
      <writer>Leonard L. Capizzi</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Monster Mash" is a 1962 novelty song and the best-known
    song by Bobby "Boris" Pickett. The song was released as a
    single on Gary S. Paxton's Garpax Records label in October 1962
    along with a full-length LP called 
    <i>The Original Monster Mash</i>, which contained several other
    monster-themed tunes. The "Monster Mash" single reached number
    one on the Hot 100 chart on October 20 of that year, just in
    time for Halloween. It has been a perennial holiday favorite
    ever since.</p>
      <p>Pickett was an aspiring actor who sang with a band called
    The Cordials at night while going to auditions during the day.
    One night, while performing with his band, Pickett did a
    monologue in imitation of horror movie actor Boris Karloff
    while performing The Diamonds', "Little Darlin'". The audience
    loved it and fellow band member Lenny Capizzi encouraged
    Pickett to do more with the Karloff imitation.</p>
      <p>Pickett and Capizzi composed "Monster Mash" and recorded it
    with Gary S. Paxton, Leon Russell, Johnny McCrae, Rickie Page,
    and Terry Berg, credited as "The Crypt-Kickers". The song was
    partially inspired by Paxton's earlier novelty hit "Alley Oop",
    as well as by the Mashed Potato dance craze of the era. A
    variation on the Mashed Potato was danced to "Monster Mash", in
    which the footwork was the same but monster gestures were made
    with the arms and hands. Mel Taylor, drummer for The Ventures
    claimed to play on this, and that fact is repeated many places,
    including Taylor's N.Y. Times obituary.</p>
      <p>The song is narrated by a mad scientist whose monster, late
    one evening, rises from a slab to perform a new dance. The
    dance becomes "the hit of the land" when the scientist throws a
    party for other monsters. The producers came up with several
    low-budget but effective sound effects for the recording. For
    example, the sound of a coffin opening was imitated by a rusty
    nail being pulled out of a board. The sound of a cauldron
    bubbling was actually water being bubbled through a straw, and
    the chains rattling were simply chains being dropped on a tile
    floor. Pickett also impersonated horror film actor Bela Lugosi
    as Dracula with the lyric "Whatever happened to my Transylvania
    Twist?"</p>
      <p>The song was re-released several times and appeared in the
    Billboard charts on three occasions after the original release
    — December 1962, August 1970 and May 1973. The BBC had banned
    the record from airplay in 1962 on the grounds that the song
    was "too morbid". It was eventually released in the United
    Kingdom in 1973, where it peaked at #3 in early October. It
    re-entered the British Charts again on November 2, 2008 at
    #60.</p>
      <p>"Monsters' Holiday", a Christmas-themed follow up, was
    recorded by Pickett and released in December 1962, peaking at
    #30 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>chart. The tune was penned by the renowned
    novelty song composer Paul Harrison. In 1985, with American
    culture experiencing a growing awareness of rap music, Pickett
    released "Monster Rap", which describes the mad scientist's
    frustration at being unable to teach the dancing monster from
    "Monster Mash" how to talk. The problem is solved when he
    teaches the monster to rap. A movie musical based on the song
    starring Pickett was released in 1995.</p>
      <p>"Monster Mash" became a pop music standard, and many cover
    versions have been recorded over the years. The Beach Boys
    covered the song just two years after its original release, on
    their 1964 album 
    <i>Beach Boys Concert</i>. That same year the Bonzo Dog Doo Dah
    Band covered it on 
    <i>Tadpoles</i>and in 1968 performed it on the British
    television series 
    <i>Do Not Adjust Your Set</i>. Boris Karloff was so taken with
    the song that he performed it himself on a 1965 episode of 
    <i>Shindig!</i>. In 1972 horror film actor and DJ Mike Raven
    performed a version of "Monster Mash" on the music show 
    <i>2 G's and the Pop People</i>. Actor Vincent Price recorded a
    version of it as well in 1977. A 1978 Halloween episode of 
    <i>Happy Days</i>featured Ron Howard performing a rendition of
    the song, using a Peter Lorre impression rather than Pickett's
    Karloff one. In 1980 the British ska band Bad Manners covered
    "Monster Mash" on their debut album 
    <i>Ska 'n' B</i>. Hardcore punk band Ill Repute covered it as
    well on their 1985 album 
    <i>Omelette</i>. In 1988, The Big O covered it for the Return
    of the Living Dead Part II Soundtrack.</p>
      <p>The 1996 album Test for Echo by the Canadian rock trio Rush
    includes an instrumental track, 
    <i>Limbo</i>, which contains several samples from "Monster
    Mash" including the line "Whatever happened to my Transylvania
    Twist?".</p>
      <p>In 1997, the horror punk group The Misfits released a music
    video of them covering "Monster Mash" live. They also released
    a studio version as a single in 1999, and recorded a separate
    version for their 2003 album 
    <i>Project 1950</i>(see below). A Kidz Bop cover version
    appeared on 
    <i>Kidz Bop Halloween</i>(2004). Mannheim Steamroller also
    covered the song for their 2006 album 
    <i>Halloween, Vol. 2: Creatures Collection</i>. The song has
    also been covered by Zombina and the Skeletones.</p>
      <p>In 2008, The Smashing Pumpkins released a live recording of
    the song from Halloween of that year through Live Smashing
    Pumpkins.</p>
      <p>Horror punk band the Misfits recorded a cover version of
    "Monster Mash" in 1997 as part of a promotion surrounding a DVD
    release of the 1969 stop motion film 
    <i>Mad Monster Party</i>. Their version was released as a
    single in 1999, and a new version was recorded for their 2003
    album 
    <i>Project 1950</i>.</p>
      <p>The Misfits recorded their version of "Monster Mash" in 1997
    in a recording studio in Newark, New Jersey. Bassist Jerry Only
    later stated that "The 'Monster Mash' was a no-brainer for the
    Misfits to cover as a timeless Halloween release. The song was
    always a childhood favorite of mine." The recording was the
    first time that Only had performed lead vocals for the band,
    while then-Misfits lead singer Michale Graves provided backing
    vocals. On October 18, 1997 a live performance of the song was
    recorded and broadcast from the studio of the New Jersey-based
    cable television music show "Power Play", the same studio in
    which the song was recorded.</p>
      <p>The Misfits' version of "Monster Mash" was used in a
    cross-promotion campaign arranged by Deluxo and John Cafiero,
    who had directed the Misfits' music videos for "American
    Psycho" and "Dig Up Her Bones", to create awareness of a home
    video release of the 1969 Rankin/Bass stop motion film 
    <i>Mad Monster Party</i>. Deluxo had recently acquired the
    rights to the film in hopes of restoring it, but could not find
    a quality print. They eventually found a quality 16 mm print
    and the Misfits hosted a special screening of the film at
    Anthology Film Archives in New York City, with the "American
    Psycho" music video as an opening featurette. Notable attendees
    at the screening included members of the Misfits, Cafiero,
    Marky Ramone, Jimmy Gestapo of Murphy's Law, and executives
    from both Geffen Records and Roadrunner Records. Deluxo
    restored 
    <i>Mad Monster Party</i>from the 16 mm print and
    re-released it on VHS in limited numbers. A music video for the
    Misfits' live recording of "Monster Mash" was created
    interspersing clips from the film with footage from their
    "Power Play" performance, and was intended to be included as a
    bonus feature on a forthcoming DVD release. However, due to
    complications over distribution rights, the DVD was not
    released and the VHS version was discontinued. A DVD version of
    the film was eventually released in 2003 by Anchor Bay
    Entertainment, restored from a different 35 mm print.</p>
      <p>As part of the promotional campaign, an image of Boris
    Karloff as he appears in 
    <i>Mad Monster Party</i>was used under license from his
    daughter Sarah Karloff in artwork for a 7" vinyl single of the
    Misfits' version of "Monster Mash". Percepto Records used the
    same image of Karloff for the cover of the film's soundtrack
    album which was released in September 1998. The Misfits single
    was intended to be released the following month, but was
    delayed due to lack of time to properly mix the studio
    recording. Instead the artwork was used in connection with a
    free MP3 download of the band's live recording of "Monster
    Mash", available through their website as a "virtual single".
    The image was used again as cover artwork when the finished
    single was released physically in October 1999 as the first
    release of the band's new label Misfits Records.</p>
      <p>The Misfits' studio recording of "Monster Mash" was included
    on their 2001 compilation album 
    <i>Cuts from the Crypt</i>. At the insistence of the band's
    label Roadrunner Records, the live recording was omitted from
    the album and only the studio version was used. The Misfits
    recorded a new version of the song, featuring Cafiero on
    backing vocals, for their 2003 album 
    <i>Project 1950</i>. By this time the band had a new lineup
    consisting of Jerry Only (bass guitar and lead vocals), Dez
    Cadena (guitar and backing vocals), and Marky Ramone (drums).
    Only called this version of the song "probably the best version
    we've ever done. I'm really happy with it. We've recorded it
    several times in the past and this is the hardest hitting
    version of them all." Ramone commented: 
    <span style="padding-right:.2em;">"</span>'Monster Mash' always
    reminded me of Boris Karloff. Our version's a lot faster than
    the original, which was a slower 4/4 beat. I always liked the
    way the drums seemed to come in out of nowhere after Igor
    walked across the room." Cadena, meanwhile, remarked that "If I
    didn't know any better ['Monster Mash'] could have been written
    for the Misfits."</p>
      <p>Two separate pressings of the Misfits single were released,
    both issued on 7" vinyl in 1999. The first pressing had the
    studio version on both sides and consisted of 1,000 copies: 800
    on green vinyl, 100 on red, and 100 on gold. It was sold by the
    band while on tour and also by mail order through their "Fiend
    Club" fan club and official website. 1,000 promotional CD
    copies of the studio version were also pressed and used for
    limited solicitation to radio stations. A second pressing of
    the vinyl single had the studio version on side A and the live
    version on side B and consisted of 1,000 copies on
    glow-in-the-dark vinyl, available exclusively by mail order
    through the band's website. The single sold out and is no
    longer in print.</p>
      <p>All songs written and composed by Bobby Pickett, Leonard L.
    Capizzi. </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
