<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Prerogative 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Prerogative</songId>
   <title>My Prerogative</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bobby_Brown</artistId>
      <artistName>Bobby Brown</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1989-01-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a5/Bobby-brown-my-prerogative.jpg/200px-Bobby-brown-my-prerogative.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bobby-Brown+My-Prerogative.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Don't Be Cruel</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 11, 1988</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1988</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>New Jack Swing</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:51</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bobby Brown</writer>
      <writer>Gene Griffin</writer>
      <writer>Teddy Riley</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bobby Brown</producer>
      <producer>Gene Griffin</producer>
      <producer>Teddy Riley</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"My Prerogative" is a song by American recording artist
    Bobby Brown from his second solo studio album, 
    <i>Don't Be Cruel</i>. It was released on October 11, 1998 as
    the second single from the album. After recording sessions for
    the album were completed, Brown and producer Gene Griffin
    travelled to New York City, since he felt something was
    "missing" from the record. "My Prerogative" was written by
    Brown as a response to the criticism he received for his
    departure from New Edition. He explained the song was about
    making decisions in your life and not caring about other
    people's judgement. "My Prerogative" is often considered a new
    jack swing anthem, and contains many elements from Teddy Riley
    productions.</p>
      <p>The song was positively received by critics and was
    nominated for a Grammy Award in the category of Best R&amp;B
    Urban Contemporary Single. It was also commercially successful,
    reaching number one in 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Hot 100 and Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs
    charts. "My Prerogative" also reached top ten positions in many
    countries, such as Ireland, New Zealand, the Netherlands and
    the United Kingdom. The music video for the song features Brown
    performing the song on stage with his band and dancers. The
    song is also performed at most of his concerts, usually as the
    last song of the set list. On the February 4, 1989 performance
    at Madison Square Garden, he was joined on stage by many
    popular rap artists and producers of the time.</p>
      <p>"My Prerogative" has been covered and sampled by a number of
    artists from different genres, most notably by Britney Spears.
    She released her cover in her similarly titled 2004 greatest
    hits compilation. The cover was produced by Bloodshy &amp;
    Avant and was noted for aptly referring to Spears's
    relationship with the media at the time. It received mostly
    unfavorable reviews from critics, with one reviewer calling it
    "unnecessary". Although the song only appeared in component
    charts in the United States, Spears's cover surpassed Brown's
    version worldwide, peaking at the top of the charts in Finland,
    Ireland, Italy and Norway and reaching the top ten in another
    fourteen countries. The music video, directed by Jake Nava,
    portrays Spears arriving at a Hollywood Hills manor in which a
    party is taking place. In the end, it is revealed that the
    party is actually Spears's wedding.</p>
      <p>Brown had already completed recording sessions for 
    <i>Don't Be Cruel</i>in Los Angeles, California, but felt
    something was missing in the record. He said, "I felt my album
    was lacking a strong, aggressive song and I thought, 'Where
    better to New York to come up with it'". He travelled to the
    city with producer Gene Griffin. "My Prerogative" was written
    and co-produced by Brown, Griffin and Teddy Riley. It was
    recorded at Axis Studios and mixed at Soundworks, in New York.
    The track was mastered at Future Disc Systems in Hollywood,
    California. During an interview with 
    <i>The Hour</i>on March 17, 1989, Brown explained the theme
    behind the song, saying, "A lot of things had been said about
    Bobby Brown, why was he doing this [a solo career]. It's my way
    of expressing to people it's your prerogative to do as you
    want, but make sure what you do is the right thing".</p>
      <p>"My Prerogative" is considered a new jack swing anthem, that
    merges hip hop beats with elements of synthpop and soul. It
    features a triplet swing in the sixteenth note, as included in
    many of Riley's productions. Jake Brown said in his book 
    <i>Your body's calling me: music, love, sex &amp;
    money</i>(2003), that like most new jack swing songs from the
    late 1980's, it was composed by "punchy, street-savvy beats,
    with sexually energetic melodies and poppy choruses". The
    bassline of the track was described by Cam'Ron Davis of 
    <i>CMJ New Music Monthly</i>as "truly sinister". According to
    the sheet music published at Musicnotes.com by EMI Music
    Publishing, the song is composed in the key of A minor, with a
    tempo of 120 beats per minute. Brown's vocal range spans from
    the high-note of C to A.</p>
      <p>Barry Michael Cooper of 
    <i>Spin</i>said "My Prerogative" "sounds like gin-drenched,
    Roaring Twenties swing". Arion Berger of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>called it "a grumpy and undeniably adult
    dance hit". "My Prerogative" was nominated for at the 30th
    Grammy Awards in the category of Best R&amp;B Urban
    Contemporary Single by a Male, but lost to Michael Jackson's
    "Man in the Mirror". The following year, 
    <i>Spin</i>listed the song at number seventy-two on the "100
    Greatest Singles of All Time" list. It ranked at number
    ninety-eight on VH1's "100 Greatest Songs of the 80's". The
    track is often referred to as Brown's signature song.</p>
      <p>"My Prerogative" debuted on the U.S. 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 during the week of October 29, 1988 at
    number sixty-one. The following week, it climbed sixteen
    positions to number forty-five. On January 14, 1989, it peaked
    at the top position of the chart. The song also peaked at
    number one in Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs and at number seven in
    Hot Dance Club Songs. It was certified gold by the Recording
    Industry Association of America (RIAA) for sales over 500,000
    copies. In Canada, the song debuted on the 
    <i>RPM</i>Singles Chart at position ninety-eight, on the issue
    dated December 23, 1989. In the United Kingdom, "My
    Prerogative" debuted at number eighty-seven on December 10,
    1998. On February 18, 1989, the song peaked at number six and
    stayed in the position for two weeks. Across Europe, the song
    reached the top ten in Ireland and the Netherlands, and the top
    twenty in Germany and Sweden. In Australia and New Zealand, the
    track peaked at number forty and number three,
    respectively.</p>
      <p>The music video for "My Prerogative" was directed by Alek
    Keshishian. It begins with Brown driving a car while his
    musicians start to perform the song on a stage. Shortly after,
    he descends to the stage in an elevator, wearing a black
    jumpsuit and a headset. He dances flanked by two women, one of
    them playing a keytar. J. D. Considine of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>wrote in the review of 
    <i>Bobby</i>(1992), "As anyone who saw him swagger through the
    videos for 'My Prerogative' and 'Every Little Step' can attest,
    Brown had a phenomenal ability to convey a sense of street
    toughness that was utterly without malice or menace, making him
    credible and likable". The music video was nominated at the
    1989 MTV Video Music Awards for Best Stage Performance in a
    Video, but lost to the music video of Living Colour's "Cult of
    Personality". It also charted at number nine on 
    <i>RPM</i>video chart on July 21, 1990.</p>
      <p>"My Prerogative" was performed during his tour in promotion
    for 
    <i>Don't Be Cruel</i>as the last song of the night. Brown
    usually performed it wearing a black outfit, flanked with two
    male dancers wearing white clothes. On the February 4, 1989
    show at Madison Square Garden in New York City, wore a red
    boxing robe with the words "King of the Stage" printed in the
    back. During the performance, Joseph Simmons of Run-DMC, LL
    Cool J and Heavy D joined him onstage and freestyle rapped.
    Eric B., KRS-One, L. A. Reid, Babyface and Teddy Riley also
    joined him onstage, with the latter performing a keyboard solo.
    Peter Watrous of 
    <i>The New York Times</i>commented that, "The communal scene on
    stage mirrored the feeling in the audience; everybody seemed
    aware that this was a generation that had rewritten the rules
    of pop entertainment, and was justifiably proud of its
    achievement". Brown also performed the song at the 1997 Home
    Again Tour with New Edition, during the second portion of the
    show in which he performed hits from his solo career. On
    November 10, 2005, he performed the song for the first time in
    eight years at a concert at House of Blues in Atlantic City. He
    wore a white suit and matching hat, and sang it as the last
    song of the evening. On January 17, 2006, he performed it at a
    New Edition show in Atlantic City's Trump Taj Mahal. During the
    performance, he tore open his orange dress shirt, singing
    bare-chested with a tie and a fur coat on. Brown also performed
    the song during his 2007 July shows in Australia.</p>
      <p>"My Prerogative" was sampled and covered by many artists
    from different genres. It was sampled in Nice &amp; Smooth's
    "O-o-h Child" (1989), Public Enemy's "Pollywanacraka" (1990),
    Nice &amp; Smooth's "Hip Hop Junkies" (1991) and LL Cool J's
    "Doin It" (1995). J.D. Considine of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>noted that the hook of Brown's 1992 single
    "Humpin' Around" from 
    <i>Bobby</i>, "bears a more than passing resemblance to the
    synth part from 'My Prerogative'". According to 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>, American R&amp;B group U.N.V.
    sampled the melody for their 1993 single "Something's Goin'
    On". Jamaican reggae singer Beenie Man covered "My Prerogative"
    for his 1998 studio album 
    <i>Many Moods of Moses</i>. American singer Rod Michael covered
    the song for his 2004 studio album, 
    <i>The Next Episode</i>. English rock band Selfish Cunt also
    covered the song for their 2004 studio album 
    <i>No Wicked Heart Shall Prosper</i>, changing the name to
    "Bobby". On July 2007, American basketball player LeBron James
    covered "My Prerogative" at the 15th ESPY Awards at the Kodak
    Theatre in Hollywood, California, wearing a wig and Hammer
    pants. 
    <i>Vibe</i>named the performance one of the "worst of the worst
    live performances of the year". Anoop Desai, contestant of the
    eight season of 
    <i>American Idol</i>, covered the song for his wildcard round
    performance. It earned him the last spot in the finals, marking
    the first time the show ever had thirteen contestants. Desai
    also performed the song during the American Idols LIVE! Tour
    2009. Graeme McRanor of 
    <i>The Vancouver Sun</i>said in the concert review that "My
    Prerogative" "really shouldn't be covered by any artist, ever
    again". On July 31, 2009, American hip hop group The Pharcyde
    covered the song at the All Points West Music &amp; Arts
    Festival in Jersey City. The song was also featured on the
    films 
    <i>Love &amp; Basketball</i>(2000), 
    <i>Wild Hogs</i>(2007) and 
    <i>Sex Drive</i>(2008).</p>
      <p>In 2004, Spears recorded a cover of "My Prerogative" with
    Swedish production team Bloodshy &amp; Avant, who produced her
    single "Toxic" from her fourth studio album, 
    <i>In the Zone</i>(2003). Bloodshy &amp; Avant recorded the
    song at Murlyn Studios in Stockholm, Sweden. Spears recorded
    the vocals at Teldex Studios in Berlin, Germany. On August 13,
    2004, Spears's label Jive Records announced through a press
    release that she had covered the song and was planning to
    release it on her first greatest hits compilation, titled 
    <i>Greatest Hits: My Prerogative</i>. The song was set to
    premiere on radio stations on September 14, 2004, however, it
    leaked in the Real Tapemasters Inc.'s mixtape 
    <i>The Future of R&amp;B</i>on September 10, 2004. Spears's
    cover of "My Prerogative" is musically different from its
    original version, with the bass and new jack swing sound
    replaced with synthesizers and elements typical of Bloodshy
    &amp; Avant productions. It was noted by Christy Lemire of
    msnbc.com that the cover also contains elements of Bollywood
    music. At the beginning of the song, Spears says in a breathy
    voice the lines "People can take everything away from you / But
    they can never take away your truth / But the question is, can
    you handle mine?". The rest of the lyrics do not deviate much
    from the original version, instead they are changed to fit a
    woman's perspective. Jennifer Vineyard of MTV commented the
    cover could be interpreted as a statement on Spears's life and
    the media reaction to some of her decisions at the time,
    including her engagement to American dancer Kevin
    Federline.</p>
      <p>Stephen Thomas Erlewine of Allmusic called the cover "a
    useless remake, which seems to exist solely for its video".
    Spence D. of IGN said that the lyrics fit perfectly with
    Spears's relationship with the media at the time. He also
    added, "As for her interpretation, it's an interesting
    chameleonic diversion that comes off like a mash-up between
    vintage Prince-styled production, Cameo swagger, and Madonna
    sultriness, but never seems to capture the gloss and glory of
    any of the aforementioned influences". Christy Lemire of
    msnbc.com called it "utterly unnecessary". Louis Pattison of
    the 
    <i>New Musical Express</i>commented that "judging by the
    fuck-you sentiments" of the cover, Spears liked to play the
    role of "[the] pop brat careering off the rails". Sarah Hepola
    of Salon.com wrote in an article about contemporary teen idols
    that the cover "became an anthem for teen-idol rebellion".
    American director Quentin Tarantino included the song in a
    playlist that inspired him during production of his 2009 film 
    <i>Inglourious Basterds</i>.</p>
      <p>In the United States, "My Prerogative" charted in 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Top 40 Tracks and Top 40 Mainstream at
    number twenty-two and thirty-four, respectively. On November
    15, 2004, the song debuted at the Australian Singles Chart at
    number seven. The same week, it debuted at number seventeen in
    New Zealand. On November 7, 2004, the song debuted at number
    three in the United Kingdom, during a competitive week of new
    releases, only surpassed by Eminem's "Just Lose It" and
    Destiny's Child's "Lose My Breath". The song also reached
    success throughout Europe, peaking at number one in Finland,
    Ireland, Italy and Norway, number two in Spain and number three
    in Belgium (Flanders and Wallonia), Denmark and Germany. It
    also reached top ten positions in Austria, Czech Republic,
    Sweden, Switzerland and the Netherlands.</p>
      <p>The music video for "My Prerogative" was filmed in August
    2004 at The Paramour Mansion in Silver Lake, Los Angeles,
    California and was directed by Jake Nava. According to Spears's
    mother Lynne, the video was "about capturing gorgeous close-ups
    and very subtle movement" since Spears could not do any
    choreography due to her knee injury at the "Outrageous" music
    video shoot. She also described the video as "[having] an
    element of old Hollywood glamour and mystery". The music video
    begins with Spears driving a Porsche 928 at high speed in the
    Hollywood Hills. She crashes through a fence and lands into a
    pool inside a manor where a party is taking place. She emerges
    from the water and crawls in top of the car to sing the first
    verse. Spears's brother Bryan makes a cameo in these scenes.
    After she leaves the pool, she enters the manor and passes
    couples making out around her. She appears in a stainless steel
    kitchen, where a maid cuts the straps of her black wet dress.
    In the next scene, she walks into a study in which her husband
    at the time, Kevin Federline, is smoking and watching a
    black-and-white video of Spears on a projection screen.
    According to Jennifer Vineyard from MTV, the clip had the style
    of pornographic films from the 1940's and 1950's. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>in their article "Britney Spears: The
    Complete Video Guide", compared it to Madonna's performances of
    her 1984 single "Like a Virgin". She then entered a dressing
    room with mirrors, wearing lingerie, high heels, stockings and
    a short fur jacket. She proceeds to a bedroom, in which a black
    dress is laid out on the comforter. She puts on the new dress
    and the camera cuts to the party outside where people gathered
    waiting. During the song's bridge, it is revealed that the
    party is actually Spears's wedding, as she starts walking
    towards the aisle and Federline waits next to a priest. The
    video ends with a shot of the black-and-white video and Spears
    looking into the camera. The footage was released as an
    alternate version of the music video in the 2004 DVD 
    <i>Greatest Hits: My Prerogative</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
