<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Give_Love_a_Bad_Name_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Give_Love_a_Bad_Name_(song)</songId>
   <title>You Give Love a Bad Name</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bon_Jovi</artistId>
      <artistName>Bon Jovi</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-11-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/1a/Bon_Jovi_You_Give_Love_A_Bad_Name.jpg/200px-Bon_Jovi_You_Give_Love_A_Bad_Name.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bon-Jovi+You-Give-Love-a-Bad-Name.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Slippery When Wet</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 1986</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD Single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1986</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Glam Metal</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:42</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Mercury</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jon Bon Jovi</writer>
      <writer>Richie Sambora and Desmond Child</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bruce Fairbairn</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Blake Lewis (EP)</i>
      </p>
      <p>"You Give Love a Bad Name" is a song written by Jon Bon
    Jovi, Desmond Child, Jack Ponti, and Richie Sambora about a
    nameless woman who has jilted her lover. Although originally
    written for the band Loverboy, the song was recorded by Bon
    Jovi. The track was released as the first single from the hard
    rock album 
    <i>Slippery When Wet</i>and hit number one on the Hot 100 on
    November 29, 1986, Bon Jovi's first number one hit. The song
    reentered the charts at #29 after Blake Lewis performed it on
    American Idol. In 2009 it was named the 20th greatest hard rock
    song of all time by VH1.</p>
      <p>The song was written with several catchy repeated lines and
    associated hooks to appeal to mainstream audiences including
    the chorus as well as several bridges.</p>
      <p>The album version of the song ends with the title being
    repeated until it fades.</p>
      <p>The music video for the song used all-color concert footage
    (the only all-color video song from 
    <i>Slippery When Wet</i>) and Soteria photogenic shots
    primarily of Jon Bon Jovi as well as other band members in
    concert. This video was filmed at the Olympic auditorium in Los
    Angeles, CA.</p>
      <p>In 1989 Bananarama did a live version of this song during
    their World Tour.</p>
      <p>The song was also covered by the metalcore band Atreyu and
    is available on the Japanese Version of their 2004 album 
    <i>The Curse</i>. It was covered on the Kerrang! CD, High
    Voltage. It is frequently played during their shows even though
    it was voted one of the years biggest rock atrocities in Total
    Guitar.</p>
      <p>In 2005, Polish singer Mandaryna released a version of "You
    Give Love a Bad Name" as the second single from her number one
    album 
    <i>mandaryna.com2me</i>. The song reached #1 on the Polish
    Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>Jonathan Fin covered this song, but, talking about how Barry
    Bonds gave baseball a bad name. The line, "shot through the
    heart and you're to blame, you give love a bad name,' was
    changed to, "Shot in the ass before the game, you give baseball
    a bad name."</p>
      <p>Some critics say that the song has the same chorus structure
    as "If You Were A Woman And I Was A Man" by Bonnie Tyler. The
    Tyler song was also cowritten by Desmond Child. There is also a
    remix called "Shock From The Heart" with a new rapper named
    Famouz. Desmond Child has stated that the song is effectively a
    reuse of the musical structure of the earlier song.</p>
      <p>Demi Lovato performed a version of the song during a concert
    at the Wiltern Theatre in December 2008.</p>
      <p>Ranked Number 20 in VH1's "
    <i>100 Greatest Hard Rock Songs</i>".</p>
      <p>In the popular game Warcraft 3, the Night Elf Archer unit
    will quote after multiple mouse clicks, "Shot through the
    heart, and I'm to blame."</p>
      <p>The song was used in the commercial of a 1995 Kia Pregio.
    (released in South Korea). [1]</p>
      <p>The song was made playable in the music video game, 
    <i>GuitarFreaks 6th Mix</i>/
    <i>Drummania 5th Mix</i>, as well as 
    <i>Lego Rock Band</i>, 
    <i>Guitar Hero On Tour: Decades</i>, and 
    <i>Guitar Hero 5</i>.</p>
      <p>This song was played on a recorder by Rainn Wilson's
    character Dwight Schrute on the NBC TV Show "The Office" in
    Episode 4 of Season 4 (Money).</p>
      <p>In the TV sitcom How I Met Your Mother, the song features
    prominently (and repeatedly) on Barney's "Get Psyched" mix in
    the episode "The Limo."</p>
      <p>On Australian music TV channel MAX, it was name #131 on
    their top 1000 80's vs. 90's countdown over Easter weekend
    2009.</p>
      <p>In 
    <i>Thunderbolts</i>#131, Black Widow shot Deadpool in the
    chest. After examining the hole, Deadpool dropped to his knees
    and sang the chorus.</p>
      <p>On the 9th Season of Dancing with the stars Donny Osmond,
    Joanna Krupa, Kelly Osbourne and there partners danced to this
    song for their Team Tango.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
