<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Livin%27_on_a_Prayer 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Livin%27_on_a_Prayer</songId>
   <title>Livin' on a Prayer</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bon_Jovi</artistId>
      <artistName>Bon Jovi</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-02-14</week>
      <week>1987-02-21</week>
      <week>1987-02-28</week>
      <week>1987-03-07</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e4/Bon-Jovi-Livin-On-A-Prayer-505.jpeg/200px-Bon-Jovi-Livin-On-A-Prayer-505.jpeg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bon-Jovi+Livin-on-a-Prayer.jpeg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Slippery When Wet</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1986</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>CD Single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1986</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Glam Metal</genre>
      <genre>Hard Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:12</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Mercury Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jon Bon Jovi</writer>
      <writer>Richie Sambora and Desmond Child</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bruce Fairbairn</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Livin' on a Prayer" is Bon Jovi's second single from their 
    <i>Slippery When Wet</i>album. Written by Jon Bon Jovi and
    Richie Sambora with Desmond Child, the single, released in late
    1986, was well-received at both rock and pop radio and its
    music video was given heavy rotation at MTV, giving the band
    their first #1 on the Hot Mainstream Rock Tracks chart. The
    single also became Bon Jovi's second consecutive #1 Hot 100 pop
    hit and has become the band's signature song, topping fan-voted
    lists and re-charting around the world decades after its
    release.</p>
      <p>Jon Bon Jovi did not like the original recording of this
    song, which can be found as a hidden track on 
    <i>100,000,000 Bon Jovi Fans Can't Be Wrong</i>. Richie Sambora
    convinced him the song was good, and they reworked it with a
    new bass line, different drum fills and the use of a talk box
    to include it on their 
    <i>Slippery When Wet</i>album. The songs verse melody closely
    resembles the verse melody of the song "Venus" by the band
    Shocking Blue. It spent two weeks at number one on the
    Mainstream Rock Tracks, from January 31–February 14, 1987, and
    four weeks at number one on the Billboard Hot 100, from
    February 14–March 7. It also hit number four on the UK singles
    chart.</p>
      <p>After the attacks of September 11th, 2001—in which New
    Jersey was the second-hardest hit state after New York,
    suffering hundreds of casualties among both WTC workers and
    first responders—the band performed an acoustic version of this
    song for 
    <i>The Concert for New York City</i>. Bon Jovi performed a
    similar version as part of the special 
    <i>America: A Tribute to Heroes</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2006, online voters rated "Livin' on a Prayer" #1 on
    VH1's "list of The 100 Greatest Songs of the '80s". More
    recently, in New Zealand, "Livin' on a Prayer" was #1 on the C4
    music channel show's "U Choose 40", on the 80's Icons list. It
    was also #1 on the "Sing-a-long Classics List". After Bon Jovi
    performed in New Zealand on January 28 2008 while on their Lost
    Highway Tour, the song re-entered the official New Zealand
    RIANZ singles chart at number 24, over twenty years after the
    initial release.</p>
      <p>Australian music TV channel MAX placed this song at #18 on
    their 2008 countdown "Rock Songs: Top 100". In 2009, the song
    returned to the charts in the UK, notably hitting the
    number-one spot on the UK Rock Chart.</p>
      <p>In 2010 the song was chosen in an online vote on the
    Grammy.com website over the group's more recent hits "Always"
    and "It's My Life" to be played live by the band on the 52nd
    Grammy Awards telecast.</p>
      <p>In the Billboard Hot 100 Anniversary 50, "Livin' on a
    Prayer" was named as 46 in the All time rock songs.</p>
      <p>The song is about a fictional working class couple, Tommy
    and Gina, who struggle to make ends meet and maintain their
    relationship. Tommy "used to work on the docks" because
    "union's been on strike, he's down on his luck". Gina works at
    a diner, "workin' for her man".</p>
      <p>While some have loosely interpreted the lyrics to be
    anti-labor, inferring that the striking labor union are the
    catalyst for the troubled chain of events for Tommy and Gina,
    others have pointed out that the song does not clarify the
    circumstances behind the strike, and the lone, vague reference
    does not equate with an anti-union political message. In fact,
    Jon Bon Jovi explained that he "wrote that song during the
    Reagan era and the trickle-down economics are really
    inspirational to writing songs".</p>
      <p>The video for the song features shots of the band
    rehearsing, then playing in front of a crowd. The first half of
    the video, featuring the rehearsal footage, is black and white,
    and the second half of the video, performing to the arena
    audience, is in color.</p>
      <p>In the beginning of the video, Jon Bon Jovi has a harness
    attached, and later in the music video he soars over the crowd
    via overhead wires.</p>
      <p>The music video was recorded at the Olympic Auditorium in
    Los Angeles, California and was directed by Wayne Isham.</p>
      <p>Bon Jovi made several references to lyrics in "Livin' on a
    Prayer" in subsequent songs.</p>
      <p>Some other bands referenced Tommy and Gina in their songs,
    too.</p>
      <p>Bon Jovi have themselves reworked the song several times,
    including an acoustic live version that served as a precursor
    to the 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>series and a re-recorded version of the
    song, "Prayer '94", which appeared on U.S. versions of their 
    <i>Cross Road</i>hits collection. But the song has had a life
    of its own beyond the band, particularly in several dance music
    incarnations. Stellar Kart covered the song for their first
    album, 
    <i>All Gas. No Brake.</i>The Audition recorded a version for
    Kerrang!'s CD Higher Voltage (June 7). Disco singer Hazell
    Dean, popular in the UK in the '80s, recorded Hi-NRG/Trance
    remixes of the song, released on Academy Street Records in
    1999. Jordan James recorded his own version, and released a
    slew of remixes of the song on the Robbins Entertainment label
    which charted on the U.S. Dance charts in 2004. Other dance
    versions of the song have been recorded by Topmodelz, Groove
    Coverage, and Heavydance.</p>
      <p>Christian rock band Stellar Kart covered the song on their
    2005 album 
    <i>All Gas. No Brake.</i>The same year, during the first
    American leg of Tori Amos' 
    <i>Original Sinsuality</i>tour she performed "Livin' on a
    Prayer" in a cover section called "Tori's Piano Bar".</p>
      <p>The song has been a popular karaoke and wedding band song
    and has been attempted by numerous contestants in the various
    worldwide 
    <i>Pop Idol</i>competitions and similar talent contest shows.
    The song was sung by 
    <i>American Idol</i>season 6 winner Jordin Sparks on May 1,
    2007 as her pick for Bon Jovi week on the show. 
    <i>American Idol</i>season 7 winner David Cook auditioned with
    the song. The song was sung also on 
    <i>Australian Idol</i>, Season One, by runner-up Shannon Noll.
    It was considered one of his better performances. 2008 
    <i>Swedish Pop Idol</i>Kevin Borg performed a rousing rendition
    of "Living on a Prayer", which many believed was the cause of
    his victory. In 2009, all-vocal rock group Face performed this
    song on NBC's a cappella competition, 
    <i>The Sing-Off</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2008, Swedish rap group Looptroop released a cover on
    their album 
    <i>Good Things</i>. They also made a remix called "Praying On A
    Liver". Alvin and the Chipmunks released a cover of the song on
    their 2008 album 
    <i>Alvin and the Chipmunks: Undeniable</i>. Kidz Bop covered
    this song on the album 
    <i>Kidz Bop 80s Gold</i>. There's even an oompah version in 3/4
    time by UK oompah band Oompah Brass featured on their 2008
    album 
    <i>Oompocalypse Now</i>.</p>
      <p>Mash-up band Rock Sugar covered the song, mixed with Guns N'
    Roses' "Sweet Child o' Mine" and Loverboy's "Working for the
    Weekend", on their album 
    <i>Reimagination</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was also sung by Steve Coogan as Alan Partridge, as
    part of his 2008 stand-up comedy tour 
    <i>Alan Partridge and Other Less Successful Characters</i>.</p>
      <p>New Jersey is the only state in the union without an
    official state anthem, but Bon Jovi's "Livin' on a Prayer" is
    cited by many, after Bruce Springsteen's 
    <i>Born To Run</i>, as a sort of unofficial anthem. "Livin' on
    a Prayer" was one of the theme songs for the 2004 presidential
    campaign of Democrat John Kerry.</p>
      <p>That same year, "Livin' on a Prayer" was the "theme song"
    for the 2004 Boston Red Sox after their historic comeback in
    the American League Championship Series against the New York
    Yankees. During halftime at Philadelphia Soul Arena Football
    games, the song is played, paying tribute to their owner Jon
    Bon Jovi. For a commercial about the Arena Football League that
    Bon Jovi did with John Elway, he asks the quarterback (who is
    suiting up to go into the fictional game) "What? Are you living
    in the past?" To which Elway says, "Better than living on a
    prayer." The song is often played during Chicago White Sox and
    Baltimore Orioles home games, during an offensive rally when
    the home team needs a big clutch hit. The Washington Nationals
    use this song in-between innings karoake contest. The Chicago
    Cubs use this song during home games when the opposing team
    makes a pitching change in the middle of an inning.</p>
      <p>The song has been performed by many college marching bands
    including San Diego State University, Michigan State
    University, The University of Tennessee, Auburn University,
    Purdue University, Notre Dame, Northern Illinois University,
    Pennsylvania State University, Eastern Michigan University,
    Niagara University, Northwestern University, University of
    Michigan, Columbia University, and Georgia Tech and it is
    frequently a crowd favorite. The song become a theme for the
    George Mason University Patriots during their run to the 
    <i>Final Four</i>in 2006. The Rutgers University Scarlet
    Knights football team plays "Livin' on a Prayer" in the 4th
    quarter of all home games. The song is performed by the Roamin'
    Bones of the Florida State University Marching Band, the
    Marching Chiefs. The Louisiana State University marching band,
    The Golden Band From Tigerland, plays the song during the
    fourth quarter of home football games with the student section
    continuing the song when the band finishes. "Livin' on a
    Prayer" is the unofficial theme song of the Stimson Superfans,
    a group of Fanatic Washington State Volleyball fans, and the
    song is sung by the group before every WSU Volleyball game.</p>
      <p>Bon Jovi's "Livin' on a Prayer" was featured in the film 
    <i>Charlie's Angels: Full Throttle</i>, and appears on its
    soundtrack album. The song was also featured on the trailer and
    a commercial for the 2009 film Paul Blart: Mall Cop.</p>
      <p>A brief a cappella set of "Livin' on a Prayer" was included
    as part of the November 7, 2006, episode of the TV show 
    <i>Gilmore Girls</i>. In 2009 the song was featured on an
    episode of the hit UK series 
    <i>Skins</i>.</p>
      <p>The song is in the 2008 version of the Cadbury's "Trucks"
    advert. The song's chorus was used in an old Filipino Zesto
    orange juice commercial in the 1990s. The lyrics were reworked
    as "Cool and refreshing, that's the way to go-o. Oh! Way to go,
    Zesto!"</p>
      <p>It is a playable track for the music video games Rock Band
    Unplugged, 
    <i>Rock Band 2</i>, and for 
    <i>Guitar Hero World Tour</i>. On the latter of the two, the
    ending is changed. Instead of it fading out on the ending
    chorus, it finishes the chorus and then has an "outro" riff.
    The song is also featured in the musical video game 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Presents: American Idol Encore 2</i>.</p>
      <p>On May 8, 2009, the song was featured prominently in the
    final scene of "Everybody Hates G.E.D.", the final episode of
    the UPN/CW sitcom 
    <i>Everybody Hates Chris</i>. The scene was a tribute to "Made
    in America", the final episode of the HBO drama 
    <i>The Sopranos</i>, which featured Journey's "Don't Stop
    Believing" in its final scene.</p>
      <p>In 2010, the song was used the 
    <i>Cold Case</i>episode "One Fall".</p>
      <p>An altered version of this song, entitled "Livin' on a
    Grant", is the anthem of the New ERA cohort of students within
    University College Dublin. The chorus is amended to reflect New
    ERA students' defiance of the status quo within Irish
    university society.</p>
      <p>In a Alvin and the Chipmunks Cd sponsoring the 2007 film,
    Livin on a prayer was one of the featured songs.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
