<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bad_Medicine_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bad_Medicine_(song)</songId>
   <title>Bad Medicine</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bon_Jovi</artistId>
      <artistName>Bon Jovi</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1988-11-19</week>
      <week>1988-11-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/5a/Badusa.jpeg/200px-Badusa.jpeg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bon-Jovi+Bad-Medicine.jpeg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>New Jersey</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1988</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD Single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1988</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Glam Metal</genre>
      <genre>Hard Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:16</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Mercury Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jon Bon Jovi</writer>
      <writer>Richie Sambora</writer>
      <writer>Desmond Child</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bruce Fairbairn</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Bad Medicine" is a number-one single by American rock band
    Bon Jovi. It was written by Jon Bon Jovi, Richie Sambora, and
    Desmond Child. It was released in 1988 as the lead single from
    the band's massively successful album 
    <i>New Jersey</i>. The song is 5 minutes and 17 seconds
    long.</p>
      <p>The song climbed to #1 on the Billboard Hot 100, #3 on the
    Mainstream Rock Tracks chart, #17 in the UK and #15 in
    Australia.</p>
      <p>The song compares a love affair to a drug addiction ("now
    this boy's addicted cause your kiss is the drug", "your love is
    like bad medicine, bad medicine is what I need") and also has
    many tongue-in-cheek medical analogies ("Let's play doctor,
    baby cure my disease"; "There ain't no paramedic gonna save
    this heart attack"; "I need a respirator cause I'm runnin' out
    of breath").</p>
      <p>The song is highlighted by a near constant keyboard playing
    by David Bryan that is well defined in the beginning of the
    song and at several interludes, as well as loud guitar playing
    by Richie Sambora, background singing in the bridge and chorus,
    and a loud fast-paced delivery of lyrics by Jon Bon Jovi. It is
    one of the more upbeat and hard rocking songs on 
    <i>New Jersey</i>.</p>
      <p>Towards the end of the song, Jon says he's got to go and
    he's running out of breath, but then says "I'm not done...one
    more time, with feelin'" and the band finishes out the song
    with another repeat of the chorus.</p>
      <p>There are two videos for the song, one with the band live in
    concert, and the more well-known live video in which a crowd of
    young people waiting in line to get into the Bon Jovi live
    video shoot is asked by Sam Kinison if they (the public) "can
    make a better Bon Jovi video than these guys can." The crowd
    gives a very enthusiastic response, and members of the crowd
    are given hand-held cameras and invited onstage to help shoot
    the video.</p>
      <p>The video was very groundbreaking at the time for using such
    a fan-inclusive approach to making a music video, and captured
    live shots not often captured by regular video crews.</p>
      <p>The video was in color, although the quality given by the
    hand-held video cameras was not as superb.,</p>
      <p>"Bad Medicine" continues to see considerable airplay on many
    rock radio stations and has always been a live staple at Bon
    Jovi concerts. In concert, an approximately 1-minute interlude
    of the classic "Shout" is incorporated into the middle of the
    song.</p>
      <p>The song was featured on the band's compilation album 
    <i>Cross Road</i>, the live album 
    <i>One Wild Night: Live 1985-2001</i>, the acoustic collection 
    <i>This Left Feels Right</i>, as well as several concert videos
    including 
    <i>Live From London</i>and 
    <i>The Crush Tour</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was covered by the post-punk band Allah &amp; The
    72 Virgins on their 2002 album 
    <i>Name Me With My Title</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
