<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tha_Crossroads 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tha_Crossroads</songId>
   <title>Tha Crossroads</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bone_Thugs-N-Harmony</artistId>
      <artistName>Bone Thugs-N-Harmony</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1996-05-18</week>
      <week>1996-05-25</week>
      <week>1996-06-01</week>
      <week>1996-06-08</week>
      <week>1996-06-15</week>
      <week>1996-06-22</week>
      <week>1996-06-29</week>
      <week>1996-07-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/98/Tha_Crossroads.jpg/200px-Tha_Crossroads.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bone-Thugs-N-Harmony+Tha-Crossroads.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>E 1999 Eternal</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 23, 1996</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1995</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Midwest Hip Hop</genre>
      <genre>Melodic Hip Hop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Ballad</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:46</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Ruthless</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bryon McCane II</writer>
      <writer>Anthony Henderson</writer>
      <writer>Steven Howse</writer>
      <writer>Charles Scruggs</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Crossroads" is a Grammy-award winning song performed by
    the hip hop group Bone Thugs-n-Harmony, dedicated to the late
    rap icon Eazy-E and released in 1995. It is one of the group's
    most popular songs to date, and their biggest selling.</p>
      <p>Originally named "Crossroad," it wasn't until the group and
    their producer, DJ U-Neek, decided to remake the song that the
    name was changed. The song "Crossroad" was originally dedicated
    to Bone's deceased friends, but after the death of Eazy-E they
    decided to remake it as "Tha Crossroads". The song is performed
    by four of the group's members, (Krayzie Bone, Layzie Bone,
    Bizzy Bone and Wish Bone). The remake contained the line "And
    I'm askin' the good Lord 'Why?' and sigh It's I, he told me we
    lived to die" from the original. Bone's lightning fast rhymes
    are delivered softer than is usual for the group, without
    profanities and creating a sad and heartfelt effect. With soft
    instrumentals revolving around a sample of The Isley Brothers'
    "Make Me Say It Again Girl (Pts. 1 and 2)," the song has a sad
    yet quick tone to it. After receiving high praise for their
    song the group decided to add it to their already launched
    album, 
    <i>E 1999 Eternal</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was a smash hit worldwide and reached the top of
    the charts in several countries, including the Billboard Hot
    100 and the UK Singles Chart. It has been certified 2X Platinum
    in the United States.</p>
      <p>The official remix, "Tha Crossroads (Tha Flesh Flip Remix)",
    features latest member Flesh-n-Bone and new &amp; old verses by
    the group's members, Krayzie Bone, Layzie Bone, Bizzy Bone and
    Wish Bone.</p>
      <p>The song was accompanied by a music video that opens with
    the female vocal group Tre singing the traditional spiritual
    "Mary Don't You Weep" in a church funeral setting, followed by
    the members of Bone Thugs-n-Harmony singing the main song in
    several settings, such as a church and a mountaintop.
    Additionally, an imposing black man with sunglasses and a
    trench coat, akin to a Reaper, appears throughout the video.
    Bone are among the few who can see the man, and watch him as he
    gathers the souls of various individuals who are marked for
    death, such as a young man who leaves his distraught mother
    behind, Bone's friend Wally, Wish Bone's Uncle Charles, Eazy-E,
    and a newborn baby. The Reaper then leads the souls, with the
    baby in his arms, up a mountain and transforms into an angel,
    taking the deceased people to Heaven.</p>
      <p>Crossroads became the first single for hip-hop/garage band
    Blazin' Squad. It became the band's only number one single,
    staying at the top spot for two weeks in August 2002. The track
    is the first to be taken from their debut album, 
    <i>In the Beginning</i>. There are three versions of the song:
    a Radio Edit lasting 3:10 (which appears on their album), the
    Full Version (which includes extra instrumental section)
    lasting 3:50, and the Extended Cut (which includes two extra
    verses), lasting 3:48. The Extended Cut only appears on the
    promotional single.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
