<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Letter_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Letter_(song)</songId>
   <title>The Letter</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Box_Tops</artistId>
      <artistName>Box Tops</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1967-09-23</week>
      <week>1967-09-30</week>
      <week>1967-10-07</week>
      <week>1967-10-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/82/The_letter.jpg/200px-The_letter.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Box-Tops+The-Letter.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Letter/Neon Rainbow</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 1967 ( U.S. )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
      <genre>Psychedelic Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>1:58</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Mala</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Wayne Carson Thompson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Dan Penn</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Letter" is a song written by Wayne Carson Thompson
    which was a #1 hit in 1967 for the Box Tops.</p>
      <p>The track was recorded at American Sound Studio in Memphis
    in a session produced by Dan Penn. Previously a musician and
    engineer at FAME Studios, Penn had been hired as production
    assistant to American Sound's owner Chips Moman, who Penn felt
    was shutting him out as a collaborator. Penn recalls: "Finally,
    I just told [Moman]...'Look, we can't produce together...I
    think I can produce records [alone]...But I do need somebody to
    cut. Give me the worst one you got'." Moman suggested Penn
    record a local five man outfit who had been pitched to him by
    disc jockey Ray Banks (Penn - "Chips was just graspin'. He'd
    never heard [the group]") and also passed on to Penn a demo
    tape of songs cut by his friend Wayne Carson Thompson which
    included "The Letter". Thompson's father dabbled in songwriting
    and would suggest ideas to his son, who had written "The
    Letter" after his father had suggested: "Give me a ticket for
    an aeroplane" as a potential opening line for a song. Penn met
    with some of the members of the group - who were eventually
    dubbed the Box Tops - "and told them to pick anything they
    wanted from this tape [by Thompson], but make sure that we do
    'The Letter'" which Penn considered the one outstanding
    song.</p>
      <p>The session for "The Letter" began at 10 o'clock on a
    Saturday morning and took over thirty takes wrapping at either
    three or five o'clock that afternoon. Penn met Box Tops'
    vocalist Alex Chilton for the first time at the session: "I
    coached him a little...told him to say 'aer-o-plane", told him
    to get a little gruff, and I didn't have to say anything else
    to him". (Composer Thompson, who says he played guitar at the
    session, was thrown by Chilton's vocal, having imagined the
    song being sung in a higher key.) Penn - "[Chilton] picked it
    up exactly as I had in mind, maybe even better. I hadn't even
    paid any attention to how good he sang because I was busy
    trying to put the band together...I had a bunch of greenhorns
    who'd never cut a record, including me...I borrowed everything
    form Wayne Thompson's original demo - drums, bass, guitar. I
    added an organ with an 'I'm a Believer' lick." Penn added the
    sound of an airplane take-off to the track by recording off of
    a special effects record played in an office adjacent to the
    recording studio. When the track was previewed for Chips Moman
    he suggested the take-off sounds be excised, to which Penn
    responded: "Give me that razor blade right there...[and] I'll
    cut this damn tape up! The airplane stays on it, or we don't
    have a record."</p>
      <p>Augmented with strings and horns (arranged by Mike Leach),
    the track was picked up by Larry Uttal of Bell Records who
    released it on the subsidiary Mala label in July 1967 to reach
    #1 that September. Retaining the #1 position for a total of
    four weeks, "The Letter" was ranked as the #1 hit of 1967. The
    track also gave the Box Tops an international hit charting in
    Australia (#4 for six weeks), Austria (#9), Belgium (Flemish
    Region) (#2), Chile (#1), Denmark (#7)France (#2), Germany
    (#5), Greece (#2 Foreign Release), Ireland (#11), Israel (#1),
    Malaysia (#4), New Zealand (#4), the Netherlands (#3) Norway
    (#1), Poland (#1),South Africa (#4), Spain (#9) and Sweden
    (#2). The Box Tops also reached #5 in the UK, besting a cover
    by the Mindbenders which reached #42.</p>
      <p>In November 1968 the Arbors recorded an easy listening style
    version of "The Letter" in a session at Record Plant Studios in
    New York City produced by Roy Cicala and Lori Burton; the
    session was arranged and conducted by Joe Scott. Released on
    CBS Records Date label, the track reached #20 in the spring of
    1969, also ranking at #26 on the Easy Listening charts and #24
    in Canada.</p>
      <p>"The Letter" returned to the U.S. Top Ten in June of 1970
    via a single release of Joe Cocker's blues-rock reinvention of
    the song as featured on the 
    <i>Mad Dogs and Englishmen</i>live album recorded that March at
    the Fillmore East. Cocker's revival was also a chart item in
    Australia (#27), Canada (#7), France (#48), the Netherlands
    (#27) and the UK (#39).</p>
      <p>In 1978 "The Letter" became a disco hit for Deborah
    Washington reaching #13 on the dance chart in tandem with
    Washington's remakes of "Standing in the Shadows of Love" and
    "Fire" - all three tracks were taken from Washington's 
    <i>Any Way You Want It</i>album. Amii Stewart also recorded a
    disco version of "The Letter" which was released on a single
    with "Paradise Bird" to become a double sided chart entry in
    the UK at #39 in 1980. Stewart's "The Letter" also reached #31
    in France, becoming the fourth version of the song to appear on
    the French charts, following the Box Tops and Joe Cocker
    versions and also a translated version by Herbert Léonard
    entitled "Une Lettre" which charted December 1967 - January
    1968 with a #82 peak.</p>
      <p>Ranked by 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>at #363 on the magazine's list of the 500
    Greatest Songs of All Time, "The Letter" was reported in July
    1979 to have been recorded in over 200 different versions.
    Among the artists who have recorded the song are Bachman-Turner
    Overdrive, the Beach Boys, Eva Cassidy, Shaun Cassidy, Classics
    IV, Bobby Darin, John Davidson, Don Fardon, Al Green, Ellie
    Greenwich, Sonny James, Robert Knight, Brenda Lee, Trini Lopez,
    Barbara Mandrell, Bob Marley and the Wailers did a cover
    re-named "give me a ticket" on the album "Selassie is the
    Chapel" Melanie, the Moments, Lou Rawls, Johnny Rivers and
    Dionne Warwick. In 1987 David Kolin as "Dr. Dave" had a 12-inch
    single release of "Vanna Pick Me a Letter" which remade "The
    Letter" substituting new lyrics by Kolin which made the
    narrator a contestant on 
    <i>Wheel of Fortune</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
