<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Boy_Is_Mine 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Boy_Is_Mine</songId>
   <title>The Boy Is Mine</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brandy_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Brandy and Monica</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1998-06-06</week>
      <week>1998-06-13</week>
      <week>1998-06-20</week>
      <week>1998-06-27</week>
      <week>1998-07-04</week>
      <week>1998-07-11</week>
      <week>1998-07-18</week>
      <week>1998-07-25</week>
      <week>1998-08-01</week>
      <week>1998-08-08</week>
      <week>1998-08-15</week>
      <week>1998-08-22</week>
      <week>1998-08-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/11/The_Boy_Is_Mine.jpg/200px-The_Boy_Is_Mine.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Brandy-and-Monica+The-Boy-Is-Mine.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Never Say NeverThe Boy Is Mine</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 12, 1998</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Los Angeles, California ; , Atlanta, Georgia</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:54 (album version)</length>
      <length>4:03 (radio version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic , Arista</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Brandy Norwood</writer>
      <writer>LaShawn Daniels</writer>
      <writer>Rodney Jerkins</writer>
      <writer>Fred Jerkins III</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Rodney Jerkins</producer>
      <producer>Dallas Austin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Boy Is Mine" is a song recorded by American R&amp;B
    singers Brandy and Monica. It was written by LaShawn Daniels,
    Fred Jerkins III, Rodney "Darkchild" Jerkins and Brandy with
    co-production by Darkchild and Dallas Austin, and released as
    the lead single from both singers' second albums during the
    second quarter of 1998. The song's lyrics tell a story about
    two women disputing the love of a man and were inspired by Paul
    McCartney and Michael Jackson's 1982 duet "The Girl Is
    Mine."</p>
      <p>"The Boy Is Mine" was the first number-one pop record for
    both artists, both stateside and internationally. Exploiting
    the media's presumption of a rivalry between the two young
    singers, the song became one of the most successful records of
    the year, spending a record-breaking thirteen weeks on top of
    the U.S. Hot 100 during the Summer of 1998, and it reached the
    top five on most of the other charts on which it appeared.</p>
      <p>The video, shot in April 1998 and directed by Joseph Kahn,
    begins with the girls in their apartments, watching television.
    Brandy watches the 
    <i>The Jerry Springer Show</i>(whose episode title is that of
    the song) but then Monica accidentally turns Brandy's TV to a
    romantic movie, in which Monica is watching on her own TV set.
    Whenever Brandy or Monica turns the channel, the other's TV
    stays on that channel and they grow sick of it. They then give
    up and start to sing. The next scene shows Brandy and Monica
    discussing their problem with their separate groups of friends.
    The video premiered on Wednesday, April 29, 1998. The "boy"
    himself (played by Mekhi Phifer, who played Brandy's boyfriend
    in the movie 
    <i>I Still Know What You Did Last Summer</i>) then appears
    outside the two girls apartment, where all their friends walk
    by him as they exit their respective friends place. The girls
    are in pajamas next, and then each one calls the man over to
    choose. After Brandy and Monica fight with words, the man comes
    to the apartment, frustrated over who to choose. The door
    opens, and only Brandy is shown. Then it swings a little wider
    and Monica comes. The man gets a startled expression, and the
    door is slammed in his face. The video was nominated for two
    1998 MTV Video Music Awards, for Best R&amp;B Video, and Video
    of the Year, which both lose for Wyclef Jean's 
    <i>Gone Till November</i>for 
    <i>Best R&amp;B Video</i>and Madonna's Ray of Light for 
    <i>Video of The Year</i>
      </p>
      <p>The song garnered the pair a number of industry awards,
    including a Grammy for "Best R&amp;B Performance by a Duo or
    Group with Vocal" and three Billboard Music Awards. It was also
    nominated for Record of the Year. 
    <i>Billboard</i>listed it 54th on the Billboard: All-Time Hot
    100 Top Songs. It is listed as the 62nd on the most successful
    singles in France ever. It is also listed among one of the most
    successful 200 singles in Australia, Netherlands and Belgium in
    music history.</p>
      <p>"The Boy Is Mine" topped the U.S. Hot 100 for thirteen weeks
    and the Canadian Singles Chart for fifteen weeks, which made it
    one of the biggest singles of the 1990s, selling over two
    million copies. The song became the first significant European
    success for Brandy and Monica and peaked at number two on the
    UK Singles Chart at number three on the Swedish Singles Chart.
    "The Boy Is Mine" also charted at number three on the
    Australian Singles Chart. In the U.S. it ascended twenty-two
    positions from number twenty-three to number one the week of
    June 6, 1998, and became one of the biggest jumps to number one
    in the history of the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100.</p>
      <p>"Gone Be Fine"  · 
    <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Still Standing"</span>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
