<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Itsy_Bitsy_Teenie_Weenie_Yellow_Polka_Dot_Bikini 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Itsy_Bitsy_Teenie_Weenie_Yellow_Polka_Dot_Bikini</songId>
   <title>Itsy Bitsy Teenie Weenie Yellow Polka Dot Bikini</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brian_Hyland</artistId>
      <artistName>Brian Hyland</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1960-08-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/8b/IBTWYPDB.jpg/200px-IBTWYPDB.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Brian-Hyland+Itsy-Bitsy-Teenie-Weenie-Yellow-Polka-Dot-Bikini.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Huggin An'a Kissin'</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1990</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Polydor Records / Carpet Records</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Timmy Mallet</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Itsy Bitsy Teenie Weenie Yellow Polka Dot Bikini" is a
    novelty song telling the story of a shy girl wearing a
    revealing polka dot bikini bathing suit at the beach, who in
    the first verse is too afraid to leave the locker where she has
    changed into the aforementioned swimwear; in the second, she
    has made it to the beach but sits on the sand wrapped in a
    blanket; and in the closing verse, she has finally gone into
    the ocean, but is too afraid to come out, and stays immersed in
    the water – despite the fact that she's "turning blue", to
    quote the song's lyrics – to hide herself from view. It was
    written by Paul Vance and Lee Pockriss and first released in
    June 1960 by Brian Hyland with orchestra conducted by John
    Dixon as "Itsy Bitsy Teenie Weenie Yellow Polkadot Bikini."
    Hyland's version hit number one on the Hot 100 on August 8,
    1960 and also made the top 10 in other countries, including #8
    on the UK Singles Chart. Trudy Packer recited the phrases
    beginning with "One, two, three, four" – i.e. "Tell the people
    what she wore", heard at the end of each verse before the
    chorus; and "Stick around, we'll tell you more", heard after
    the first chorus and before the start of the second verse.</p>
      <p>In September 2006, the song's co-writer Paul Vance read his
    own mistaken obituary. Paul Van Valkenburgh, who had long
    claimed to have written the song, died and the false
    information was included in the newspaper. The impostor had
    explained his lack of royalty payments for the song by further
    claiming that he'd sold the rights to his alleged composition
    as a teenager. Vance, the song's true co-author, has earned
    several million dollars from the song since 1960, describing it
    as "a money machine."</p>
      <p>The song was featured in the 1961 Billy Wilder film comedy 
    <i>One, Two, Three</i> — in a key scene, the character 
    <i>Otto</i>(Horst Buchholz), suspected of being a spy, is being
    tortured by East German police playing the song to him
    repetitively, eventually with the record off-center to create a
    weird howling variation of pitch. The actual recording was
    re-released in 1962 to capitalize on the film's success, but it
    did not rechart.</p>
      <p>A faster version of the song appears on North American
    commercials for Yoplait Light yogurt. The song is also used in
    a television commercial for the YWCA, and in films such as 
    <i>Sister Act 2</i>and 
    <i>Revenge of the Nerds II</i>.</p>
      <p>At the beginning of 2006 this song was also used in an
    advert for TV Easy magazine.</p>
      <p>At a time when bikini bathing suits were still seen as too
    risque to be mainstream, the song prompted a sudden takeoff in
    bikinis sales and is credited as being one of the earliest
    contributors to the acceptance of the suit in society. The
    early 60s saw a slew of surf movies and other film and
    television productions that rapidly built on the song's
    momentum.</p>
      <p>There have been cover versions in many languages, for
    example, a French and Italian version by Dalida in 1960. It has
    also been sung in German with Club Honolulu (Caterina Valente
    &amp; her brother Silvio Francesco) the same year. It was also
    remade in 1990 by Bombalurina which featured Timmy Mallett,
    star of then-popular United Kingdom children's television show,
    
    <i>Wacaday</i>. The song reached #1 in the UK Singles Chart on
    August 19, 1990, and stayed at the position for three weeks.
    The song was released around the world and topped the charts in
    over a dozen countries, selling more than a million copies.
    Another version was made by Devo on the CD 
    <i>Pioneers Who Got Scalped</i>. The video featured Timmy
    Mallett along with two dancers, Dawn and Annie. Dawn later went
    onto marry Gary Barlow of Take That fame.</p>
      <p>A Spanish version, titled "Bikini Amarillo," very faithful
    to the original, was an enormous hit for Mexican singer Manolo
    Muñoz in the 1960s.</p>
      <p>Another interesting cover version is 
    <i>El Cohete Americano</i>, a Cuban propaganda song sung by 
    <i>Las D'Aida</i>in Album de la Revolucion Cubana (2000).</p>
      <p>In Serbian, it was sung by Ljiljana Petrovic. In Croatian,
    there is cover by trio Tividi.</p>
      <p>A Brazilian version, a little faithful to the original,
    titled "Biquíni de Bolinha Amarelinha Tão Pequenininho," was a
    hit in 1965 when it was sung by Ronnie Cord , and had some
    re-recordings, as Blitz's 1983 version .</p>
      <p>A parody of the song was used for a TV Easy magazine advert
    entitled 'I need an Itsy Bitsy Teenie Weenie TV Easy
    Magaziney'.</p>
      <p>German punk band Die Toten Hosen covered the Club Honolulu
    version (in German) on their 1987 cover album 
    <i>Never Mind the Hosen, Here's Die Roten Rosen</i>. It was
    released as a promo single under the alias Die Roten Rosen.
    Also, on the 2007 re-release the English version was added as a
    bonus track.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
