<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/3_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/3_(song)</songId>
   <title>3</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Britney_Spears</artistId>
      <artistName>Britney Spears</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2009-10-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/48/Britney3.png/200px-Britney3.png</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Britney-Spears+3.png</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Singles Collection</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 29, 2009  (2009-09-29)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>July 12–18, 2009; Maratone Studios , ( Stockholm, Sweden )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Electropop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:33</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Jive</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Max Martin</writer>
      <writer>Shellback</writer>
      <writer>Tiffany Amber</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Max Martin</producer>
      <producer>Shellback</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"3" is a song by American recording artist Britney Spears,
    from her second greatest hits compilation 
    <i>The Singles Collection</i>. It was released on September 29,
    2009, as the lead single of the album by Jive Records. The song
    was produced by Max Martin and Shellback while Spears was on
    tour in Sweden. "3" is an uptempo electropop song, that
    features a heavy bassline and has influences of dance and rave.
    The song's lyrics refer to threesomes, while referencing Peter,
    Paul &amp; Mary during the chorus.</p>
      <p>The song received positive appreciation from contemporary
    critics, with some reviewers calling it a classic Spears song.
    "3" has also achieved commercial success by topping charts in
    the United States and Canada as well as reaching the top ten in
    many countries around the world, including Australia, Finland,
    Norway, Sweden and the United Kingdom. In the United States,
    the song debuted at number one in the Hot 100, becoming the
    first song to debut at the top position in over three years.
    The accompanying music video, directed by Diane Martel,
    featured Spears and her dancers in different black and white
    backgrounds. It received positive reviews from critics.</p>
      <p>In July 2009, Spears went into the studio to work with
    Swedish songwriter and producer Max Martin, while she was in
    Stockholm, during the European leg of The Circus Starring
    Britney Spears. They had previously collaborated on earlier
    hits including "...Baby One More Time", "Oops!...I Did It
    Again", "Stronger" and "If U Seek Amy". Spears recorded the
    song with Martin and Shellback at Maratone Studios.
    Instrumental work was done by Martin and Shellback. The song
    was later mixed by Serban Ghenea at MixStar Studios in
    Virginia. "3" was announced as the lead single along with the
    release of 
    <i>The Singles Collection</i>, and was sent to radio stations
    on September 29, 2009.</p>
      <p>"3" is an uptempo electropop song, which opens with synths
    and vocal effects. The song is written in the key of F minor
    and is set in time signature of common time with a tempo of 138
    beats per minute. Spears' vocal range spans from the high-tome
    of C
    <sub>4</sub>to the lower register of C
    <sub>5</sub>. The song has a basic sequence of Fm–E
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♯
</span>–B
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♯
</span>m–Fm as its chord progression. During the middle eight, the
song slows down with synthetic strings and bass beats, and the
section ends with a beat similar to a four-on-the floor, a rhythm
pattern popularized in 1970's disco music. Throughout the song,
Spears' vocals are autotuned that, according to the 
    <i>Daily Mail</i>, gives the song "a futuristic, contemporary
    feel".</p>
      <p>The song's lyrics is about threesomes. Unlike "If U Seek
    Amy", the song has no double entendre and it’s more
    straightforward lyrically. The innuendo in the lyrics such as
    "Merrier the more, triple fun that way" have been compared to
    the songs in Prince’s 1980's studio album 
    <i>Dirty Mind</i>. The chorus has been compared to a playground
    chant and closes with an extended moan. During the second part
    of the chorus, there is a reference to the folk group Peter,
    Paul &amp; Mary, that in the song is used as sexual slang for a
    threesome. Todd Martens of the 
    <i>Los Angeles Times</i>called the reference "the cut's biggest
    oddity".</p>
      <p>"3" received positive reviews from contemporary music
    critics. Monica Herrera of 
    <i>Billboard</i>commented that the song "builds to a climax of
    wildly pulsing bass that summons fans to the dancefloor" and
    added that "[it] will be another notch in this pop
    provocateur's belt". On its online edition, 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s writer Daniel Kreps praised the song for
    its up-tempo melody and racy lyrics, while comparing it to Flo
    Rida's recent work, saying that "3" "is more of a surefire
    dance-floor stomper than anything Brit loaded onto 
    <i>Blackout</i>or 
    <i>Circus</i>". On the printed issue, the magazine gave the
    song four stars and called it an "instant Britney classic".
    Clark Collis of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>called it "a fembot voice,
    near-seizure-inducing dance-floor frenzy". While crediting the
    production for "elevating the song above typical dance
    products", the 
    <i>Los Angeles Times</i>said that Spears sounded "sweetly
    generic". Bill Lamb of About.com said that although the lyrics
    are controversial, "the bottom line is this is another
    irresistibly catchy pop confection that beats out most
    everything else on pop radio today". He praised the chorus and
    the middle section and called the track "classic Britney". The
    song was also compared to Madonna’s "Celebration" (2009), since
    they "musically present nothing particularly new, but they do
    manage to encapsulate many of the elements that make the singer
    a star". Lamb later named it the most essential pop song of its
    time in the week of November 20, 2009. A.J. Mayers of MTV
    picked it as the eighth best song of 2009.</p>
      <p>On October 8, 2009, "3" entered at number fourteen on the
    U.S. Bubbling Under Hot 100 and at number thirty-eight on the
    U.S. Pop Songs, becoming Spears' twenty-fourth career entry in
    the latest chart, most among all artists. On the following
    week, the song debuted at number one on the Hot 100, becoming
    Spears’ third number-one single in the United States and
    breaking many of the chart records. It made Spears the first
    artist in over three years to debut at the top position and the
    only non-
    <i>American Idol</i>artist in eleven years to do so. It was the
    sixteenth song in the chart history to debut at the top
    position and also the shortest title for a song reaching the
    top of the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100. The song also charted at number one on
    the Digital Songs, selling 255,000 downloads in its first week
    and having the highest one week total of any song, since Black
    Eyed Peas' "Boom Boom Pow" back in April 2009. "3" has sold
    over 1,600,000 copies in the United States as of February 2010.
    In Canada, the song debuted at number eighty-six on the
    Canadian Hot 100 on October 17, 2009 and rose up to number one
    the following week. It was certified two times platinum by the
    Canadian Recording Industry Association (CRIA) for sales over
    80,000 copies.</p>
      <p>The track debuted at number fifty on the Australian ARIA
    Singles Chart on February 16, 2009, with only two days of
    digital sales. The song peaked at number six on the week of
    October 26, 2009. It has since been certified platinum by the
    Australian Recording Industry Association (ARIA) with sales of
    over 70,000 copies. On October 12, 2009, the song debuted at
    number sixteen in New Zealand, making it her highest chart
    debut since "Womanizer". On its fifth week on the chart, "3"
    reached its peak position at number twelve.</p>
      <p>On the UK Singles Chart, "3" debuted at number seven on
    November 16, 2009, becoming Spears' twentieth top ten hit on
    the chart. The track has achieved similar success throughout
    Europe reaching the top ten in Belgium (Wallonia), Czech
    Republic, Finland, Norway, Sweden as well as the top twenty in
    Austria, Belgium (Flanders) and Denmark.</p>
      <p>The music video was filmed on October 5 and October 6, 2009
    in Los Angeles, California, directed by Diane Martel and
    choreographed by Tone &amp; Rich. Fashion stylist GK Reid
    worked closely with Spears to design the fashion. On October
    15, 2009, images of the video were released. A countdown,
    including images and video previews, was announced on her
    official website and the release date was revealed to be on
    October 30, 2009. When asked about the video, Diane Martel
    said,</p>
      <p>"I think it's her next sexy video. It's a very simple video
    for her – I don't think you've seen her this much under a
    magnifying glass. Everything's really strong and playful. We
    collaborated on the wardrobe and had meetings about hair and
    makeup people, we talked a lot on the phone and met Tone and
    Rich — two of the best choreographers. [..] [Spears]' so sweet
    and funny and so normal and down to earth. It's really fun as a
    director to see her in front of the camera. She's so creative
    with this stuff. The video is very simple, it's very, very
    minimal. So it's her, her, her. And she's totally engaging
    every second. She really knows how to work with a camera and
    move. I was really impressed, and I have worked almost with
    every female artist in the business".</p>
      <p>The video begins with Spears wearing a sparkly black dress
    at a dressing table, putting mascara and Circus Fantasy on.
    Then, it cuts to her holding her hair up and singing the first
    lines in front of a white background. There are also black and
    white scenes of her wearing a white leotard behind a foggy
    glass. She then appears wearing the leotard and glasses, while
    surrounded by four female dancers wearing black outfits,
    hanging from a raised barre. The word "sin" is censored and
    changed for the word "this" during the pre-chorus. In the
    chorus, she dances in front of a white wall with barcode-like
    light installations with six male dancers. There also scenes of
    her dancing provocatively with two male dancers. At the bridge,
    there are intercut close-ups of her that end with a smirk. The
    video concludes with Spears dancing with the two male dancers
    and cuts to a close-up of her looking into the camera.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Rolling Stone</i>writer Daniel Kreps compared the video with
    the music video of "Single Ladies" and complimented the
    choreography saying Spears had not danced with so much
    conviction since the 
    <i>In the Zone</i>era. Jocelyn Vena of MTV gave the video a
    positive review, stating that it's a "sexy, fast-paced clip"
    and that "there are a few moments in the video where Britney's
    personality shines" adding that "she smiles at the song's
    tongue-in-cheek lyrics, particularly when she finishes the
    song's bridge." Tanner Stransky of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>complimented the video’s choice of
    wardrobe, but said that the video was "sparse", adding "there’s
    not much to the single besides trite, ridiculous advocation for
    a ménage à trois anyway, so why would the video go any
    deeper?". The 
    <i>Daily Mail</i>said the video "features Britney writhing
    around in scantily-clad outfits with male dancers in the best
    way she knows how".</p>
      <p>On December 15, 2009, the director's cut version of the
    video leaked online. Kreps commented that the new version
    "offers up a slightly more NSFW edit of Martel’s dance-heavy
    vid that seems to find a better cadence with the music, as
    opposed to the original version, which was essentially filmed
    and edited in the matter of days to coincide with 
    <i>The Singles Collection</i>release".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
