<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Womanizer_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Womanizer_(song)</songId>
   <title>Womanizer</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Britney_Spears</artistId>
      <artistName>Britney Spears</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2008-10-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/c/c9/Britney_Spears_Womanizer.jpg/200px-Britney_Spears_Womanizer.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Britney-Spears+Womanizer.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Circus</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 26, 2008  (2008-09-26)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>September 2008</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Electropop</genre>
      <genre>Synthpop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:43</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Jive</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Nikesha Briscoe</writer>
      <writer>Rafael Akinyemi</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>K. Briscoe/ The Outsyders</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Womanizer" is a song by American recording artist Britney
    Spears from her sixth studio album 
    <i>Circus</i>. It was released on September 26, 2008 by Jive
    Records as the first single of the album. The song, described
    by Spears as a girl anthem, recalls a womanizing man, while the
    protagonist of the song makes clear she knows who he really is.
    Produced and co-written by Nikesha Briscoe and Rafael Akinyemi
    of The Outsyders, the song is musically an uptempo electropop
    song with influences of Spears' songs from her previous two
    studios albums. Spears re-recorded some vocals after a snippet
    of the track was leaked before it was released.</p>
      <p>The song was well-received by contemporary critics, with
    reviewers complimenting its hook and deeming it as a comeback
    single for Spears. "Womanizer" was commercially successful,
    topping the charts in Belgium, Canada, Turkey, Denmark,
    Finland, France, Norway, Sweden and the United States. It also
    reached the top ten in Australia, Japan, New Zealand and many
    European countries. In the United States, it was her first
    single to reach number one since "...Baby One More Time",
    almost 10 years prior.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by Joseph Kahn and was created
    by Spears as a sequel to the music video of "Toxic". The video
    portrays Spears as a woman who disguises herself in different
    costumes and follows her boyfriend through his daily activities
    to expose him in the end. The video also contains scenes of
    Spears naked in a steam room, as a response to the attacks she
    had received over the years about her weight. It received
    positive reviews and was considered as a return to form for
    Spears.</p>
      <p>Spears performed "Womanizer" on various TV shows and on The
    Circus Starring Britney Spears, where she performed it as the
    encore number of the show, wearing a policewoman uniform. The
    song has been covered by a number of artists from different
    genres, including Lily Allen, Franz Ferdinand and Girls Aloud.
    It received a Grammy Nomination in 2010 in the Best Dance
    Recording category.</p>
      <p>The song was written and co-produced by Nikesha Briscoe and
    Rafael Akinyemi of the production team, The Outsyders. Spears
    recorded main vocals with Brendan Dakora at Glenwood Place
    Studios in Burbank, California and Bojan "Genius" Dugic at
    Legacy Studios in New York City. ProTools engineering was done
    by John Hanes, assisted by Tim Roberts. On September 19, 2008,
    a low quality 37 second snippet of the song was posted on the
    official website of 107.5 The River, a radio station in
    Lebanon, Tennessee. According to Jive Records, a representative
    of the label played a rough mix of the song for people at the
    station, who recorded it and leaked it on the Internet. The
    snippet was later removed from the website. The song was
    scheduled to premiere on September 23, 2008, but the release
    was delayed when Spears went into the studio to re-record some
    vocals. The new recordings were done with Jim Beanz and
    Marcella "Ms. Lago" Araica. The song was finally mixed by
    Serban Ghenea at MixStar Studios in Virginia.</p>
      <p>"Womanizer" was officially sent to radio stations on
    September 26, 2008. A few days later, Spears talked about it
    during a live interview with New York's Z100 on October 18,
    2008, stating, "It's basically saying, 'We know what you're up
    to.' It's about guys cheating on girls, it's a girl anthem.
    That's why I like it".</p>
      <p>"Womanizer" is an uptempo electropop song with dark synths
    that runs through a dance oriented beat. It has been compared
    to previous Spears' songs such as "Toxic" (2003) and "Ooh Ooh
    Baby" (2007). It is written in the verse–pre-chorus–chorus
    form. The track opens with its characteristical sirens.
    According to Ann Powers of the 
    <i>Los Angeles Times</i>, Spears "quick-witted" vocals are
    similar to the style of the Andrew sisters. It was also noted
    by 
    <i>Daily News</i>writer Jim Farber that Spears' delivery has a
    "tone of petulance". After the bridge, Spears sings the chorus
    one more time and the song ends while the beat drops and Spears
    sings the "you’re a womanizer, baby" hook. The song is composed
    in the key of C# minor with 139 beats per minute. The chord
    progression in the song is C#m-F#m-E-Eb-D. Lyrically, the song
    refers to a womanizing man. It has been suggested that the
    lyrics address Spears' ex-husband Kevin Federline.</p>
      <p>Peter Robinson of 
    <i>The Observer</i>gave the song the maximum five stars
    referring to it as a "comeback single" and as having a "genius
    hook". He added that the song "[has] been called lazy, largely
    by misinformed people who also think that Kylie's 'la la la's
    would have been better with proper words". Popjustice compared
    it to "Some Girls" by Rachel Stevens and added "[The] track
    lays a really strong foundation for the fully-realised comeback
    that didn't quite happen last time and it's hard not to think
    of it as a late contender for single of the year. [...] It's
    literally quite good". Myrddin Gwynedd of 
    <i>The New Zealand Herald</i>said "it's got hit written all
    over it". On the week of November 24, 2008, the 
    <i>Derby Telegraph</i>chose it as single of the week. In the
    album review, Nekesa Mumbi Moody of 
    <i>The Providence Journal</i>said that along with "Shattered
    Glass", they were "[two] fun disco tracks".</p>
      <p>
         <i>USA Today</i>writer Steve Jones named it one of the standout
    tracks of the album and commented that "she seems most at ease
    when she's playing the teasing tart". Talia Kraines of the BBC
    commented that Spears needed more songs like "Womanizer",
    saying "Britney 2.0 needs to be full of wild dancefloor driven
    moves". Simon Price of 
    <i>The Independent</i>commented the song borrows its electronic
    sound from Goldfrapp. Ann Powers of the 
    <i>Los Angeles Times</i>complimented Spears' delivery and the
    lyrics, saying the song is "about the kind of girl power that's
    focused on besting one obnoxious man, is also vintage and
    contemporary at the same time – more feminism as
    individualism". Mike Newmark of PopMatters called the song " a
    meaty, high-voltage shuffler helmed by the Outsyders, who do an
    admirable job of recreating the chemistry of Spears and Danja
    on last year’s single 'Gimme More'". 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>praised the song as an "electro-glam stomp"
    and went on to describe it as "head-boppingly hypnotic".</p>
      <p>Bill Lamb of About.com thought that Spears was confident,
    but the song sounded "like a rather weak attempt to approach
    the attitude of Katy Perry in a classic Britney futuristic
    bubblegum pop context". He would later name "Womanizer" the
    third most annoying pop song of 2008. Jim Farber of the 
    <i>Daily News</i>said the pre-chorus was the most repetitive in
    a pop song since The Shaggs's "Gimmie Dat Ding". Jim Abbott of
    the 
    <i>Orlando Sentinel</i>called it "basically an adult update of
    her teen-pop tease act". Ian Watson of Dotmusic wrote that
    Spears sounded "trapped on this single. Not trapped, as in
    desperate and distraught, but trapped as in literally frozen –
    like she's been placed into a robot on a production line and
    she has to sing these words, dance these steps, work it like
    this, until the spotlight snaps off and the factory's powered
    down for the night". The song has been nominated for a Grammy
    Award in the category of Best Dance Recording on December 2,
    2009. Spears had previously won the category in the 2004
    ceremony for her single "Toxic". However, it lost to Lady
    Gaga's "Poker Face". The song was also nominated for Best Track
    at the 2008 Virgin Media Music Awards, but it lost to Katy
    Perry's "I Kissed a Girl".</p>
      <p>In the United States, the song entered the Hot 100 at number
    ninety-six on the issue dated October 8, 2008. The following
    week, the song jumped to number one breaking the records for
    largest jump to number one and largest jump to any position in
    the history of the chart, previously held by T.I.'s "Live Your
    Life" and Beyoncé and Shakira's "Beautiful Liar", respectively.
    The record was later broken by Kelly Clarkson's "My Life Would
    Suck Without You". It also garnered first-week download sales
    of 286,000, the biggest opening-week tally by a female artist
    since Nielsen SoundScan began tracking digital downloads in
    2003, surpassing the record previously held by Mariah Carey's
    "Touch My Body". The record was broken on January 27, 2010 by
    Taylor Swift's "Today Was a Fairytale". "Womanizer" was Spears'
    first number one single since her debut "...Baby One More Time"
    in 1999. On the week of January 3, 2009, the song reached
    number one on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Pop Songs and number six on Radio Songs.</p>
      <p>As of July 2009, "Womanizer" was listed at number
    thirty-nine in the best selling digital songs of all time, with
    sales over 2,777,600. In Canada, the single topped the Canadian
    Hot 100 on October 18, 2008, and stayed in the position for
    five consecutive weeks. "Womanizer" entered the Australian
    charts on October 13, 2008 at number sixteen. Three weeks
    later, it peaked at number five. It shipped over 70,000 copies,
    earning a platinum certification by the Australian Recording
    Industry Association (ARIA). In New Zealand, the song peaked at
    number nine on October 27, 2008. The song was certified gold
    according to the Recording Industry Association of New Zealand
    (RIANZ), selling over 7,500 copies. The track debuted at number
    four in the United Kingdom on November 9, 2008 and reached its
    peak position of number three four weeks later. On January 16,
    2009, it was certified silver by the British Phonographic
    Industry (BPI), with sales over 60,000 copies. The song reached
    the peak in a number of European countries, including Belgium
    (Flanders), Denmark, Finland, France, Norway and Sweden. It
    also reached the top ten in Austria, Belgium (Wallonia), Czech
    Republic, Italy, Spain and the Netherlands. In addition, the
    track became Spears' sixth European number-one single.</p>
      <p>The music video was filmed on September 24 and September 25,
    2008 in Los Angeles, California, directed by Joseph Kahn, who
    previously worked with Spears for the music videos of
    "Stronger" and "Toxic". According to Kahn, Spears pitched him
    her original concept, which included all the main elements used
    in the final version. Spears thought of the video as a sequel
    to "Toxic", as seen in her documentary 
    <i>Britney: For the Record</i>, whereas Kahn approached it as
    "a 2008 answer" to the previous clip. He added that, "'Toxic'
    was a crystallization of her career at that time, [...] There
    are elements and moments of that I felt could [have been]
    improved. ['Womanizer'] is a bit more fashion-forward". About
    how the concept of the video related to their previous work,
    Kahn commented that "It's just a great girl fantasy. There are
    things she's really good at, like having a really natural knack
    for knowing what girls want. [...] It's a much more mature
    sound and much more mature lyrics, and she always has the
    greatest ideas. She's hyper-aware of pop culture". The costumes
    and looks for each of the different women were chosen by Spears
    and Kahn. The scenes in the sauna were suggested by Kahn, as a
    response to the attacks Spears received over the years about
    her weight. He stated, "I knew that the whole world would be
    watching, so I wanted something in there that stated, 'This is
    Britney, this is why you should respect her'". The set was
    cleared for two hours, leaving her and Kahn alone shooting the
    sequence. Kahn also decided to end the video with an image of
    Spears smiling, because "We just needed to tell everybody she's
    OK". A censored version of the music video premiered on October
    10, 2008 on ABC's 
    <i>20/20</i>at the end of their show. The uncensored version
    premiered on MTV the same night.</p>
      <p>The video begins with an opening caption that reads
    "Womanizer". During the introduction, Spears is naked and
    smiling at a sauna, while covering herself with her hands.
    These scenes are seen throughout the video. When the first
    verse begins, a blond Spears wearing a slip nightgown is making
    breakfast for her boyfriend as he gets ready for work. When he
    is at the office, he sees a new secretary, which is actually
    Spears in disguise wearing horn-rimmed glasses and a pencil
    skirt. She starts dancing in front of him and sings the chorus.
    She makes him follow her into the photocopier, where she
    photocopies her buttocks. On the back, we see an
    awkward-looking man, the same who appears in the plane scene on
    "Toxic". Then, Spears is disguised as a redhaired waitress in a
    restaurant. She dances around him with her dancers and plays
    with him over the kitchen counter. After this, her boyfriend is
    seen getting driven home by Spears, disguised as chauffeur. She
    starts to kiss him, driving the car with her heel until both
    get home. Once they get into the bedroom, Spears reveals that
    she was the three women he was "womanizing" all along. She then
    begins attacking her boyfriend. This is shown through Spears as
    her three alter egos, and then as the real version of herself.
    Spears throws a blanket over him and making the bed. The video
    ends with Spears smiling and the opening caption.</p>
      <p>Margeaux Watson of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>said the video "looks promising.
    [...] The dancing is stiff and minimal, a disappointment since
    her moves are her strong suit. But this is a welcome return to
    the Britney we love — gorgeous, gyrating, greased up, and
    gamely playing the vamp". 
    <i>OK!</i>commented that "in addition to seeing Brit in three
    different sexy getups, the video [...] features an oiled-up
    Britney writhing around in nothing but a smile". 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>said the video was "a cross between 'Toxic'
    and 
    <i>The Office</i>" and added, "she’s dancing [and] looking like
    the old Britney". Courtney Hazlett of msnbc.com claimed "When
    Spears isn’t shown naked and writhing in a steam room, she’s
    fired up". news.com.au stated that "Britney Spears is back to
    her old sexy self and she's not afraid to flaunt it". 
    <i>TV Guide</i>writer Adam Bryant said that "the music video
    features some of the most strategically placed hands in
    music-video history [...] [The] video is quite a return to form
    for the troubled pop star".</p>
      <p>The music video for "Womanizer" became a worldwide success
    right after it premiered on the Internet, gaining seven million
    viewers in less than 48 hours. The music video was listed as
    the best video of 2008 in polls by MTV and Fuse TV. It won
    Music Video of the Year at the 2009 NRJ Music Awards. The video
    was also nominated for Best Pop Video and Video of the Year at
    the 2009 MTV Video Music Awards. It lost the latter category to
    Beyoncé's "Single Ladies", but won Best Pop Video.</p>
      <p>The song was performed for the first time at the Bambi
    Awards in Germany, on November 27, 2008. For the performance
    Spears wore hot pants, fishnet stockings and a black top hat.
    The ensemble was compared to the costume Madonna wore during
    the first act of her Sticky &amp; Sweet Tour. Spears was also
    presented with an award for Best International Popstar by Karl
    Lagerfeld, who said, "I admire you ... not just for your
    art, but for your energy. [You are] coming back not only as a
    phoenix but as a bird of paradise". The following night, Spears
    performed the song at 
    <i>Star Academy</i>, with similar choreography and dance moves
    but wearing a red strapless dress. On November 30, 2008, Spears
    performed at 
    <i>The X Factor</i>. The performance was watched by over
    thirteen million UK citizens, making it the most viewed episode
    in the show’s history. On December 2, 2008, she performed the
    song at 
    <i>Good Morning America</i>along with a performance of
    "Circus". On December 15, 2008, she performed at the Japanese
    music show 
    <i>Hey! Hey! Hey! Music Champ</i>. The following day, she
    performed at 
    <i>NTV Best Artist 2008</i>in a black and gold bra, hot pants
    and a white top hat. She also sported a fake tattooed heart in
    her cheek.</p>
      <p>The song was a major part in The Circus Starring Britney
    Spears, as the encore of the show. After a video interlude of
    Spears's music videos set to "Break the Ice" ended, Spears
    appeared wearing a police officer uniform designed by Dean and
    Dan Caten, with black sunglasses, a hat with her trademark logo
    and sequined handcuffs. Her female dancers were also dressed as
    policewomen, while her male dancers were dressed as criminals.
    During the performance, she danced and flirted with the male
    dancers. At the end of the song, she returned to the main stage
    while her dancers surrounded her and a shower of sparks fell
    over them. She thanked the audience and bowed to each side of
    the arena. She left the stage with an instrumental version of
    "Circus" playing in the background. The performance was praised
    for being a standout number in the show.</p>
      <p>"Womanizer" has been covered by many artists from a variety
    of music genres, as well as a great number of amateurs. Clark
    Collis of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>explained that "the song has been
    covered by other artists with an enthusiasm only matched in
    recent times by musicians’ desire to remake Radiohead’s 'Creep'
    in their own image". On December 8, 2008, New Zealand singer
    Ladyhawke performed a cover at BBC Radio 1's Live Lounge. The
    song was covered by American band The All-American Rejects on
    the Yahoo! Music Pepsi Smash show in December 2008. It was
    performed in an acoustic version, in which the band members
    played percussions with beer bottles. The cover also included
    an excerpt from The Turtles's "Happy Together". British singer
    Lily Allen also covered the song, because "simple really, I
    love Britney and I love the song". Her cover was a stripped
    down version, that according to Nick Levine of Digital Spy,
    "might provoke those who reckon it doesn't have much of a
    chorus to revise their opinion". Allen also performed the song
    as the encore during her 2009 tour. French singer Sliimy cover
    was deemed as an "indie makeover". He would later be the
    opening act of the second Paris date at The Circus Starring
    Britney Spears. On January 13, 2009, English singer Ana Silvera
    covered the song during one of her London concerts. On April 6,
    2009, Scottish band Franz Ferdinand also covered the song at
    Radio 1's Live Lounge. Lead singer Alex Kapranos claimed "It's
    been the best song out in the last few months". It was also
    covered regularly by them during their 2009 American spring
    tour. The song was performed live by UK girl group Girls Aloud
    during their Out of Control Tour, starting April 24, 2009.
    Their version was released on their 2009 live album 
    <i>Out of Control: Live from the O2</i>. "Womanizer" was also
    covered by Fall Out Boy, among others.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
