<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/...Baby_One_More_Time_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/...Baby_One_More_Time_(song)</songId>
   <title>...Baby One More Time</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Britney_Spears</artistId>
      <artistName>Britney Spears</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1999-01-30</week>
      <week>1999-02-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/87/Babycover.jpg/200px-Babycover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Britney-Spears+Baby-One-More-Time.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>...Baby One More Time</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 23, 1998  (1998-10-23)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>March 1998 , Cheiron Studios, Sweden</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Bubblegum Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:30</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Jive</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Max Martin</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Denniz PoP</producer>
      <producer>Max Martin</producer>
      <producer>Rami</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"…Baby One More Time" is the debut song by American pop
    singer Britney Spears from her debut album 
    <i>...Baby One More Time</i>on Jive Records. It was released on
    October 13, 1998 in the United States and in the first quarter
    of 1999 internationally as the album's lead single. The song
    was written by Max Martin and was originally intended for TLC
    but after they rejected it, Spears and Martin decided to record
    the track. The song’s lyrics refer to breaking up with someone
    and regretting the decision.</p>
      <p>The song was well received by music critics, most calling it
    the highlight of the album and was nominated for a Grammy Award
    for Best Female Pop Vocal Performance. The track also achieved
    commercial success and remains Spears' most successful single,
    topping the charts in Australia, Canada, New Zealand, the
    United States and every European country in which it charted.
    In the United Kingdom, it became the highest selling single of
    the year and one of the highest selling singles of all
    time.</p>
      <p>After being signed by Jive Records, Spears started working
    with a number of producers. In early 1998, she flew to Cheiron
    Studios in Sweden to work with Max Martin, Denniz PoP and Rami,
    among others. Martin had originally written a song titled "Hit
    Me Baby One More Time" for popular R&amp;B group TLC; however,
    when the song was submitted to them they rejected it because
    they had already completed their third studio album, 
    <i>FanMail</i>. Martin showed Spears and her management the
    track. Spears later claimed that she felt excited when she
    heard it and knew it was going to be a hit record. Of the
    recording sessions she said, "I didn’t do well at all the first
    day in the studio, I was just too nervous. So I went out that
    night and had some fun. The next day I was completely relaxed
    and nailed it. You gotta be relaxed singing ‘… Baby One More
    Time’". Executives at Jive Records were concerned that the line
    "Hit Me" would condone domestic violence. The title was later
    revised to its current title.</p>
      <p>Musically, "…Baby One More Time" is a pop song set in common
    time and has a metronome of 93 beats per minute. The song
    begins with three piano notes, an opening that has been
    compared to many other songs, such as "We Will Rock You",
    "Start Me Up" and the theme song of the film 
    <i>Jaws</i>due to the fact the track “makes its presence known
    in exactly one second”. According to 
    <i>Blender</i>, musically the song is composed by “wah-wah
    guitar lines and EKG-machine bass-slaps”.</p>
      <p>Lyrically, the song speaks about lost love. Spears has said
    that it’s “[a song] every girl can relate to. She regrets it.
    She wants him back." The track is also easily recognizable for
    its opening line “Oh baby baby”, a phrase coined by Spears that
    is also used in future recordings such as "Oops!... I Did It
    Again" and "If U Seek Amy". The song’s lyrics caused
    controversy in the United States because the line “Hit me baby
    one more time” seem to have an S&amp;M connotations.</p>
      <p>Amanda Murray of Sputnikmusic called it "undoubtedly the
    high point of this album. It is well-composed, tightly
    arranged, and even with Spears' vocal limitations it goes
    straight for the proverbial pop jugular". She also said that
    the song was a highlight in the pop music genre and added,
    "There is little doubt that '...Baby One More Time' will be
    long remembered as one of the cornerstones of pop music in
    general, and it is a strong front-runner as the prototype for
    the late 90s pop resurgence". Beth Johnson of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>called it a
    "candy-pop-with-a-funky-edge smash". Stephen Thomas Erlewine of
    Allmusic said the track was "ingenious", while 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s Barry Walters compared it to early hits
    of Samantha Fox claiming that the song "effectively
    [transforms] this ex-Mouseketeer born in a tiny Louisiana town
    into a growling jailbait dynamo". Brian Raftery of 
    <i>Blender</i>called it a "a perfectly fine, slickly conceived
    pop tune. [..] At the time, teen-pop was still a boys’ club,
    but while the guys were crooning about crushes, Spears was
    already planning the sleep-over party".</p>
      <p>"...Baby One More Time" earned Spears her first nomination
    for a Grammy Award for Best Female Pop Vocal Performance. It
    also won other numerous awards, including a Teen Choice Award
    for Single of the Year and an MTV Europe Music Award for Best
    Song.</p>
      <p>The song was officially sent to the American radio stations
    on October 23, 1998. On November 21, 1998, "...Baby One More
    Time" debuted at number-seventeen on the Hot 100 and topped the
    chart two and a half months later for two consecutive weeks,
    replacing R&amp;B-singer Brandy's "Have You Ever?".
    Simultaneously, it climbed to number-one on the Canadian
    Singles Chart. The song reached the top spot of the Hot 100
    Singles Sales and stayed there for a solid four-week reign.
    This eventually propelled the single to a platinum
    certification by the Recording Industry Association of America.
    Though not as strong as its sales tallies, "...Baby One More
    Time" also experienced considerable airplay becoming her first
    top ten hit on the Hot 100 Airplay peaking at number-eight. The
    single also became an all-around hit on Top 40 radio, going top
    ten on both the Top 40 Tracks and Rhythmic Top 40, and to
    number-one for five weeks on the Mainstream Top 40. "...Baby
    One More Time" spent thirty-two weeks on the Hot 100 and ended
    up at number-five on Billboard magazine's year-end chart.</p>
      <p>The track reached the top spot in every European country in
    which it charted. It topped the Eurochart Hot 100 Singles for
    ten consecutive weeks. Notably, "...Baby One More Time" spent
    two consecutive weeks at number-one on the French Singles Chart
    and was certified platinum by the Syndicat National de
    l'Édition Phonographique after selling over 500,000 units in
    the country. Additionally, the song topped the German Singles
    Chart for six consecutive weeks and sold over 750,000 copies,
    resulting in a three-times gold certification by the
    International Federation of the Phonographic Industry In the
    United Kingdom, according to her label Jive Records said that
    the single "…Baby One More Time" has sold more than 250,000
    copies in a mere three days. Spears broke a first-week sales
    record for a female act at the time when "...Baby One More
    Time" sold a total of 460,000 copies in the United Kingdom. The
    single went on to sell over 1.45 million units, making it the
    highest-selling single of the year and the 25th best-selling of
    all-time in Britain. Eventually, the British Phonographic
    Industry certified it two-times platinum on March 26, 1999.
    Additionally, Spears joined a selected group of seven female
    acts with million-selling singles, which includes singers Kylie
    Minogue, Whitney Houston, Cher, Céline Dion, among others.</p>
      <p>"...Baby One More Time" debuted at number-twenty on the
    Australian Singles Chart, a month later reached number-one and
    stayed there for nine consecutive weeks. The song eventually
    became the second highest-selling single of the year, only
    behind Lou Bega's "Mambo#5", and was certified three-times
    platinum by the Australian Recording Industry Association for
    selling over 210,000 copies. In New Zealand, the single spent
    four non-consecutive weeks at the top of the charts and after
    shipping over 15,000 units to retailers the Recording Industry
    Association of New Zealand certified it platinum.</p>
      <p>The music video was filmed on August 7 and August 8, 1998,
    in Los Angeles, California and was directed by Nigel Dick.
    After being chosen, Dick received criticism from her colleagues
    about wanting to work with Spears. He responded saying, "It's a
    great song. I don't know anything about Britney. I never
    watched the "Mickey Mouse Club". She seems like a great kid and
    she's very enthusiastic, but I just love the song. It's just a
    great song".</p>
      <p>The video's original setup was in high contrast to what
    eventually became the final product. The plan was to have the
    video in a cartoon-like environment, in a likely attempt to
    attract the audience of younger children. However, Spears was
    unhappy with this. She argued that she wanted her video to
    reflect the lives of her fans and wanted to set the video in a
    school. Spears pitched this idea to Dick, and further explained
    she wanted the video to have dance scenes. The original setting
    was scrapped and replaced with Spears's concept.</p>
      <p>Dick’s original idea for the wardrobe was jeans and a
    t-shirt, but during the wardrobe fitting Spears decided to
    change it for a schoolgirl outfit. Dick said that "Every piece
    of wardrobe in the video came from Kmart, and I was told at the
    time not one piece of clothing in the video cost more than $17.
    On that level, it's real. That probably, in retrospect, is a
    part of its charm." The knotted shirt design was Spears' idea,
    she recollects saying, "The outfits looked kind of dorky, so I
    was like, 'Let's tie up our shirts and be cute'". About the
    experience of shooting her first music video, Spears said, "It
    was a wonderful experience. All these people there, working for
    you. I had my own trailer. It was an amazing experience". The
    music video was shot at Venice High School, the same school
    used to film the movie 
    <i>Grease</i>.</p>
      <p>The video begins with Spears in a particularly boring class
    at a Catholic school. Her assistant Felicia Culotta played the
    role of Spears's teacher. When the bell rings, Spears runs out
    into the hall and begins a choreographed dance. After this,
    Spears is outside, now adorned in an athletic outfit. Along
    with a couple of other students, she performs a number of
    gymnastic moves before heading back inside. She is then sitting
    on the bleachers in the gymnasium watching a basketball game.
    Her love interest is revealed sitting close to her, played by
    her real-life cousin Chad. After this short segment, Spears
    begins her final dance routine and the video ends shortly
    afterwards, revealing that the whole thing had actually just
    been Spears's daydream.</p>
      <p>The music video for “…Baby One More Time” helped propel
    Spears into superstardom. The schoolgirl outfit is considered
    to be one of Spears' iconic looks and is on display at the Hard
    Rock Hotel and Casino in Las Vegas, Nevada. The ensemble caused
    controversy among parents associations for showing the midriff
    of a sixteen year old. Spears faced the criticism saying, "Me
    showing my belly? I'm from the South; you're stupid if you
    don't wear a sports bra [when you] go to dance class, you're
    going to be sweating your butt off."</p>
      <p>In 1999, "...Baby One More Time" earned Spears her first
    three MTV Video Music Award nominations in the categories of
    Best Pop Video, Best New Artist and Best Female Video. In a
    list compiled by VH1 in 2001, it was listed at number ninety in
    the best videos of all time. The video was the first of
    fourteen of her videos to retire on MTV 's television series
    TRL. On its final episode, a three hour special aired on
    November 16, 2009, “…Baby One More Time” was number one in
    their final countdown as the most iconic music videos of all
    time and was the last video to be played on the show. On MTV
    Latin America the video came in at number seven of "The Most
    MTV-like Videos" and at number three on "The Top 100 Pop
    Videos" only after Madonna's "Like a Virgin" and Michael
    Jackson's "Billie Jean".</p>
      <p>Wesley Yang in his essay “Inside the Box” in 
    <i>n+1</i>, compared the music video to Britny Fox’s
    “Girlschool” because it featured “a classroom full of Catholic
    schoolgirls gyrating to the beat in defiance of a stern
    teacher. [..] But that was a sexist video by a horrible hair
    metal band that exploited women. Britney Spears was something
    else—an inflection point in the culture".</p>
      <p>The music video is also referenced in the music video of her
    2009 single, "If U Seek Amy". After she comes out of the house
    dressed as a housewife, her daughter is dressed with a similar
    schoolgirl outfit while wearing pink ribbons in her hair.</p>
      <p>"…Baby One More Time" has been covered on numerous
    occasions. One of the earliest live covers of the song was by
    Scottish band Travis, recorded during one of their concerts at
    "The Bay Tavern" in Robin Hood's Bay, North Yorkshire, England.
    The song was later included in the release of their 1999
    single, "Turn". Lead singer Francis Healey said, "We did it for
    a laugh the first time. [..] And as we played it, the irony
    slipped from my smile. It’s a very well-crafted song. It [has]
    that magic thing."
    <i>The Guardian</i>said this cover showed a new and more "dark"
    side of the band, commenting "slowed down to a mournful crawl,
    it was amazing how ominous the couplet "This loneliness is
    killing me / Hit me, baby, one more time" sounded".
    PopWreckoning.com called it "perhaps the most well done cover
    of Britney’s catalyst to eternal fame". Spears heard their
    version while shopping in a mall and said, "It was so weird. I
    liked it though, I thought it was cool. It was a very different
    vibe from what I did". On July 2005, The Dresden Dolls
    performed a cover during their summer concerts while opening
    for Panic! at the Disco. On July 18, 2006, frontman Brendon
    Urie joined the band to perform the song in Pittsburgh,
    Pennsylvania. PopWreckoning.com said the cover was "a strange
    twist to this pop ditty. It’s obviously darker and actually
    tortured as opposed to Britney’s school girl despair". On
    November 29, 2008, the same day Spears performed "Womanizer" on
    
    <i>The X Factor</i>, contestants JLS performed a cover of the
    song that was deemed "lame" by judge Simon Cowell. On July 13,
    2009, Tori Amos covered the song live during her Sinful
    Attraction Tour at the Paramount Theatre in Oakland,
    California. On October 15, 2009, Kris Allen covered the song
    for the first time at a concert in Seton High School in
    Cincinnati, Ohio. His rendition received positive reviews.</p>
      <p>Swedish humorist heavy metal band Black Ingvars covered the
    song for their 2000 album 
    <i>Kids Superhits</i>. The same year, British death metal cover
    band Ten Masked Men included a rendition of the song on their 
    <i>Return of the Ten Masked Men</i>album. A cover by Ahmet and
    Dweezil Zappa was featured in the soundtrack of the 2000 film 
    <i>Ready to Rumble</i>. In 2003, the song was covered by
    American pop punk band Bowling for Soup for the soundtrack of
    the remake film 
    <i>Freaky Friday</i>and commented that their version was
    "really, really, dark and really rock, [..] not the kind of
    'pop'-py stuff that we usually do." In 2005, power pop band
    Fountains of Wayne covered the song for their compilation album
    
    <i>Out-of-State Plates</i>. Robert Christgau of 
    <i>The Village Voice</i>highlighted their rendition saying the
    song is "as redolent and fetching as any of [Fountains of
    Wayne]'s peaks". Japanese pop singer Shiori Takei covered the
    song of her 2005 album 
    <i>The Note of My Nineteen Years</i>. In 2006, a lounge music
    style cover of the song by Trombo Combo was included on their
    covers album 
    <i>Trombo Combo: Swedish Sound Deluxe</i>. A hi-NRG-eurodance
    cover by Jayne Montgomery was released through Almighty
    Records.</p>
      <p>In the 2009 compilation 
    <i>Punk Goes Pop 2</i>, a cover of the song by metalcore band
    August Burns Red was included along with a cover of ”Toxic” by
    A Static Lullaby. Both received generally negative reviews.
    Music duo Doll Factory included a cover of the song as a bonus
    track on later printings of their album 
    <i>Weightless</i>. Singer-songwriter Christopher Dallman
    released an EP titled 
    <i>Sad Britney</i>that includes a cover of the song along with
    covers of "Toxic", "Gimme More" and "Radar".</p>
      <p>The song has also been covered by Brainshake, Intwine,
    Kevorkian, P.T. Grimm and the Dead Puppies, Jenny Owen Youngs,
    Neil Sahgal and Annie Bethancourt, among others.</p>
      <p>In 2005, the song was performed on Australian Idol by
    eventual runner up Emily Williams on the Final 3 Number 1 hits
    special.</p>
      <p>Frequently listed in best songs listings, “…Baby One More
    Time” was listed at number twenty five in the greatest pop
    songs since 1963, in a list compiled by 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>and MTV in 2000. 
    <i>Blender</i>listed it at number nine in The 500 Greatest
    Songs Since You Were Born. The song was also listed as the
    seventh best song of the nineties by VH1 and in a listing
    compiled in 2003, ranked at number twenty eight in 100 Best
    Songs of the Past 25 Years.</p>
      <p>In April 2005, the British TV network ITV aired a short
    series called 
    <i>Hit Me Baby One More Time</i>hosted by Vernon Kay. The show
    pitted one-hit wonders who generally had their moments of fame
    in the 1980s against each other to play their own hits and a
    currently popular cover song. The favorites were chosen by
    audience voting. The American version of the show also aired on
    NBC later in the year, and it was also hosted by Kay. In 2008,
    the South Korean girl group, Jewelry, had a hit song titled 
    <i>One More Time</i>, which contains the lyrics "Baby One More
    Time".</p>
      <p>An excerpt was used in 20th Century Fox's CGI-animated
    comedy film 
    <i>Robots</i>, but was not included on the soundtrack album.
    The song was featured in Britney Spears' video game 
    <i>Britney Dance Beats</i>. A cover of the song was used for
    the video game 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Volume 2</i>. The song was covered in the
    game 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Presents: American Idol Encore</i>as
    downloadable content. The song was also used as part of the
    plot for an episode of the Canadian television drama series
    Being Erica.</p>
      <p>These are the formats and track listings of major single
    releases of "…Baby One More Time".</p>
      <p>Australian CD Single</p>
      <p>Europe 2-Track CD</p>
      <p>UK CD #1/Maxi-Single</p>
      <p>UK Limited Edition CD #2</p>
      <p>French CD Single / Boxset Single</p>
      <p>U.S. CD Single</p>
      <p>U.S. 12" Vinyl</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
