<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heaven_(Bryan_Adams_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heaven_(Bryan_Adams_song)</songId>
   <title>Heaven</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bryan_Adams</artistId>
      <artistName>Bryan Adams</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1985-06-22</week>
      <week>1985-06-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/5d/Bryanadams_-_Heaven_Cover.jpg/200px-Bryanadams_-_Heaven_Cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bryan-Adams+Heaven.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Reckless</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 9, 1985  (1985-04-09)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>The Power Station , New York City , June 6–7, 1983</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
      <genre>Adult Contemporary</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:04</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>A&amp;M</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bryan Adams</writer>
      <writer>Jim Vallance</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bryan Adams</producer>
      <producer>Bob Clearmountain</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Heaven" is a power ballad written by Bryan Adams and Jim
    Vallance and performed by Bryan Adams. The song first appeared
    on the 
    <i>A Night in Heaven</i>soundtrack album in 1983 and was later
    included on Adams' album 
    <i>Reckless</i>in 1984. It was released as the third single
    from 
    <i>Reckless</i>and reached number 1 on the Billboard Hot 100 in
    June 1985, over a year and a half after the song first appeared
    on record. The single was certified Gold in Canada in 1985.</p>
      <p>Adams recorded "Heaven" at The Power Station in New York
    City on June 6 and 7, 1983.</p>
      <p>Adams didn't think "Heaven" was suitable for 
    <i>Reckless</i>, a feeling that was echoed by producer Jimmy
    Iovine, who was working with Adams at the time. Iovine thought
    the song was too 'light' for the album and recommended that
    Adams not include it. At the last moment, Adams changed his
    mind.</p>
      <p>Half way through the recording session drummer Mickey Curry
    announced that he had to leave since he committed in advance to
    a Hall &amp; Oates session. Curry had warned Adams about his
    limited availability that day. The recording session for
    "Heaven" was running behind schedule and Adams called Journey
    drummer Steve Smith. Smith happened to be in New York at the
    time and he filled Curry's drumming position.</p>
      <p>While writing "Heaven", Adams and Vallance were influenced
    by Journey's music and lyrical style, particular their song
    "Faithfully".</p>
      <p>In 1984 "Heaven" won the Procan Award (Performing Rights
    Organization of Canada) for Canadian radio airplay, in 1985 it
    won the BMI (Broadcast Music Inc.) Citation of Achievement for
    U.S. radio airplay and ten years later it won a Socan Classics
    Award for more than 100,000 Canadian radio performances.</p>
      <p>Live tracks recorded at the Hollywood Palladium on February
    1, 1985.</p>
      <p>"Heaven" first appeared on the 
    <i>A Night in Heaven</i>soundtrack album in 1983 and received
    substantial airplay on album-oriented rock radio stations,
    reaching number 9 on Billboard's Top Tracks chart in early
    1984. It was released as the third single from the album 
    <i>Reckless</i>in April 1985 and reached number 1 on the
    Billboard Hot 100. The song also re-entered the Top Rock Tracks
    chart in 1985, peaking at number 27. "Heaven" also peaked at
    number 12 on the Adult Contemporary chart during its second
    run, becoming Adams' second single to reach that chart after
    "Straight from the Heart" in 1983, and his biggest AC hit until
    1991.</p>
      <p>In Canada "Heaven" was officially released to radio on
    January, 1985. The song reached the top twenty on the Canadian
    Singles Chart and remained in the top twenty for another month.
    "Heaven" was the highest charting single from 
    <i>Reckless</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was released in Australia, Europe and New Zealand
    in 1985. "Heaven" reached the UK top forty. "Heaven" continued
    the trend of higher-charting singles when it debuted and peaked
    at top twenty in most of the European countries in which it
    charted. Adams' previous singles had charted much weaker in
    Europe and "Heaven" would be Adams' first single to chart in
    mainland Europe.</p>
      <p>Although "Heaven" reached the top ten in Sweden and Norway
    and then the top twenty in Austria, Ireland, Switzerland and
    Sweden, it was a moderate top hundred success in Germany where
    it peaked at number 62.</p>
      <p>The music video was shot in London, England, and was
    directed by Steve Barron. It features Adams singing the song in
    a live concert setting; behind him, stacked video monitors show
    his band playing along. Video monitors also occupy each seat of
    the otherwise empty theater. The video was nominated for an MTV
    Video Music Award for Best Cinematography.</p>
      <p>[1]</p>
      <p>In 2002 DJ Sammy and Yanou released a dance cover of 
    <i>Heaven</i>with vocals by Do. It was the second single of the
    album 
    <i>Heaven</i>and reached number one on the UK Singles Chart and
    number eight on the US 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100. It re-entered the chart on the week of
    November 17, 2007. This version was sampled by Nina Sky in
    their 2009 hit, "Beautiful People". On October 28, 2009, over
    seven years after its release, the song was certified gold by
    the Recording Industry Association of America for sales of over
    500,000.</p>
      <p>Because of the dance version's popularity, a stripped-down,
    ballad-like "Candlelight Mix" version was made and sang by Do,
    and received airplay on Adult Contemporary radio stations as
    well as CHR stations.</p>
      <p>An unauthorized remix of the "Candlelight Mix" was also made
    by KISS FM in Bakersfield, California to commemorate the
    September 11 terrorist attacks. The song features a little girl
    talking about her father who presumably died in the attacks,
    with the original chorus intermittently playing. A popular
    Flash animation plays out this version of the song. The little
    girl's vocal was actually the daughter of the program director
    at the time. He simply read her the lines and had her repeat
    them for him, with a little emotional prompting. Then he edited
    himself out of the voice track. This was one of the most
    requested songs in the station's history, and had all of the
    local market talking. It even crossed over to Clear Channel's
    other stations for a wider audience.</p>
      <p>The music video for the single features Yanou, DJ Sammy and
    Do viewed briefly from a TV. It was directed by Oliver
    Bradford. The video features two Asian girls, androgynous
    people and a black man. There is a second version, with
    extended scenes of a stationary Do singing.</p>
      <p>"Heaven" has been covered by numerous artists. One of the
    first cover recordings was by rock artist Gerd Rube on 
    <i>The Way I Feel</i>(1992). Eyra Gail covered the song
    identically to DJ Sammy on the album 
    <i>Eyra Gail</i>(2002). R&amp;B singer Kate DeAraugo covered
    the song on 
    <i>A Place I've Never Been</i>(2005). Scottish singer-actor
    John Barrowman's version appears on his cover album 
    <i>Another Side</i>(2007). Ruben Studdard also recorded a
    version as a bonus track for his fourth studio album, Love Is.
    Italian singer Martina Stavolo covered the song on her debut EP
    "Due Cose Importanti". DJ Manian covered the song with a series
    of remixes featuring Alia on the album 
    <i>Heaven</i>(2007). David Archuleta beautifully sang "Heaven"
    as a part of Hollywood Week during American Idol Season 7. The
    original DJ Sammy radio edit was sampled in 2009 to create Nina
    Sky's single "Beautiful People". In November 2009, Pitbull
    released "Pearly Gates", produced by Jim Jonsin, on the mixtape
    International Takeover: The United Nations which covers the
    "Heaven" chorus sang by Nayer.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
