<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/(Everything_I_Do)_I_Do_It_for_You 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/(Everything_I_Do)_I_Do_It_for_You</songId>
   <title>(Everything I Do) I Do It for You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bryan_Adams</artistId>
      <artistName>Bryan Adams</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1991-07-27</week>
      <week>1991-08-03</week>
      <week>1991-08-10</week>
      <week>1991-08-17</week>
      <week>1991-08-24</week>
      <week>1991-08-31</week>
      <week>1991-09-07</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/b/b5/IDoItForYou.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Bryan-Adams+Everything-I-Do-I-Do-It-for-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Waking Up the Neighbours</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>18 June 1991</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>March 1991</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:06 (radio edit)</length>
      <length>6:34 (album edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>A&amp;M Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bryan Adams</writer>
      <writer>Michael Kamen</writer>
      <writer>Robert John "Mutt" Lange</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Adams</producer>
      <producer>Lange</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"(Everything I Do) I Do It for You" is a hugely successful
    song co-written and performed by Bryan Adams, featured on his
    1991 album 
    <i>Waking up the Neighbours</i>and on the soundtrack for the
    film 
    <i>Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves</i>(1991). It was an enormous
    chart success internationally, sixteen consecutive weeks at
    number one on the UK Singles Chart (the longest in British
    chart history), spending seven weeks at number one in the
    United States' 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100, and nine weeks atop the 
    <i>RPM</i>singles chart in Canada.</p>
      <p>The record won a Grammy Award for Best Song Written
    Specifically for a Motion Picture or Television at the Grammy
    Awards of 1992, and was nominated for an Academy Award for Best
    Song. Subsequently, the song has been covered by numerous
    singers around the world.</p>
      <p>The song ranked at #16 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top 100.</i>
      </p>
      <p>The idea of a song to promote the movie 
    <i>Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves</i>came late in the making of
    the film. Michael Kamen, had originally wanted the song to be
    as if it were Maid Marian singing it to Robin Hood. He offered
    it to Kate Bush, Annie Lennox and Lisa Stansfield but they all
    turned it down. David Kerschenbaum of Morgan Creek Records
    invited Adams – whom he had worked with in the early 1980s at
    A&amp;M Records – to write the song based on the score from
    Kamen. Initially, Adams was to write the lyrics for another
    artist to perform, but it was decided that he should perform
    the song after writing it with 
    <i>Waking up the Neighbours</i>producer Mutt Lange. The pair
    recorded the song in Mayfair Studios in London.</p>
      <p>Neither Kamen nor the film company were happy with the song
    and tried at length to have Adams change it due to Adams and
    Lange writing an entirely different melody to the theme, but
    Adams refused..</p>
      <p>The song is credited to Adams, Lange, and Kamen, and is
    played over the film's credits. A&amp;M Records were at first
    reluctant to have the song appear on the film soundtrack, which
    was released through Morgan Creek, but the success of the
    record benefited both companies.</p>
      <p>"I Do It for You" was the last of three songs added to 
    <i>Waking up the Neighbours</i>. The album benefited from the
    success of the lead single; the song proved to be a hit
    throughout the world. In all, it topped the charts in thirty
    countries, becoming the best-selling song of 1991 and one of
    the best-selling singles of all time.</p>
      <p>In the U.S. it topped the chart for seven weeks, selling
    three million singles, making it the second-best-selling song
    after "We Are the World" by USA for Africa, and it also broke
    the record for longest run at number one on the Hot 100 Single
    Sales, becoming the best-selling single in America for 17
    weeks.</p>
      <p>In the UK, it sold almost 1.53 million copies, making it the
    best selling single in the UK since "Band Aid" in 1984. The
    song broke the record for 
    <i>the most consecutive</i>weeks on top of the UK charts, with
    16 weeks at number one from 7 July 1991 (holding Right Said
    Fred's "I'm Too Sexy" at number two for six consecutive weeks).
    The previous record-holder, "Rose Marie" by Slim Whitman, had
    been top of the charts for 11 weeks in 1955 (the single did not
    break the record for the most weeks at number one on the UK
    charts, held by the 1953 Frankie Laine song "I Believe" which
    spent 18 non-consecutive weeks at number one). The success of
    the single led to 
    <i>Waking up the Neighbours</i>receiving pre-order sales of
    200,000.</p>
      <p>Elsewhere in Europe, the song reached number one in Germany,
    Holland, Belgium, Austria, Switzerland, Finland, France,
    Norway, Sweden, and Denmark. The success of the single led to
    pre-order sales of a million for 
    <i>Waking up the Neighbours</i>throughout Europe. The album
    went on to sell 15 million copies around the world due in part
    to the song but also due to other singles.</p>
      <p>In 1998, American R&amp;B singer Brandy re-recorded the song
    for her second studio album 
    <i>Never Say Never</i>(1998). A year later, her cover version
    was released as the album's final single on a double A-side
    with "U Don't Know Me (Like U Used To)" on the New Zealand
    music market, where it reached the top 30 on the RIANZ singles
    chart.</p>
      <p>These are the formats and track listings of major
    single-releases of "I Do It for You".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
