<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Party_Doll 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Party_Doll</songId>
   <title>Party Doll " Buddy Knox</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Butterfly_(1957_song)</artistId>
      <artistName>"Butterfly" Andy Williams</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1957-03-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>???</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1957</released>
   <formats>
      <format>45 rpm</format>
      <format>78 rpm</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rockabilly</genre>
      <genre>Rock And Roll</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:12</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Roulette</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Buddy Knox</writer>
      <writer>Jimmy Bowen</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Norman Petty</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Party Doll" is a 1950s rockabilly song written by Buddy
    Knox and Jimmy Bowen. It was performed by Buddy Knox with the
    Rhythm Orchids and became a hit on the Roulette label.</p>
      <p>Buddy Knox was a teenager living near Happy, Texas in 1948
    when he wrote the original verses of "Party Doll" behind a
    haystack on his family farm. While attending college at West
    Texas State University, he and two college friends, Jimmy Bowen
    and Don Lanier, traveled to Clovis, New Mexico to record the
    song at the studio of Norman Petty. Knox's sister and two of
    her friends sang background vocals on the song, and a girl from
    the marching band of Clovis High School was recruited to play
    cymbal. After pressing copies of the record, a DJ in Amarillo
    began playing "Party Doll" in 1956, and it soon became a
    regional hit. After being contacted by Roulette Records in New
    York City, the song was distributed around the U.S. and became
    a chart-topping hit, spending a week at #1 on the Top 100
    chart, the precursor to the Hot 100, in March 1957.</p>
      <p>Almost immediately after Roulette released Knox's version of
    the song, competing versions of "Party Doll" were recorded and
    released by other record labels. Wingy Manone and Roy Brown
    recorded R&amp;B versions of the song which saw some success. A
    less rock and roll version by singer Steve Lawrence (with Dick
    Jacobs conducting the orchestra) also became a pop hit that
    year, reaching #5 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Top 100. Lawrence's version was released on the
    Coral Records label.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
