<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convoy_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convoy_(song)</songId>
   <title>Convoy</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C.W._McCall</artistId>
      <artistName>C.W. McCall</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1976-01-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Black Bear Road</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 1975</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1975</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Country</genre>
      <genre>Truck Driving Country</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:49</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>American Gramaphone</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>William D. Fries Jr. (lyrics)</writer>
      <writer>Louis F. Davis Jr. (music)</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Louis F. Davis Jr.</producer>
      <producer>Don Sears</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Convoy" is a 1975 novelty song performed by C. W. McCall
    (pseudonym of Bill Fries) that became a number-one song on both
    the country and pop charts in the USA. The song spent six weeks
    at number one on the country charts and one week at number one
    on the pop charts "Convoy" also peaked at number two in the UK.
    The song's success helped start a fad for citizens band (CB)
    radio. The song was the inspiration for the 1978 Sam Peckinpah
    film 
    <i>Convoy</i>.</p>
      <p>The song consists of three types of interspersed dialog: a
    simulated CB conversation with CB slang, the narration of the
    story and the chorus. It is about a fictitious trucker
    rebellion that drives from the west to the east coast of the
    United States without stopping. What they are protesting
    against (other than the 55 mph speed limit), is shown by lines
    such as "We tore up all our swindle sheets and left 'em settin'
    on scales." (The reference is to log sheets used to record
    driving hours; the sheets were referred to on occasion as
    'swindle sheets' as they were often created to show that
    drivers were getting proper sleep when, in reality, the drivers
    were driving more than the prescribed number of hours before
    mandatory rest; 'Scales' refers to Department of Transportation
    weigh stations on Interstates and highways to verify the weight
    of the truck and the drivers' hours of working through log
    books). The song also refers to toll roads: "We just ain't
    a-gonna pay no toll."</p>
      <p>The conversation is between "Rubber Duck," "Pig Pen" and
    "Sodbuster," primarily through Rubber Duck's side of the
    conversation. The narration and CB chatter are by Fries.</p>
      <p>At the beginning of the song a "Kenworth pullin' logs,"
    being driven by Rubber Duck, is the "front door" (the leader)
    of three eighteen-wheelers (tractor and semi-trailer) when he
    realizes they have a convoy. Following the Rubber Duck is an
    unnamed trucker in a "cab-over Pete with a reefer on" (a
    refrigerated trailer, hauled by a Peterbilt truck configured
    with the cab over the engine), while Pig Pen brings up the rear
    (the "back door") in a "'Jimmy' (GMC truck) haulin' hogs."</p>
      <p>The convoy begins toward "Flagtown" (Flagstaff, Arizona) at
    night on June 6 on "I-one-oh" (I-10) just outside "Shakytown"
    (Los Angeles, California, due to its earth tremors). By the
    time they get to "Tulsatown" (Tulsa, Oklahoma), there are 85
    trucks and the "bears" (police) have set up a road block and
    have a "bear in the air" (police helicopter). By the time they
    get to "Chi-town" (Chicago, Illinois), the convoy has been
    joined by "Sodbuster" (another trucker in an unspecified make
    of truck), a "suicide jockey" (truck hauling explosives) and
    "eleven long-haired friends of Jesus (11 hippies) in a
    chartreuse microbus" (a Volkswagen Type 2), and the police have
    called out "reinforcements from the 'Illinois' (Illinois)
    National Guard." The convoy crashes another road block when
    crossing a toll bridge into New Jersey, and by this time they
    have "a thousand screamin' trucks" in all.</p>
      <p>The song's running gag has Rubber Duck complaining about the
    smell of the hogs that Pig Pen is hauling. He repeatedly asks
    the offending driver to "back off" (fall further behind). By
    the end, Pig Pen has fallen so far back that when Rubber Duck
    is in New Jersey, Pig Pen has only gotten as far as Omaha (a
    reference to the headquarters of American Gramaphone, which
    released the song).</p>
      <p>McCall's "'Round the World with the Rubber Duck" is the
    sequel to "Convoy." In this continuation, the convoy leaves the
    United States and travels around the world, through England,
    France, West and East Germany, the USSR, Japan, and
    Australia.</p>
      <p>C. W. McCall recorded a new version of the song with saltier
    lyrics for the soundtrack of the 1978 film 
    <i>Convoy</i>. McCall also made two additional re-recordings of
    the original song, one for his 1990 album 
    <i>The Real McCall: An American Storyteller</i>, and the other
    for the 2003 Mannheim Steamroller album 
    <i>American Spirit</i>.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by artists such as Ferlin Husky,
    Boxcar Willie, and Tommy Hill's Music Festival.</p>
      <p>In 1976 a British version, 
    <i>Convoy GB</i>, featuring BBC Radio 1 DJs Dave Lee Travis and
    Paul Burnett as Laurie Lingo &amp; The Dipsticks, made #4 on
    the UK singles chart. In this version, the two truckers are
    "Superscouse" and "Plastic Chicken".</p>
      <p>Also in 1976, the skateboarding craze gave birth to
    "Sidewalk Convoy" by a high school group called Sneakers and
    Lace, on Pickwick Records.</p>
      <p>The song made an appearance in 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>, in the episode "Radio Bart". Another
    episode, "'Tis the Fifteenth Season", featured a Christmas
    themed version called "Christmas Convoy". An excerpt of the
    song was featured in the "Grand Wheelchair Rally" sketch of 
    <i>The Benny Hill Show</i>(episode #33, original airdate
    1978-12-26). The song was also sung by Earl, Joy and Randy in
    an episode of 
    <i>My Name is Earl</i>, entitled "Made a Lady Think I Was God".
    The song was featured in the television series 
    <i>Futurama</i>, in the episode "Parasites Lost". The current
    Fire in the Night show at the Pacific National Exhibition in
    Vancouver, BC is also based upon the most recent Paul Brandt
    version of the song.</p>
      <p>In 1990, husband-and-wife comedy duo Sheeler and Sheeler
    recorded a parody of the song entitled "Car Phone," about a
    self-centered yuppie in Southern California making calls on his
    cellular telephone while stuck in traffic, with cell phone
    chatter replacing the CB chatter. The song was featured on Dr.
    Demento's 25th Anniversary Collection album.</p>
      <p>In July 2003, a parody of the song entitled "Chat Room" was
    recorded by radio personality Bob Rivers. In this version, a
    middle-aged man using the screen name "Mickey17" has a racy
    online conversation with a stranger who turns out to be his own
    teenaged son, Chip (a reference to Chip Davis of Mannheim
    Steamroller fame).</p>
      <p>The song was covered in 2004 by Paul Brandt. The video
    features Brandt and fellow country singers Jason McCoy and
    Aaron Lines as well as then Calgary Flames defensemen Mike
    Commodore and Rhett Warrener as truckers and George Canyon, of
    Nashville Star fame, as the highway patrol officer. The video
    can be seen on CMT in both Canada and the United States.
    Brandt's version of the song peaked at #9 on the Canadian
    Country Singles chart.</p>
      <p>Throughout the song they purport that they are in America.
    When they start to show the Military, they are clearly in
    Canadian digital camouflage pattern and with Canadian cap
    brasses on their berets; the National Guard do not wear cap
    brasses on their berets. At the end of the song when they were
    in the jail cell, the Canadian Flag can be see on one of the
    soldier's combats. The music video was filmed outside of
    Wainwright, Alberta, and military from CFB Wainwright.</p>
      <p>The song was re-written into a Christmas song by Paul Brandt
    on his 
    <i>A Gift</i>album. This re-written version was called
    "Christmas Convoy" and it peaked at #28 on the Canadian country
    charts.</p>
      <p>Paul Brandt was at the Dauphin Country Music Festival in
    Manitoba and saw a trucking company with his name on it. After
    some talking, the owner of the company agreed to let Paul
    Brandt use his trucks for the music video.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
