<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kung_Fu_Fighting 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kung_Fu_Fighting</songId>
   <title>Kung Fu Fighting</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Douglas</artistId>
      <artistName>Carl Douglas</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-12-07</week>
      <week>1974-12-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/74/Kung_Fu_Fighting.jpg/200px-Kung_Fu_Fighting.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Carl-Douglas+Kung-Fu-Fighting.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Kung Fu Fighter</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1974</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>06:18</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Pye Records (UK), , 20th Century Records (US)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Carl Douglas</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Biddu Appaiah</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Kung Fu Fighting" is a song written and performed by Carl
    Douglas, and produced by Biddu. It was released as a single in
    1974, at the cusp of a chopsocky film craze, and quickly rose
    to the top of British and American charts. "Kung Fu Fighting"
    was also number one on the soul singles chart for one week. The
    song also is famous for its use of the quintessential Oriental
    Riff, a short musical phrase that is used to signify Chinese
    culture.</p>
      <p>It originally was meant to be a B-side to 
    <i>I Want to Give You My Everything</i>by Brooklyn songwriter
    Larry Weiss, and was recorded in the last ten minutes of his
    studio time. This song has been featured prominently in pop
    culture including Mott's Clamato advertisements.</p>
      <p>Douglas states that his inspiration to write the song was
    affected by three factors: he had seen a kung fu movie, later
    visited a jazz concert by Oscar Peterson, and was suffering
    from side-effects of pain killers (Douglas had injured his foot
    playing football). Another account gives his inspiration simply
    as seeing two kids in London doing kung fu moves.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Kung Fu Fighting</i>was rated #100 in VH1's 
    <i>100 Greatest one-hit wonders</i>, and number 1 in the UK
    Channel 4's 
    <i>Top 10 One Hit Wonders</i>list in 2000, the same channel's 
    <i>50 Greatest One Hit Wonders</i>poll in 2006 and 
    <i>Bring Back ... the one-hit Wonders</i>, for which Carl
    Douglas performed the song in a live concert.</p>
      <p>Patti Rothberg covered the song for the 
    <i>Beverly Hills Ninja</i>soundtrack in 1997.</p>
      <p>The song was very popular in Jamaica, and there were several
    cover versions by reggae artists including Lloyd Parks, The
    Maroons, The Cimarons, and Pluto Shervington.</p>
      <p>Jerry Lo (DJ Jerry, Taiwan) also produced a remake of the
    song [1].</p>
      <p>There's also a Finnish version of this song, sung by
    Frederik. The song's translated name is "Kung-Fu
    Taistelee".</p>
      <p>A cover version of the song was performed by Cee-Lo Green
    and Jack Black for the 2008 animated movie 
    <i>Kung Fu Panda</i>.</p>
      <p>Robyn Hitchcock also covered the song for the anti-poll tax
    album 
    <i>Alvin Lives (in Leeds)</i>in 1990.</p>
      <p>In 2004, the German record label Echo Beach released an
    album entitled 
    <i>Kung Fu Fighting Remixes (Dub Drenched Soundscapes)</i>that
    featured remixes of the track by 16 different artists including
    Adrian Sherwood, Dreadzone and Pole.</p>
      <p>British dance act Bus Stop reached #8 on the U.K. charts
    with their 1998 remix single of "Kung Fu Fighting", which
    sampled the original vocals by Carl Douglas and added rap
    verses. Iconic DJ Fatboy Slim is sometimes mistakenly credited
    for this remix.</p>
      <p>The song was used as the title song in the German version of
    the TV series 
    <i>Kung Fu</i>. It has been used in several movies and
    television shows since 1990 where there is a light-hearted
    spirit to the martial arts, including 
    <i>Mighty Morphin Power Rangers: The Movie</i>, 
    <i>Shaolin Soccer</i>, 
    <i>Little Manhattan</i>, 
    <i>Epic Movie</i>, 
    <i>City of God</i>, 
    <i>Beverly Hills Ninja</i>, 
    <i>Sin noticias de Dios</i>, 
    <i>Scrubs</i>, 
    <i>Bowfinger</i>, 
    <i>Kung Fu Panda</i>, 
    <i>Rush Hour 3</i>.</p>
      <p>It also has been used in trailers for the films 
    <i>Kung Fu Panda</i>, Disney's 
    <i>Wendy Wu: Homecoming Warrior</i>, &amp; 
    <i>Kung Fu Hustle</i>, and a cover by Cee-Lo Green and Jack
    Black is used over the end credits of 
    <i>Kung Fu Panda</i>. This version has partially rewritten
    lyrics more in keeping with the film's themes.</p>
      <p>It is used as the theme song for the Xbox game Kung Fu
    Chaos.</p>
      <p>A re-recorded version of the song by Douglas are featured in
    
    <i>Lego Rock Band</i>&amp; 
    <i>Band Hero</i>.</p>
      <p>The Bus Stop version has appeared in the video game 
    <i>Dance Dance Revolution</i>, and the original version
    appeared in 
    <i>Dancing Stage MAX</i>.</p>
      <p>Iron Fist mentions the first line of the song in 
    <i>Marvel Ultimate Alliance 2</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
