<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You%27re_So_Vain 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You%27re_So_Vain</songId>
   <title>You're So Vain</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carly_Simon</artistId>
      <artistName>Carly Simon</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1973-01-06</week>
      <week>1973-01-13</week>
      <week>1973-01-20</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/21/Carly_Simon_-_You%27re_So_Vain.jpg/200px-Carly_Simon_-_You%27re_So_Vain.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Carly-Simon+You-re-So-Vain.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>No Secrets</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 2, 1972</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1972</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:18</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Elektra</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Carly Simon</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"You're So Vain" is a song written and performed by Carly
    Simon, released in December 1972. The song is a critical
    profile of a self-absorbed lover; Simon asserts "You're so
    vain, you probably think this song is about you." The subject's
    identity has been the matter of speculation, fueled by Simon
    slowly revealing clues as to his identity.</p>
      <p>The song was a number-one hit. It topped the Billboard Hot
    100 for three weeks in early 1973, and also spent two weeks at
    the top of the Adult Contemporary chart, her first #1 song on
    either chart. "You're So Vain" was Simon's breakthrough hit in
    the United Kingdom market, reaching #3 on the UK chart on its
    original release in 1973. The song was re-released there in the
    spring of 1991 to cash in on its inclusion in a commercial for
    Dunlop Tyres, and came very close to making the UK top 40 a
    second time, peaking at #41.</p>
      <p>The song is #72 on 
    <i>Billboard's Greatest Songs of All-Time.</i>"You're So Vain"
    was voted #216 in RIAA's Songs of the Century.</p>
      <p>Simon has never publicly acknowledged in full the subject of
    "You're So Vain". Before the song became a hit single, she told
    an interviewer that the song was about "men," not a specific
    "man." Since its release, many have speculated about the
    identity of its subject (or subjects).</p>
      <p>In a 1989 interview, Simon acknowledged that the song is a
    little bit about Warren Beatty but said that the subject of the
    song is a composite of three men from her L.A. days. In a 2007
    interview, Beatty said, "Let's be honest. That song was about
    me." Simon has said that Beatty had called and thanked her for
    the song.</p>
      <p>In 1983, she told the 
    <i>Washington Post</i>that it is not about Mick Jagger, who
    contributed uncredited backing vocals to the song. In the 1993
    book 
    <i>Backstage Passes</i>, Angela Bowie claimed to be the "wife
    of a close friend" in "You're So Vain," and that Jagger, for a
    time, had been "obsessed" with her. Simon made another comment
    about the subject's identity as a guest artist on Janet
    Jackson's 2001 single, "Son of a Gun (I Betcha Think This Song
    Is About You)," which sampled "You're So Vain." In the song,
    Simon says "The apricot scarf was worn by Mick. Nothing in the
    words were referred to Mick."</p>
      <p>In February 2010, Simon told 
    <i>Uncut</i>that the name of the subject was whispered
    backwards in a re-recording of "You're So Vain": "There's a
    little whisper -- and it's the answer to the puzzle." A
    representative for Simon confirmed that the name whispered
    during the song is "David". Multiple media outlets quickly
    reported that the subject was actually Simon's former boss at
    Elektra, David Geffen (full name David Lawrence Geffen), and
    that the song had been inspired by her jealousy of the
    attention Geffen had lavished on label-mate Joni Mitchell. The
    following day, Jim Hart, Simon's ex-husband and close friend,
    denied that the song was about Geffen. Simon's publicist
    confirmed that the song was not about Geffen, but that there
    was indeed "a David who is connected to the song in some way,
    shape, or form." 
    <i>Vanity Fair</i>noted that in addition to "David", "Warren"
    and an unintelligible name are whispered during the recording,
    further adding to the mystery.</p>
      <p>Over the years, Simon has divulged "letter clues", and has
    allowed that the subject's name contains the letters A, E, and
    R.</p>
      <p>Shortly before the writing of the song, Simon was married to
    James Taylor; she has said that he was "definitely not" the
    subject of the song. Kris Kristofferson, David Bowie, David
    Cassidy and Cat Stevens have all been cited by the press as
    possible candidates. In 2005, Simon's ex-husband Jim Hart said
    he was sure that the song was not about anyone famous.</p>
      <p>In August 2003, Dick Ebersol, president of NBC Sports and a
    friend of Simon, was the highest bidder for a Martha's Vineyard
    Possible Dreams charity auction offering in which the prize was
    the revelation of the person that "You're So Vain" was about.
    After making the winning bid of $50,000, Ebersol was given a
    private performance of the song at Simon's home and Simon
    whispered the subject into his ear. A condition of the prize
    was that Ebersol would not reveal the person to anyone. Ebersol
    said that Simon allowed him to divulge a clue about the
    person's name: "Carly told me that I could offer up to the
    entire world, a clue as to what she'll tell me when we have
    this night in about two weeks. And the clue is: The letter 'E'
    is in the person's name."</p>
      <p>In 2004, Simon told Regis Philbin, "If I tell it, it's going
    to come out in dribs and drabs. And I've given out two letters
    already, an 'A' and an 'E.' But I'm going to add one to it. I'm
    going to add an 'R,' in honor of you."</p>
      <p>Several days after the identity of Watergate-era press
    source Deep Throat was revealed during the summer of 2005,
    Simon joked to 
    <i>USA Today</i>that the song was about Mark Felt, who revealed
    himself as the legendary Watergate source.</p>
      <p>On November 4th, 2009, while being interviewed on WNPR's 
    <i>Soundcheck</i>, Simon revealed that she had hidden the name
    of the subject in a certain version of the song. The next day,
    the program's crew revealed the name concealed in a back-played
    whisper: David. Assuming all of the clues to-date are true,
    this would not be David Bowie (no R); however, Bowie's real
    name is David Robert Jones, making it a possibility.</p>
      <p>On June 19, 2008, Howard Stern claimed Simon privately
    revealed who the song was written about to him after her
    interview on his popular radio show heard on Sirius Satellite
    Radio. Stern commented, "There is an odd aspect to it ... he's
    not that vain." On March 17 2009, Stern, recalling that Simon
    had told him who the song was written about, claimed that Simon
    said it was a "composite of three people".</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by Chocolate Starfish, David
    Axelrod, John Barrowman, Liza Minnelli, Jack Klugman and Tony
    Randall (as "The Odd Couple"), Chimira, Venice, Jann Arden,
    Janet Jackson (who sampled the song in "Son of a Gun (I Betcha
    Think This Song is About You)," with Simon providing featured
    vocals), Anna Waronker, Faster Pussycat, Romantic Guitar, Dres,
    Daryll-Ann, Smokie, Foo Fighters and Matthew Sweet &amp;
    Susanna Hoffs.</p>
      <p>In 1973 Swedish singer Anna-Lena Löfgren recorded the song
    in Swedish translation "Moln i mitt kaffe" (Clouds in my
    Coffee) as a single. In 1990, composer John Oswald produced an
    early mashup, entitled "Vane," which digitally merged Simon's
    original with the cover version by Faster Pussycat. The
    Illuminoids produced a mash-up of "You're So Vain" with two
    Rolling Stones songs "Brown Sugar" and "Bitch," referencing the
    roles of Carly Simon and Mick Jagger in creating the song. It
    was featured as the closing song of the 1999 film 
    <i>Dick</i>, a film satirizing the identity of Deep Throat;
    Richard Nixon leaves the White House and flies away in his
    helicopter as the song plays. A cover by The Mountain Goats,
    which appears on 
    <i>Hail and Farewell, Gothenburg,</i>features vocalist John
    Darnielle singing the verses only—the famous chorus goes unsung
    throughout the entire recording. Indie violinist and singer
    Andrew Bird satirizes the song in "Lull", on the album 
    <i>Weather Systems</i>(2003).</p>
      <p>Queens of the Stone Age spoofed the song on the special
    edition of Rated R, with a track titled "You're So Vague", and
    featuring the lyric, "
    <i>You're so vague / That you probably think this song ain't
    about you.</i>" In 2007, as part of BBC Radio 1's 40th
    Anniversary events, The Feeling covered the song. The Foo
    Fighters performed their version of the song at the 2008 Grammy
    Awards nomination show. On the 2009 song "Cooler Than Me" by
    Mike Posner featuring Big Sean, Mike Posner sings "You're so
    vain, you probably think that this song is about you, don't
    you?" in the chorus. The song's central line was also used in
    the Nine Inch Nails song "Starfuckers, Inc."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
