<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Power_of_Love_(Jennifer_Rush_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Power_of_Love_(Jennifer_Rush_song)</songId>
   <title>The Power of Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celine_Dion</artistId>
      <artistName>Céline Dion</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1994-02-12</week>
      <week>1994-02-19</week>
      <week>1994-02-26</week>
      <week>1994-03-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f3/Jennifer_rush_the_power_of_love.jpg/200px-Jennifer_rush_the_power_of_love.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Celine-Dion+The-Power-of-Love.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Jennifer Rush</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 30, 1985</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1984</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:44</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Gunther Mende</writer>
      <writer>Candy DeRouge</writer>
      <writer>Jennifer Rush</writer>
      <writer>Mary Susan Applegate</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Power of Love" is a power ballad co-written and
    originally recorded by Jennifer Rush. It has been covered by
    several artists, most notably by Laura Branigan and Céline
    Dion, and translated into several languages, becoming a pop
    standard.</p>
      <p>In 1985, Jennifer Rush's version spent 5 weeks at number 1
    on the UK Singles Chart. However, the song spent much of the
    summer of 1985 being largely ignored, taking a massive 13 weeks
    of yo-yoing outside of the top 40, before the song climbed to
    No.1 in its 17th week on the chart. In total, it spent 33 weeks
    on the chart and effectively eclipsed the success of the three
    follow-up singles: "Ring of Ice" (#14), "Madonna's Eyes" (#84)
    and "Destiny" (#96). It became the first single by a female
    solo artist to sell a million copies in the United Kingdom and
    it remains among the UK's best-selling singles of all time.
    This initial success stood in contrast to the song's reception
    in the United States, where Rush's original could only scrape
    to number 57 on the Billboard Hot 100 and did not even hit the
    Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks despite a performance by Rush on
    the April 12, 1986 broadcast of 
    <i>American Bandstand</i>. The song was a major hit in the rest
    of Europe — notably so in Germany, where Rush was based at the
    time. Her accompanying album became one of the biggest sellers
    of the decade there. The song itself is a straightforward love
    song, with the narrator telling of her first experience of true
    love. The song gained interest due to the strength of Rush's
    voice, which was classically trained and unusual in a pop
    ballad.</p>
      <p>The song was subsequently covered by other artists, two of
    whose recordings eclipsed all earlier versions on the U.S.
    charts. A recording by Laura Branigan became a top 40 hit on
    both Hot 100 and Adult Contemporary charts in late 1987; Céline
    Dion enjoyed a number 1 U.S. hit on both Billboard Hot 100 and
    Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks with her version, which was
    nominated for a 1995 Grammy Award.</p>
      <p>Though best known for dance classics like "Gloria" and "Self
    Control," Branigan had previously had major success introducing
    the ballad "How Am I Supposed to Live Without You" (number 1
    AC, number 12 Pop) and minor success introducing the ballad "I
    Found Someone" (number 25 AC, number 90 Pop), among others.
    Incorrectly supposed by some to have introduced "Power of Love"
    as well, Branigan was the first to take the song into the U.S.
    top 40, where it spent 9 weeks. While the single actually
    peaked at number 26 on the Billboard Hot 100 chart, its sales
    points outranked its pop airplay points, reaching number 19
    during the 1987-88 holiday season. Branigan's recording also
    peaked at number 19 on the AC chart. This success came without
    benefit of a music video.</p>
      <p>"Power of Love" (Branigan's version omitted the "The") was
    the second single from the 1987 album 
    <i>Touch</i>, following the number 13 Dance hit "Shattered
    Glass." Produced by Grammy winner David Kershenbaum, Branigan's
    vocal brought a rawer rock edge than Rush's mutedly operatic
    sheen. The song was a favorite of Branigan's to sing, and it
    continued to appear in even abbreviated set lists throughout
    the rest of her life.</p>
      <p>The song appears on the 2007 re-release of 
    <i>Touch</i>on Wounded Bird Records and on the collections 
    <i>The Best of Branigan</i>, 
    <i>The Essentials: Laura Branigan</i>and 
    <i>The Platinum Collection</i>.</p>
      <p>7" vinyl single/cassette single</p>
      <p>"The Power of Love" is the second (if counting "When I Fall
    in Love" as first) single from Céline Dion's 1993 album, 
    <i>The Colour of My Love</i>. It was released on November 1,
    1993 in North America, in December in Japan, and the next year
    in the rest of the world.</p>
      <p>"The Power of Love" is the second Jennifer Rush song Dion
    has covered. Earlier the same year she recorded a French
    adaptation of "Higher Ground," called "Plus haut que moi."</p>
      <p>The music video made for the radio edit was directed by
    Randee St. Nicholas and released in November 1993. It appeared
    on Dion's 2001 DVD video collection 
    <i>All the Way… A Decade of Song &amp; Video</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was nominated for a Grammy Award for Best Female
    Pop Vocal Performance and an American Music Award for Favorite
    Pop/Rock Single in 1995.</p>
      <p>"The Power of Love" was included on Céline Dion's greatest
    hits compilations: 
    <i>All the Way… A Decade of Song</i>in 1999 and 
    <i>My Love: Essential Collection</i>in 2008. Live versions of
    this song can be found on 
    <i>À l'Olympia</i>and 
    <i>Live à Paris</i>albums. It's one of the most often performed
    songs by Céline Dion. She sang it also five nights a week in
    her show 
    <i>A New Day...</i>at Caesars Palace, Las Vegas, and later
    during her 2008-09 Taking Chances Tour.</p>
      <p>"The Power of Love" became an international smash hit. The
    song rose to the top of the charts in the United States,
    Australia and Canada. In the U.S. it topped the Billboard Hot
    100 for 4 weeks, the first Céline Dion single to do so. It also
    went to number 1 for 5 weeks on the Hot 100 Singles Sales and
    to number 2 on the Billboard Hot 100 Airplay. It was also
    number 1 for 4 weeks on the Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks.</p>
      <p>The song spent 12 weeks at the top in Canada and 70 weeks on
    the chart in total. "The Power of Love" was a top 10 hit in the
    rest of the world (number 3 in France, number 4 in the United
    Kingdom and Belgium, number 6 in Sweden, number 7 in New
    Zealand). It was certified platinum in the U.S. (1,120,000
    copies sold) and Australia (70,000), gold in New Zealand
    (5,000) and silver in France (225,000 copies sold).</p>
      <p>Japanese CD single</p>
      <p>Worldwide CD single</p>
      <p>European CD maxi single</p>
      <p>Japanese CD maxi single</p>
      <p>Anglo-Australian duo Air Supply reversed the pronouns in the
    chorus ("You are my lady, and I am your man") in their
    recording of the song from their 1985 album. It only peaked at
    number 68 on the Billboard Hot 100 but peaked at number 13 on
    Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks. Other male artists to have
    recorded the English version of the song include Andrea Bocelli
    and Michael Crawford. In addition to Jennifer Rush, Laura
    Branigan and Celine Dion, other female artists to have recorded
    the English version of the song include Nana Mouskouri and
    Shirley Bassey.</p>
      <p>In Spanish the song was dubbed "Si Tú Eres Mi Hombre" ("If
    You Are My Man") and has been recorded by many Latin artists
    like Yolandita Monge, Amanda Miguel, Angela Carrasco, La India,
    also by Los Melódicos, and Operación Triunfo alumna Dulce. Some
    versions of the song have been made in a Latin style featuring
    salsa and merengue rhythms. Brazilian singer Rosana recorded a
    Portuguese version, "O Amor e o Poder," in the 1980s. Dominican
    singer Anaís sang a Spanglish version of the song in her Así
    Soy Yo Tour concerts.</p>
      <p>Petra Janů, a Czech female singer, recorded with the band
    Golem Jana Václavíka a Czechoslovakian version of the song, "Už
    nejsem volná", which she released as a single from her album 
    <i>Už nejsem volná</i>(1986). Janů released a live version in
    1988 and re-recorded the song in 1997. A German version, "Die
    Macht der Liebe," made it onto West German pop charts in the
    1980s. A Punjabi version of the song ("Sitam," sung by Amar)
    was featured in the 2002 film 
    <i>Bend It Like Beckham</i>. Japanese singer Yuna Ito recorded
    the song for her sophomore album 
    <i>Wish</i>.</p>
      <p>A Swedish song with a different theme, "Ängel i natt"
    ("Angel Tonight"), was written and recorded to the music of
    "The Power of Love" in 1985 by Elisabeth Andreassen. In 1995,
    Swedish dansband Sten &amp; Stanley recorded "Ängel i
    natt."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
