<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jailhouse_Rock_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jailhouse_Rock_(song)</songId>
   <title>Jailhouse Rock "/ "Treat Me Nice" Elvis Presley</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chances_Are_(song)</artistId>
      <artistName>"Chances Are" Johnny Mathis</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1957-10-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>September 24, 1957</released>
   <formats>
      <format>45 rpm single</format>
      <format>78 rpm single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1956</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock And Roll</genre>
   </genres>
   <writers>
      <writer>Leiber/Stoller</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Leiber/Stoller</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Jailhouse Rock" is a song written by Jerry Leiber and Mike
    Stoller that first became a hit for Elvis Presley. The song was
    first released as a 45rpm single on September 24, 1957, to
    coincide with the release of Presley's motion picture, 
    <i>Jailhouse Rock</i>. Composer Mike Stoller can be seen
    playing piano in the film presentation of the song.</p>
      <p>The song as sung by Elvis Presley is #67 on Rolling Stone's
    list of The 500 Greatest Songs of All Time and was named one of
    The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame's 500 Songs that Shaped Rock and
    Roll.</p>
      <p>The single, with its B-side "Treat Me Nice," was a US #1 hit
    for 7 weeks in the fall of 1957, and a UK #1 hit for three
    weeks early in 1958. in addition "Jailhouse Rock" spent one
    week at the top of the country charts .</p>
      <p>Also in 1957, "Jailhouse Rock" was the lead song in an EP
    (extended play single), together with other songs from the
    film, namely "Young and Beautiful," "I Want to be Free," "Don't
    Leave Me Now," and "(You're So Square) Baby I Don't Care." It
    topped the 
    <i>Billboard</i>EP charts, eventually selling an additional two
    million copies and earning another double-platinum RIAA
    certification.</p>
      <p>In 2005, the song was re-released in the UK and reached #1
    for a single week. The song, which is an example of simple
    verse form, eventually sold four million copies in the US, thus
    earning a Double Platinum certification by the RIAA.</p>
      <p>Some of the characters named in the song are real people.
    Shifty Henry was a well known L.A. musician, not a criminal.
    The Purple Gang was a real mob. "Bugs" was probably Bugsy
    Siegel, the Jewish gangster. "Sad Sack" was a U.S. Army
    nickname in World War II for a loser, who also became a popular
    comic strip and comic book character.</p>
      <p>As noted by 
    <i>Rolling Stone magazine</i>parts of the lyrics in which the
    prisoners flirt and dance with one another may be hinting at
    homosexual relationships between inmates.</p>
      <p>"Jailhouse Rock" was performed regularly in a medley along
    with many old rock and roll hits by Queen and was the opening
    song on Queen's 1980 North American tour for 
    <i>The Game</i>. It was the last song in the motion picture 
    <i>The Blues Brothers</i>. This song was featured on 
    <i>American Idol</i>when Season 5 contestant Taylor Hicks
    performed it on May 9, 2006 and when Season 7 contestant Danny
    Noriega performed it on February 20, 2008. The song was also
    featured in Disney's animated film 
    <i>Lilo &amp; Stitch</i>during the ending credits. In an
    episode of 
    <i>Full House</i>Jesse and Becky sing this song at their
    wedding reception.</p>
      <p>The German rock band Spider Murphy Gang is named after one
    of the characters in the lyrics. In Stephen King's novel
    Christine, "Jailhouse Rock" is playing when the car runs down
    Buddy Repperton, one of the guys who smashed up the car at the
    garage.</p>
      <p>American rock and roll revival act Sha Na Na performed 
    <i>Jailhouse Rock</i>live at the Woodstock Festival in August
    of 1969.</p>
      <p>"Jailhouse Rock" has also been recorded by:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
