<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Believe_(Cher_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Believe_(Cher_song)</songId>
   <title>Believe</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cher</artistId>
      <artistName>Cher</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1999-03-13</week>
      <week>1999-03-20</week>
      <week>1999-03-27</week>
      <week>1999-04-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/7a/Cher-believe-cover.JPG/200px-Cher-believe-cover.JPG</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Cher+Believe.JPG</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Believe</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 18, 1998 ( UK ) , October 19, 1998 ( France ) , November 24, 1998 ( US ) , April 20, 1999 ( Canada ) , May 25, 1999 ( Japan )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>CD maxi-single</format>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1998</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>House</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:01</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Warner Bros. , Wea</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Brian Higgins</writer>
      <writer>Stuart McLennen</writer>
      <writer>Paul Barry</writer>
      <writer>Steven Torch</writer>
      <writer>Matthew Gray</writer>
      <writer>Timothy Powell</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mark Taylor</producer>
      <producer>Brian Rawling</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Believe" is a pop song by American singer-actress Cher. It
    was released in most countries at the end of 1998 by Warner
    Bros., as the first single from her twenty third album, 
    <i>Believe</i>.</p>
      <p>It became one of the best-selling singles of all time.
    having sold over 10 million copies worldwide. It won the 2000
    Grammy Award for Best Dance Recording and was also nominated
    for Record of the Year.</p>
      <p>"Believe" is noted for its use of the Auto-Tune
    pitch-correction software on the singer's vocals to create a
    peculiar sound effect, sometimes referred to as the "Cher
    effect".</p>
      <p>As released, the single incorporates the work of six
    different songwriters, two producers and executive producer Rob
    Dickins, the erstwhile chairman of Warner Bros, but according
    to Mark Taylor the creation of "Believe" was a "strange one."
    Originally written only by Brian Higgins, Matthew Gray, Stuart
    McLennen and Tim Powell and circulated on Warner as a demo for
    months, nobody wanted it. Mark Taylor said that:</p>
      <p>"Everyone loved the chorus but not the rest of the song; As
    we were already writing other songs for Cher, Rob asked us if
    we could sort it out. Two of our writers, Steve Torch and Paul
    Barry, got involved and eventually came up with a complete song
    that Rob and Cher were happy with."</p>
      <p>Once the demo version was agreed, Mark and Brian took over
    for the actual production, working at Dreamhouse; Mark
    said:</p>
      <p>"We knew the rough direction to take, because Rob had said
    he wanted to make a Cher dance record. The hard part was trying
    to make one that wouldn't alienate Cher's existing fans."</p>
      <p>The entire track was assembled with Cubase VST on an iMac G3
    computer, with other synthesizers, including a Clavia Nord Rack
    and an Oberheim Matrix 1000, while Cher's vocals were recorded
    on three TASCAM DA88 digital audio recorders with a Neumann U67
    vacuum tube-amplified microphone.</p>
      <p>The song was recorded approximately in ten days in Surrey,
    England and also contains samples from the Electric Light
    Orchestra songs "Prologue" and "Epilogue."</p>
      <p>Cher's voice is altered by a pitch correction speed that is
    "set too fast for the audio that it is processing." Producer
    Mark Taylor added the effect to Cher's vocal simply as a lark.
    In interviews at the time, he claimed to be testing out his
    recently purchased DigiTech Talker. It later emerged that the
    effect was not created by a vocoder, but by using extreme (and
    then-unheard-of) settings on Antares Auto-Tune software.</p>
      <p>Taylor said about the effect that "this was the most
    nerve-wracking part of the project, because I wasn't sure what
    Cher would say when she heard what I'd done to her voice", but
    that when she heard it she said, "It sounds great." When her
    record company requested that the effect be removed, she
    responded, "Over my dead body!". After the massive success of
    the song, use of Auto-Tune became very popular and many other
    artists imitated this technique, and it would eventually become
    known as the "Cher effect".</p>
      <p>
         <i>Billboard</i>gave the song a positive review, saying that
    the song is "the best darn thing that Cher has recorded in
    years".</p>
      <p>The song, recorded and released in 1998, peaked at number
    one in 23 countries worldwide. On January 12, 1999, it reached
    the Top 40 on the Billboard Hot 100 and reached number one on
    the chart on March 2, making Cher the oldest female artist (at
    the age of 52) to perform this feat. Cher also set the record
    for a solo artist with the longest span of time between #1
    hits. Her previous #1 hit, "Dark Lady" had been in 1974.
    "Believe" also was ranked as the number-one song of 1999 by 
    <i>Billboard</i>on both the Billboard Hot 100 and Hot Dance
    Club Play charts, and became the biggest single in her entire
    career. "Believe" also spent seven weeks at number one in the
    UK singles chart and is still the best selling single by a
    female artist in the UK.</p>
      <p>The success of the song not only expanded through each
    country's singles chart, but also most countries' dance charts.
    In the United States "Believe" spent 23 weeks on the U.S. Hot
    Dance Club Play chart, five of those weeks at #1, and 22 weeks
    on the European Hot Dance Charts. "Believe" also set a record
    in 1999 after spending 21 weeks in the top spot of the
    Billboard Hot Dance Singles Sales chart, it was still in the
    top ten even one year after its entry on the chart..</p>
      <p>On 13 October 2008, the song was voted #10 on Australian
    VH1's Top 10 Number One Pop Songs countdown. "Believe" was
    nominated for Record of the Year and Best Dance Recording at
    42nd Grammy Awards, it won the latter. It is the only Grammy
    that Cher has won in her entire music career.</p>
      <p>The international music video for "Believe", directed by
    Nigel Dick, features Cher in a nightclub in a double role as
    singer on stage, and as supernatural being in a cage (with
    auto-tuned voice), surrounded by many people to whom she is
    giving advice. The video includes a woman who is broken hearted
    and feels that she can't go on when she sees her ex-boyfriend
    with a new spouse. The version on The Very Best of Cher: The
    Video Hits Collection is slightly different to the previous
    version (the version that is also included on the Mallay
    Believe Bonus VCD) with additional scenes towards the end that
    were not in the original video. There are also 2 'rough'
    versions of the video as the song was released in The UK and
    Europe before a video was completed. The first is a compilation
    of scenes from the videos of Cher's previous singles "One by
    One" and "Walkin' in Memphis" and the second includes a brief
    scene of the Believe video where Cher sings the chorus while
    the rest of the video is composed of scenes from "One by
    One".</p>
      <p>Three official remix videos exist for this song. Two of the
    remix videos were created by Dan-O-Rama in 1999. Both follow
    different concepts from the original unmixed video. Instead of
    showing the significance of the lyrics the videos mostly show
    Cher with different colored backgrounds and people dancing. The
    two remixes used for these videos were the Almighty Definitive
    Mix and the Club 69 Phunk Club Mix. The third video entitled
    Wayne G. Remix was released by Warner Bros. and the concept is
    similar to the Club 69 Phunk Club Mix video.</p>
      <p>Cher performed the song during the Do You Believe? Tour, The
    Farewell Tour and the Cher at the Colosseum While she would
    lip-synch the entire song on various television programs, she
    would only lip-synch the synthesized verses when performing on
    her Believe and Farewell tours and on the 2002 edition of VH1
    Divas Live Since 1999, the song has been the encore to all of
    Cher's concerts.</p>
      <p>In the episode "Living Conditions" of the TV series 
    <i>Buffy the Vampire Slayer</i>, Buffy's roommate listens to
    this song repeatedly.</p>
      <p>The song is featured on the Karaoke Revolution video
    game.</p>
      <p>A cover version of this song was used in the Nintendo DS
    game Elite Beat Agents in the first bonus level.</p>
      <p>Indie rock bands Macha and Bedhead recorded a cover of the
    song on their 2000 joint EP 
    <i>Macha Loved Bedhead</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2001, "Ian Watkins" from the British pop group Steps
    performed this song during their Gold Greatest Hits Tour.</p>
      <p>In the 2009 movie adaptation of Land of the Lost, two of the
    main characters, Dr. Rick Marshall and Will Stanton, sing the
    song while touching a vibrating "vortext triangle"</p>
      <p>The 
    <i>South Park</i>episode 
    <i>Two Guys Naked in a Hot Tub</i>lampoons the song. The kids
    in the episode hate the song; the adults love it.</p>
      <p>In 
    <i>Brothers &amp; Sisters</i>episode 12 of season 2 titled
    "Compromises", the Sarah Walker character, played by Rachel
    Griffiths, sings a karaoke version of the song in the aftermath
    of the break-up with her husband Joe, played by John
    Pyper-Ferguson.</p>
      <p>The song is also used in the Friends episode in which Monica
    Geller and Chandler Bing, before their wedding, go to see
    Chandler's father in Vegas to invite him to their wedding and
    reconcile.</p>
      <p>In the film Land of the Lost (film) when Marshall and Will
    touch the Pylon, they make reference to Cher by singing Believe
    as the Pylon changes their voices with its energy field as if
    it was an auto-tune device.</p>
      <p>Believe US CD Single</p>
      <p>Believe US/Canadian Maxi Single</p>
      <p>Believe European/UK CD Single Pt. 1</p>
      <p>Believe European/UK CD Single Pt. 2</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
