<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_Lady_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_Lady_(song)</songId>
   <title>Dark Lady</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cher</artistId>
      <artistName>Cher</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-03-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/51/Dark_Lady_%28song%29.jpg/200px-Dark_Lady_%28song%29.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Cher+Dark-Lady.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Dark Lady</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 1974</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1973/74</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Adult Contemporary</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:27</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Johnny Durrell</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Snuff Garrett</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Dark Lady" is an pop rock song recorded by American singer
    actress Cher from eleventh studio album, 
    <i>Dark Lady</i>. Produced by Snuff Garrett, it was released as
    the album's first single in early 1974. The song became Cher's
    third solo U.S. number one hit on March 23, 1974 and her last
    until "Believe" a quarter-century later.</p>
      <p>"Dark Lady" was written by The Ventures keyboard player
    Johnny Durrill. He recalled: "I spent a week in his (Snuff
    Garrett's) office playing him songs, one of which Cher
    recorded. Later, when I was on tour in Japan with the Ventures,
    I was writing an interesting song. I telegraphed the unfinished
    lyrics to Garrett. He said to 'make sure the bitch kills him.'
    Hence, in the song both the lover and fortune teller were
    killed."</p>
      <p>The "Dark Lady" of the song's title is a fortune teller. The
    narrator of the song learns that her lover has been unfaithful
    to her with, as the fortune teller says, "someone else who is
    very close to you." The narrator returns home in a state of
    shock and then realizes that she had once smelled, in her own
    room, the perfume the fortune teller had been wearing. She
    races back to the fortune teller's place with a gun and catches
    her lover and the fortune teller "laughing and kissing", and
    shoots them both to death in a fit of rage.</p>
      <p>In 1974, "Dark Lady" topped the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 for
    one week, becoming Cher's third solo #1 hit. The song was also
    a #1 hit in Canada and Sweden, a top ten hit in Norway and a
    top twenty hit in the Netherlands. Like 
    <i>Half-Breed</i>, the song struggled in Germany and the UK,
    though it managed to reach top forty status in the UK.</p>
      <p>There are two version of the video. The first version of the
    video is a live performance that was aired in the third season
    of The Sonny &amp; Cher Comedy Hour in 1973. In this
    performance Cher was dressed in all black and was wearing a
    black veil on her head. The second video of the song is a
    cartoon. This second video follows the whole story of the
    song.</p>
      <p>In 2002, a special remix medley was created by Dan-O-Rama
    for a video montage that was used in Cher's Living Proof: The
    Farewell Tour. The medley contains videos of "All I Really Want
    to Do", "Gypsys, Tramps &amp; Thieves", "Half-Breed" and "Dark
    Lady". Unlike the other videos "Dark Lady" was unique because
    both, the live and the cartoon videos had been mixed.</p>
      <p>In 1999, Cher performed this song throughout her Do You
    Believe? Tour, for the first time in twenty-five years. In
    2002, she performed the song 325 times in her Living Proof: The
    Farewell Tour.</p>
      <p>Cher performed the song on the following concert tours:</p>
      <p>In 1974, Finnish singer Lea Laven covered this song under
    the title "Tumma Nainen", and the song proved successful in
    Finland.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
