<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_Times_(Chic_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_Times_(Chic_song)</songId>
   <title>Good Times</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chic_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Chic</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1979-08-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/1c/Chicgoodtimes.jpg/200px-Chicgoodtimes.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Chic+Good-Times.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Risqué</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1979</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1979</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:24 (7")</length>
      <length>8:08 (12"/LP)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic 3584</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bernard Edwards</writer>
      <writer>Nile Rodgers</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bernard Edwards</producer>
      <producer>Nile Rodgers</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Good Times" is a 1979 song composed by Bernard Edwards and
    Nile Rodgers. It was first recorded by their band Chic, for
    their 1979 album 
    <i>Risqué</i>. In August of that year, it became the band's
    second number one single on both the Billboard Hot 100 and soul
    singles chart. Along with the tracks, "My Forbidden Lover", and
    "My Feet Keep Dancing", "Good Times" reached number three on
    the disco charts The song has become one of the most sampled
    tunes in music history, most notably in rap and hip-hop
    music.</p>
      <p>The song is ranked #224 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time.</p>
      <p>The lyrics are largely based on Milton Ager's "Happy Days
    Are Here Again." It also contains lines based on lyrics
    featured in "About a Quarter to Nine" made famous by Al Jolson.
    Nile Rodgers has stated that these depression-era lyrics were
    used as a hidden way to comment on the then-current economic
    depression in the United States. The line during the chorus,
    "Our new state of mind", is infamous for being mistaken as "Are
    you straight or bi?"</p>
      <p>In late 1979, Debbie Harry suggested that Nile Rodgers join
    her and Chris Stein at a Hip hop event in a communal space
    taken over by young kids and teenagers with boom box stereos,
    who would play various pieces of music to which performers
    would break dance. The main piece of music they would use was
    the break section of "Good Times." A few weeks later, Blondie,
    The Clash and Chic were playing a gig in New York at Bonds
    nightclub. When Chic started playing "Good Times," rapper Fab
    Five Freddy and members of the Sugarhill Gang jumped up on
    stage and started freestyling with the band; Rodgers allowed
    them to "do their improvisation thing like poets, much like I
    would playing guitar with Prince."</p>
      <p>A few weeks later Rodgers was on the dance floor of New York
    club LaViticus and suddenly heard the DJ play a song which
    opened with Edwards bass line from "Good Times". Rogers
    approached the DJ who said he was playing a record he had just
    bought that day in Harlem. The song turned out to be an early
    version of "Rapper's Delight" by The Sugarhill Gang, which
    Rogers noted also included a scratched version of the song's
    string section. Rogers and Edwards threatened The Sugarhill
    Gang with legal action, which resulted in them being credited
    as co-writers on "Rappers Delight".</p>
      <p>In the USA "Rapper's Delight" did not achieve as much chart
    success as "Good Times" (peaking at #36 on the U.S. pop chart
    and #4 on the American R&amp;B charts, compared to Chic's #1
    peak on both charts) but it helped to popularize the bassline
    and the song, and it became one of the most sampled tracks (and
    hence one of the most distinctive basslines) in the history of
    recorded music. Having agreed on a commercial structure for the
    use of their song in "Rappers Delight", Edwards and Rodgers
    agreed to later uses in other songs, subject to their strict
    criteria.</p>
      <p>This is an incomplete list of songs that either use direct
    samples from "Good Times", or feature an original recording
    where the bassline or other motifs (particularly that of the
    instrumental break) are inspired by the song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
