<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/What_a_Girl_Wants_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/What_a_Girl_Wants_(song)</songId>
   <title>What a Girl Wants</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christina_Aguilera</artistId>
      <artistName>Christina Aguilera</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2000-01-15</week>
      <week>2000-01-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/4a/Christina_Aguilera_-_What_a_Girl_Wants_CD_cover.jpg/200px-Christina_Aguilera_-_What_a_Girl_Wants_CD_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Christina-Aguilera+What-a-Girl-Wants.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Christina Aguilera</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 28, 1999</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>CD maxi single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>September 1999</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Teen Pop</genre>
      <genre>Bubblegum Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:35 (Video/New Album Version)</length>
      <length>3:20 (Radio Version)</length>
      <length>3:52 (Original Album Version)</length>
      <length>3:14 (Spanish Version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Shelly Peiken</writer>
      <writer>Guy Roche</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Guy Roche</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"What a Girl Wants" is the second single from Christina
    Aguilera's debut album, 
    <i>Christina Aguilera</i>. Released in late 1999, the single
    peaked at number one on the Billboard Hot 100 on January 15,
    2000 for two weeks, becoming Aguilera's second number-one
    single. In the U.S., it became the first #1 single of the
    2000s. The single also peaked at number three in the UK and at
    number five in Australia. Often considered one of her signature
    songs, the single is most known for establishing Aguilera's
    placement in the music industry. Many critics had written off
    the success of her last single, "Genie in a Bottle", as a
    fluke; "What a Girl Wants" served to prove that Aguilera was
    not a one-hit wonder. The single earned her five MTV Video
    Music Awards nominations; Best Female Video, Best New Artist,
    Best Pop Video, Viewer's Choice, and Best Choreography (Tina
    Landon), and also a Grammy Award nomination for Best Female Pop
    Vocal Performance in 2001.</p>
      <p>The song appears on the game .</p>
      <p>The song's music video was directed by Diane Martel.</p>
      <p>"What a Girl Wants" was written by Shelly Peiken and Guy
    Roche, and was produced by Roche as well. In her first anthem
    dedicated to appreciating gentlemen, Aguilera wants to thank a
    man who stood by her, and did not abandon her while she was
    confused and needed time to 'breathe'. He knew exactly what his
    girl wanted and needed. To show her appreciation for the guy in
    her life, Aguilera sings, "What a girl wants, what a girl
    needs; Whatever makes me happy and sets you free, and I'm
    thanking you for knowing exactly..". Unlike her previous
    single, "Genie in a Bottle", this song is not meant to deal
    with the sexual aspect of relationships, but rather the
    romantic and loving part of them, despite the fact that a few
    of the lyrics suggest otherwise (e.g. "What I want is what you
    got, What you got is what I want").</p>
      <p>Besides "Genie in a Bottle" and "Beautiful", the song is
    often considered to be one of her signature songs, but
    ironically, it almost did not become the second single.
    Aguilera's record company, RCA Records, had originally felt
    that the track "So Emotional" should become the second single.
    The label even promoted the song as if it were a single by
    having Aguilera perform the song on several occasions, such as
    on 
    <i>TRL</i>and 
    <i>Soul Train</i>. Aguilera felt that was a poor choice for the
    next single and that she would end up as a one hit wonder if it
    became the next single.</p>
      <p>Originally her insecurities were brushed off by RCA, but
    Aguilera continued to fight. Her record company finally
    relented, and "What a Girl Wants" was given the go-ahead to be
    the next single. However, Aguilera was still not comfortable as
    she felt that the song did not have single potential in its
    current form. Instead, she decided that the song needed to be
    remixed and re-recorded (as the original album version of "What
    a Girl Wants" had been a slow jam unsuitable for pop radio at
    the time). When redone, the new version of "What a Girl Wants"
    kept much of the original melody, but showed new energy and
    zest as the song was now uptempo, had new lyrics, a new bridge,
    a Baroque-style breakdown and new powerful vocals (since the
    original album version had been recorded in June 1998,
    Aguilera's vocal strength had increased considerably).</p>
      <p>As the new version of the song was not on the original
    album, the album was re-released with the video version of the
    new version replacing the original version. For fans of
    Aguilera who already had the album and did not want to buy it
    again, the Radio Edit of the new version was also released as
    one of the last major releases of CD singles in the U.S. The
    Spanish version, "Una Mujer" (English: "A Woman"), is included
    on 
    <i>Mi Reflejo</i>.</p>
      <p>Aguilera has sung "What a Girl Wants" differently from the
    album version since around 2002. Her most noticeable change has
    been on the Justified and Stripped Tour, where she changed
    tempo, and sings the word knew in "You're the one who always
    knew" regularly, but built up into whistle register and whistle
    register vocal acrobatics. Aguilera also sang the song in her
    2006 - 2007's tour 
    <i>Back to Basics Tour</i>but sang it in a reggae style with no
    whistle notes.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by Diane Martel, who also done
    a music video for Aguilera's previous and chart topping single
    "Genie in a Bottle". The video begins with Aguilera and her
    friends walking into an arcade-themed room, dancing for a group
    of guys, including then-unknown actor Brandon Routh. Suddenly
    the music video breaks into a scene where Aguilera is seen
    laying down wearing a corset, with a group of girls dancing
    around her. Then it returns to its original scene, where
    Aguilera continues dancing for a group of guys with her
    friends. The video ends with Aguilera in the arms of her love
    interest. The music video became the 6th most requested ever on
    TRL. The video was shot in early November 1999 and premiered on
    November 25, 1999 on MTV's Total Request Live.</p>
      <p>The song appeared in the 2000 hit romantic comedy 
    <i>What Women Want</i>starring Mel Gibson and Helen Hunt.</p>
      <p>US Promo CD [1]</p>
      <p>US 3-track Promo [2]</p>
      <p>2 Track US CD single</p>
      <p>US/Germany single</p>
      <p>Maxi-CD</p>
      <p>US Promo Remixes</p>
      <p>UK Promo CD [3]</p>
      <p>UK CD 1'</p>
      <p>'UK CD 2</p>
      <p>Japanese Promo [4]</p>
      <p>Germany Maxi-CD</p>
      <p>After the massive success of Aguilera's number-one debut
    single "Genie in a Bottle", there was pressure for its
    follow-up to succeed, as well. "What a Girl Wants" proved to be
    another big hit, though not to quite the same degree as "Genie
    in a Bottle". The song topped the Billboard Hot 100 and Hot 100
    Singles Sales charts for two weeks, and peaked at number two on
    the Hot 100 Airplay; the single's strong sales would later
    assure it a gold certification. Once again, the song was an
    all-around huge hit, topping the Top 40 Tracks, Top 40
    Mainstream and Rhythmic Top 40 charts. The track was
    international success, reaching #3 in the U.K.. "What a Girl
    Wants" also entered the Top 10 in Canada, landing at #5.</p>
      <p>A CD maxi single release late into the song's run helped the
    song peak at number two on the Hot Dance Music/Maxi-Singles
    Sales; unfortunately in terms of club play, the song was not as
    successful peaking at number eighteen on Hot Dance Club Play.
    There are several different versions of "What a Girl Wants"
    including the Adult Contemporary Mix which includes lyrics from
    the video version, but a track closer the original album
    version.</p>
      <p>Elsewhere, the single fared success within the top twenty in
    most countries. The single also reached #1 in New Zealand,
    where it held that position for 5 consecutive weeks. During the
    week of March 13, 2000, Aguilera visited the country while the
    single remained at #1. "What a Girl Wants" was certified Gold
    in New Zealand for selling more than 7,500 units, and certified
    gold in Sweden. It landed at #19 on the Year-End charts in
    America and #32 in New Zealand.</p>
      <p>A different version was used as the single version than the
    album version. In the video, a slightly altered version of the
    single version is used, which includes a classical-themed
    breakdown in the video and an extended ending in the video
    version as well. Four official remixes were released in the US
    on the CD maxi-single, including two each by Eddie Arroyo and
    Thunderpuss. Further remixes were released on international
    versions of the single.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
