<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Come_on_Over_Baby_(All_I_Want_Is_You) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Come_on_Over_Baby_(All_I_Want_Is_You)</songId>
   <title>Come on Over Baby (All I Want Is You)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christina_Aguilera</artistId>
      <artistName>Christina Aguilera</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2000-10-14</week>
      <week>2000-10-21</week>
      <week>2000-10-28</week>
      <week>2000-11-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/ac/Christina_Aguilera_-_Come_on_Over_CD_cover.jpg/200px-Christina_Aguilera_-_Come_on_Over_CD_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Christina-Aguilera+Come-on-Over-Baby-All-I-Want-Is-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Christina Aguilera</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 26, 2000</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1998 (original version) , May 2000 (re-recorded version)</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>Teen Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:23 (Radio/New album version)</length>
      <length>3:41 (Video Version)</length>
      <length>3:07 (Original album version)</length>
      <length>3:11 (Spanish version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Johan Aberg</writer>
      <writer>Paul Rein</writer>
      <writer>Christina Aguilera</writer>
      <writer>Ron Fair</writer>
      <writer>C. Blackmon</writer>
      <writer>R. Cham</writer>
      <writer>E. Dawkins</writer>
      <writer>Shelly Peiken</writer>
      <writer>Guy Roche</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Ron Fair</producer>
      <producer>Celebrity Status</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Come On Over Baby (All I Want Is You)" is a song co-written
    by American pop singer Christina Aguilera, Paul Rein, Johan
    Aberg, Celebrity Status (C. Blackmon, R. Cham, E. Dawkins), Guy
    Roche, Shelly Peiken and Ron Fair for Aguilera's debut album 
    <i>Christina Aguilera</i>(1999). It was co-produced by Fair and
    Celebrity Status.</p>
      <p>The song is about Aguilera eying a prospective boyfriend and
    declaring 
    <i>come on over baby ... 'cause all I want is you</i>. It was
    released as the album's fourth single in the summer of 2000
    (see 2000 in music), and was the first single on which Aguilera
    had been given significant creative control. It peaked at
    number one in the U.S., and was very successful elsewhere as
    well. This was also the first time in which Aguilera was
    allowed to toy with her image in the music video for the song,
    kicking off a long evolution of looks the singer would end up
    doing over the span of her career. The brand new look, which
    included more revealing outfits and streaks of red and blue in
    her hair, was also used for her debut Spanish language album 
    <i>Mi Reflejo</i>and also for her first headlining tour in
    Summer 2000.</p>
      <p>The Spanish version of the song is called "Ven Conmigo
    (Solamente Tú)".</p>
      <p>Both music videos - "Come On Over Baby (All I Want Is You)"
    and "Ven Conmigo (Solamente Tú)" - were directed by Paul Hunter
    from June 12–13, 2000.</p>
      <p>Like "What a Girl Wants" (the second single from 
    <i>Christina Aguilera</i>), a new remixed and re-recorded
    version of "Come On Over Baby (All I Want Is You)" was released
    as a single rather than the original album version. The album
    version, which had been known simply as "Come On Over (All I
    Want Is You)", was seen as unsuitable for single release. Since
    the single had been originally produced and written by Paul
    Rein and Johan Aberg in 1998, the pair were given the first
    opportunity to change the song. Aguilera and Ron Fair (her
    mentor) were not impressed with their efforts, and turned to
    the producing team known only as Celebrity Status in May
    2000.</p>
      <p>With Celebrity Status and Ron Fair producing, "Come On Over
    (All I Want Is You)" (the album version) was transformed into
    "Come On Over Baby (All I Want Is You)" with a more pop
    oriented, hip hop-influenced production (as opposed to the
    original piano rich production). New and more sexual lyrics, a
    chord progression for the song's b-section, a bridge (the
    original song did not have a bridge), a "rap" from Aguilera, a
    new mid-song dance breakdown, and more powerful vocals by
    Aguilera were also added. (The song also features limited new
    elements from Guy Roche and Shelly Peiken.)</p>
      <p>As the original album version does not have a bridge, it had
    previously been performed live with an interlude that sampled
    the disco song "Got to Be Real" by Cheryl Lynn. When the
    original songwriters of "Got to Be Real" were contacted for
    permission to sample their song, they denied clearance.
    Instead, Aguilera's team added a part to the song referencing
    "What a Girl Wants":</p>
      <p>You give me, what a girl feels, what a girl likes, what a
    girl needs, what a girl wants.</p>
      <p>Aguilera helped write the song's controversial and slightly
    sexual rap section: (not in the album version)</p>
      <p>Don't ya wanna be the one tonight? We can do exactly what
    you like. Don't ya wanna be just you and me? We can do what
    comes naturally.</p>
      <p>This rap (and also a section in the second verse in which
    Aguilera discusses sexuality and a man's hands on her body)
    caused Radio Disney to ban the song initially, as it had done
    to "Genie in a Bottle" (the album's first single). The original
    album version of the song, "Come On Over (All I Want Is You)",
    was allowed to be played, and an edited version of "Come On
    Over Baby" (which removed the second verse and the rap) was
    also given some airplay. Reportedly, the edited single version
    received more airplay on the station than the album version of
    the song.</p>
      <p>Major tracks released for "Come on Over Baby (All I Want Is
    You)".</p>
      <p>UK single</p>
      <p>US Single[1]</p>
      <p>US Maxi-CD</p>
      <p>Australia single</p>
      <p>UK Vinyl, 12"</p>
      <p>Directed by Paul Hunter, the music video begins with
    Aguilera talking on the phone with her boyfriend, telling him
    to come over her house. After she hangs up the phone, the scene
    breaks out into Aguilera wearing a white midriff and white
    pants, with red streaks in her hair. In the next scene,
    Aguilera has loose braided pigtails, a blue midriff, and blue
    and white checkered pants. She is in her bedroom, when suddenly
    her and her backup dancers begin dancing in front of a white
    background. The male dancers come out, and begin dancing with
    the female dancers. After that, Aguilera and her then-real life
    boyfriend Jorge Santos dance together with her backup dancers
    in the scene where everyone is wearing yellow and green
    outfits, first in a yellow-green background followed by a
    yellow-orange background. The next scene is where her dancers
    dance on chairs in white open-faced cubes, intercut with
    Aguilera singing in a blue-walled background and a white
    drapery background. Aguilera and her backup dancers then dance
    in front of a white background. It cuts into a scene where
    Aguilera walks down a flight of steps in a red room, with her
    backup dancers on each step. They begin dancing again, and
    Aguilera's backup dancers hold up pieces of puzzle paper that
    shows Aguilera's face.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Come on Over Baby (All I Want Is You)"
    was an instant hit, shooting to #1 on TRL. It featured a more
    racier image from Aguilera, quite different from her previous
    singles, Genie in a Bottle and I Turn To You. Unlike her
    previous singles, she had red streaks in her hair, and wore
    tighter clothing. The video was shot from June 12–13, 2000, and
    was the last music video from her chart topping self-entitled
    debut album, 
    <i>Christina Aguilera</i>. The image Aguilera used in "Come on
    over Baby (All I Want Is You)" was also used for 
    <i>Mi Reflejo</i>and her first headlining tour in 2000.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Ven Conmigo" was a bit different from
    "Come on Over (All I Want Is You), although some scenes were
    the same. In "Ven Conmigo", Aguilera wears darker eye makeup.
    Her lipstick is also light pink. In a few scenes she is seen
    sitting on a red bench in a white background. Both videos were
    directed by Paul Hunter.</p>
      <p>When the music video for "Come on Over Baby (All I Want Is
    You)" aired on the Disney channel, some scenes were edited out
    and some of the sexual lyrics were censored/muted.</p>
      <p>"Come On Over Baby (All I Want Is You)" became Aguilera's
    third number-one hit on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100, and the
    RIAA eventually certified the single gold. It spent twenty-one
    weeks on the Hot 100, and ranked thirty-eight on the Hot 100's
    2000 year-end charts. The Spanish-language version of the
    single, "Ven Conmigo (Solamente Tú)", sticking to the original
    arrangement, was also a huge latin music success, becoming
    Aguilera's first number-one single on Billboard's Hot Latin
    Tracks chart, and reaching #1 as well in Spain.</p>
      <p>After receiving a strong push from the record label and
    Aguilera herself, the single became a big hit for Aguilera,
    with many considering it a 'comeback' due to the slight
    underperformance of her previous single 
    <i>I Turn To You</i>. Not only did the single hit #1 on the
    Billboard Hot 100 and had stronger airplay than the previous
    single, but the video also became Aguilera's most popular video
    to date, becoming a huge #1 hit on TRL and receiving strong
    airplay on MTV, VH1, and even Disney and Nickeoldeon.</p>
      <p>"Come On Over Baby (All I Want Is You)" reached the top ten
    in the UK, Japan and Australia and the top twenty in Canada,
    but was less successful in Continental Europe, reaching the top
    forty in most markets. The single became yet another
    international success for Aguilera ,reaching #2 in New Zealand,
    where it stayed on the charts for 13 weeks. "Come on Over Baby
    (All I Want is You)" was eventually certified Gold in the U.S.
    for selling over 500,000 units in Physical CD sales. The single
    was also certified Platinum in Australia . "Come on Over"
    stayed at #1 on Billboard for four weeks, and stayed on the
    Australian charts for 20 weeks.</p>
      <p>The Spanish version of the single, "Ven Conmigo", peaked at
    #1 on the U.S. Latin Charts, and #4 in Argentina. "Ven Conmigo"
    became the only #1 single on the U.S. Latin Charts from her
    album 
    <i>Mi Reflejo</i>. "Ven Conmigo" peaked at #8 in Spain, making
    it her second Top 10 hit in Spain. "Come on Over" was featured
    on Aguilera's Greatest Hits album 
    <i>Keeps Gettin Better: A Decade Of Hits</i>. The single was
    released as a Maxi-CD Single during its release.</p>
      <p>Christina Aguilera performed "Come on Over Baby (All I Want
    is You)" at the 2000 MTV Video Music Awards. She wore a
    striking red tight outfit, with black streaks in her hair
    previous to how she wore them in her music video, black high
    heels, and a tight ruby red midriff. At the end of Aguilera's
    performance, Fred Durst walked onstage and performed part of
    his band's song "Livin' It Up" with Aguilera. After eliciting
    charged reactions from his fans, Durst stated: "I already told
    you guys before, I did it all for the nookie, man." The feud
    died weeks later. Aguilera denied Durst's statement, saying
    Durst "got no nookie". Aguilera and pop peer Britney Spears
    disproved rumors of a rivalry when they came onstage, holding
    hands, and introduced Whitney Houston. Christina also performed
    "Come on Over Baby (All I Want is You)" on her headlining 2007 
    <i>Back to Basics Tour</i>.</p>
      <p>The single was released to radio stations in the U.S. on
    September 26, 2000. The track was available in several formats,
    including a CD Single and maxi single. In the U.K. it was also
    released along with a cassette single, with the B Side of the
    track being the Radio Version and "Ven Conmigo". On the 12"
    U.K. Vinyl single, it featured two remixes by Blacksmtih Club
    Mix two Sunship remixes. On the Australian single, the CD
    featured "Come On Over Baby (All I Want Is You) [Radio
    version]", "Ven Conmigo (Solamente Tú)", and "I Turn To You"
    [Cutfeather &amp; Joe Remix].</p>
      <p>Notes:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
