<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genie_in_a_Bottle 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genie_in_a_Bottle</songId>
   <title>Genie in a Bottle</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christina_Aguilera</artistId>
      <artistName>Christina Aguilera</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1999-07-31</week>
      <week>1999-08-07</week>
      <week>1999-08-14</week>
      <week>1999-08-21</week>
      <week>1999-08-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/d2/Genie_In_A_Bottle_US.jpg/200px-Genie_In_A_Bottle_US.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Christina-Aguilera+Genie-in-a-Bottle.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Christina Aguilera</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 22, 1999</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>February 1999</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Bubblegum Pop</genre>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:36</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>David Frank</writer>
      <writer>Steve Kipner</writer>
      <writer>Pamela Sheyne</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>David Frank</producer>
      <producer>Steve Kipner</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Genie in a Bottle" is the first hit single and signature
    song from Christina Aguilera's debut album, 
    <i>Christina Aguilera</i>. It was co-written by David Frank,
    Steve Kipner, and Pamela Sheyne. The song was released on June
    22, 1999 as the album's lead single. It became a smash hit
    overnight, becoming one of Aguilera's most successful singles
    worldwide. The track went #1 on Billboard Hot 100 for five
    weeks, having had the longest stay at number one for the entire
    year. The track established Aguilera's place in pop culture as
    a pop phenomenon, going platinum within a few months of
    release. The single earned her a Grammy nomination for Best
    Female Pop Vocal Performance in 2000 and helped her win the
    Best New Artist Grammy that same year. Many consider this her
    signature song (along with "Beautiful").</p>
      <p>The song is featured on the video games 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Volume 2</i>and 
    <i>Dance Dance Revolution Extreme 2</i>.</p>
      <p>The Spanish version of the song is called "Genio Atrapado".
    The music videos for both "Genie in a Bottle" and "Genio
    Atrapado" were directed by Diane Martel.</p>
      <p>After being signed to RCA, Aguilera began working on her
    self-entitled debut album 
    <i>Christina Aguilera</i>. The track was written by Dan Frank,
    Steve Kipner and Pamela Sheyne. According to Aguilera's early
    songwriters who appeared on the documentary series Driven,
    Aguilera was not convinced that the track would highlight her
    voice. Her songwriter claimed that there was a "battle" between
    Aguilera and her producers because she wanted to display the
    power and audacity in her voice, whereas her producers would
    hold her back. The original title of the song was "If You Wanna
    Be With Me", but RCA thought "Genie in a Bottle" was more
    appealing to audiences.</p>
      <p>Directed by Diane Martel, filming took place in April 1999
    in Malibu. Aguilera wore tiny hip hugging outfits throughout
    the video, which stirred controversy. The press felt Aguilera
    was too young to wear erotic clothing and singing suggestive
    lyrics. Aguilera ended up re-recording the track for Radio
    Disney and 
    <i>Mi Reflejo</i>, which featured her hit "Genio Atrapado".</p>
      <p>The music video begins with Aguilera laying on a beach,
    wearing a white midriff and tiny shorts. In the next scene,
    she's seen wearing a jean outfit while sitting on a deck. The
    video suddenly breaks into a dance scene, where Aguilera wears
    a white midriff with orange pants and a mini turquoise shawl.
    Aguilera's friends in the music video come over to her house
    where they meet up with a group of guys driving a red
    chevrolet. She is then on top of the chevrolet on her knees
    singing, wearing a pink midriff and white capris. The music
    video ends with a guy chasing after Aguilera, and together they
    sit with a group of friends while a bonfire is lit.</p>
      <p>The video became an instant hit on MTV and other music
    channels, including TRL, and eventually retired on TRL.</p>
      <p>Aguilera performed at the 2008 MTV Video Music Awards in
    Hollywood. She previewed the remade version of it, called
    "Genie 2.0", wearing a tight leather outfit. She later
    performed the lead single of the compilation, "Keeps Gettin'
    Better".</p>
      <p>In her sexually driven debut single, Aguilera begins the
    song as a sexually repressed young woman stating that she feels
    like she's been "locked up tight for a century of lonely
    nights", and that she is waiting for sexual release. She then
    sees a young man who sexually arouses her, making her exclaim,
    "My body's saying let's go". However, even though her hormones
    are "racing at the speed of light", she realizes "my heart is
    saying no". Nevertheless, Aguilera offers herself to the man by
    stating, "If you wanna be with me, baby there's a price to pay,
    I'm a Genie in a Bottle, You gotta rub me the right way".</p>
      <p>The song's lyrics caused minor controversy at the time, as
    it was felt by some that Aguilera was too young to be singing
    such relatively suggestive lyrics, particularly as her music
    was marketed to young girls. The song was censored in some
    markets with tamer lyrics, in which Aguilera sings "you gotta
    treat me the right way" (instead of "you gotta rub me the right
    way"). The censored version was played in preteen-oriented
    markets such as Radio Disney.</p>
      <p>In Aguilera's 2006 album, 
    <i>Back to Basics</i>, a track dedicated to her fans titled 
    <i>"Thank You (Dedication to Fans...)"</i>used samples of Genie
    in a Bottle. Extracts used such as "I feel like I been locked
    up", "My body's saying let's go", "oh, oh, oh", "Come on, Come
    on" and "Baby, Baby, Baby". Aguilera refers to the lock up
    mentioned in the beginning of the song to her being a prisoner
    of her dreams.</p>
      <p>The song was released on June 22, 1999. Based on strong
    airplay and CD sales, "Genie in a Bottle" reached number one on
    the Billboard Hot 100 and stayed there for five consecutive
    weeks. At that point, it had the longest stay at number for the
    entire year, tying Ricky Martin's "Livin' La Vida Loca" and
    Jennifer Lopez's "If You Had My Love", although Santana would
    later in the year take the single, "Smooth", to number one on
    the chart with a ten-week run. The success of "Genie in a
    Bottle" marked the third time that year that a new female
    artist reached number one on the Hot 100 with her debut single,
    the first being Britney Spears with "...Baby One More Time" and
    the second being Jennifer Lopez with "If You Had My Love". The
    success and achievement for Spears' and Aguilera's debut
    singles caused a lot of rivalry and comparisons between the two
    in the media.</p>
      <p>The song also crossed-over successfully to other Billboard
    charts, topping the Top 40 Mainstream, Top 40 Tracks and
    Rhythmic Top 40 charts. The song even managed to reach the
    Adult Top 40, and the Spanish version of the song, "Genio
    Atrapado" (English: "Trapped Genie"), was a modest hit on the
    Latin chart. Strong sales assured the single a platinum
    certification. "Genie in a Bottle" stayed on Billboard Hot 100
    for 25 weeks, and 43 weeks in the U.K.. Internationally, a
    similar chart dominance was seen, as the track went to number
    one in both the UK and Canada for multiple weeks. It charted
    within the top five in every country it charted. Overall, the
    song is Aguilera's second-highest charting single, behind "Lady
    Marmalade", a collaboration with Lil' Kim, Mýa and Pink. "Genie
    in a Bottle" was certified platinum in Germany for selling over
    500,000 units. The single was also certified platinum in
    Australia for selling over 70,000 units.</p>
      <p>"Genie in a Bottle" became Aguilera's first #1 on the
    Worldwide Singles chart, where it stayed on the charts for 29
    weeks and ended up at no.3 onthe Year-End chart selling
    7,391,000 points. "Genie in a Bottle" was certified platinum in
    almost every country it was released in, making it's selling
    exceed over one million worldwide. It peaked at #7 on the
    Year-End charts in the U.S., and #7 on the European Year-End
    charts.</p>
      <p>Parodist 'Hawaiian Ryan' also recorded a spoof of the song,
    called "Weenie in a Bottle", one of the tracks from his Shaving
    Ryan's Privates album. This parody is often incorrectly
    attributed to "Weird Al" Yankovic. Aguilera also used the line
    "weenie in a bottle" when she played Samantha Jones at an
    episode of Saturday Night Live that she hosted in 2004, where
    in her character revealed to everyone that she was a man the
    entire time.</p>
      <p>The song was translated to "Genio Atrapado," ("Trapped
    Genie") in Spanish. It was the first single from the album 
    <i>Mi Reflejo</i>, which was Aguilera's first Spanish studio
    album.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Genio Atrapado" mostly remained the
    same from the English language version, "Genie in a Bottle,"
    except the scenes in which Aguilera actually sings were re-shot
    with a slightly different backdrop in order for her lips to
    match the Spanish lyrics. These re-shot scenes were mixed into
    scenes in which she is not singing from the original "Genie in
    a Bottle" music video in order to make it seem as if both
    videos are seamlessly the same.</p>
      <p>A new electronic version of the song, named "Genie 2.0", was
    performed at the 2008 MTV Video Music Awards, to commemorate
    Aguilera's first greatest hits compilation 
    <i>Keeps Gettin' Better: A Decade of Hits</i>and the 25th
    anniversary of the MTV Video Music Awards. Both the original
    version and the remake are included on 
    <i>Keeps Gettin' Better</i>.</p>
      <p>Aguilera performed "Genie in a Bottle" on her tour and at
    the 2008 MTV Video Music Awards. The Freelance Hellraiser
    created a bootleg remix of "Genie in a Bottle" and the
    instrumental track of The Strokes' "Hard to Explain", called "A
    Stroke of Genie-us". The remix was played on the UK radio
    station Xfm, and received favorable reviews. This song is one
    of the earliest examples of the mashup genre.</p>
      <p>"Genie in a Bottle" earned Aguilera a Grammy nomination for
    "Best Female Pop Vocal Performance" in 1999. The single earned
    Aguilera many awards, including "Best Selling New Artist" from
    the World Music Awards. On MTV Asia the track won the "Hotseat
    Artist Of The Month" award, proving that "Genie in a Bottle"
    had garnered worldwide success.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
