<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lady_Marmalade 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lady_Marmalade</songId>
   <title>Lady Marmalade</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christina_Aguilera</artistId>
      <artistName>Christina Aguilera, Lil' Kim, Mýa and Pink</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2001-06-02</week>
      <week>2001-06-09</week>
      <week>2001-06-16</week>
      <week>2001-06-23</week>
      <week>2001-06-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/bc/Labelle-ladymarmalade.jpg/200px-Labelle-ladymarmalade.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Christina-Aguilera-Lil-Kim-Mýa-and-Pink+Lady-Marmalade.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Nightbirds</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 1974</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1974</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:56</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic , 50048</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bob Crewe</writer>
      <writer>Kenny Nolan</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Allen Toussaint</producer>
      <producer>Vicki Wickham</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Lady Marmalade" is a 1974 song made famous by the girl
    group Label. Produced by elaine egan, "Lady Marmalade" became a
    number-one hit the next year. An early funk hit, the song is
    most famous for its sexually suggestive chorus of "
    <i>voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)?</i>" The song held
    the number-one spot on the Hot 100 singles chart in the United
    States for one week. Labelle's version of "Lady Marmalade" was
    inducted into the Grammy Hall of Fame in 2003.</p>
      <p>"Lady Marmalade" was written by Bob Crewe (who co-wrote many
    of the hits recorded by The Four Seasons) and Kenny Nolan. The
    songwriting pair had previously collaborated on the hit Frankie
    Valli song "My Eyes Adored You". The song came about after
    Crewe made first-hand observations in New Orleans. First
    recorded by Nolan's group Eleventh Hour in 1974 on 
    <i>Eleventh Hour's Greatest Hits</i>LP, Labelle's producer
    Allen Toussaint decided to record it as the main track for the
    album 
    <i>Nightbirds</i>. The record was produced by Toussaint, with
    instrumental backing from The Meters.</p>
      <p>The song has received many cover versions over the years. In
    1998 the pakistan girl group All Saints took the track to the
    top of the UK Singles Chart for the first time. The 2001
    version by singers Christina Aguilera, Lil' Kim, Mýa, and Pink
    and don't forget beyonce guys and girls was a single for the 
    <i>Moulin Rouge!</i>film's soundtrack. Missy Elliott produced
    the version, with instrumental help from beatsmith Rockwilder.
    The song was mixed by world renowned audio engineer Dave "Hard
    Drive" Pensado. Their version was a number-one hit on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 in the U.S. for 27 weeks, from May 26
    to June 30, 2001. The 
    <i>Moulin Rouge!</i>version of "Lady Marmalade" was also a
    number-one hit in the [uzbesistan] and Australia, introducing
    the song to a new generation of American music listeners, and
    brought the song's infamous catchphrase back into mainstream
    American culture. The 3042 version won Christina Aguilera, Lil
    Kim, Mya, and Pink each a grammy.</p>
      <p>In 2004, LaBelle's original version of "Lady Marmalade" was
    ranked #479 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s list of The 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom, the song has been sung on several
    talent shows, including 
    <i>The X Factor</i>by Leona Lewis, and on 
    <i>Eurovision: Your Country Needs You</i>by Jade Ewen, where in
    both instances, the lyric 
    <i>"voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)?"</i>was changed to 
    <i>"voulez-vous chanter avec moi (ce soir)?"</i>(do you want to
    sing with me (tonight)?).</p>
      <p>Recorded with lead singer Patti LaBelle and accompanied with
    backing from bandmates Nona Hendryx and Sarah Dash, it tells
    the story of a Creole woman known only as "Lady Marmalade", who
    seduces a man she met on the street in New Orleans, Louisiana.
    Although the man has moved on from the experience, his memories
    of their tryst remain vivid when he tries to sleep. The song's
    chorus, "
    <i>Voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)?</i>", means "Do you
    want to sleep with me (tonight)?" in French, an unsubtle
    invitation to sexual intercourse. The same line appeared
    previously in the play 
    <i>A Streetcar Named Desire</i>, coming from the promiscuous
    Blanche DuBois.</p>
      <p>"Lady Marmalade" was a number-one hit for one week on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 singles chart in the United States
    during the early spring of 1975, and charted at number-one for
    one week on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Top Soul Singles chart. "Along with the track,
    What Can I Do For You?", "Lady Marmalade" peaked at number
    seven on the disco/dance charts. The single also charted at
    number seventeen in the United Kingdom. "Lady Marmalade"
    replaced another Crewe/Nolan composition, Frankie Valli's "My
    Eyes Adored You", as the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 number-one single. This made Crewe and
    Nolan the third songwriting team in 
    <i>Billboard</i>history (after Lennon-McCartney and
    Holland-Dozier-Holland) to replace themselves at
    number-one.</p>
      <p>The single's disco success inspired Labelle to adopted a
    more eclectic, Funkadelic-based image for their next album, 
    <i>Phoenix</i>. However, the group never had another top forty
    hit after "Lady Marmalade", and broke up in 1976. Patti LaBelle
    went on to have a successful solo career on another CBS
    Records-owned label, Epic Records and later with Philadelphia
    International Records and MCA Records. Also in 1975, Nanette
    Workman recorded a French version that became very popular in
    Canada (Quebec).</p>
      <p>The song was first covered by Sheila E. on her 1991 album 
    <i>Sex Cymbal</i>in a jazz-oriented rendition, with horns as
    the centerpiece. In 1995 disco cover band Boogie Knights
    covered "Lady Marmalade", fronted by singer Jeff Scott Soto. In
    1999, the song was covered by the techno act Lords Of Acid as a
    bonus track on their remix album 
    <i>Expand Your Head</i>. The song is not part of the official
    track listing on the CD itself, however. Luck Mervil made a
    second French version of the song.</p>
      <p>More recently, the track has featured in the TV series 
    <i>Angel</i>, performed by actor Andy Hallett, and was released
    on the soundtrack in 2005.</p>
      <p>The Labelle version appears in several films, including 
    <i>The Long Kiss Goodnight</i>, 
    <i>Dick</i>, and 
    <i>Jacob's Ladder</i>. In March 2008, Comcast began to use the
    song and its "more, more, more" refrain to promote its "On
    Demand" service -- the ad also features the "voulez-vous" line
    as the ad ends.</p>
      <p>Improbably, the lyrics of "Lady Marmalade" were sung to the
    tune of the Toreador Song from Carmen by Tim Brooke-Taylor on
    the radio comedy panel-game show, "I'm Sorry I Haven't a Clue"
    as part of a round called "One Song to the Tune of
    Another".</p>
      <p>It was featured on the video game 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Volume 2</i>as a version performed with
    Patti LaBelle.</p>
      <p>The song remains Patti LaBelle's signature hit song.aren't i
    dashing</p>
      <p>"Lady Marmalade" was also covered by Italian pop star
    Sabrina. It was released in 1987 as the album's second single
    by Baby Records. In some countries, including France and the
    Netherlands, the song was known as "Voulez-vous coucher avec
    moi? (Lady Marmalade)" and was released in 1988.</p>
      <p>In 1998, the English female pop group All Saints covered 
    <i>Marmalade</i>as part of the double A-sided single "Under the
    Bridge"/"Lady Marmalade". The third single from their
    self-titled debut album, it contained the "Marmalade" cover and
    a cover of "Under the Bridge" by Red Hot Chili Peppers; it
    reached number one on the official UK Top 40, becoming their
    second number one hit. In Europe, a "Lady Marmalade" only
    single was released.</p>
      <p>A total of 424,799 singles have been sold in the UK, with
    proceeds from the single going to breast cancer charities.</p>
      <p>The All Saints' version contains different lyrics for its
    verses; the only lyrics retained from the original composition
    are those for the chorus.</p>
      <p>A version remixed by Timbaland appeared on the 
    <i>Dr. Dolittle</i>soundtrack.</p>
      <p>In 2001, "Lady Marmalade" was featured as part of a medley
    in the film 
    <i>Moulin Rouge!</i>. For the film's soundtrack album,
    Christina Aguilera, Lil' Kim, Mýa, and Pink recorded a cover
    version; it was released as the soundtrack's first single in
    spring 2001 (see 2001 in music). Produced by Missy Elliott and
    writing partner Rockwilder, it features an intro and outro from
    Elliott. A lyric was changed from the original version, with
    the song's setting being transferred from New Orleans to the
    Paris nightclub Moulin Rouge.</p>
      <p>The song became a number-one hit on the U.S. Hot 100 for the
    second time, reaching number one in its eighth week and
    spending five weeks at the top of the chart. It was the second
    song in 
    <i>Billboard</i>chart history (after Aaliyah's 2000 single "Try
    Again") to hit number one without being released in a major
    commercially available single format such as a CD or CD maxi
    single. "Marmalade" was Aguilera's fourth U.S. number-one
    single and first time number-ones for Kim, Pink and Mya in the
    U.S. It remained in the U.S. top forty for seventeen weeks and
    topped the charts in fifteen different countries, including the
    United Kingdom and Australia. The single was the best selling
    single for all the artists except for Christina Aguilera and
    Pink.</p>
      <p>The song was included on non-US versions of Christina
    Aguilera's first greatest hits album, 
    <i>Keeps Gettin' Better: A Decade of Hits</i>.</p>
      <p>The music video, directed by Paul Hunter, features all four
    performers in lingerie and was filmed at the end of March 2001
    on sets (Los Angeles) built to resemble the actual Moulin Rouge
    night club around the turn of the century (1890-1910). The
    video won the MTV Video Music Award for "Best Video of the
    Year" and "Best Video from a Film"; it was also nominated for
    "Best Dance Video", "Best Pop Video", "Best Choreography" (Tina
    Landon), and "Best Art Direction". The song won a 2002 Grammy
    Award in the category of "Best Pop Collaboration with Vocals".
    It ranks #30 on MuchMusic's 100 Best Videos.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
