<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kiss_Kiss_(Chris_Brown_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kiss_Kiss_(Chris_Brown_song)</songId>
   <title>Kiss Kiss</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Brown_(American_singer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Chris Brown featuring T-Pain</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2007-11-10</week>
      <week>2007-11-17</week>
      <week>2007-11-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e9/ChrisBrownKissKiss.png/200px-ChrisBrownKissKiss.png</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Chris-Brown-featuring-T-Pain+Kiss-Kiss.png</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Exclusive</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 18, 2007  (2007-09-18) ( U.S. )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2007</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:11</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Jive</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Christopher Brown</writer>
      <writer>Faheem Najm</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>T-Pain</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Kiss Kiss" is a song by Chris Brown, released as the second
    single from his second studio album 
    <i>Exclusive</i>. The track features R&amp;B
    Singer-Songwriter/rapper T-Pain and is also produced by him.
    Both Brown and T-Pain use the Auto-Tune in the song. The single
    has been certified triple Platinum by the RIAA.</p>
      <p>On October 16, 2007, "Kiss Kiss" became available as digital
    track download on the U.S. iTunes Store. It was number-1 on The
    Billboard Hot 100 on October 30 (succeeded by "No One" by
    Alicia Keys), giving both Chris Brown and T-Pain their second
    number-one singles on that chart. This song was #48 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s list of the 100 Best Songs of 2007.</p>
      <p>It is noted that the radio version cuts out the intro
    dialogue because it is often mistaken to be a snippet from
    local radio stations, where T-Pain voices an eccentric disc
    jockey broadcasting the song "live" and taking calls.</p>
      <p>The song was given a full single re-release in the UK on 15
    September 2008, after the song was initially given a download
    only release in 2007.</p>
      <p>The official remix features rapper Nelly with Brown &amp;
    T-Pain.</p>
      <p>After Brown's previous single, "Wall to Wall" being his
    least charting single thus far (reaching only number 79 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100), "Kiss Kiss" was released as the
    second single in early September, and 
    <i>Exclusive'</i>s release date was pushed back to November.
    The song reached number 22 on the U.S. 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 without any assistance from digital
    sales, due to heavy airplay (it peaked at number two for ten
    weeks on the Hot 100 Airplay). Once released to iTunes, the
    track jumped twenty spots to #2 being held back by "Crank That
    (Soulja Boy)" by Soulja Boy Tell 'Em. The following week, it
    moved up to #1, giving both Brown and T-Pain their second #1
    singles on the chart. The song became Brown's sixth top ten hit
    on the U.S. Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs chart, and also reached
    number one on the U.S. iTunes top 100 selling songs. It was No.
    1 for three weeks on the Hot 100 before being replaced by
    Alicia Keys' "No One" on the November 22, 2007 chart. The song
    is Brown's second number-one in New Zealand, after his debut
    "Run It!". This is Chris Brown's second biggest single to date,
    trailing behind "Run It!", as well as T-Pain's second one,
    trailing behind "Buy U a Drank (Shawty Snappin')". It is also
    interesting to note that when "Kiss Kiss" reached #1 on the Hot
    100 it became only the eighth song that debuted on the chart at
    the lowest position of #100, and climbed all the way to #1. In
    the UK the track managed to debut at #40 on the UK Singles
    Chart on downloads alone and has peaked at #38. The song was
    re-released in the UK with a physical release on 15 September
    2008, following the Top 10 successes of singles "With You," and
    "Forever,". As of September 21, 2008, the re-release has so far
    peaked at #39 on the UK Singles Chart. In Ireland, the song
    debuted on the Irish Singles Chart at #47 in 2007, and rose to
    #26. In September 2008, the song re-entered the chart at a new
    peak of #23. As of September 26 the song has climbed to its
    current peak of #19, giving Brown his 5th Top 20 hit on the
    Irish Singles Chart. In Australia it peaked at 8 after several
    weeks of bulleting positions, and was certified Platinum</p>
      <p>The music video was shot at Florida International
    University's University Park campus, in Miami, Florida. This
    video premiered on BET's 
    <i>106 &amp; Park</i>on August 30, 2007. The music video is
    also available on iTunes. This song was voted #1 on MTV's 27
    Essential R&amp;B Songs of 2007. The song had its debut on VH1
    at #6 on January 5.</p>
      <p>In the video Brown plays two different versions of himself,
    a nerdy person and a jock persona, both trying to get the
    attention of a pretty girl who also attends the college. The
    jock side of Brown is constantly picking on the nerdy Brown
    around the girl, thinking it will impress her, whereas the
    nerdy Brown is always being nice to her. In one scene of the
    video the jock Brown is playing football in a field by the
    school, while the nerdy Brown is attempting to talk to the
    girl. The jock Brown seeing this runs and tackles the nerdy
    Brown to the ground. At the end of the video the two Browns are
    standing in front of their cars in the parking lot. The girl
    comes up, passes the jock Brown and kisses the nerdy Brown and
    proceeds to get in his vehicle, while the jock looks on,
    bewildered.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
