<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Ding-a-Ling 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Ding-a-Ling</songId>
   <title>My Ding-a-Ling</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chuck_Berry</artistId>
      <artistName>Chuck Berry</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1972-10-21</week>
      <week>1972-10-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>The London Chuck Berry Sessions</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1972</released>
   <formats>
      <format>45 rpm</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1972</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
      <genre>Novelty Song</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>11:33 (album)</length>
      <length>4:19 (single)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Chess 2131</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Chuck Berry</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Esmond Edwards</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"My Ding-a-Ling" was a 1972 novelty hit record for Chuck
    Berry, and his only U.S. number-one single on the pop charts.
    Later that year the song was on the album 
    <i>The London Chuck Berry Sessions</i>.</p>
      <p>The song titled "Little Girl Sing Ding-a-Ling" was recorded
    by Dave Bartholomew in 1952. In 1954, The Bees released a
    version entitled "Toy Bell." Berry recorded a version called
    "My Tambourine" in 1968, but the version which topped the
    charts was recorded live during the Lanchester Arts Festival at
    the Locarno ballroom in Coventry, England, on 3 February 1972,
    where Berry - backed by The Roy Young Band - topped a bill that
    also included Slade and Billy Preston. Boston radio station
    WMEX disc jockey, Jim Connors, was credited with a gold record
    for discovering the song and pushing it to #1 over the airwaves
    and amongst his peers in the United States.</p>
      <p>The song tells of how the singer received two silver bells
    on a string from his grandmother, who calls them his 
    <i>ding-a-ling</i>. According to the song, he plays with it in
    school, and holds on to it in dangerous situations like falling
    after climbing the garden wall, and swimming across a creek
    infested with snapping turtles. The lyrics consistently
    exercise the 
    <i>double entendre</i>with 
    <i>ding-a-ling</i>standing in for the penis. In the final
    verse, Berry admonishes "those of you who will not sing" and
    concludes that they "must be playing with [their] own
    ding-a-ling". Bartholomew has stated in interviews that the
    song was written as an allegory for the struggle for racial
    equality from the days of slavery to the Civil Rights
    movement.</p>
      <p>The Average White Band members guitarist Onnie McIntyre and
    drummer Robbie McIntosh played on the single.</p>
      <p>The lyrics with their sly tone and innuendo (and the
    enthusiasm of Berry and the audience) caused many radio
    stations to refuse to play it, and British morality campaigner
    Mary Whitehouse tried unsuccessfully to get the song banned.
    Moreover, pop critics generally dislike the song (especially
    the fact that it was Berry's sole #1 single in his career) and
    say that it is unworthy for someone who was so important in
    early rock 'n' roll (Alan Freeman once introduced the song by
    saying "oh Chuck baby, how could you!?!"). Nevertheless, Berry
    still likes it and on the recording calls it "our Alma
    Mater".</p>
      <p>This controversy was lampooned in 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>episode "Lisa's Pony", in which a
    Springfield Elementary School student attempted to sing the
    song during the school's talent show. He barely finished the
    first line of the refrain before an irate Principal Skinner
    rushed him off the stage.</p>
      <p>The censorship of this song continues even today - in one
    case, for a re-run of 
    <i>American Top 40</i>, some stations, such as WOGL in
    Philadelphia, replaced this song with an optional extra when it
    aired a rerun of a November 18, 1972 broadcast of AT40 (where
    it ranked at #14) on December 6, 2008. Among other stations,
    most Clear Channel-owned radio stations to whom the AT40 '70s
    rebroadcasts were contracted did not air the rebroadcast that
    same weekend, although it was because they were playing
    Christmas music and not because of the controversy. It should
    be noted that, even back in 1972, some stations would refuse to
    play this song on AT40, even when it reached number one.</p>
      <p>Berry's resulting live album was named, 
    <i>The London Chuck Berry Sessions</i>, even though London is
    more than 100 miles away from where the live tracks were
    recorded.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
