<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goodies_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goodies_(song)</songId>
   <title>Goodies</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ciara</artistId>
      <artistName>Ciara featuring Petey Pablo</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2004-09-11</week>
      <week>2004-09-18</week>
      <week>2004-09-25</week>
      <week>2004-10-02</week>
      <week>2004-10-09</week>
      <week>2004-10-16</week>
      <week>2004-10-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/55/Ciara_goodies.jpg/200px-Ciara_goodies.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Ciara-featuring-Petey-Pablo+Goodies.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Goodies</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 27, 2004  (2004-07-27) , (See release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2004 , Hitco, Atlanta, Georgia and Circle House Studios, Miami , FL and Sony Music Studios, NYC</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Crunk&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:43</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>LaFace</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ciara Harris</writer>
      <writer>Sean Garrett</writer>
      <writer>LaMarquis Jefferson</writer>
      <writer>Craig Love</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Lil Jon</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Goodies" is a pop song recorded by American R&amp;B singer
    Ciara and rapper Petey Pablo for Ciara's debut album 
    <i>Goodies</i>(2004) and written by Ciara, Sean Garrett,
    LaMarquis Jefferson, Craig Love and Jonathan Smith.Which monica
    appeared in the music video"Goodies" is a combination of crunk
    and R&amp;B. The song's lyrics are about female empowerment and
    virginity. The protagonist does not want to be an object. The
    song's protagonist rejects a male's sexual advances,
    proclaiming that he will never get her "goodies" because "they
    stay in the jar".</p>
      <p>"Goodies" was released as the album's lead single in third
    and fourth quarters of 2004, and first quarter of 2005. As the
    album's opening track, the song made a successful debut single,
    becoming Ciara's first number one single in the UK Singles
    Chart and on the Billboard Hot 100, and stayed number one for
    seven consecutive weeks. The song charted well on international
    markets. It was certified Platinum in the United States.</p>
      <p>After the success of Usher's "Yeah!" and Petey Pablo's
    "Freek-a-Leek", LaFace executive L.A. Reid wanted a female
    version of Pablo's "Freek-a-Leek". Ciara went in the recording
    studio with Hip-hop producer Lil Jon. She began writing a demo,
    but she had difficulty composing lyrics and creating a melody.
    Reid asked songwriter Sean Garrett, who was co-writer of
    Usher's Yeah!, to help Ciara write a song. The process took
    several days including Ciara and Garrett writing verses over
    the phone. The demo became "Goodies", which is the answer song
    to Pablo's "Freek-a-Leek". Lil Jon heard the demo and wanted to
    record the full track and Ciara became the first woman to
    record a crunk song.</p>
      <p>"Goodies" received positive reviews from music critics.
    Fazed.com called the song, "both clever and ironic considering
    how sexy her image" and "singularly disarming combination of an
    empowering message backed by an intoxicatingly sexy beat". 
    <i>The Situation</i>declared the track as "a great dance tune
    with a solid beat". Also it noted, Ciara shows "a lot of
    attitude, with girl empowering lyrics". 
    <i>Slant</i>published, "it's not the chorus that gets stuck in
    your head... but the incessant oscillating whistle (I swear you
    can hear dogs barking halfway through the song.)" Musiccomh.com
    reviewed, "Goodies" as "an instantly recognisable tune" and
    called it a "typically upbeat benefiting from Lil' Jon".
    Hiphopgalaxy.com called the track a "ultimate party anthem of
    the summer, but it’s one of the best singles of the year." The
    song has "an infectious chorus" and "a crunked up groove." 
    <i>Blender</i>published that Ciara "sounds like she's rapping
    right back at him, delivering her lines in a measured, sultry
    cadence with hardly any variation in tone or pitch.</p>
      <p>In 2005, "Goodies" was nominated for "Best R&amp;B/Soul or
    Rap Song of the Year" at Soul Train Lady of Soul Music Awards
    and in 2006. It won the Best Performed Songs in the ASCAP
    Repertory for the 2005 Survey Year at the ASCAP Pop Music
    Awards, including "1, 2 Step" and "Oh".</p>
      <p>"Goodies" is featured in the 2006 film 
    <i>Just My Luck</i>. "Goodies" is also featured in the 2009
    film 
    <i>Land of The Lost (film)</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Goodies" is Ciara's biggest single in the United States; it
    debuted at ninety-four on the Billboard Hot 100 and stayed at
    number one for seven consecutive weeks making it the longest
    run at number one for any debut artist, later tied with Katy
    Perry's "I Kissed A Girl" at seven weeks. It topped several
    Billboard charts including the Hot 100 Airplay, Hot
    R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs, Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Airplay, Rhythmic
    Top 40 and Top 40 Tracks charts. The single reached three on
    the Top 40 Mainstream and four on the Hot Digital Tracks. The
    song replaced "Lean Back" by Terror Squad, and was subsequently
    replaced by "My Boo" by Usher and Alicia Keys on both the Hot
    100 and R&amp;B/Hip-Hop charts. It ranked number nine on the
    2004 U.S. Billboard year-end chart.</p>
      <p>"Goodies" reached number one in Canada and the United
    Kingdom. In the UK, it replaced "One Night/I Got Stung" by
    Elvis Presley and replaced another Presley re-release single
    "It's Now or Never". The single peaked in the top twenty in
    Australia and Norway. The single reached ten in Germany and New
    Zealand. It was a moderate success in Austria, France, and
    Netherlands.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Goodies" was directed by Benny Boom. It
    shows Ciara and her friends driving in an Oldsmobile 442
    convertible along the Atlanta, Georgia streets to the local car
    wash. It features cameo appearances by BoneCrusher, Monica,
    Rasheeda, Jazze Pha, Young Jeezy, Lil Jon and among others.
    Ciara filmed the video for 27 straight hours with director
    Benny Boom.</p>
      <p>She gave her first performance ever of "Goodies" on BET's 
    <i>106 &amp; Park</i>.</p>
      <p>The music video begins with Ciara leaving her house, and her
    friend screams out, "What Up Dawg", with Ciara replying the
    same way. Then Ciara's sister runs outside saying that Jazze
    Pha is on the phone. Jazze tells Ciara that they are going to
    the carwash to hang out and Ciara says she will also be coming
    along. She then gives the phone back to her sister and tells
    her to stay out of her room. The song then begins with Ciara
    singing her intro and Petey Pablo, rapping his verse. During
    this intro, we see Ciara going along with her friends driving
    to the carwash. On her way there she meets a few young men and
    invites them also to the carwash. She then arrives to the
    carwash and meets up with different people, including Monica
    during the song, Ciara is in front of a blue and white back
    ground with Jazze Pha at the end, and with her backup dancers
    at the in the beginning, during, and at the end of the
    song.</p>
      <p>The extended version of the video includes Ciara full-length
    dance with the backup dancers, and also features more of her
    and Monica duo shot.</p>
      <p>These are the formats and track listings of major single
    releases of "Goodies".</p>
      <p>(Released October 18, 2004)</p>
      <p>(Released October 18, 2004)</p>
      <p>(Released 2005)</p>
      <p>(Released 2005)</p>
      <p>(Released January 11, 2005)</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
