<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Gotta_Feeling 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Gotta_Feeling</songId>
   <title>I Gotta Feeling</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>#cite_note-34[35]</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2009-07-11</week>
      <week>2009-07-18</week>
      <week>2009-07-25</week>
      <week>2009-08-01</week>
      <week>2009-08-08</week>
      <week>2009-08-15</week>
      <week>2009-08-22</week>
      <week>2009-08-29</week>
      <week>2009-09-05</week>
      <week>2009-09-12</week>
      <week>2009-09-19</week>
      <week>2009-09-26</week>
      <week>2009-10-03</week>
      <week>2009-10-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f4/I_Gotta_Feeling.png/200px-I_Gotta_Feeling.png</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/cite-note-34-35+I-Gotta-Feeling.png</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The E.N.D.</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 16, 2009  (2009-06-16)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
      <format>vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Square Prod, Paris , France and Metropolis Studios, London , England</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Electro Hop</genre>
      <genre>Electro House</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:50 (Album/Video Version)</length>
      <length>4:05 (Radio Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Interscope</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>William Adams</writer>
      <writer>Allen Pineda</writer>
      <writer>Jaime Gomez</writer>
      <writer>Stacy Ferguson</writer>
      <writer>David Guetta</writer>
      <writer>Frédéric Riesterer</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>David Guetta</producer>
      <producer>Frédéric Riesterer</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Gotta Feeling" is a song by the group Black Eyed Peas and
    their second official single from their fifth studio album 
    <i>The E.N.D.</i>. The song debuted on May 21, 2009. The song
    was produced by acclaimed French house DJ David Guetta. "I
    Gotta Feeling" debuted at number two behind the group's own
    "Boom Boom Pow" on the week of June 27, 2009, on both the
    Canadian and 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 charts, making the group one of only
    eleven artists who have occupied the top two positions at the
    same time on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100. The song went on to replace "Boom Boom
    Pow" at Number 1 on the US charts and eventually reach Number 1
    on 20 charts worldwide. It tied with "We Belong Together" by
    Mariah Carey for longest weeks at number one for the 2000's
    decade and also tied with Whitney Houston's 
    <i>I Will Always Love You</i>for the second-longest running
    number one of all time, only behind "One Sweet Day" by Mariah
    Carey feat. Boyz II Men. It was named 5th on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade. The song was
    nominated for Record of the Year at the 52nd Grammy Awards and
    won the Grammy for Best Pop Performance by a Duo or Group with
    Vocals. The song is also nominated as Song of the Year at the
    2009 World Music Awards. The song is the most downloaded song
    ever on iTunes. To date the song has sold over 5 million copies
    in the United States according to Nielson SoundScan.</p>
      <p>On Dipdive, while premiering "I Gotta Feeling" and cover
    artwork, underneath both, will.i.am posted of the topics
    related in the song:</p>
      <p>"this song is dedicated to everyone who is getting ready to
    go out...</p>
      <p>it's the song to listen to when you drive to the club or
    party...</p>
      <p>it's the song to listen to after a long day or week at
    work...</p>
      <p>it's the song to that makes me wanna throw my stress
    away..."</p>
      <p>It is set in common time and is composed in the key of G
    major with a moderate tempo of 128 beats per minute. The
    group's vocal range spans from G
    <sub>3</sub>to A
    <sub>5</sub>.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Billboard</i>gave the song a positive review: "The Black
    Eyed Peas proved with their massive international chart-topper
    "Boom Boom Pow" that they're a group still to be reckoned with.
    The official follow-up single "I Gotta Feeling" may be their
    most mainstream release yet. Over a pop-throbbing beat,
    courtesy of the famed club hitmaker David Guetta, the Peas
    trade off on a simple, yet effective melody and message:
    "Tonight's gonna be a good night." Having already shown what
    they can do at the peak of a party, now they're out to prove
    they can get it started even earlier". Bill Lamb of 
    <i>About.com</i>gave the song 4 out of 5 stars commenting on
    the feel-good mood, distinct change of pace for them, and that
    it is a great choice for summer. Overall, he thinks that "Boom
    Boom Pow" and "I Gotta Feeling" deliver contributions that make
    it obvious Black Eyed Peas are still a four-person group and
    that this is a hit.</p>
      <p>David Balls of Digital Spy gave the song 4 out of 5
    stars:</p>
      <p>Now, hot on the heels of the heavy Auto-Tune and futuristic
    synths of 'Boom Boom Pow', they're back with a single that's
    already made number one in Oz and the US. What's more, 'I Gotta
    Feeling' is every bit as quirky as its predecessor. Built
    around a sample from David Guetta's 'Love Is Gone', it begins
    in relatively restrained fashion before suddenly morphing into
    a throbbing rave-up... and proceeds to flit between tempos for
    the rest of its five-minute duration. A bit like Girls Aloud's
    'Biology', it's a random, rather barmy mish-mash of musical
    ideas that only really makes sense after a few listens, but
    there's no doubt the Peas still know how to get us dancing.</p>
      <p>Comedy website Cracked.com however, gave the song a rather
    scathing review, with host Wayne Gladstone stating, "I don't
    care how many gangly superfluous band members you float in the
    air, at this point you need to start the song." This was in
    reference to the repetition of the chorus of 'tonight's gonna
    be a good night' for roughly a minute and a half. The review
    was scathing in its critique of auto-tune, lyrics, rhyming the
    same word with itself ("Up and "Up"), naming days of the week
    (which was seen as comparable to "Naming the Alphabet") and
    Jewish religious phrases being used out of context.</p>
      <p>A remix edit by David Guetta appears on his latest album,
    .</p>
      <p>In her 2009 comedy special Ellen's Bigger, Longer &amp;
    Wider Show, comedian Ellen DeGeneres performed a dance to the
    song during the opening segment of the show.</p>
      <p>The song was performed on the first results show of 
    <i>The X Factor</i>UK Series Six, by all the 12 Finalists,
    before the first act was eliminated. It is also performed by
    the finalists on the opening of the current X Factor Tour.</p>
      <p>On September 8, 2009, the song was performed by the Black
    Eyed Peas for the taping of the Kickoff Party for the 24th
    season of 
    <i>The Oprah Winfrey Show</i>, with 21,000 fans performing a
    flash mob dance on the "Magnificent Mile" portion of Michigan
    Avenue in Chicago, Illinois.</p>
      <p>A version celebrating the Philadelphia Phillies National
    League victory is titled "Phillies Gotta Feeling."</p>
      <p>Alvin and the Chipmunks &amp; The Chipettes covered the song
    for the movie, 
    <i>Alvin and the Chipmunks: The Squeakquel</i>and the movie's
    soundtrack.</p>
      <p>A remix performed by reggaeton artist MJ was released on the
    Internet. Black Eyed Peas performed this song at the 52nd
    Grammy Awards nomination announcement ceremony known as 
    <i>The GRAMMY Nominations Concert Live!! — Countdown To Music's
    Biggest Night</i>along with David Guetta.</p>
      <p>This song is now the official support song for the
    Portuguese National Team towards the 2010 Football World Cup.
    In a video spread in the Internet, the band members show their
    support to Portugal and its players. ' The song is featured in
    commercials for the 2010 movie 
    <i>Valentine's Day</i>.</p>
      <p>The group performed the song in a commercial for Target
    stores.</p>
      <p>The song was featured during the 2010 Winter Olympics for a
    member of the women's snowboarding team.</p>
      <p>The song was covered by the Top 20 in American Idol as a
    group song.</p>
      <p>An unfinalized version of the music video was leaked on May
    29, 2009. The official final version was released on June 2 on
    Dipdive and on June 16 on iTunes.</p>
      <p>There is both a censored version and an explicit version of
    the music video. The video first starts out with some scenes in
    Hollywood Blvd. Then it shows will.i.am combing his hair and
    Fergie putting on makeup wearing lingerie. It also shows Taboo
    checking his messages on Dipdive and apl.de.ap checking his
    text messages. Then it cuts to the party as the first verse
    starts. In the uncensored version, two women are kissing at the
    two minute mark, at which point the lyrics "Let's take
    it...off!" are heard, and a hand grabs the top of the dress of
    one of the women, and pulls it down, exposing her left breast.
    All members of the Black Eyed Peas are shown dancing. Later,
    they are dancing with their faces and hands painted with
    phosphorescent paint. The video ends with a large sign with
    human-sized letters that reads "The E.N.D."</p>
      <p>The video is directed by Ben Mor of 
    <i>Little Minx</i>and features guest appearances by David
    Guetta, Kid Cudi, Katy Perry, Chantal Jones, members of the
    indie rock band Gossip, the designer duo Dean and Dan Caten of
    Dsquared and a few well-known personalities of the LGBT
    community, including Ongina of 
    <i>RuPaul's Drag Race</i>fame.</p>
      <p>"I Gotta Feeling" was the group's highest debut on the Hot
    100, debuting at number two. As of the end of 2009 the song has
    sold 4,500,000+ copies. "I Gotta Feeling" ended the 12 week
    number-one run of the band's previous single "Boom Boom Pow",
    when it reached number one on the Hot 100 the chart week of
    July 11, 2009, their second single to do so. It makes the band
    only the fourth group to replace themselves at number one in
    the chart's history, following The Beatles, Boyz II Men, and
    OutKast, and the first to do it in the digital download era. "I
    Gotta Feeling" had remained Number 1 on the Hot 100 for
    fourteen weeks, extending the band's run at number one on the
    Hot 100 to 26 consecutive weeks, or half a year straight. The
    song was knocked off the top of the chart to Number 5 on
    October 17 by "Down" by Jay Sean featuring Lil Wayne. The
    longest running #1 hit of 2009, the tune is tied with five
    other songs as the second longest running Hot 100 Number 1. It
    is also tied with Mariah Carey's "We Belong Together" as the
    longest running Hot 100 Number 1 of the 2000s. Apart from that,
    the group holds the record for longest consecutive run at
    Billboard's Hot 100 number one. The Black Eyed Peas are also
    just the third artist to have multiple songs spend 12 weeks at
    Number 1 on the Hot 100. Boyz II Men and Mariah Carey are the
    only other artists to do this. In fact, 
    <i>I Gotta Feeling</i>is the highest-charting hip-hop song on
    the adult contemporary chart. The song has become the group's
    most successful digital single selling 5,179,513 copies by the
    end of February.</p>
      <p>On the American Top 40, the song made a long-week run on the
    top. It topped the AT40 chart for seven weeks, tied with Lady
    Gaga's "Poker Face". The song peaked at #1 on the said
    countdown on August 22, 2009, and ended its long-week run at
    the top on October 3. On the next week, October 10, "I Gotta
    Feeling" fell to #4, and Taylor Swift held the top spot with
    "You Belong With Me".</p>
      <p>"I Gotta Feeling" has become the Black Eyed Peas' most
    successful single of their career, topping over 25 charts
    internationally. It replaced "Boom Boom Pow" at number one on
    the Canadian Hot 100 and Australian ARIA Chart. In New Zealand
    the song debuted at number seven on June 15, 2009, reaching
    number one two weeks later, making the song their fifth
    number-one single in New Zealand. The song has spent nine
    consecutive weeks at number one, becoming their longest-running
    number one single there. It was certified 2x Platinum after
    twenty-two weeks on the chart, selling over 30,000 copies.</p>
      <p>In Ireland, on its third week on the chart "I Gotta Feeling"
    jumped from Number 18 to 2 with strong download sales,
    outpeaking their last single "Boom Boom Pow", which reached
    Number 3. The next week, it climbed to Number 1 giving them
    their fourth number-one single there. The song spent 12
    non-consecutive weeks at Number 1 in Ireland.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom the song debuted at number 70 in June
    2009 and entered the top 40 of the UK Singles Chart on the week
    ending July 11, 2009. It slowly worked its way up the chart and
    in its eighth week (August 2, 2009) it peaked at number one on
    downloads alone (with its physical release being August 10).
    Therefore giving the group their second consecutive number one
    hit from 
    <i>The E.N.D.</i>, their third number one overall and their
    ninth top ten hit in the country. On the same week it reached
    the summit of the UK singles chart, "I Gotta Feeling" became
    the new number one on the UK R&amp;B Chart. Although it was
    knocked off the number one spot of the UK Singles Chart by
    Tinchy Stryder the following week, it regained its position at
    Number 1 on August 16 marking the Black Eyed Peas second (and
    consecutive) song to have had two separate runs at number one,
    and one of only six songs to have managed the feat in the 21st
    century (including "I Gotta Feeling" and "Boom Boom Pow"). The
    song appeared in the top 10 of the UK Singles Chart for 17
    weeks, which is longer than the time spent in the top 100 as a
    whole for several other Black Eyed Peas songs, and stayed in
    the top 40 for over half a year, finally dropping to #41 on the
    first chart of March 2010. I Gotta Feeling has sold 950,000
    copies in the United Kingdom, outselling the biggest selling
    single of 2009, Lady Gaga's "Poker Face". It was also announced
    as the 18th biggest selling single of the decade. "Boom Boom
    Pow" was the 7th best selling single of the year with around
    600,000 copies sold, and "Meet Me Halfway" was the tenth
    biggest selling, with over 500,000 copies.</p>
      <p>The song was the third most successful song of the decade in
    Australia, as announced on January 7, 2010. The decade-end
    chart also revealed the song to be the most successful song of
    2009. As of February 2010, "I Gotta Feeling" holds the record
    as the most downloaded song on iTunes of all time.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
