<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confessions_Part_II 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confessions_Part_II</songId>
   <title>Confessions Part II</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>#cite_note-38[39]</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2004-07-24</week>
      <week>2004-07-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/0a/Usher_-_Confessions_Part_II_-_CD_cover.jpg/200px-Usher_-_Confessions_Part_II_-_CD_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/cite-note-38-39+Confessions-Part-II.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Confessions</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 8, 2004</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>July 2003</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:49</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Arista</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Usher Raymond</writer>
      <writer>Jermaine Dupri</writer>
      <writer>Bryan-Michael Cox</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jermaine Dupri</producer>
      <producer>Bryan-Michael Cox</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Confessions Part II" is a song by R&amp;B singer Usher, and
    co-produced by Jermaine Dupri and Bryan-Michael Cox for Usher's
    fourth album 
    <i>Confessions</i>. Written by Usher, Dupri and Cox, the song
    is a confession of a man to his woman about his impregnated
    mistress, a continuation of "Confessions Part I" which relates
    a man's infidelity. Its personal content evoked rumors and
    early responses from the public even before its release,
    believing that Usher was asserting the truth; however, Dupri
    divulged that the story behind the album is his and Usher
    explained that he only took inspiration from his friends'
    similar experiences. The song received mixed reviews from
    critics.</p>
      <p>"Confessions Part II" was released as the third single from
    the album, following the success of "Burn". The single reached
    number one on Hot 100 for two weeks, becoming the album's third
    consecutive number-one single. Internationally, the single had
    lesser success than the album's previous releases.</p>
      <p>When he started working on his fourth studio album 
    <i>Confessions</i>after the release of his 2001 album 
    <i>8701</i>, Usher chose not to branch out much with musical
    collaborators; instead, he chose to continue creating music
    with his previous producers. He again enlisted
    producer-songwriter Jermaine Dupri, who had produced songs for
    Usher's two previous albums. Dupri approached Bryan-Michael
    Cox, asking him to become a collaborator. Cox has been a
    frequent partner of Dupri who had produced hits for Usher as
    well. Like "Burn", the second single from the album, Dupri and
    Cox conversed about a situation, creating the idea of the
    prospective song. However, they were concerned because they
    needed somebody to write such a song and they never thought
    Usher would do it. The concept became "Confessions".</p>
      <p>Usher started recording the song on July 2003 in New York
    City. One day, before the night was over, Usher was singing
    about impregnating a mistress and becoming displeased, having
    found that she is three months pregnant. The theme of cheating
    inspired him and Dupri, and they then decided to produce two
    parts of "Confessions": Part I and Part II. Usher said that the
    former is a "dramatization where a guy confesses all the stuff
    he's been doing" against his woman. The latter speaks of
    impregnating a mistress.</p>
      <p>While 
    <i>Confessions</i>was still in production, Usher promised "real
    talk" in it. He decided "to let it all hang out by singing
    about some of his own little secrets, as well as a few bones
    from his homies' skeleton-filled closets." He explained: "All
    of us have our Pandora's boxes or skeletons in our closets. I
    let a few of them out, you know. I've got a lot to say. I've
    got a lot of things and stuff built in me that I just want to
    let go of." He further noted that, for the most part, the
    album's subject matter is "very personal". Dupri expected
    people to question some of the personal lyrics they associated
    in the song.</p>
      <p>"Confessions Part II" is an R&amp;B song composed in the key
    of A♭. Set in common time, the song is performed with a
    moderate groove. The lyrics are constructed in the inverted
    chorus-verse form. There are four choruses and two verses, and
    then a break between the third and final chorus which Usher
    speaks the lyrics.</p>
      <p>The lyrics of "Confessions Part II" centers on a confession
    about impregnating a mistress. For the prelude, Usher tells his
    significant other that he impregnated his mistress.
    "Confessions Part II" apologizes what he had done in part one.
    Usher said of the song that right after he confessed with his
    real woman, he hoped she would still give him a chance. Dupri
    said that "Confessions Part II" is one of the songs which speak
    about breakups in relationships.</p>
      <p>Usher held few listening parties for the album prior to its
    release. Shortly after, people came up with different
    interpretations of "Confessions Part II", among other personal
    songs in the album. In 2003, Usher's two-year relationship with
    TLC's Chilli was going to "flame-out", which partly contributed
    to the concept of "Burn". They finally broke up early in 2004
    because of "irreconcilable differences and because the two
    found it almost impossible to make compromises" which partly
    triggered public speculation that some of the songs in the
    album are in reference to his personal struggle. They referred
    to the song speaking about Usher's "infidelity" to Chilli.</p>
      <p>Alongside the "cheating" rumors, the public inferred from
    the lyrics that Usher had impregnated a mistress in real life.
    Usher, however, emphasized that he was not in a relationship
    and "got another girl pregnant" and he was singing a
    "character". The similarity of situations he faced before and
    experiences of his friends collectively inspired him to write
    the song. In the middle of rumors, Dupri admitted that the
    stories behind the songs in the album are his. He stated, "me
    cheating on my steady girlfriend, having a baby with that other
    woman and having to confess to everything that happened to my
    main girl."</p>
      <p>Behind rumors, Usher refuted in an interview with MTV
    News:</p>
      <p>People assume things, because as I said, I pull from my
    personal experiences to make my music ... I never
    experienced [fathering a child outside of a relationship]
    firsthand, but it's something I wanted to talk about  ...
    and it's something that has happened to me in the past ...
    As I said, I have a few deep, dark ones that I've kept stowed
    away in a closet for a minute ... That's why I take this
    time to speak to you guys and let you know really what it
    is ... I will tell you that I loved [Chilli] a lot and she
    obviously loved me; it just didn't work out. But cheating is
    not what caused the relationship to collide and crash. That
    ain't what broke it up.</p>
      <p>"Confessions Part II" was released as the third single from
    the album, following "Burn". The single was released in the
    United States as a 12" single on August 24, 2004. It was
    released in Germany on October 18, and Australia on October 26,
    2004, featuring the album and remix version of the track and a
    song called "Whatever I Want". In the United Kingdom, it was a
    double A-side with "My Boo", the fourth single from the album.
    It was released in the country on December 28, 2004, and
    re-released on January 18, 2005.</p>
      <p>Many critics found the song intriguing and came up with
    interpretations of it as well. Andrew McGregor of the BBC
    questioned if "Confessions Part II", as well as "Truth Hurts",
    are only "mere theatre" or telling the truth. Laura Sinagra of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>focuses on how Usher admits in the song
    about impregnating a mistress. Sal Cinquemani of Slant Magazine
    commented that Usher's age when the song was recorded was the
    right take to "getting his 'chick on the side'".</p>
      <p>Outside of rumors, Jem Aswad of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>said that the best songs from the
    album were "Confessions Part II" and "Burn", which he described
    as having smooth melodies. Matt Cibula of Popmatters said of
    the flow of the concept does not work. He pointed out that in
    the second part, Usher claims he "barely knows the other lady",
    while in the first part, he already said that she was his
    ex-girlfriend. He furthered called it the "wimpiest" song on
    the theme of the album. Kelefa Sanneh of 
    <i>The New York Times</i>called it a "tricky infidelity
    narrative".</p>
      <p>"Confessions Part II" was nominated for Best R&amp;B/Soul,
    Male at the 2005 Soul Train Music Awards. At the 2005 American
    Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers Pop Music Awards,
    Dupri received the ASCAP Golden Note Award for co-writing the
    song, alongside his many achievements and contributions to
    American popular music. British record company EMI was
    recognized as Publisher of the Year for the song, including
    "Burn" and songs by Alicia Keys, Beyoncé Knowles, Britney
    Spears.</p>
      <p>"Confessions Part II" lived up to the success of its
    predecessors in the United States, though not as
    overwhelmingly. The single debuted on the Hot 100 at number 48,
    a higher entry than those of "Yeah!" and "Burn" did, while
    "Yeah!" was still at the top of the chart and "Burn" at number
    three. It peaked at number one on July 27, 2004, replacing
    "Burn"'s eighth non-consecutive chart run, and stayed there for
    two weeks. It failed to match the number of days at top spot of
    the previous two releases, and remained on the top ten for 13
    weeks. The single left the chart after 25 weeks. The single was
    certified gold by the Recording Industry Association of America
    on for reaching half million shipments.</p>
      <p>Internationally, "Confessions Part II" had lesser success.
    The single debuted at number five in Australia, becoming its
    highest entry, and failed to reach a higher position. The
    single reached number five in the United Kingdom, peaked at
    number seven in Ireland, and below top ten in the Netherlands
    and France, where it reached #43</p>
      <p>The music video of "Confessions Part II" was co-directed by
    Usher and music video director Chris Robinson, who also
    directed the video for the album's fourth single, "My Boo".
    "Confessions Part I" serves as the opening of the video. Set in
    a studio, Usher receives a phone message and knows that he
    impregnated his mistress. After he speaks the spoken section of
    the song, "Confessions Part II" proceeds. Usher is set in a
    dark lit room, with only one chair. He occasionally shows a
    large ring in his ring finger. In the middle of the video, he
    lies on a piano and in his imagination, his woman and mistress
    are beside him. The next scene shows Usher in a brown car
    singing, goes out and kneels before his woman to confess. She
    refuses to listen and slaps Usher, then leaves. Alone, Usher
    stands in front of a wide mirror, which breaks into pieces
    accompanied by a roaring sound, ending the video with him
    sitting on a chair.</p>
      <p>The music video successfully charted on video programs. It
    debuted on MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>on June 28, 2004, the same entry as
    "Burn". The music video reached number one on the countdown,
    and retired on September 15, 2004 at number seven. Like
    "Yeah!", "Confessions Part II" video remained on 
    <i>TRL</i>for 50 days.</p>
      <p>The official remix of the song was added the re-release of
    "Confessions" and it features a new verse by Usher, Shyne
    (rapped his verse on the phone while in prison), Kanye West,
    Twista and Jermaine Dupri.</p>
      <p>The song is parodied by "Weird Al" Yankovic on his album 
    <i>Straight Outta Lynwood</i>as "Confessions Part III".</p>
      <p>A mash-up of the song with It's My Life recorded by the cast
    of Glee appeared in an episode of the show's first season, and
    got to number 14 on the UK singles chart.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
