<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_on_Me_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_on_Me_(song)</songId>
   <title>Lean on Me</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Club_Nouveau</artistId>
      <artistName>Club Nouveau</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-03-21</week>
      <week>1987-03-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Still Bill</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 1972</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:17</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Sussex Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bill Withers</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bill Withers</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Lean on Me" is a popular song performed by Bill Withers on
    the 1972 album 
    <i>Still Bill</i>.</p>
      <p>It was his first (and only) number one on both the soul
    singles and the Billboard Hot 100. It is ranked number 205 on
    the 
    <i>Rolling Stone's 500 Greatest Songs of All Time</i>. Numerous
    cover versions have been recorded, and it is one of only nine
    songs to have scored #1 with versions recorded by two different
    artists. Withers' childhood in the coal mining town of Slab
    Fork, West Virginia was the inspiration for "Lean on Me", which
    he wrote after he had moved to Los Angeles and found himself
    missing the strong community ethic of his hometown. He lived in
    a decrepit house in the poor section of town.</p>
      <p>Withers recalled to Songfacts the original inspiration for
    the song; "I bought a little piano and I was sitting there just
    running my fingers up and down the piano. In the course of
    doing the music, that phrase crossed my mind, so then you go
    back and say, 'OK, I like the way that phrase, Lean On Me,
    sounds with this song.'"</p>
      <p>Several members of the Watts 103rd Street Rhythm Band were
    used for the recording session in 1972.</p>
      <p>The song was used in a 1970s drug awareness film titled "
    <i>Dead Is Dead</i>", hosted and produced by actor Godfrey
    Cambridge.</p>
      <p>R&amp;B group Club Nouveau covered the song and took it to
    number one on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts in 1987. It also scored number one on
    the dance charts, and won a Grammy award.</p>
      <p>Club Nouveau's version spent three weeks at number one. It
    was ranked #94 on VH1's 
    <i>100 Greatest One Hit Wonders of the 80s</i>, although "Why
    You Treat Me So Bad" went to #39 that same year.</p>
      <p>"Lean on Me" has been interpreted by various artists ever
    since, including Will Smith, Mud (1976), Al Jarreau (1985), DC
    Talk (1992), Michael Bolton (1994), Bonnie Tyler (1999), Anne
    Murray (1999), 2-4 Family (1999), and frequently in concert by
    Rascal Flatts.</p>
      <p>In 1989, covers of "Lean on Me" by The Winans and Sandra
    Reaves-Phillips provided the emotional uplift for a motion
    picture of the same name. Additionally, for the same film, the
    song was adapted by Big Daddy Kane in "hip hop" form. Mitchel
    Musso recorded a version of the song for the 2008 film 
    <i>Snow Buddies</i>.</p>
      <p>UK Singer Elkie Brooks performed the song as the title music
    for BBC comedy program 
    <i>Agony Again</i>.</p>
      <p>American group Counting Crows used the song as entrance
    music before nearly every show they performed in during their
    2008 American tour in support of their album, 
    <i>Saturday Nights and Sunday Mornings</i>.</p>
      <p>Mary J. Blige performed this song at the HBO We Are One: The
    Obama Inaugural Celebration at the Lincoln Memorial. The next
    day, a crowd of hundreds, if not thousands spontaneously began
    singing the song in the Purple Tunnel of Doom under the
    National Mall as they waited to gain entrance to the
    inauguration ceremonies. Kid Rock, Sheryl Crow, and Keith Urban
    performed this song at the 2010 Hope for Haiti earthquake
    relief telethon.</p>
      <p>The Cast of Glee interpreted at the end of Episode # 10 of
    the first season, "Ballads" as support for Finn and Quinn.</p>
      <p>American Idol Season 9 finalist Didi Benami performed a
    cover of the song on the Top 10 female performances on
    Wednesday, 
    <span class="mw-formatted-date" title="2010-03-03">
            <span class="mw-formatted-date" title="03-03">
March 3
</span>, 2010
</span>.</p>
      <p>The song was featured in a Brawny paper towel commercial in
    2010.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
