<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viva_la_Vida 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viva_la_Vida</songId>
   <title>Viva la Vida</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coldplay</artistId>
      <artistName>Coldplay</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2008-06-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/84/Coldplay_-_Viva_la_Vida.jpg/200px-Coldplay_-_Viva_la_Vida.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Coldplay+Viva-la-Vida.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Viva la Vida or Death and All His Friends</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>25 May 2008</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2007–2008</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Baroque Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:01 (Full album version)</length>
      <length>3:45 (Radio edit)</length>
      <length>4:04 (New edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Parlophone , Capitol</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Guy Berryman</writer>
      <writer>Jonny Buckland</writer>
      <writer>Will Champion</writer>
      <writer>Chris Martin</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Coldplay</producer>
      <producer>Brian Eno</producer>
      <producer>Markus Dravs</producer>
      <producer>Rik Simpson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Viva la Vida" is a song by the English alternative rock
    band Coldplay. It was written by all members of the band for
    their fourth album, 
    <i>Viva la Vida or Death and All His Friends</i>(2008). On the
    album, this song segues directly into the next track on the
    album, "Violet Hill".</p>
      <p>The lyrics to the song contain historical and religious
    references, and the track is built around a repeating string
    section with a percussion background.</p>
      <p>The song was released on 12 June 2008 as the album's second
    single, debuting to critical and commercial success. "Viva la
    Vida" reached the top spot of the UK Singles Chart and Hot 100,
    becoming the band's first number-one single and a Transatlantic
    number-one. The song won the Grammy Award for Song of the Year
    at the 51st Grammy Awards in 2009. The song became the sixth
    song in digital history to reach the 4 million mark in paid
    downloads.</p>
      <p>The song's Spanish title, "Viva la Vida", is taken from a
    painting by 20th century Mexican artist Frida Kahlo. It
    translates into English as "Long live life".</p>
      <p>During the album's production, "Viva la Vida" is one of the
    songs that had polarized each member's opinion over which
    version they should choose. In an interview, vocalist Chris
    Martin recalls, "... we did quite a few different versions
    and went round the houses a bit and eventually settled on those
    treatments for it."</p>
      <p>"Viva La Vida" soars in with a grandiose instrumental
    arrangement and sweeping lyrics detailing the pain of being
    deposed from a lofty position. The big sound of the song
    constantly verges on becoming overblown, but Coldplay know how
    to walk the tightrope perfectly. Bells and chimes and
    orchestral swells are all there on the chorus, but Chris
    Martin's voice still pierces through like a clarion call.
    Lyrically, the pain of the protagonist is clear, but the sweep
    of words about Jerusalem bells, Roman cavalry, and Saint Peter
    give "Viva La Vida" an air of intelligence rare in today's most
    popular pop songs.</p>
      <p>The lyrics to "Viva la Vida" contain many religious
    references. For example, "pillars of sand" is a clear reference
    to the Biblical parable given by Jesus about the fool who built
    his house on sand, and the wise man who built it on solid rock,
    while "pillars of salt" is a reference to Lot's wife, who was
    turned into a pillar of salt. "I know Saint Peter won't call my
    name" refers to Matthew 16:19 where Jesus tells Peter that he
    will give him the keys to the Kingdom of Heaven and the belief
    that the apostle stands at the Gates of Heaven, permitting or
    denying admission. Other likely (but ambiguous) Biblical
    references are "Seas would rise when I gave the word" (Moses
    parting the Red Sea), and "... my head upon a silver plate"
    (the beheading of St. John the Baptist: Salome asked to have
    his head delivered to her upon a platter).</p>
      <p>The song has inspired a great deal of debate about its
    meaning. People have claimed that the song may be about various
    subjects, such as the French Revolution. The band members
    themselves do not appear to have corroborated any of these
    claims, and have referred only to kings and revolutionaries in
    general, rather than any particular king.</p>
      <p>Martin has explained the song lyric "I know Saint Peter
    won't call my name" in an interview with 
    <i>Q</i>magazine: "It's about ... You're not on the list.
    I was a naughty boy. It's always fascinated me that idea of
    finishing your life and then being analyzed on it. And this
    idea runs throughout most religions. That's why people blow up
    buildings. Because they think they're going to get lots of
    virgins. I always feel like saying, just join a band ...
    That is the most frightening thing you could possibly say to
    somebody. Eternal damnation. I know about this stuff because I
    studied it. I was into it all. I know it. It's still mildly
    terrifying to me. And this is serious." When asked about the
    song, bass guitarist Guy Berryman said: "It's a story about a
    king who's lost his kingdom, and all the album's artwork is
    based on the idea of revolutionaries and guerrillas. There's
    this slightly anti-authoritarian viewpoint that's crept into
    some of the lyrics and it's some of the pay-off between being
    surrounded by governments on one side, but also we're human
    beings with emotions and we're all going to die and the
    stupidity of what we have to put up with every day. Hence the
    album title."</p>
      <p>Unlike the typical arrangement of Coldplay songs, in which
    either the piano or guitar is the prominent instrument, the
    track mostly consists of a string section playing the song's
    upbeat riff, along with a steady bass drum beat, percussion
    (including a timpani and a church bell), bass guitar, and
    Martin's vocals; there is limited use of electric guitar in the
    song. All the strings are arranged and performed by violinist
    Davide Rossi, who is also one of the main collaborators of the
    album. Rossi's strings comprise the main driving force
    throughout the song, with a strong beginning loop that supports
    Martin's voice, until the choruses where the symphonic power of
    the orchestra takes its fullest shape. The song is played in
    the key of Ab Major at a tempo of 137bpm, while the vocal range
    is Eb4-Ab5. Although Coldplay are widely labeled as an
    "alternative rock" band, the classical composition and
    historical subject matter of "Viva la Vida" have led to the
    song being labeled as "baroque pop" and "chamber pop".</p>
      <p>"Viva la Vida" was initially released only with iTunes Store
    pre-orders of 
    <i>Viva la Vida or Death and All His Friends</i>on 7 May
    2008 – the "new edit" version of the song – which led
    to the song's temporary exclusion from the UK Singles Chart. It
    was released as a download-only single on 25 May 2008, and a
    physical CD single in Europe on 29 July 2008 to coincide with
    the release of the single's music videos. "Viva la Vida" was
    well-downloaded in the internet, becoming iTunes' best-selling
    song of 2008. From 24 December 2008 to 5 January 2009 an
    official remix of the song, named the "Thin White Duke Mix",
    was given away for free as a Christmas gift via the band's
    website.</p>
      <p>The song was used as part of Apple Inc.'s iPod + iTunes
    advertisement campaign. Coldplay performed the song live for
    the first time at the 2008 MTV Movie Awards. It has since gone
    on to make many media appearances, including being featured
    throughout the episode "A Person of Interest" from the
    paranormal drama 
    <i>Medium</i>, as a song played on the radio in the episode
    "We're Not in Kansas Anymore" from the teen drama 
    <i>90210</i>, and on the international soundtrack to the
    Brazilian soap opera 
    <i>A Favorita</i>which helped push "Viva la Vida" up the charts
    in Brazil, where the telenovela been shown. "Viva la Vida" is
    now the entrance music for Birmingham City Football Club. In
    2009, Solange Knowles covered the song. Lady Gaga also covered
    the song for BBC Radio 1. A live version of the song appeared
    on Coldplay's 2009 live album 
    <i>LeftRightLeftRightLeft</i>. Pet Shop Boys also performed the
    song live on their 2009 Pandemonium Tour and the song appeared
    on their Christmas EP.</p>
      <p>Critics were positive towards the song. In the 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>review of the album, critic Chris
    Willman wrote: "Take the title track ... on which [Martin]
    imagines himself as a paranoid monarch. 'Who would ever want to
    be king?' Martin asks. 'Revolutionaries wait/For my head on a
    silver plate!'. The confident majesty of the music, however,
    belies how he and his bandmates have invigorated their
    rock-lite reign." Josh Hathaway from 
    <i>The Plain Dealer</i>noted "Viva la Vida" as the "catchiest"
    song on the album. Chris Jones of the BBC noted: "The
    string/brass mutations that bolster a track like 'Viva La
    Vida' ... conjure tunes so sweetly melancholy." In the IGN
    review, critic Chad Grischow wrote, "It is their one and only
    foray into unabashed orchestral pop, but the punchy strut of
    the strings and fantastic marching vocals make it far too
    charming and lively to dislike, and even harder not to love."
    "Viva la Vida" was nominated for "Record of the Year", and won
    "Song of the Year", and "Best Pop Performance by a Duo or a
    Group" at the 2009 Grammy Awards. This song also won the Ivor
    Novella Award for "Best Selling British Single". The song was
    included in 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s annual "100 Best Songs" of 2008 at
    number nine, it was also voted number two on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s Readers' Rock List: Best Songs of 2008.
    "Viva la Vida" was also listed at number five on 
    <i>Blender</i>'s 1001 Downloads: The Top 144 Songs of 2008, as
    well in the number eight position on 
    <i>Village Voice</i>'s Pazz and Jop list.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Viva la Vida</i>has also been sampled in other several
    songs, such as in Flo-Rida's single 
    <i>Be on You</i>as well as a similar riff heard at the start of
    Agnes' song 
    <i>Release Me</i>.</p>
      <p>"Viva la Vida" has become the band's highest-charting
    single. Fueled by high digital sales, the song peaked at the
    top spot of the U.S. Hot 100, becoming the band's first US
    number-one single and their second top ten on the Hot 100. It
    is the first song by a British group to reach number-one on the
    Hot 100 since "Wannabe" by the Spice Girls in 1996, and it is
    the first song by a British rock band to top the chart since
    UB40's 1993 song "Can't Help Falling in Love". Although the
    song was initially successful in digital sales, after being
    released, it went on to become the band's highest-charting
    single in American radio, becoming their first top ten hit on
    the Hot 100 Airplay where it peaked at number eight. It had
    also become the band's first number-one single on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Modern Rock Tracks chart. "Viva la Vida" also
    became the first song to top both the Hot 100 and Modern Rock
    chart since Nickelback's "How You Remind Me" in 2001 and 2002.
    On the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Adult Top 40 Tracks, the song has become
    the band's first number one, as well as the first single on the
    Capitol Records label to ever top the chart. The single has
    been certified triple platinum by the Recording Industry
    Association of America.. The song also become one of six songs
    to reach the 4 million mark in paid digital downloads.</p>
      <p>The single was also successful in the United Kingdom.
    Although the song had been disqualified from the UK charts due
    to initially being available only by pre-ordering the album on
    iTunes, it became eligible to chart after the album was
    released. "Viva la Vida" hit number one on the UK Singles
    Chart, becoming Coldplay's first chart-topping single in the
    UK. The song remained in the top 40 through early 2009, and on
    15 March 2009 dropped to number 34.</p>
      <p>In Canada, the single made a "Hot Shot Debut" at number four
    on the Canadian Hot 100 on the issue of 24 May, making it
    Coldplay's highest debut there. It is also Coldplay's highest
    charting single in Australia, where it reached number 2.</p>
      <p>In Spain, the single peaked at #2 and achieved Double
    Platinum status due to the 80,000 copies sold. It also had a
    strong airplay in the Spanish radio stations.</p>
      <p>During the 2008/2009 season, the German football club
    Hamburger SV used "Viva la Vida" as their goal celebration
    song.</p>
      <p>The song also became the anthem of Spanish football club FC
    Barcelona during the 2008-09 season. It turned out to be a
    season of unprecedented success for the Spanish side, as they
    won all six competitions they could possible be involved in,
    which no football club has ever managed before. The song was
    selected by the manager of the club, Josep Guardiola - himself
    a Coldplay fan - to help motivate and encourage his team. It is
    often played at the Camp Nou before the start of a Barcelona
    match.</p>
      <p>Canadian figureskater Patrick Chan has used this song for
    his short program.</p>
      <p>Coldplay were first accused of plagiarism of "The Songs I
    Didn't Write" by American alternative band Creaky Boards, for
    the melody of "Viva la Vida". Creaky Boards' band member Andrew
    Hoepfner claimed that Martin had heard them playing the song at
    a live show in October 2007. The band released a video clip, in
    which it compares sections of both songs. Coldplay denied the
    claim; band spokesman Murray Chambers said Martin was working
    in AIR Studios in London at that time, having checked the
    singer's diary. In addition, Coldplay had recorded a demo
    version of "Viva la Vida" in March 2007, long before Creaky
    Boards performed it live in October of the same year. Creaky
    Boards later retracted the accusations and speculated that both
    songs may have been inspired by the video game 
    <i>The Legend of Zelda</i>.</p>
      <p>On 4 December 2008, American guitarist Joe Satriani filed a
    copyright infringement suit against Coldplay in Los Angeles.
    The suit claims that "Viva la Vida" incorporates "substantial,
    original portions" of his instrumental track "If I Could Fly"
    from his 2004 album 
    <i>Is There Love in Space?</i>. The band has denied the
    allegation, saying the similarities were "entirely
    coincidental". On 14 September 2009, the case was dismissed by
    the California Central District Court, with both parties
    potentially agreeing to an out-of-court settlement.</p>
      <p>In May 2009, Yusuf Islam stated that the song is very
    similar to his song "Foreigner Suite," (recorded under his
    former stage name, Cat Stevens) saying "My son brought it to my
    attention and said: 'Doesn't that sound like 'Foreigner
    Suite?'" Islam said that any legal action he might take
    "depends on how well Satriani does." Coldplay drummer Will
    Champion denied the claim, stating, "We're confident we haven't
    done anything wrong." In June 2009, Islam later said, "They did
    copy my song but I don't think they did it on purpose," adding,
    "I don't want them to think I am angry with them. I'd love to
    sit down and have a cup of tea with them and let them know it's
    okay."</p>
      <p>The official music video for "Viva la Vida" was directed by
    Hype Williams and premiered at Coldplay's official website on 1
    August 2008. The video depicts the band performing against a
    blurry, warped version of Eugène Delacroix's painting "La
    Liberté guidant le peuple." Since its release, this video "Viva
    La Vida" has become one of the most viewed music videos on
    YouTube, with over 70,000,000 views worldwide.</p>
      <p>A second, alternate video was shot in The Hague, the
    Netherlands, directed by Anton Corbijn and released alongside
    the first. This second version is a tribute to Corbijn's video
    for Depeche Mode's "Enjoy the Silence" and portrays Chris
    Martin as the king from whose perspective the song is sung.
    During the video, he carries Eugène Delacroix's painting "La
    Liberté guidant le peuple.". At the end, he hangs the picture
    up in a white stall on top of a hill. As he sings the last
    chorus, his band mates surface heading his way, tying in loose
    ends from the "Violet Hill" video.</p>
      <p>Swedish singer Darin's cover of the song reached number 1 on
    30 October 2009 on the Swedish Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>In 2010, it was yet again included as the B-side of Darin's
    "You're Out of My Life" single, reaching #3 in the Swedish
    Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>Coldplay's original single had already charted in Sweden for
    a total of 49 weeks between 15 May 2008 and 23 October 2009,
    peaking at number seven.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
