<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three_Times_a_Lady 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three_Times_a_Lady</songId>
   <title>Three Times a Lady</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commodores</artistId>
      <artistName>Commodores</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1978-08-12</week>
      <week>1978-08-19</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Natural High</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1978</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:36 (7" )</length>
      <length>6:36 (12" )</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Motown Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lionel Richie</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>James Anthony Carmichael</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Three Times a Lady" is a 1978 single from the funk/soul
    band the Commodores, from their 1978 album 
    <i>Natural High</i>. It was produced by James Anthony
    Carmichael and the Commodores and it was the most popular track
    of the album.</p>
      <p>In an appearance on 
    <i>The Early Show</i>on June 12, 2009, Richie said he was
    inspired to write it by a comment his father made about his
    mother. Reportedly his father said to his mother "I love you. I
    want you. I need you. Forever" hence the three times. It became
    the Commodores's first Billboard Hot 100 number-one hit,
    topping the chart for two weeks on August 12, 1978. . It was
    also the only Motown song to reach the Top 10 that year. The
    song also spent three weeks at #1 on the adult contemporary
    chart. It was one of only a few Motown singles to reach the top
    spot in the UK. In the years since the Commodores had started
    in 1974 it has been one of their most emotional songs since
    "You Don't Know That I Know" from the album 
    <i>Caught in the Act</i>in 1975.</p>
      <p>The original Commodores' version of the song was included as
    the final track on Lionel Richie's greatest hits compilation
    album Back To Front, released in 1992.</p>
      <p>In the movie Garden State, the song is performed at a
    funeral by actress Jackie Hoffman.</p>
      <p>The chorus of the song was parodied on 
    <i>Saturday Night Live</i>. Eddie Murphy, in the Buckwheat
    persona, would use numeric hand gestures and yell, "Unce! Tice!
    Fee tines a mady!"</p>
      <p>Comedian Bill Bailey performed a German translation of the
    song in his 
    <i>Part Troll</i>set. According to Radio 1 DJ Scott Mills, the
    song is about Richie professing his love for fat women.</p>
      <p>In an episode of 
    <i>Will &amp; Grace</i>, after Grace admits to having breakup
    sex and doing it not only twice but three times, Will responds,
    "Let's see. Once, twice, three times... I don't think that
    makes you a lady."</p>
      <p>Episode 709 of 
    <i>South Park</i>, "Christian Rock Hard", Cartman uses
    Christian rock to win a $10 bet by taking pre-existing lyrics
    and substituting his own. One of the songs of the self-titled
    album for their band "Faith + 1", was "Three Times My
    Savior".</p>
      <p>The most successful cover version was performed by Conway
    Twitty, who took his version into the top 10 of the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Country Singles chart in 1984. Twitty's
    version appeared on his 1983 album, 
    <i>Lost in the Feeling</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was also covered in the country genre by country
    singer Billy "Crash" Craddock on his 1986 album 
    <i>Crash Craddock</i>and in 2007 by Cobra Starship as an iTunes
    bonus track for their album 
    <i>¡Viva La Cobra!</i>. In 2001 it was covered by
    Anglo-Norwegian boy band a1 and featured on 
    <i>Motown Mania</i>and as a bonus track on their hit single "No
    More".</p>
      <p>The song appears on the episode of 
    <i>In the Heat of the Night</i>on Season 2's "The Hammer and
    the Glove" aired on December 13, 1988.</p>
      <p>In an episode of 
    <i>Seinfeld</i>, Newman sings part of this song, while his mail
    truck catches fire.</p>
      <p>Was used in 
    <i>The Sopranos</i>episode, 
    <i>The Test Dream</i>as the end credits rolled.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
