<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Break_the_Heart_That_Loves_You 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Break_the_Heart_That_Loves_You</songId>
   <title>Don't Break the Heart That Loves You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Connie_Francis</artistId>
      <artistName>Connie Francis</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1962-03-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>January 1962</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>November 2, 1961</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Country</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:05</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MGM Records 13059</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Benny Davis</writer>
      <writer>Ted Murry</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Danny Davis</producer>
      <producer>Arnold Maxin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Don't Break the Heart That Loves You" is an American song
    written by Benny Davis and Ted Murry. The song would become a
    success for two artists in two different genres: Connie Francis
    in the pop field in 1962, and Margo Smith as a country version
    in 1978.</p>
      <p>Benny Davis and Ted Murry became associated with Connie
    Francis by suggestion of Francis' father, George Franconero.
    The idea was to combine the skills of Tin Pan Alley veterans
    Davis and Murry with the current sound of the day. Francis
    signed Murry and Davis as regular composers to her own music
    publishing company, Francon Music Incorporated. Over the
    following years, Davis and Murry wrote further hits for
    Francis, such as the country ballad 
    <i>The biggest sin of all</i>and the theme song for Francis'
    third movie, 
    <i>Follow The Boys</i>, which she also recorded in French,
    Italian, Spanish, Japanese, and German. Neither of the songs
    left a bigger impact on 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Pop Charts, but became notable successes on
    the Adult Contemporary Charts.</p>
      <p>Francis recorded "Don't Break the Heart That Loves You" in a
    2 November 1961 session which also produced "I'm Falling in
    Love With You Tonight," "When the Boy in Your Arms (Is the Boy
    in Your Heart)," "'Baby's First Christmas," "'Mon Cœur est un
    Violon," and "Personne au Monde."</p>
      <p>The ballad, recorded by Francis in two-part harmony with a
    spoken bridge, is a plea from a heartbroken lover who is trying
    to understand why her lover is going out of his way to treat
    her unkindly. The song ends with her begging him not to break
    her heart.</p>
      <p>"Don't Break the Heart That Loves You" went to No. 1 on the
    Billboard Hot 100 on March 31, 1962 for one week, becoming her
    third and final chart-topping single.</p>
      <p>The song charted in the UK in April 1962 without paralleling
    its US chart impact; rather "Don't Break the Heart That Loves
    You" became Francis' first single to miss the UK Top 30 with a
    #39 peak.</p>
      <p>Following the success in the US, Francis recorded "Don't
    Break the Heart That Loves You" subsequently also in German
    ("Tu mir Nicht Weh"), Spanish ("Mi Corazón te Adora"), Japanese
    (Latin writing of Japanese title unknown) and in both regular
    Italian and the Italian dialect Neapolitan (both as "Un
    Desiderio Folle")</p>
      <p>In 1977, the ballad was recorded by country singer Margo
    Smith. Her version — featuring a saxophone solo during the
    musical bridge but not the recitation of Francis's version —
    topped the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Country Singles chart in February 1978, and
    crossed over to the Easy Listening chart at #40.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
