<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gangsta%27s_Paradise_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gangsta%27s_Paradise_(song)</songId>
   <title>Gangsta's Paradise</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coolio</artistId>
      <artistName>Coolio featuring L.V.</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1995-09-09</week>
      <week>1995-09-16</week>
      <week>1995-09-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/c/c6/Gangsta%27s_paradise.jpg/200px-Gangsta%27s_paradise.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Coolio-featuring-L-V+Gangsta-s-Paradise.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Gangsta's Paradise, Dangerous Minds OSTI Am L.V.</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 31, 1995</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette</format>
      <format>12-inch single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1995</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>West Coast Hip Hop</genre>
      <genre>Gangsta Rap</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:00</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Tommy Boy Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Coolio</writer>
      <writer>Doug Rasheed</writer>
      <writer>Larry Sanders</writer>
      <writer>Stevie Wonder</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Doug Rasheed</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Gangsta's Paradise" is a rap song by Coolio featuring L.V.
    from the movie 
    <i>Dangerous Minds</i>(1995). The song was later released on
    the albums 
    <i>Gangsta's Paradise</i>and soundtrack in 1995. Coolio was
    awarded a Grammy for the song/album. The song was voted as the
    best single of the year in 
    <i>The Village Voice</i>Pazz &amp; Jop critics poll.</p>
      <p>It sampled the chorus and music of the song "Pastime
    Paradise" by Stevie Wonder (1976). Wonder performed the song
    with Coolio and L.V. at the 1995 Billboard Awards.</p>
      <p>The song was also listed at #69 on 
    <i>Billboard's Greatest Songs of All-Time</i>and #1 biggest
    selling single of 1995 on U.S. 
    <i>Billboard</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2008, it was ranked number 38 on VH1's 100 Greatest Songs
    of Hip Hop.</p>
      <p>L.V. released a solo version of the single in 1996 on his
    debut album, 
    <i>I Am L.V.</i>. This version did not feature Coolio, and
    featured additional lyrics written by L.V. himself. The single
    did not repeat the popularity of the original with Coolio.</p>
      <p>The music is a reworking of Stevie Wonder's "Pastime
    Paradise", a song from his album 
    <i>Songs in the Key of Life</i>. "Gangsta's Paradise" uses the
    same tune, and a different orchestration of the same backing
    music. Coolio changed the lyrics to be more relevant to life on
    the streets.</p>
      <p>The song begins with a line from Psalm 23:4 from the Bible: 
    <i>As I walk through the valley of the shadow of death</i>, but
    then diverges with: 
    <i>I take a look at my life / And realize there's nothin'
    left.</i>Adding to some of the religious overtones are choral
    vocals in the background.</p>
      <p>Many of the lyrics are very dark and tragic and are meant to
    be a criticism of the violence and tragedy of the "gangsta"
    life. The choral lines (sung by L.V.) 
    <i>Tell me why are we so blind to see / That the ones we hurt
    are you and me</i>offer an especially plaintive
    self-criticism.</p>
      <p>The music video for the song was directed by Antoine Fuqua
    of Propaganda Films, and featured Michelle Pfeiffer reprising
    her earlier role in 
    <i>Dangerous Minds</i>.</p>
      <p>When Coolio won the Best Rap Video at the MTV Video Music
    Awards in 1996, he said in a press conference that Bone
    Thugs-n-Harmony deserved the award for "Tha Crossroads".</p>
      <p>The single reached number one in the United States, United
    Kingdom, Ireland, France, Germany, Italy, Sweden, Austria,
    Netherlands, Norway, Switzerland, Australia, and New Zealand,
    making it Coolio's most successful single. Following Coolio's
    appearance in the UK TV show Celebrity Big Brother 2009
    Gangsta's Paradise re-entered the UK singles chart peaking at
    #31.</p>
      <p>There are some parodies of the song, including "Amish
    Paradise" by "Weird Al" Yankovic, which was released the
    following year, reaching #53 on the U.S. chart. Coolio claimed
    that he did not give permission for the parody, which led to
    disagreements between the two. Yankovic claimed that he had
    been told Coolio had given the go-ahead through his record
    label, and apologized. Because of this incident, Yankovic now
    only does parodies by artists that he has spoken with directly,
    rather than through intermediaries. Photos from the XM
    Satellite Radio booth at the 2006 Consumer Electronics Show
    suggest Yankovic and Coolio may have made amends.</p>
      <p>The Christian rock band ApologetiX also did a parody called
    "Shepherd's Paradise" based on Psalm 23.</p>
      <p>Another parody by Paul Shanklin using Gangsta's Paradise is
    "Algore Paradise," in which Shanklin sings in the voices of Al
    Gore and Bill Clinton. The Choral Line as sung by Shanklin (as
    Clinton) goes, 
    <i>Tell me why is it / so hard to see / If he's really a man,
    or just a tree.</i>
      </p>
      <p>Death metal parody-group Ten Masked Men have also done a
    rendition of the song. The former boy band Blue used a sample
    of the instrumental for their single "Curtain Falls".</p>
      <p>Metalcore band In Fear and Faith covered this song as well,
    as well as Death/Thrash band Artas.</p>
      <p>The song appeared on the television show 
    <i>New York Undercover</i>.</p>
      <p>The song also appeared in an episode of 
    <i>Ross Kemp on Gangs</i>
      </p>
      <p>Sturman George Russian band ("Штурман Жорж") used a sample
    of the instrumental for their single "Ausweis" ("Аусвайс").</p>
      <p>Billboard</p>
      <p>MTV</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
