<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_the_Door,_Richard 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_the_Door,_Richard</songId>
   <title>Open the Door, Richard</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Count_Basie</artistId>
      <artistName>Count Basie</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1947-02-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Open the Door, Richard" is a song first recorded on the
    Black &amp; White Records label by saxophonistist Jack McVea at
    the suggest of A&amp;R man Ralph Bass. In 1947, it was the
    number-one song on 's "Honor Roll of Hits" and became a runaway
    pop sensation.</p>
      <p>"Open the Door, Richard" started out as a black vaudeville
    routine. Pigmeat Markham, one of several who performed the
    routine, attributed it to his mentor Bob Russell. The routine
    was made famous by Dusty Fletcher on stages like the Apollo
    Theater in New York and in a short film [Archive.org]. Dressed
    in rags, drunk, and with a ladder as his only prop, Fletcher
    would repeatedly plunk the ladder down stage center, try to
    climb it to knock on an imaginary door, then crash sprawling on
    the floor after a few steps while shouting, half-singing "Open
    the Door, Richard". After this he would mutter a comic
    monologue, then try the ladder again and repeat the process,
    while the audience was imagining what Richard was so occupied
    doing.</p>
      <p>Jack McVea was responsible for the musical riff which became
    associated with the words "Open the Door, Richard" that became
    familiar to radio listeners and as many as 14 different
    recording were made.</p>
      <p>In the song, accompanied by a rhythm section and McVea's
    expressive tenor honking, the intoxicated, rowdy band members
    come home late at night, knowing Richard has the only key to
    the house. Knocking and repeated calls from McVea and the band
    members for Richard to open the door get no result. The musical
    refrain kicks in with the musicians singing in unison:</p>
      <p>The spoken dialog makes humorous references to negative
    aspects of urban African-American life, including poverty and
    police brutality. The narrator explains, "I know Richard's home
    'cause I got on the clothes." He also says, "I was on relief,
    but they got short of help and you had to go downtown to pick
    up the checks, so I gave it up." Later, when a policeman tells
    him to come down from the ladder and begins hitting his feet,
    the narrator protests, "You act like one of them police that
    ain't never arrested nobody before."</p>
      <p>Although the neighbors are being disturbed, McVea continues
    knocking as the song fades away.</p>
      <p>The recording by Count Basie was released by RCA Victor
    Records as catalog number 20-2127. It first reached the
    Billboard magazine Best Seller chart on February 7, 1947 and
    lasted four weeks on the chart, peaking at number one.</p>
      <p>The recording by Dusty Fletcher was released by National
    Records as catalog number 4012. It first reached the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Best Seller chart on January 31, 1947, and
    lasted five weeks on the chart, peaking at number three.</p>
      <p>The recording by The Three Flames was released by Columbia
    Records as catalog number 37268. It first reached the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Best Seller chart on February 14, 1947, and
    lasted three weeks on the chart, peaking at number four.</p>
      <p>The recording by Louis Jordan was released by Decca Records
    as catalog number 23841. It first reached the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Best Seller chart on March 7, 1947, and lasted
    two weeks on the chart, peaking at number seven.</p>
      <p>The recording by Jack McVea, recorded in October 1946, was
    released by Black &amp; White Records as catalog number 792. It
    first reached the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Best Seller chart on February 14, 1947, and
    lasted two weeks on the chart, peaking at number seven. As
    stated above, this was the original recording.</p>
      <p>For all the artists above except Jordan, this was their only
    hit on the charts. (This even includes Count Basie, despite his
    great fame, and despite the fact that this was a number-one hit
    for him. In Whitburn's later 
    <i>Pop Memories</i>, Basie was indeed recognized for his many
    chart singles outside the retail Top 10. The Basie string of
    "hits" continued on different Billboard charts through
    1968.)</p>
      <p>The origins of the piece in a vaudeville routine led to
    there being several claimants to the rights. Russell was no
    longer alive, but both Mason and Fletcher came forth claiming
    to have written it; Fletcher even claimed that he had written
    the tune. By the time the dust settled, the official credits
    read "Words by Dusty Fletcher and John Mason, music by Dusty
    Fletcher and Don Howell". Howell appears to have been an
    entirely fictional front through which someone managed to
    pocket some of the royalties at McVea's expense.</p>
      <p>"Open the Door, Richard" was an early R&amp;B novelty
    record, a song category that became a basic genre of rock and
    roll in the 1950s. It started the fad of answer song records.
    It was also the first commercial record to use a fade out
    ending.</p>
      <p>When "Open the Door, Richard" landed on the "Honor Roll of
    Hits" it joined such white pop songs as "Zip-A-Dee Doo-Dah" for
    a Walt Disney film. But a black ballad "(I Love You) For
    Sentimental Reasons" sung by Al Jolson was also on the list.
    These two songs became the first rhythm and blues songs since
    "I Wonder" to achieve sensational success in the white market
    and indicated that the pop mainstream was open to R&amp;B.</p>
      <p>The phrase "Open the Door, Richard" passed into African
    American Vernacular English and became associated with the
    Civil Rights Movement. When college students marched in 1947 to
    the state capitol demanding the resignation of segregationist
    governor Herman Talmadge, some of their banners read "Open the
    Door Herman". The 
    <i>Los Angeles Sentinel</i>used "Open the Door Richard" as the
    title of an editorial demanding black representation in city
    government and a Detroit minister used the title for a sermon
    on open housing.</p>
      <p>"Open the Door, Richard" became a catchphrase in broader
    American society, as well; the line appeared in routines by
    Jack Benny, Fred Allen, and Phil Harris. Jimmy Durante and Burl
    Ives each recorded versions of the song; opera star Lauritz
    Melchior performed it on national radio. Molly Picon recorded a
    Yiddish language version; it was also covered in Spanish,
    Swedish, French, and Hungarian. There were "Richard" hats,
    shirts, and jeans, and ads for products ranging from ale to
    perfume incorporated references to the song.</p>
      <p>A reference to the phrase appears in the 1947 Looney Tunes
    short 
    <i>Crowing Pains</i>uses a pun on this title, "Open the Window,
    Richard", when Foghorn Leghorn outfits Henery Hawk with an egg
    shell.</p>
      <p>Another reference appears in a 1949 Looney Tunes cartoon, 
    <i>High Diving Hare</i>, featuring Yosemite Sam and Bugs Bunny
    (a riff on the song also appears in this cartoon). In this
    cartoon, Sam climbs up a ladder of a high-diving board, only to
    find a door on it. When he tries to open it he shouts, "Open up
    this door!!", then breaks the fourth wall and says, "D'ja
    notice I didn' say 'Richard'?"</p>
      <p>In 1967, Bob Dylan and the Band recorded an homage to the
    song as part of The Basement Tapes. Entitled "Open the Door,
    Homer", its chorus nevertheless repeated the phrase "Open the
    door Richard."</p>
      <p>The Cuban Boys released a re-mix of the song with the same
    title on their 2000 'Old Skool For Scoundrels' EP.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
