<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karma_Chameleon 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karma_Chameleon</songId>
   <title>Karma Chameleon</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture_Club</artistId>
      <artistName>Culture Club</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1984-02-04</week>
      <week>1984-02-11</week>
      <week>1984-02-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a8/Nw171.jpg/200px-Nw171.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Culture-Club+Karma-Chameleon.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Colour by Numbers</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>5 September 1983</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1983</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
      <genre>Folk Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:12 (album version)</length>
      <length>3:51 (single edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Virgin</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>George O'Dowd</writer>
      <writer>Jon Moss</writer>
      <writer>Mikey Craig</writer>
      <writer>Phil Pickett</writer>
      <writer>Roy Hay</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Steve Levine</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Karma Chameleon" is a song by British New Wave band Culture
    Club, featured on the group's 1983 album 
    <i>Colour by Numbers</i>. The song spent three weeks at number
    one on the US Hot 100 in 1984, becoming the group's biggest hit
    and only US number one. "Karma Chameleon" hit number one in
    sixteen countries worldwide. In the group's home country, it
    became the second Culture Club single to reach the top of the
    UK singles chart, where it stayed for six weeks in September
    and October 1983, and became the biggest-selling single of
    1983.</p>
      <p>In an interview, Culture Club frontman Boy George explained:
    "The song is about the terrible fear of alienation that people
    have, the fear of standing up for one thing. It's about trying
    to suck up to everybody. Basically, if you aren't true, if you
    don't act like you feel, then you get Karma-justice, that's
    nature's way of paying you back."</p>
      <p>The prominent harmonica part was played by Judd Lander, who
    had been a member of Merseybeat group The Hideaways in the
    1960s. The song was originally to be called "Cameo Chameleon".
    The band were recorded in interviews in late 1983 stating this
    was to be the title of their next single.</p>
      <p>Likely because of the lyric "I'm a man without conviction,"
    and the chorus, which repeats the word "chameleon," "Karma
    Chameleon" has been used by several politicians in political
    ads. In 2006, Britain's Labour Party used "Karma Chameleon" as
    the theme song for a series of political advertisements against
    Conservative party leader David Cameron in the 2006 UK
    Elections. Also, during the 2010 U.S. senate race in
    Pennsylvania, Republican Pat Toomey used the song as backing
    music for his video "Happy Anniversary Arlen Specter!" as a way
    to criticize a sitting Senator from Pennsylvania and
    recently-turned Democrat Arlen Specter.</p>
      <p>The song won Best British Single at the 1984 Brit
    Awards.</p>
      <p>The "Karma Chameleon" music video was filmed at Desborough
    Island in Weybridge during the summer of 1983. According to
    caption, the video is set in Mississippi in 1870, and depicts
    people in colourful costumes, including dancers in "red, gold
    and green", waiting on a riverbank. Boy George is dressed in a
    colourful costume and is depicted singing the title song. A
    pickpocket is seen wandering through the crowd.</p>
      <p>A riverboat, "The Chameleon", arrives and people board. A
    game of cards takes place, as Boy George continues to sing in
    the background. The pickpocket is discovered cheating and is
    forced to walk the plank. Throughout the video, Blacks and
    Caucasians are depicted singing and dancing together.</p>
      <p>The boat used in the video belongs to Turk Launches of
    Kingston-upon-Thames, and it is still in use, mainly on the
    Kingston to Hampton Court route during the summer months.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
