<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_After_Time_(Cyndi_Lauper_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_After_Time_(Cyndi_Lauper_song)</songId>
   <title>Time After Time</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyndi_Lauper</artistId>
      <artistName>Cyndi Lauper</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1984-06-09</week>
      <week>1984-06-16</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/33/Cyndi_Lauper_Time_After.jpg/200px-Cyndi_Lauper_Time_After.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Cyndi-Lauper+Time-After-Time.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>She's So Unusual</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1984</released>
   <formats>
      <format>12" vinyl</format>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1983</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:03</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Cyndi Lauper</writer>
      <writer>Rob Hyman</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Rick Chertoff</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Time After Time" is a single by singer Cyndi Lauper, the
    second from her album 
    <i>She's So Unusual</i>. It reached number one on the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100 chart on June 9, 1984, and remained there for
    two weeks. Worldwide, the song is her most commercially
    successful single after "Girls Just Want to Have Fun", and
    reached number 3 on the UK Singles Chart and number 6 on the
    ARIA Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>"Time After Time" was nominated for Song of the Year at the
    1985 Grammy Awards. The ballad is considered a classic of the
    1980s and is still played frequently on adult contemporary
    radio. The song is known for its numerous covers by a wide
    range of artists, including an instrumental version by Miles
    Davis.</p>
      <p>Lauper co-wrote "Time After Time" with Philadelphia rocker
    Rob Hyman of The Hooters, who also supplied backup vocals to
    the song. In a 2006 interview with 
    <i>Sound Off with Matt Pinfield</i>(episode 212) on HDNet,
    Lauper related how the song was written. She indicated much of
    the lyrics were written about occurrences in the studio and her
    life at the time. The line "the second hand unwinds" referred
    to producer Rick Chertoff's watch which was winding
    backwards.</p>
      <p>Hyman explained in an interview with Songfacts that he and
    Lauper stayed in the studio after the sessions composing the
    song.</p>
      <p>Drums were provided by a Linn drum machine, particularly the
    'salt-shaker' sound. The guitar was recorded with a Marshall
    2x12 combo amp, where a rackmountable Publison DHM89 harmoniser
    was used in the effects loop, set to delay-pitch-shift up the
    signal on the left channel and delay-pitch-shift up the signal
    on the right channel, to create a rich &amp; lush chorus-like
    effect.</p>
      <p>The video for "Time After Time" was about a runaway leaving
    her lover behind. The video opens with Lauper watching the 1936
    film 
    <i>The Garden of Allah</i>. Lauper sings (signs) the title of
    the song to the deaf as she is leaving the train station. The
    video was played in heavy rotation on MTV. Lauper's mother,
    brother, and then-boyfriend David Wolff appear in the video,
    and Lou Albano, who played her father in the "Girls Just Want
    to Have Fun" video, can be seen as a cook. The video was
    directed by Ed Griles. Portions of the video were filmed at the
    now closed Tom's Diner in Roxbury, the intersection of Central
    Ave &amp; Main St in Wharton, New Jersey, and at the Morristown
    train station.</p>
      <p>"Time After Time" has been covered, either in live
    performance or on a recording, by at least 120 different
    artists across a broad spectrum of genres. A partial list
    includes:</p>
      <p>The song was used as a main theme sung by Katie Cook in 
    <i>View from the Top</i>(2003). Mark Williams and Tara Morice
    performed the song in the 
    <i>Strictly Ballroom</i>soundtrack (in the scene where Scott
    and Fran dance on the rooftop). Eva Cassidy's version was
    featured in the TV series, 
    <i>Smallville</i>, and it was added to the first 
    <i>Smallville</i>soundtrack, 
    <i>The Talon Mix</i>. The 2006 cover by Quietdrive appeared
    during the dance scene of the film 
    <i>John Tucker Must Die</i>. It also contributed to a running
    gag in the second season of the TV series 
    <i>My Name Is Earl</i>.</p>
      <p>The song has been performed on 
    <i>American Idol</i>three times. In 2005, Nadia Turner
    performed the song on Billboard #1 Hits week in the fourth
    season. In 2007, Brandon Rogers performed the song on the
    second week of the semi-finals in honor of his grandmother in
    the sixth season. In 2009, 4th place finisher Allison Iraheta
    performed it as a duet with Lauper in the eighth season finale.
    Season 7 Semi-Finalists Kady Malloy and Colton Berry released a
    video of their cover on YouTube.</p>
      <p>On Channel 4's show 
    <i>Mobileact Unsigned</i>, The Bad Robots performed a version
    of this track.</p>
      <p>INOJ's cover version of "Time After Time" reached number six
    on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 chart in 1998.</p>
      <p>The song is briefly sung by Anna Kendrick's character as a
    karaoke song in the film 
    <i>Up in the Air</i>.</p>
      <p>Quietdrive's version can be heard in the film, 
    <i>John Tucker Must Die</i>, during the food fight at John's
    birthday party. The song was also used in the 2008 remake of
    the film 
    <i>Prom Night</i>. It peaked at number two on 's Bubbling Under
    Hot 100 Singles chart (the virtual equivalent of #102 on the
    Hot 100).</p>
      <p>The song is featured numerous times in the film 
    <i>Romy and Michele's High School Reunion</i>.</p>
      <p>Elements of this song, mainly the guitar melody during the
    bridge, were used in the 2009 Black Eyed Peas song "Meet Me
    Halfway".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
