<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bad_Day_(Daniel_Powter_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bad_Day_(Daniel_Powter_song)</songId>
   <title>Bad Day</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_Powter</artistId>
      <artistName>Daniel Powter</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2006-04-08</week>
      <week>2006-04-15</week>
      <week>2006-04-22</week>
      <week>2006-04-29</week>
      <week>2006-05-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/3e/Bad_Day_single.jpg/200px-Bad_Day_single.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Daniel-Powter+Bad-Day.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Daniel Powter</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 2005  (2005-01) , (See release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2004</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:53</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Warner Music Group (USA) , Sony BMG (Europe/Korea/Latin America)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Daniel Powter</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Bad Day" is a pop song written by Canadian singer Daniel
    Powter. It was released as the first single from his second
    album 
    <i>Daniel Powter</i>(2005) and achieved the #1 spot in the U.S.
    and Ireland. In the U.S. it became the most successful single
    of 2006 as ranked by 
    <i>Billboard Magazine</i>.</p>
      <p>Despite the song's success, Powter failed to release any
    more pop hits, proving to be a very successful one-hit
    wonder.</p>
      <p>The music video is directed by Marc Webb and features two
    single people, a male (Jason Adelman) and a female (Samaire
    Armstrong), waking and going about their daily schedule. The
    video shows this happening over a three-day period, but makes
    no distinction between the days apart from the different
    clothing worn for each day. The main event is the two adding
    graffiti to the same wall, separately, on each day, culminating
    in the completion of a heart. At the end of the video, life
    mirrors the image created on the wall, with the boy offering
    the soaking wet girl a red umbrella in the pouring rain, as a
    cab stops for them. Parts of it were shot in a split-screen.
    Throughout the video, Powter is shown with his tuque, playing
    his piano. The Metro Red Line subway in Los Angeles was used
    during the shooting of this video and prominently featured
    throughout. The area where the two meet and add the graffiti on
    the wall is on the mezzanine level of Pershing Square Station
    in downtown Los Angeles.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Billboard</i>called the song "one of the great discoveries
    of the year" and the top One Hit Wonder of the 2000s.</p>
      <p>"Bad Day" reached number seven on the Canadian Singles
    Chart; it was also successful in the United Kingdom, where it
    reached number two on the UK Singles Chart after it was used in
    an advertising campaign for Coca-Cola. In the United States, it
    reached number one on the Hot 100. The song grew in popularity
    in the United States when it was used in the fifth season of 
    <i>American Idol</i>in the farewell video packages for
    eliminated contestants. It was also featured in the compilation
    album 
    <i>Voices from the FIFA World Cup</i>during the 2006 FIFA World
    Cup. It is also currently a popular song to play in sporting
    events, usually whenever the home team loses. It was even
    played after the 2008 U.S. Presidential election after John
    McCain's concession speech.</p>
      <p>"Bad Day" has been certified 2x platinum by the RIAA in the
    U.S. for digital sales of over 2 million. The song was featured
    as a free download on the iTunes Store from August 2–9, 2005.
    It was nominated for a 2007 Grammy Award for "Best Male Pop
    Vocal Performance".</p>
      <p>named "Bad Day" the No. 1 Hot 100 song of 2006. It is one of
    three "one hit wonders" to become Billboard's single of the
    year, following 1958's "Volare (Nel Blu Di Pinto Di Blu)" by
    Domenico Modugno and 1962's "Stranger On The Shore" by Mr.
    Acker Bilk.</p>
      <p>On the 16th July 2008, it was revealed by BBC News that "Bad
    Day" was the most played song in the UK during the period
    2003-2008.</p>
      <p>"Bad Day" was covered by the fictional music group Alvin and
    the Chipmunks for their 2007 film 
    <i>Alvin and the Chipmunks</i>. Their version made the charts
    in January 2008, peaking at #86 on the Billboard Hot 100.</p>
      <p>"Bad Day" was also covered by Kidz Bop, also the first Kidz
    Bop song to be a single.</p>
      <p>The Maccabeats, the all-male acapella group of Yeshiva
    University recorded an acapella version of the song on their
    2010 album, 
    <i>Voices From The Heights</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
