<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maneater_(Hall_%26_Oates_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maneater_(Hall_%26_Oates_song)</songId>
   <title>Maneater</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hall_%26_Oates</artistId>
      <artistName>Daryl Hall and John Oates</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1983-01-01</week>
      <week>1983-01-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/bc/Hall_%26_Oates_Maneater.jpeg/200px-Hall_%26_Oates_Maneater.jpeg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Daryl-Hall-and-John-Oates+Maneater.jpeg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>H2O</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1982</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop / Rock</genre>
      <genre>Dance Rock</genre>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
      <genre>Blue Eyed Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:33</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Sara Allen</writer>
      <writer>Daryl Hall</writer>
      <writer>John Oates</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Daryl Hall</producer>
      <producer>John Oates</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Maneater" is a single recorded by American duo Hall &amp;
    Oates from their 1982 album 
    <i>HO</i>. It reached number-one on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 chart on December 18, 1982. It remained
    in the top spot for four weeks, more than any of the duo's five
    other number-one hits. According to John Oates the inspiration
    for this song was English model and actress Kelly LeBrock.</p>
      <p>In an interview with American Songwriter, Daryl Hall states:
    John had written a prototype of “Maneater”; he was banging it
    around with Edgar Winter. It was like a reggae song. I said,
    “Well, the chords are interesting, but I think we should change
    the groove.” I changed it to that Motown kind of groove. So we
    did that, and I played it for Sara (Allen) and sang it for
    her…[Sings] “Oh here she comes/Watch out boy she’ll chew you
    up/Oh here she comes/She’s a maneater…and a …” I forget what
    the last line was. She said, “Drop that shit in the end and go,
    ‘She’s a maneater,’ and stop! And I said, ‘No, you’re crazy,
    that’s messed up.’” Then I thought about it, and I realized she
    was right. And it made all the difference in the song.</p>
      <p>The Hall &amp; Oates music video opens with a woman walking
    down a red staircase, and the band playing in a dimly lit
    studio with shafts of light projecting down on them. The band
    members step in and out of the light for their lip sync. A
    young woman in a short party dress is shown in fade-in and
    fade-out shots, along with a black jaguar, hence the song line
    "The woman is wild, a she-cat tamed by the purr of a Jaguar."
    The song refrain is "Whoa, oh here she comes; watch out boy,
    she'll chew you up; whoa, oh here she comes, she's a
    maneater".</p>
      <p>In 2006, the song and its subject matter were adapted and
    re-interpreted by Nelly Furtado for her song, also called
    "Maneater" from her album 
    <i>Loose</i>. The song was sampled once more in 2006 when the
    Ying Yang Twins (featuring Wyclef and Mr. Collipark) released
    the song "Dangerous". The Hall &amp; Oates version features a
    saxophone solo by Charles "Mr. Casual" DeChant. American rapper
    Hot Karl used the music and chorus of Maneater in a song
    satirizing the hip hop industry, also called "Maneater". In his
    intro, Karl alludes to the original song's popularity, telling
    the audience "I don't want to see any of you really hard guys
    not singing the words, because I know you know 'em! You don't
    not know 'Maneater'!" A cover of the song is also used as the
    theme for the pilot episode of the Adult Swim show 
    <i>Lucy, the Daughter of the Devil</i>. Hall and Oates also
    appeared on Will and Grace during Grace's wedding to James,
    singing Maneater as she walked down the aisle.</p>
      <p>In 2009, the song appeared on the 
    <i>Ballad Of Gay Tony</i>episode of the X-Box 360 exclusive
    video game, 
    <i>Grand Theft Auto: Episodes From Liberty City</i>, as a part
    of the Vice City FM radio station.</p>
      <p>In November 2008, Hall &amp; Oates initiated legal action
    against their music publisher (Warner/Chappell Music). An
    unidentified singer-songwriter was alleged to have used
    Maneater in a 2006 recording, infringing copyright, and by
    failing to sue for copyright infringement, Warner Chappell
    Music were alleged to have breached their contract with Hall
    and Oates.</p>
      <p>The song "We're Live (Danger)" by rapper Royce Da 5'9"
    (which was featured in the highly acclaimed game Grand Theft
    Auto III) contains a sample from the Hall &amp; Oates song
    "Maneater".</p>
      <p>The now defunct Chicago band Split Habit covered the song
    live, and also included it on their 2004 album Put Your Money
    Where Your Mouth Is.</p>
      <p>Las Vegas band The Kickwurmz released two versions of the
    song circa 1998: Maneater, and Man Eata' Digital Media House
    Remix.</p>
      <p>The original version of the song is heard in the 1999 film 
    <i>Runaway Bride</i>, and appears on the soundtrack. Early in
    the movie Richard Gere's character Ike Graham describes several
    mythological 'Maneaters' in a newspaper column, and then cites
    one human one, Julia Roberts's Maggie Carpenter, who's left
    multiple men standing at the altar.</p>
      <p>Jazz/electronica group The Bird and the Bee covered the song
    live with John Oates on March 5, 2010 at the El Rey Theater in
    Los Angeles, California. Their upcoming album 
    <i>Interpreting the Masters Volume 1: A Tribute to Daryl Hall
    and John Oates</i>will include a studio recorded cover of
    "Maneater", featuring backing vocals from Garbage vocalist
    Shirley Manson, and is to be released March 23, 2010.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
