<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fame_(David_Bowie_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fame_(David_Bowie_song)</songId>
   <title>Fame</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Bowie</artistId>
      <artistName>David Bowie</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1975-09-20</week>
      <week>1975-10-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/1/1b/Bowie_Fame.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/David-Bowie+Fame.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Young Americans</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 25, 1975  (1975-07-25)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Electric Lady Studios , New York January 1975</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Funk Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>03:30 Single edit</length>
      <length>04:12 Full-length album version</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA Records , Rykodisc / EMI ("Fame '90")</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>David Bowie</writer>
      <writer>Carlos Alomar</writer>
      <writer>John Lennon</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Harry Maslin</producer>
      <producer>David Bowie</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Fame" is a song recorded by David Bowie, initially released
    in 1975 and in remixed versions, in 1990.</p>
      <p>With the 
    <i>Young Americans</i>sessions mostly concluded in late 1974,
    the material was delayed while Bowie extricated himself from
    his contract with manager Tony DeFries. During this time he was
    staying in New York, and met John Lennon. The pair socialised
    and jammed together, which led to a one-day session at Electric
    Lady Studios in January 1975. There, Bowie contacted several
    members of his tour band. Firstly a cover of The Beatles’
    "Across the Universe" was recorded. Then a new song called
    "Fame", inspired by "Walk On", from the Jackson Five's "Going
    Back to Indiana" live album, and a guitar riff written by
    Carlos Alomar and with the title from Lennon, was then
    hurriedly developed by Bowie, and recorded. Both tracks were
    then added to the 
    <i>Young Americans</i>album. Despite having only a minor
    contribution, Lennon was given a co-writing credit due to the
    lyrics (bemoaning the nature of celebrity) being inspired by
    conversations he had with Bowie on the subject, and because
    Bowie acknowledged that Lennon singing "Fame!" over Alomar’s
    guitar riff was the catalyst for the song. The songwriting
    credit list order is David Bowie, Carlos Alomar, and John
    Lennon. Lennon's voice is also heard singing the repeated words
    "FAME, FAME,FAME" with his voice heard at a fast, normal, and
    slow track, making it sound like a recording on the fast and
    slow speeds, until Bowie's voice is heard singing the final
    lyrics of the song before the fade.</p>
      <p>An edited version of "Fame" was issued as the second single
    from the album, and shot to number one on the U.S. Billboard
    Hot 100 (a few months before a reissue of "Space Oddity" would
    give Bowie his first UK number-one single). In the UK, "Fame"
    would only reach number seventeen.</p>
      <p>A remixed version of "Fame" was released by EMI in 1990 to
    coincide with the 
    <i>Sound + Vision</i>tour and the release of the 
    <i>ChangesBowie</i>compilation. The "Gass Mix" was also
    included on the "Pretty Woman" soundtrack.</p>
      <p>Song written by David Bowie, Carlos Alomar, and John
    Lennon.</p>
      <p>Film director Gus Van Sant directed the promotional video
    for this version, which featured clips from many of Bowie’s
    previous videos. In the music video, Bowie also performs a
    dance with Louise Lecavalier, one of the main dancers of the
    Québécois contemporary dance troupe La La La Human Steps (whom
    Bowie would collaborate with on the 
    <i>Sound + Vision</i>tour).</p>
      <p>In both the UK and the U.S. this appeared in a variety of
    formats, including a 7" picture disc, an "Arthur Baker Remixes"
    12 inch single and a "Changes pack" with three prints of Bowie
    at different eras. None of the British releases (on EMI USA)
    feature the "Absolutely Nothing Premeditated mix". It stayed in
    the UK chart for four weeks, peaking at number
    twenty-eight.</p>
      <p>, "Fame" is a cover version by the band God Lives Underwater
    of the 1975 David Bowie song "
    <strong class="selflink">
Fame
</strong>". It was in 1998, resulting in significant airplay.</p>
      <p>God Lives Underwater's Fame music video is a video for the
    remake of Bowie's "Fame" on the soundtrack to the movie 15
    minutes.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
