<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Stripper 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Stripper</songId>
   <title>The Stripper</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Rose</artistId>
      <artistName>David Rose</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1962-07-07</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Stripper" is an instrumental composed by David Rose and
    recorded in 1962. It evinces a jazz influence with especially
    prominent trombone lines, and evokes the feel of music used to
    accompany striptease artists.</p>
      <p>The piece features in the films 
    <i>Slap Shot</i>, 
    <i>Used Cars</i>, 
    <i>The Full Monty</i>and 
    <i>Wallace &amp; Gromit: The Curse of the Were-Rabbit</i>as
    well as TV series 
    <i>Monty Python's Flying Circus</i>, 
    <i>Coupling</i>, 
    <i>Little Britain</i>, 
    <i>Are You Being Served?</i>and 
    <i>Scrubs</i>. It was also famously used in a parody by British
    comedy duo Morecambe and Wise, where they danced to the tune
    while making breakfast. A PG Tips tea commercial featured a
    parody of the Morcambe and Wise sketch with Johnny Vegas and
    Monkey making a cup of tea in a similar manner.</p>
      <p>American hard rock band Mötley Crüe occasionally used the
    original song as an intro during performances in the late 80s,
    most notably at the one-time Moscow Music Peace Festival which
    were held in August 1989. Rod Stewart has also used this song
    as intros on several tours, like on Tonight I Am
    Yours-Tour.</p>
      <p>A famous Noxzema shave-cream advertising campaign developed
    by the William Esty Advertising Agency used the piece as
    background music for a television commercial that featured
    Swedish model Gunilla Knudson telling men to 
    <i>“Take it off! Take it all off!”</i>. Cut to closeups of the
    faces of men shaving with safety razors, the razor strokes
    coinciding with the emphatic parts of the tune.</p>
      <p>The song reached number one on Billboard magazine's Pop
    Singles and Adult Contemporary charts in 1962.</p>
      <p>The late professional wrestler, Rick Rude, utilized this as
    his theme song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
