<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Chipmunk_Song_(Christmas_Don%27t_Be_Late) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Chipmunk_Song_(Christmas_Don%27t_Be_Late)</songId>
   <title>The Chipmunk Song (Christmas Don't Be Late)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ross_Bagdasarian</artistId>
      <artistName>David Seville and The Chipmunks</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1959-01-05</week>
      <week>1959-01-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1958 ( U.S. )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Christmas Song</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:17</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Liberty Records (F-55168)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ross Bagdasarian</writer>
      <writer>Sr. (a.k.a. David Seville)</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Ross Bagdasarian</producer>
      <producer>Sr. (a.k.a. David Seville)</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Chipmunk Song (Christmas Don't Be Late)" is a song
    written by Ross Bagdasarian, Sr. (a.k.a. David Seville) in
    1958. Although it was written and sung by Bagdasarian (in the
    form of a high-pitched chipmunk voice), the singing credits are
    given to The Chipmunks, a fictional singing group consisting of
    three chipmunks by the names of Alvin, Simon, and Theodore. The
    song won three Grammy Awards in 1958: Best comedy performance,
    Best children's recording, and Best engineered record
    (non-classical).</p>
      <p>The song was very successful, reaching #1 on the Billboard
    Hot 100 Pop Singles chart, becoming The Chipmunks' first (and
    only), as well as David Seville's second and final, #1 single.
    It has the distinction of being the only Christmas record to
    reach #1 on the same chart. The single sold 4.5 million copies,
    according to Ross Bagdasarian, Jr. Ironically, before the
    song's success, "The Chipmunk Song" was featured on 
    <i>American Bandstand's</i>"Rate-A-Record" segment and received
    the lowest possible rating of 35 across the board.</p>
      <p>Between 1959–1962, the single managed to re-enter the Hot
    100, peaking at #41 in 1959, #45 in 1960, and #39 in 1962.
    (Starting in 1963, Billboard would list re-current Christmas
    songs on a separate chart.) The song managed to chart on the
    Hot Digital Songs for the first time in 2005, peaking at #35 on
    that chart.</p>
      <p>"The Chipmunk Song" is the last Christmas song to reach #1
    on any US single record chart totaling performance of all
    available records.</p>
      <p>With the release and popularity of the film 
    <i>Alvin and the Chipmunks</i>in December 2007, "The Chipmunk
    Song" re-entered the Billboard Hot 100 at #70. At the same
    time, a remixed version of the song that appears on the
    Chipmunks' 2007 album (and soundtrack to the film) 
    <i>Alvin and the Chipmunks: Original Motion Picture
    Soundtrack</i>, peaked at #66 and was credited as "The Chipmunk
    Song (Christmas Don't Be Late) (2007 Version)".</p>
      <p>The song has been adapted in 
    <i>The Alvin Show</i>as one of its musical segments. The short
    depicts Alvin looking through various presents to find a hula
    hoop, even as he reluctantly sings along with the other
    Chipmunks. At the end of the song, Seville rewards Simon and
    Theodore with toy planes and Alvin with his hula hoop. The
    subsequent argument about singing the song again ends abruptly
    with their Christmas tree falling over, and Seville and the
    Chipmunks emerge from the mess to wish the viewers a merry
    Christmas. One notable thing in this segment is that Theodore's
    voice is lower and deeper.</p>
      <p>The song was featured in 
    <i>A Chipmunk Christmas</i>. A depressed Alvin sings along
    flatly at first (much like the 1958 original), but then leaves
    the studio to give away his harmonica to a sick boy. As Seville
    starts to resume recording the song without Alvin, Alvin
    returns in the nick of time to sing the song with the
    others.</p>
      <p>The song was featured in the '80s and '90s version of 
    <i>Alvin and the Chipmunks</i>, in the episode "Merry
    Christmas, Mr. Carroll." In that version, Alvin is taken by
    Dave (as the Spirit of Christmas Past) to his old house, a
    cabin lodge where he saw Dave and younger versions of himself,
    Simon and Theodore. There, it was revealed that Dave wrote the
    song (called "The Christmas Song" in this episode), because it
    was inspired by the gifts that the young Chipmunks gave him
    (which was an eraser, a pencil and a piece of paper).</p>
      <p>The song was used for he opening credits of the film, Almost
    Famous.</p>
      <p>The song was featured in the film 
    <i>Alvin and the Chipmunks</i>. There were multiple versions of
    the song in that film, the original with Ross Bagdasarian,
    Sr.'s voice, a new one with Jason Lee's voice as David Seville,
    and a rock mix.</p>
      <p>The original recording featured in the film 
    <i>Donnie Brasco</i>(1997).</p>
      <p>In the 2009 film Ice Age: Dawn of the Dinosaurs, The song is
    briefly sung by Crash and Eddie while in a gas which was like
    helium.</p>
      <p>In most subsequent releases since the song's original
    release, the first verse on the original recording has been
    re-recorded, sounding more exaggerated than the original
    release, which contained "Almost Good" as the flip side. There
    is also a version with the Chipmunks and rock group Canned Heat
    which was first issued as a single in 1968, which is a bonus
    track on the 2007 re-release of the Chipmunks' first Christmas
    album, Christmas with The Chipmunks, this version is the
    official remix of the original version of the song. On the 
    <i>Solid Gold Chipmunks: 30th Anniversary Edition</i>greatest
    hits album (1988), this song appears, but with an altered
    bridge and ending. Instead of Dave yelling at Alvin for how
    flat he is in the first verse, Alvin instead appeals that he
    has asked for the hula-hoop for years but has never gotten it.
    Dave answers by telling him to finish the song, and they'll
    discuss it later. After they finish, Dave tells Alvin that
    something came in for him. It's the hula-hoop that he's been
    asking for, and the song fades out with Alvin now rattling off
    a long list of what else he desires for Christmas. The 
    <i>Solid Gold Chipmunks</i>album, 
    <i>Here's Looking at Me</i>album, and 
    <i>The Chipmunk's 35th Birthday Party</i>(1993) are currently
    the only known albums that contains this version. There are two
    versions of the song that both feature Kenny G on the album 
    <i>A Very Merry Chipmunk</i>(1995), that features a more jazz
    version of the song with Kenny G playing the saxophone during
    the song, the first is the long version with Alvin complaining
    about Kenny G and his success as a jazz saxophone player and
    him helping Alvin to learn to play the sax, the second version
    called 
    <i>The Chipmunk Song (Christmas Don't Be Late) (Reprise)</i>is
    the first version but with the talking removed and just the
    song with Kenny G playing the sax and the Chipmunks singing the
    song. There was also a version with the Chipmunks and CCM
    singer, Jaci Velasquez in which Alvin fell in love with Jaci
    and changed the line "Hula Hoop" into "Date With You".</p>
      <p>On the album, "Disney's Merry Christmas Carols," Chip 'n
    Dale sing "The Chipmunk Song" with Donald Duck in the
    background.</p>
      <p>In 2008 Rosie Thomas released "A Very Rosie Christmas" which
    featured a slower tempo contemplative rendering of Christmas
    Don’t Be Late.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
