<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Let%27s_Dance_(David_Bowie_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Let%27s_Dance_(David_Bowie_song)</songId>
   <title>Let's Dance</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Bowie</artistId>
      <artistName>David Bowie</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1983-05-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/41/LetsDance.jpg/200px-LetsDance.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/David-Bowie+Let-s-Dance.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Let's Dance</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 17, 1983  (1983-03-17)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"/12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Power Station , New York , December 1982</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop / Dance</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>7:37 (Album version)</length>
      <length>4:10 (Single edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>EMI America Records - EA152</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>David Bowie</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Nile Rodgers</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Let’s Dance" is the title album track on David Bowie's
    album 
    <i>Let's Dance</i>. It was also released as the first single
    from that album in 1983, and went on to become one of his
    biggest-selling tracks.</p>
      <p>The single was one of Bowie’s fastest selling to date,
    entering the UK singles chart at number five on its first week
    of release, and deposing Duran Duran’s “Is There Something I
    Should Know?” two weeks later, staying at the top of the charts
    for three weeks. Soon afterwards, the single would top the
    Billboard Hot 100, Bowie’s only single to reach number one on
    both sides of the Atlantic. It narrowly missed topping the
    Australian charts, peaking at number two. Let's Dance is the
    fourth best-selling single of 1983 in the UK, selling over
    500,000 copies.</p>
      <p>“Let’s Dance” would introduce Bowie to a new younger
    audience oblivious to his former career in the '70s. The track
    was a regular on the Serious Moonlight Tour (the name derived
    from a lyric in “Let’s Dance”), the 1987 Glass Spider Tour and
    the 1990 Sound + Vision Tour, and was then reworked for the
    2000 tour. Most recently a remix version of it appears on a
    commercial for the March 22nd 2010 season of the ABC television
    show Dancing With The Stars.</p>
      <p>Heavily influenced by producer Nile Rodgers’ work with his
    band Chic, “Let’s Dance" features a thumping bassline, and was
    arguably Bowie’s most commercial record up to that point. While
    the lyrics are ostensibly just those of a dance song, there is
    some discord struck by lines such as “Let’s dance, for fear
    tonight is all”. The 7:38 album version was heavily edited for
    single release, though the 12” single retained the full
    length.</p>
      <p>This loneliness and desperation seeps into the music video,
    made with David Mallet on location in Australia including
    Sydney Harbour, which features Bowie watching an Aboriginal
    couple’s struggles against metaphors of Western cultural
    imperialism impassively while playing with his band.</p>
      <p>Bowie featured blues guitarist Stevie Ray Vaughan on the
    track. Vaughan was asked to go on tour with Bowie, but declined
    so he could continue to play with his band Double Trouble.
    Reportedly, Vaughan, who was still driving a delivery truck to
    support himself, was furious when he saw Bowie pantomiming over
    Vaughan's guitar solo in the video.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
