<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tie_a_Yellow_Ribbon_Round_the_Ole_Oak_Tree 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tie_a_Yellow_Ribbon_Round_the_Ole_Oak_Tree</songId>
   <title>Tie a Yellow Ribbon Round the Ole Oak Tree</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tony_Orlando_and_Dawn</artistId>
      <artistName>Dawn featuring Tony Orlando</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1973-04-21</week>
      <week>1973-04-28</week>
      <week>1973-05-05</week>
      <week>1973-05-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1973</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1973</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Bell</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Irwin Levine</writer>
      <writer>L. Russell Brown</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Hank Medress</producer>
      <producer>Dave Appell</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Tie a Yellow Ribbon Round the Ole Oak Tree" was a song by
    Dawn featuring Tony Orlando.</p>
      <p>Written by Irwin Levine and L. Russell Brown and produced by
    Hank Medress and Dave Appell, "Tie a Yellow Ribbon Round the
    Ole Oak Tree" was a massive worldwide hit in 1973 for Dawn
    featuring Tony Orlando.</p>
      <p>It reached number one on both the US and UK charts for four
    weeks in April 1973 and number one on the Australian charts for
    seven weeks from May to July 1973. It was the top-selling
    single for the year 1973 in both the US and UK.</p>
      <p>The song enjoyed duplicate success on country radio, as a
    cover version by Johnny Carver and one by Barry Manilow.
    Carver's rendition - titled simply "Yellow Ribbon" - was a top
    10 on the 
    <i>Billboard magazine</i>Hot Country Singles chart in June
    1973.</p>
      <p>The song had renewed popularity in 1981, in the wake of the
    Iranian hostage crisis The song lists at #37 on 
    <i>Billboard's Greatest Songs of all time.</i>[1]</p>
      <p>The origin of the idea of a yellow ribbon as a token of
    remembrance may have been the 19th century practice that some
    women allegedly had of wearing a yellow ribbon in their hair to
    signify their devotion to a husband or sweetheart serving in
    the U.S. Cavalry - and the song "'Round Her Neck She Wears a
    Yeller Ribbon" which later inspired the John Wayne movie "She
    Wore a Yellow Ribbon, is a reference to this. (See main article
    at yellow ribbon).</p>
      <p>The symbol of a yellow ribbon became widely known in
    civilian life in the 1970s as a reminder of an absent loved
    one, either in the military or in jail that they would be
    welcomed home on their return.</p>
      <p>The story of a convict who had told his love to tie a ribbon
    to a tree outside of town is an American folk tale, dating to
    before 1959. In October 1971, newspaper columnist Pete Hamill
    wrote a piece for the New York Post called "Going Home." In it,
    he told a variant of the story, in which college students on a
    bus trip to the beaches of Fort Lauderdale make friends with an
    ex-convict who is watching for a yellow handkerchief on a
    roadside oak in Brunswick, Georgia. Hamill claimed to have
    heard this story in oral tradition.</p>
      <p>In June 1972, nine months later, Reader's Digest reprinted
    "Going Home." Also in June 1972, ABC-TV aired a dramatized
    version of it in which James Earl Jones played the role of the
    returning ex-con. A month-and-a-half after that, Irwin Levine
    and L. Russell Brown registered for copyright a song they
    called "Tie a Yellow Ribbon 'Round the Ole Oak Tree." The
    authors said they heard the story while serving in the
    military. Pete Hamill was not convinced and filed suit for
    infringement.</p>
      <p>One factor that may have influenced Hamill's decision to do
    so was that, in May 1973, "Tie A Yellow Ribbon" sold 3 million
    records in three weeks. When the dust settled, BMI calculated
    that radio stations had played it 3 million times--seventeen
    continuous years of airplay. Hamill dropped his suit after
    folklorists working for Levine and Brown turned up archival
    versions of the story that had been collected before "Going
    Home" had been written.{</p>
      <p>In 1979-1980, while American diplomats were being held by
    Iranian students on the grounds of the American Embassy in
    Tehran, a Yellow Ribbon campaign was used to show support to
    the captives. While the radical students attempted to convince
    them that Americans had forgotten them, the yellow ribbons
    showed continuing support for the POWs.</p>
      <p>This song has been widely popular in the Philippines during
    early and mid-80s, particularly at the time when opposition
    leader Benigno "Ninoy" S. Aquino, Jr. expressed his intentions
    in 1983 to go back to his country from a 3-year exile in the
    United States and face President Ferdinand Marcos. After
    Ninoy's assassination at then Manila International Airport, the
    song and the yellow motif became synonymous with Ninoy, and was
    very much visible during anti-Marcos protests. In 1986, the
    yellow motif made a more thematic impact when his widow,
    Corazon Aquino, and the opposition used it during the campaign
    in the 1986 snap elections, she was swept to the presidency
    after the EDSA People Power Revolution. Everytime the
    Philippines celebrate Ninoy Aquino Day (August 21), yellow
    ribbons can be seen tied at many trees in Metro Manila along
    with yellow streamers of the late senator. A parody of the song
    was also made by Larry Henares in memory of the slain
    senator.</p>
      <p>In Singapore, an initiative by the Singapore Prison Service
    to generate social acceptance of ex-offenders is named the
    Yellow Ribbon Project, having drawn inspiration from the song's
    title.</p>
      <p>This was one of the songs performed by Don "No Soul" Simmons
    in 
    <i>Amazon Women On The Moon</i>(1987).</p>
      <p>In a 1990 "The Kids in the Hall" sketch, Dave Foley and
    Kevin McDonald portray "The Sizzler Sisters"--two clearly
    insane people--who perform the song as part of a lounge
    act.</p>
      <p>The song is sung by Hercules in Hercules Returns, when the
    hero is contemplating his upcoming lounge act.</p>
      <p>The song is featured in the films 
    <i>Addams Family Values</i>(1993) and 
    <i>Forrest Gump</i>(1994).</p>
      <p>In 2006, a widely circulated viral video featured the Asylum
    Street Spankers doing a satirical parody of the song, "Stick
    Magnetic Ribbons on Your SUV," which mocked the popular ribbon
    car magnets intended to show support for American soldiers in
    the Iraq War.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
