<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Everybody_Loves_Somebody 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Everybody_Loves_Somebody</songId>
   <title>Everybody Loves Somebody</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dean_Martin</artistId>
      <artistName>Dean Martin</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1964-08-15</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Everybody Loves Somebody The Hit Version</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1964</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:48</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Reprise</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Irving Taylor</writer>
      <writer>Ken Lane</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Everybody Loves Somebody" is a song written in 1947 by
    Irving Taylor and Ken Lane. The song had already been recorded
    by several artists (including Frank Sinatra) by 1964, but
    without much success. But it was in that year that Lane was
    playing piano for Dean Martin on his 
    <i>Dream With Dean</i>LP sessions, and with an hour or so of
    studio time left and one song short, Lane suggested that Martin
    take a run at his tune. Dean was agreeable, and the small combo
    of piano, guitar, drums and bass performed a relatively quiet,
    laid back jazz version of the song.</p>
      <p>Almost immediately thereafter, Martin re-recorded the tune
    for his next album, this time with an orchestra and chorus. His
    label, Reprise Records, was so enthusiastic about the hit
    potential of this version, they even titled the LP 
    <i>Everybody Loves Somebody</i>to capitalize on it.</p>
      <p>Although still a major recording artist, Martin had not had
    a Top 40 hit since 1958. And with the British Invasion ruling
    the U.S. charts, few had hopes that a middle aged Italian
    crooner would sway many teenagers. And yet, defying the odds, 
    <i>Everybody Loves Somebody</i>shot straight up to the top of
    the Billboard Hot 100. The song also topped the Billboard "easy
    listening" chart for eight weeks. It ultimately replaced
    "That's Amore" as Martin's signature song, and he sang it as
    the theme of his weekly television variety show from 1965 until
    1974. The song has become so identified with Dean Martin, that
    later cover versions are invariably compared to his hit take on
    the tune.</p>
      <p>By 1964, Dino, Frank, Sammy and the rest of the Rat Pack's
    martini-swilling lounge sound was out of synch with the Rock n'
    Roll now dominating the Top 100 Billboard. Dean in particular,
    resented and despised anything rock n' roll, which created
    conflict at home with his fourteen year old son Dean Paul
    Martin, who like every other teenager in the Western world,
    worshipped the Beatles. Tiring of his son's infernal boasting
    of how great the Beatles were, Dino told Dino, Jr., "I'm gonna'
    knock your pallies off the charts". Quoted from 
    <i>Dino: Living High in the Dirty Business of Dreams</i>by Nick
    Toches. Having not had a hit for six year, Dino Jr. rolled his
    eyes, and simply cast the prediction off as nonsense and forgot
    about it. That is until August 15, 1964 when 
    <i>Everybody Loves Somebody</i>knocked the Beatles off the
    Number One slot on Billboard. Dino smugly remarked to Dino Jr.,
    "I told you I'd knock your pallies off the charts.". Dino Jr.
    stood there speechless and gazed at his father in utter
    amazement, wonder, and with a newfound idolatry. Dean Martin
    became the only person in history to ever predict he'd knock
    the Beatles off the charts, and actually succeed.</p>
      <p>Following the song's peak at the top of the charts, Martin
    sent his close friend Sinatra a telegram saying "THAT'S THE WAY
    YOU DO IT". Dean sent a message to Elvis Presley "IF ONE OF US
    CAN BEAT THE BEATLES -- I'LL DO IT!!" In the 1990s the song was
    licensed to Western Union for use in a series of television
    commercials.</p>
      <p>The words "Everybody Loves Somebody" appear on Dean Martin's
    grave marker in Los Angeles.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
