<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Light_Up_My_Life_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Light_Up_My_Life_(song)</songId>
   <title>You Light Up My Life</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Debby_Boone</artistId>
      <artistName>Debby Boone</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1977-10-15</week>
      <week>1977-10-22</week>
      <week>1977-10-29</week>
      <week>1977-11-05</week>
      <week>1977-11-12</week>
      <week>1977-11-19</week>
      <week>1977-11-26</week>
      <week>1977-12-03</week>
      <week>1977-12-10</week>
      <week>1977-12-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>You Light Up My Life</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 16, 1977 (Elvis Presley's death)</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop/Easy Listening</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:35</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Curb</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Joe Brooks</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Joe Brooks</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"You Light Up My Life" is both a Grammy Award and an Academy
    Award winning ballad written by Joe Brooks and originally
    recorded by the late Kasey Cisyk for the soundtrack to the film
    of the same name. The song was performed in the film by its
    lead, Didi Conn, who lip synched Cisyk's version. Pat Boone's
    daughter, Debby Boone, was recruited to record the single,
    which became a massive success, topping the Billboard Hot 100
    chart for a record-setting ten consecutive weeks. It easily
    became the most successful single of the 1970s in the United
    States and set a new Hot 100 record for longest reign at No.1.
    (Elvis Presley's double-sided "Don't Be Cruel/Hound Dog", then
    recognized as the longest-running No.1 of the Rock Era, spent
    11 weeks atop the Billboard Best Sellers chart in 1956, before
    the debut of the Hot 100.) The record was matched in 1982 by
    Olivia Newton-John's Physical, but never surpassed until a 1991
    change in chart methodology allowed songs to achieve longer
    reigns at No.1 ("End of the Road" by Boyz II Men set the new
    record, 13 weeks). The single, which was certified platinum by
    the RIAA, also hit #1 on the Adult Contemporary chart and even
    reached #4 on the Country chart. Although written by Brooks as
    a love song, the devout Boone interpreted the song as
    inspirational and proclaimed that it was instead God who "lit
    up her life."</p>
      <p>Cisyk's soundtrack recording was released as a single to
    bolster sales of the soundtrack after Boone included her
    version on her first solo album also entitled 
    <i>You Light Up My Life</i>. (Although the soundtrack was
    certified gold, peaking at No. 17 on the Billboard 200 albums
    chart, it never included Boone's version of the song.) Cisyk's
    single was credited to "Original Cast", not to Cisyk herself,
    and only reached No. 80 on the Billboard Hot 100. Brooks also
    released an instrumental version of the song from the
    soundtrack as a single, but his version failed to chart.
    Boone's success resulted in Grammy nominations for Best Pop
    Vocal Performance Female and Record of the Year and won her the
    1977 Grammy for Best New Artist and the 1977 American Music
    Award for Favorite Pop Single. The song earned Brooks the 1977
    Song of the Year Grammy (tied with "Love Theme from "A Star Is
    Born" (Evergreen)") as well as the Best Original Song awards at
    the 1977 Golden Globe and Academy Awards.</p>
      <p>The song ranks #7 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top 100.</i>[1]</p>
      <p>Many artists have covered "You Light Up My Life" since 1977.
    The following year, Johnny Mathis recorded and named his album
    after the song. LeAnn Rimes released her version as a single in
    1997 – 20 years after Boone's version was released and on the
    same record label (Curb Records). Her version fared modestly by
    comparison to the original at radio (No. 34 Pop, No. 48
    Country). However, her single was certified gold and was the
    title track to her No. 1 Pop and Country album, 
    <i>You Light Up My Life: Inspirational Songs</i>.</p>
      <p>Among the other diverse artists who have recorded and/or
    performed the song are:</p>
      <p>The song was also parodied in the Six Feet Under episode The
    Rainbow of Her Reasons.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
