<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Runaway_(Del_Shannon_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Runaway_(Del_Shannon_song)</songId>
   <title>Runaway</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Del_Shannon</artistId>
      <artistName>Del Shannon</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1961-04-24</week>
      <week>1961-05-01</week>
      <week>1961-05-08</week>
      <week>1961-05-15</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>February 1961</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>21 January 1961</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock And Roll</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:20</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>BigTop 45-3067 (USA) London HLX 9317 (UK) Heliodor 453099 (Germany) London HL-1796</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Del Shannon</writer>
      <writer>Max Crook</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Harry Balk</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>453099 (Germany) London</p>
      <p>"Runaway" was a number one Billboard Hot 100 song in the
    spring of 1961 by Del Shannon. It was written by Shannon and
    keyboardist Max Crook, and became a major international
    hit.</p>
      <p>It is #466 on Rolling Stone's list of The 500 Greatest Songs
    of All Time.</p>
      <p>Singer-guitarist Charles Westover and keyboard player Max
    Crook performed together as members of "Charlie Johnson and the
    Big Little Show Band" in Battle Creek, Michigan, before their
    group won a recording contract in 1960. Westover took the new
    stage name "Del Shannon", and Crook, who had invented his own
    clavioline-based electric keyboard called a Musitron, became
    "Maximilian".</p>
      <p>After their first recording session for Big Top Records in
    New York had ended in failure, their manager Ollie McLaughlin
    persuaded them to rewrite and re-record an earlier song they
    had written, "Little Runaway", to highlight Crook's unique
    instrumental sound. On January 21, 1961, they recorded
    "Runaway" at the Bell Sound recording studios, with Harry Balk
    as producer, Fred Weinberg as audio engineer and also session
    musician on several sections- session musician Al Caiola on
    guitar, and Crook playing the central Musitron break. "Runaway"
    was released in February 1961 and was immediately successful.
    In April, Shannon appeared on Dick Clark's 
    <i>American Bandstand</i>helping to catapult it to the number
    one spot on the Billboard charts where it remained for four
    weeks. Two months later, it also reached number one in the UK..
    On the R&amp;B charts, "Runaway" peaked at number three .</p>
      <p>The following year champagne music maker Lawrence Welk who
    hosted a music tv series released and had a hit with the song.
    In 1961 Japanese singer 飯田久彦 (IIDA Hisahiko) made a cover of
    the song, called in Japanese 悲しき街角 ("Kanashiki Machikado"). The
    next notable cover of "Runaway" was by the Small Faces in 1967,
    appearing on the 
    <i>From the Beginning</i>album. Elvis Presley also covered it
    (during his return to live performances in Vegas, 1969), while
    the Beach Boys were known to have played it live. Charlie Kulis
    charted with a cover of "Runaway" on Playboy Records in 1975 at
    #46 while two years later Bonnie Raitt's cover performance of
    the song reached #57 in 1977 and was included album 
    <i>Sweet Forgiveness</i>and later on her 1990 greatest hits
    album.</p>
      <p>Country versions of the song have been recorded by Narvel
    Felts in the 70s, the bluegrass-based group The Cox Family in
    1996, the latter produced by Alison Krauss, and by Gary Allan
    on his album 
    <i>Smoke Rings in the Dark</i>. "Runaway" was covered by The
    Sensational Alex Harvey Band on 
    <i>The Penthouse Tapes</i>album. Marty Friedman and Rolly
    covered "Runaway" on 
    <i>Rock Fujiyama</i>. The song was covered in French by Dutch
    singer Dave; the cover was called "Vanina". The song was later
    covered by the punk rock group Me First and the Gimme Gimmes on
    their 
    <i>Blow in the Wind</i>, as well as horrorpunk band The Misfits
    on their covers album 
    <i>Project 1950</i>. 1986 brought a rock cover by Luis
    Cardenas.</p>
      <p>It was also recorded by the Traveling Wilburys during
    sessions for their second album, released as 
    <i>Traveling Wilburys Vol. 3</i>in 1990. The Wilburys had all
    been involved in sessions or production for Shannon's last
    album, released posthumously as 
    <i>Rock On</i>, and had it not been for his death in 1990,
    there was some speculation that he would have played and sung
    on their album as well, perhaps as a replacement for Roy
    Orbison, a former Wilbury who had died in 1988. However, this
    has never been documented.</p>
      <p>In 1988, influential Chicago punk band, Screeching Weasel,
    covered the song on their 
    <i>Boogadaboogadaboogada!</i>album. Blood For Blood cover
    "Runaway" on their album 
    <i>Serenity</i>. Samhain drummer Steve Zing, with some members
    of the band Mourning Noise, recorded a cover of "Runaway" that
    was released as a single in 1986.</p>
      <p>John Frusciante, guitarist of the Red Hot Chili Peppers, is
    known to do a live version of "Runaway" at his solo
    concerts.</p>
      <p>"Runaway" briefly returned in 1986 when Shannon recorded a
    revised version for the theme song of the television show 
    <i>Crime Story</i>. Coincidentally, one episode of the show's
    second season featured Bonnie Raitt's cover of the song.</p>
      <p>The Disco/Soul band Eruption covered this song in 1981 with
    new lead singer Jane Jochen</p>
      <p>Brazilian band Ultraje a Rigor covered the song on their
    album 
    <i>Por quê Ultraje a Rigor?</i>.</p>
      <p>DION (Dimucci) covers the song on his CD published in 2003,
    DION NEW MASTERS, in a much longer version (3:38).</p>
      <p>In Canada, the original version was released on QUALITY
    label, in 1961.</p>
      <p>In 2007 a cover of this song by The Zutons was released on
    the album Rhythms del Mundo Classics.</p>
      <p>Queen + Paul Rodgers covered the song as an iTunes-only
    bonus track on their 2008 album, 
    <i>The Cosmos Rocks</i>.</p>
      <p>Cajun Dance Party have covered the song as a b-side to their
    new single "The Colouful Life" in 2008.</p>
      <p>British indie rock band Kasabian has played the song several
    times live. A recorded version of the cover is found as a
    b-side on their single Fire, released on 1 June, 2009.</p>
      <p>The song "Runaway" has appeared in the following movies and
    TV shows:</p>
      <p>This song is referenced in Tom Petty's song Running Down a
    Dream "Me and Del were singin' little runaway." It was also
    referenced in the Barenaked Ladies song When you Dream from the
    album Stunt with "Do you hear Del Shannon's Runaway playing on
    transistor radio waves?"</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
