<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Independent_Women_Part_I 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Independent_Women_Part_I</songId>
   <title>Independent Women Part I</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Destiny%27s_Child</artistId>
      <artistName>Destiny's Child</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2001-01-06</week>
      <week>2001-01-13</week>
      <week>2001-01-20</week>
      <week>2001-01-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/72/Destiny%27s_child-independent_women.jpg/200px-Destiny%27s_child-independent_women.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Destiny-s-Child+Independent-Women-Part-I.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>SurvivorCharlie's Angels</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 31, 2000  (2000-10-31) , November 20, 2000  (2000-11-20) , February 13, 2001  (2001-02-13)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
      <format>maxi single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>April 2000</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:41</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Beyoncé Knowles</writer>
      <writer>Sam Barnes</writer>
      <writer>Jean-Claude Olivier</writer>
      <writer>Cory Rooney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Beyoncé Knowles</producer>
      <producer>Cory Rooney</producer>
      <producer>Poke &amp; Tone</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Independent Women" is a song by American girl group
    Destiny's Child. It was written and produced by Beyoncé
    Knowles, Sam Barnes, Jean-Claude Olivier and Cory Rooney for
    the group's third studio album, 
    <i>Survivor</i>(2001), although the song first appeared on the
    soundtrack to the 2000 film adaption of 
    <i>Charlie's Angels</i>. It is also the first single with
    Michelle Williams on vocals.</p>
      <p>Originally, part two of the song was the actual song and
    part one was known as the Pasadena remix, but it was chosen in
    favor of the original and was dubbed part one.</p>
      <p>Released as both the soundtrack's and album's leading single
    in fall 2000, the song held the number one spot on the Hot 100
    chart for eleven consecutive weeks from November 2000 to
    February 2001. Later it was named the 18th most successful song
    of the 2000s, on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade. Although, for the
    United Kingdom, it was released on the same day, with both Part
    I and Part II counting as the song release.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by Francis Lawrence. At the
    end, the women are greeted by the ever-mysterious "Charlie".
    The song was nominated for "Best Song Written for a Motion
    Picture, Television or Other Visual Media" at the 2001 Grammy
    Awards.</p>
      <p>The song ranked at number 85 on the list of Britain's
    favorite 100 songs, published in May 2002.</p>
      <p>The song was the 25th best selling of 2000 in the UK.</p>
      <p>"Independent Women" was a chart success in the United
    States. The single peaked at number one on the Hot 100, during
    which 
    <i>Charlie's Angels</i>just filled North American movie
    theaters. The feat gave the group their third number-one single
    in the country. The single hold to the top position in the
    following week, which was seen as bouyed by the strong box
    office performance of the film and the heavy rotation it
    received. The song had a massive radio airplay, staying almost
    ten weeks at the top of the Hot 100 Airplay, significantly
    contributing to the performance of the single on the main
    chart. Subsequently, the single spent eleven consecutive weeks
    on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 top position. During its tenth
    week at the top spot, the music press had expected that the
    single will fall off the top position because of strong
    competition at retail; however, it sustained due to the high
    sales of the single's maxi version, released in December 2000.
    It was in the 2000-2001 edition of the 
    <i>Guinness Book of World Records</i>for longest-running song
    by a female group. "Independent Women" also topped the Hot
    R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Singles &amp; Tracks chart for three weeks,
    becoming Destiny's Child fourth number one single on this
    chart.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom, "Independent Women" debuted at number
    one, becoming the group's first number-one single in the
    country. The British Phonographic Industry has certified the
    single gold for sales of over 400,000 physical singles. It also
    reached the number one position in Canada, Ireland, and New
    Zealand.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
