<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bills,_Bills,_Bills 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bills,_Bills,_Bills</songId>
   <title>Bills, Bills, Bills</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Destiny%27s_Child</artistId>
      <artistName>Destiny's Child</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1999-07-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/6/62/Dc_bills.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Destiny-s-Child+Bills-Bills-Bills.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Writing's on the Wall</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 15, 1999  (1999-06-15) , (see Release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD maxi single</format>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1999</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:33 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>3:54 (Video Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Kevin Briggs</writer>
      <writer>Kandi Burruss</writer>
      <writer>Beyoncé Knowles</writer>
      <writer>LeToya Luckett</writer>
      <writer>Kelly Rowland</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>She'kspere</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Bills, Bills, Bills" is a 1999 smash hit single by
    Destiny's Child, released as the first single from their second
    album 
    <i>The Writing's on the Wall</i>. It echoed the female
    empowerment sentiments of TLC's single "No Scrubs", and
    featured the same producer (Kevin She'kspere Briggs) and
    songwriter (Kandi Burruss). The song provided the quartet with
    their first US chart-topper in July 1999, and also reached the
    UK Top 10. The album featured a greater creative input from the
    quartet, although they still relied on a heavyweight production
    crew including Rodney Jerkins, Missy Elliott, Chad Elliot, and
    Dwayne Wiggins of Tony! Toni! Tone!. The song was nominated for
    "Best R&amp;B Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocals" at the
    2000 Grammy Awards.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Bills, Bills, Bills" (directed by
    Darren Grant) was shot in a beauty salon as a tribute to Tina
    Knowles, group member Beyoncé Knowles mother. It was also the
    first of three videos that would include Farrah Franklin,
    though she played only a minor role as a salon client.</p>
      <p>"Bills, Bills, Bills" debuted at #84 on the Hot 100 and
    climbed to #1 five weeks later, where it remained for a week
    and spent a total of twenty weeks on the chart. It was the
    first Destiny's Child song that peaked at number one on the
    Billboard Hot 100 chart. The song also won a BMI Pop award for
    being the most played song. Before "Bills, Bills, Bills," the
    only top ten single the group had achieved was "No, No, No Pt.
    2".</p>
      <p>"Bills, Bills, Bills" also reached number one on the Hot
    R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Singles &amp; Tracks for nine consecutive
    weeks, making it one of the longest running number one singles
    ever on this chart and the most weeks at the summit in 1999. It
    was also the ninth best-selling single of the year in the
    U.S.</p>
      <p>In the UK "Bills, Bills, Bills" peaked at number six and
    went onto sell over 165,000 copies.</p>
      <p>Despite the success of the single, some listeners questioned
    the theme, interpreting the demand that the man pay the woman's
    bills and the accompanying threat of leaving him if he didn't
    as male bashing. Additionally, the man in the song is subjected
    to insults, accusing him of being a 
    <i>"triflin', good for nothing type of brother."</i>Destiny's
    Child countered that their lyrics were meant to be empowering
    for women.</p>
      <p>Certain lyrics within the song reveal that the targets of
    its criticism are men who do not repay debts, not all men in
    general. These include lines such as 
    <i>"Now you've been maxing out my card,"</i>
         <i>"And then you use my cell phone / And when the bill comes,
    all of a sudden you be acting dumb,"</i>and 
    <i>"And now you ask to use my car / Drive it all day and don't
    fill up the tank."</i>These same complaints are referred to in
    the refrain, when the women ask, 
    <i>"Can you pay my bills? / Can you pay my telephone bills? /
    Do you pay my automo' bills?"</i>
      </p>
      <p>Sporty Thievz, the same group that wrote "No Pigeons" as
    response to TLC's "No Scrubs", wrote a response to "Bills,
    Bills, Bills" entitled "No Billz (Why, Why, Why)." Sporty
    Thievz were also featured on the main remix of Bills, Bills,
    Bills produced by the Trackmasters, along with a female rapper
    called Jazz.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Side A</i>
      </p>
      <p>
         <i>Side B</i>
      </p>
      <p>
         <i>Side A</i>
      </p>
      <p>
         <i>Side B</i>
      </p>
      <p>
         <i>Side A</i>
      </p>
      <p>
         <i>Side B</i>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
