<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bootylicious 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bootylicious</songId>
   <title>Bootylicious</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Destiny%27s_Child</artistId>
      <artistName>Destiny's Child</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2001-08-04</week>
      <week>2001-08-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/b6/Bootylicious_CD_Cover.jpg/200px-Bootylicious_CD_Cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Destiny-s-Child+Bootylicious.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Survivor</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 20, 2001 (U.S.) , July 3, 2001 (world-wide) , July 23, 2001 (UK)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop Soul</genre>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:27</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Beyoncé Knowles</writer>
      <writer>Rob Fusari</writer>
      <writer>Falonte Moore</writer>
      <writer>Frank Tai Stevie Nicks</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Beyoncé Knowles</producer>
      <producer>Rob Fusari</producer>
      <producer>Falonte Moore</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Bootylicious" is a song by American R&amp;B group Destiny's
    Child. It was written and produced by Rob Fusari, Falonte
    Moore, and band member Beyoncé Knowles for the band's third
    studio album 
    <i>Survivor</i>(2001), and contains a prominent sample from the
    1981 recording "Edge of Seventeen," as written and performed by
    Stevie Nicks.</p>
      <p>The track was released as the album's second single from the
    album in 2001 and became the band's fourth U.S. non-consecutive
    number-one single. It also reached the top-five in Australia,
    Canada and the United Kingdom.</p>
      <p>The song "Bootylicious" is about a confident woman taunting
    a man, suggesting that he is not ready because her body is "too
    bootylicious". Beyoncé Knowles has stated in her "I am...
    Yours" tour that she was inspired to write the song on a flight
    to Japan as she was listening to the guitar riff of the Stevie
    Nicks song "Edge of Seventeen", which reminded her of a
    "voluptuous woman." Platinum music producers Rob Fusari and
    Falonte Moore produced this record and featured a sample from
    the Stevie Nicks song, and Stevie herself appears in the
    beginning of the video. It is also one of the few times that
    Kelly Rowland takes the lead, having two verses to Beyoncé
    Knowles' one, though Knowles still ad libs. Despite Rowland's
    lead in the song, Kelly Rowland has mentioned that
    "Bootylicious" is the most irritating Destiny's Child song for
    her since she has heard it too many times.</p>
      <p>In the February 27th, 2010 edition of Billboard magazine,
    Rob Fusari is interviewed about his career and briefly
    discusses the song and its genesis. In the article he states
    that he alone had the idea for the song and had originally
    intended to use another guitar riff but after not being able to
    find it he happened to come across the Stevie Nicks CD instead.
    He goes on to say that he was so upset when he saw Beyonce
    claim credit for the song in an interview with Barbara Walters
    that he telephoned Mathew Knowles. According to Fusari, Mr
    Knowles told him "People don't want to hear about Rob Fusari,
    producer from Livingstone, NJ....that's not what sells
    records".</p>
      <p>"Bootylicious" debuted at #66 on the Hot 100 on June 9, 2001
    and climbed to its peak position nine weeks later, and remained
    on the chart for a relatively short nineteen weeks. The song
    became Destiny's Child's fifth consecutive No.1 on the Hot 100
    Airplay chart, despite Mariah Carey's "Loverboy" keeping it
    from topping the Hot 100 Singles Sales.</p>
      <p>In the UK Chart (2001) Peak position Greece IFPI Top 20
    Singles Chart 18 Italy Top 50 Singles Chart 16 New Zealand
    RIANZ Singles Chart 4 Norwegian Singles Chart 5 Swedish Singles
    Chart 8 Swiss Singles Chart 11 UK Singles Chart 2 U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100 1 U.S. Billboard Hot Dance Club Play 13 U.S.
    Billboard Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs 2 "Bootylicious" was
    released on July 23, 2001 and debuted at #2 on the singles
    chart behind the Atomic Kitten cover single "Eternal Flame". It
    sold over 169,000 copies and propelled 
    <i>Survivor</i>back to the top of The Official UK Albums
    Chart.</p>
      <p>A hip hop-styled remix (the "Rockwilder Remix") was produced
    by Rockwilder, Knowles, and Missy Elliott. This version was
    issued to urban markets, and had a hip-hop culture-based music
    video to accompany it, in which Beyoncé wears a belt that has
    the word "Bootylicious" misspelled as "Bootyliciuos", as
    pointed out by Carson Daly on an episode of 
    <i>TRL</i>.</p>
      <p>A combination of the R&amp;B vocals from this song and the
    grunge rock music of Nirvana's "Smells Like Teen Spirit" is one
    of the best-known examples of the "bastard pop" or "mashup"
    genre, where elements from seemingly incompatible songs are
    mixed together. A later mashup used the music of Stevie
    Wonder's "Superstition" with the "Bootylicious" vocals.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Bootylicious", directed by Matthew
    Rolston, showed Destiny's Child performing dance steps from
    Michael Jackson's famous "Billie Jean" performance from the
    special 
    <i>Motown 25: Yesterday, Today, Forever</i>. During the video,
    moves from several other Michael Jackson videos can be seen
    such as parts of the choreograpy from "Thriller", "Beat it",
    "Bad" and "The Way You Make Me Feel". Dance moves that were
    used by Jackson during live performances of "They Don't Care
    About Us" can be seen as well.</p>
      <p>As the group is dancing, the members appear in several
    different costumes. These scenes are interloped with the group
    dancing in front of a dance troupe made of all boys. Stevie
    Nicks makes an appearance in the beginning of the song's video.
    Solange Knowles, Beyonce's sister, also makes a brief cameo in
    the video.</p>
      <p>The song created moderate controversy, in a time when late
    '90s teen pop was pushing the boundaries of female sexuality.
    Destiny's Child was claiming "G-rated fun" and confidence in
    body image though the lyrics yet the music video suggested much
    more with the group wearing lots of make-up, form-fitting
    clothes, performing sexually suggestive dancing, and the video
    featuring close-ups on several dancers buttocks .</p>
      <p>The group later performed the song in front of Jackson for
    his thirtieth Anniversary concert, complete with their
    rendition of his dance moves. Before the premiere of the video
    on MTV's Making the Video, the girls dedicated the video to
    Michael Jackson.</p>
      <p>The song popularised the portmanteau term 'bootylicious', a
    combination of the words booty and delicious. The success of
    the song came after the rise in media visibility of voluptuous
    'non-skinny' personalities like Jennifer Lopez and later
    Beyonce. There was a media perception that the appearance of
    these women corresponded to an appreciation of the supposedly
    neglected larger hips and thighs common in the figures of
    African-American, Hispanic and some Middle-Eastern women. The
    approving neologism 'bootylicious' has entered the mainstream
    English language as part of the 'crossover' of African-American
    popular culture, fashion and sexual politics.</p>
      <p>Many unofficial or bootleg mixes have been released of this
    track, usually on limited vinyl promo's or special mix CD
    versions. Some listed below.</p>
      <p>English rock band Keane performed a medley consisting of
    "Bootylicious" and Christina Aguilera's "Dirrty" on Jo Whiley's
    Live Lounge. An audio recording is available on Radio 1's Live
    Lounge – Volume 2. The cast of the Fox television show
    performed a cover version in the episode "Hairography".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
