<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Come_on_Eileen 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Come_on_Eileen</songId>
   <title>Come on Eileen</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dexys_Midnight_Runners</artistId>
      <artistName>Dexys Midnight Runners</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1983-04-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/7/78/DexysMidnightRunnerComeOnEileen7InchSingleCover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Dexys-Midnight-Runners+Come-on-Eileen.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Too-Rye-Ay</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>25 June 1982</released>
   <recorded>1981-1982</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>Album Version (4:28)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Mercury</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Kevin Rowland</writer>
      <writer>Jim "Big Jim" Paterson</writer>
      <writer>Billy Adams</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Clive Langer</producer>
      <producer>Alan Winstanley</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Come On Eileen" was a single released by Dexys Midnight
    Runners in 1982. The song was written by Kevin Rowland, "Big"
    Jim Paterson, and Billy Adams; it was produced by Clive Langer
    and Alan Winstanley. It originally appeared on the album 
    <i>Too-Rye-Ay</i>. It was their first #1 hit in the United
    Kingdom since 1980's "Geno".</p>
      <p>The song won Best British Single at the 1983 Brit
    Awards.</p>
      <p>The song begins with Celtic-style fiddle played over a drum
    beat, with the bass guitar and piano providing accompaniment.
    An extended version has an additional intro of a Celtic fiddle
    solo, playing Thomas Moore's Irish folk song 
    <i>Believe Me, if All Those Endearing Young Charms</i>.</p>
      <p>The chorus was loosely inspired by the song "A Man Like Me"
    by the 1960s British soul group Jimmy James and the
    Vagabonds.</p>
      <p>The bridge of "Come On Eileen" features an improvised
    counter-melody which begins in a slow tempo and gets faster and
    faster over an accelerando vocal backing. The chord sequence of
    the bridge is actually the same as the verses but transposed up
    by a whole tone.</p>
      <p>Throughout the song, there are numerous tempo changes and
    key changes:</p>
      <p>The music video to accompany the single was directed by
    Julien Temple. It features members of the band wearing
    sleeveless shirts and overalls. The "Eileen" as featured in the
    video (and on the record sleeve) is Máire Fahey, sister of
    Siobhan Fahey, former singer with Bananarama and Shakespear's
    Sister. The American singer Johnnie Ray, an early rock-and-roll
    crooner mentioned in the opening lyrics, is also featured in
    the video using old film footage.</p>
      <p>Filming took place on Brook Drive, Kennington, London. The
    shop which was called "Vi's Stores" in the video can be seen on
    Google Street View and is now called the Brook Drive Mini
    Market.</p>
      <p>In the British charts, the song spent four weeks at number
    one in August 1982. This success was repeated around the globe;
    spending five weeks as the Kent Report's number one in
    Australia and reaching number one in April 1983 on the
    Billboard Hot 100 in the United States. It also holds the
    distinction of preventing Michael Jackson from having
    back-to-back number one hits in the U.S. The number one hits
    "Billie Jean" and "Beat It" were separated by Dexys Midnight
    Runners' one week stay at the top.</p>
      <p>The song was also successful in Ireland, where it reached
    number one and spent a total of eleven weeks in the charts.</p>
      <p>It is a common example of a one-hit wonder in the U.S., as
    the band failed to reach similar popularity with any of their
    later songs, though in the UK they had already reached number
    one two years earlier with "Geno", and went on to have further
    hits.</p>
      <p>In a poll by the UK TV Channel, 
    <i>Channel 4</i>, the song was placed at number 38 in the 100
    greatest number 1 singles of all time. A similar poll by the
    music channel 
    <i>VH1</i>placed the song at number 3 in the 
    <i>100 Greatest One-hit Wonders</i>of all time.</p>
      <p>The song reached #18 on VH1's Top 100 Songs of the
    1980s.</p>
      <p>The song was named #1 on VH1's 
    <i>100 Greatest One Hit Wonders of the 80s</i>.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by several artists including the
    ska band Save Ferris (which replaced the strings with a horn
    section), folk metal Skyclad, French art band Nouvelle Vague,
    the Atlantic Canadian folk rockers Kilt, Blackthorn, the
    Japanese band nil, and Badly Drawn Boy. In June 2004 in the UK,
    the tune was used for the song "Come on England", by a group of
    football fans working at talkSPORT radio calling themselves
    "4-4-2". The song was intended to support the England football
    team during the Euro 2004 competition. In 2006, a cover version
    by Hermes House Band was released as a single in France.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
