<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You%27ll_Never_Know 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You%27ll_Never_Know</songId>
   <title>You'll Never Know</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dick_Haymes</artistId>
      <artistName>Dick Haymes</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1943-07-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"You'll Never Know" is a popular song. The music was written
    by Harry Warren and the lyrics by Mack Gordon, based on a poem
    written by a young Oklahoma war bride named Dorothy Fern
    Norris. The lyrics can be found at [1].</p>
      <p>The song was introduced in the 1943 movie 
    <i>Hello, Frisco, Hello</i>where it is sung by Alice Faye. It
    was also performed by Faye in the 1944 film 
    <i>Four Jills in a Jeep</i>. It was recorded in 1943 by, among
    others, Frank Sinatra and Dick Haymes. Haymes’ version was a
    number one hit for four weeks on the R&amp;B charts that year
    .</p>
      <p>Sinatra recorded his version at his first recording session
    at Columbia as a solo artist. (He had recorded at Columbia in
    1939 as a member of Harry James’s band.) It was arranged and
    conducted by Alec Wilder with the Bobby Tucker Singers
    providing accompaniment. Sinatra’s version charted for 16 weeks
    starting July 24 and spent two weeks at number 2.</p>
      <p>In Britain, the recording by Vera Lynn was very popular due
    to the ongoing Second World War.</p>
      <p>A 1952 recording by Rosemary Clooney with Harry James is
    also well known, as well as a version recorded in 1954 by Big
    Maybelle.</p>
      <p>The Sinatra and Haymes records were made during the
    1942–1944 strike against the recording companies a strike by
    the American Federation of Musicians. As a result, the
    recordings were made without musicians, with vocal groups
    replacing the usual instrumental backup. The group backing
    Haymes, The Song Spinners, was actually given credit on the
    Haymes record. (The Song Spinners number one hit, "Comin' In on
    a Wing and a Prayer" had held the number one spot on the charts
    for three weeks preceding Haymes' "You'll Never Know" replaced
    it. Margaret Johnson of that group did the vocal arrangments
    for both.)</p>
      <p>The song was the first song that Barbra Streisand ever
    recorded in 1955. It was the opening song on her 4-CD box-set 
    <i>Just for the Record</i>(1991). The box-set closed with
    another version of the song, sung as a duet by Streisand in
    1991 and herself as a girl of 13.</p>
      <p>The song won the 1943 Academy Award for Best Original Song,
    one of nine nominated songs that year.</p>
      <p>In 1961, a version by Shirley Bassey made #6 in the UK
    charts.Elkie Brooks recorded it for her 1984 album !!
    Screen Gems !!</p>
      <p>Alice Faye's recording is the opening song in the 1974 film 
    <i>Alice Doesn't Live Here Anymore</i>.</p>
      <p>Trini Lopez included "You'll Never Know" on his Reprise
    Records album 
    <i>The Sing Along World of Trini Lopez</i>(Reprise 6183).</p>
      <p>The Mamas &amp; the Papas vocalist Denny Doherty included
    the song on his 1974 solo album "Waiting for a Song"
    (Ember-Paramount EMA 0286 - 1974). The single was released with
    'Goodnight and Good Morning', from the same album, as the
    B-side. This version reached the top 15 of Billboard's Easy
    listening survey.</p>
      <p>Lew DeWitt, formerly of The Statler Brothers, released a
    version in 1985 on the Compleat label.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
