<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Then_Came_You_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Then_Came_You_(song)</songId>
   <title>Then Came You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dionne_Warwick</artistId>
      <artistName>Dionne Warwick and Spinners</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-10-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Then Came You</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1974</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1974</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:15</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Sherman Marshall</writer>
      <writer>Philip Pugh</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Thom Bell</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Then Came You" is a 1974 Grammy-nominated hit for American
    soul singer Dionne Warwick and American R&amp;B group The
    Spinners, and credited to 
    <i>Dionne Warwicke and Spinners</i>(from 1971–1975, Warwick
    added a final 'e' to her last name). The track was written by
    Sherman Marshall and Phillip T. Pugh, and produced by Thom
    Bell.</p>
      <p>Released during a time that Warwick's chart fortunes were at
    an ebb after moving to Warner Bros. Records in the early-1970s,
    the Philadelphia soul single was a rare mid-1970s success for
    the singer. Sung as a duet with Spinners main lead singer Bobby
    Smith and the Spinners, who were one of the most popular groups
    of the decade, the song became Warwick's first ever single to
    reach number one on the Billboard Hot 100 and also became her
    highest-charting R&amp;B record reaching number two on that
    chart. It was also the first number-one pop hit for the
    Spinners. Spinners member Phillippe Wynne took over lead duties
    at the very end of the song, as he did on another one of the
    group's big hits, "Could It Be I'm Falling in Love".</p>
      <p>It should be noted that while Warwick was signed to Warner
    Bros. at the time, this release actually came out on Atlantic
    Records, which was the Spinners' label, but also a sister label
    to Warner Bros..</p>
      <p>Warwick eventually left Warner Bros. for Arista Records in
    1978 where she regrouped and found consistent success again as
    an artist.</p>
      <p>"Then Came You" is tied with the record that preceded it at
    the top of the Billboard Hot 100, "Nothing From Nothing" by
    Billy Preston, for the biggest fall from number one in the
    history of the Hot 100. Both "Nothing From Nothing" and "Then
    Came You" spent only one week at number one and then dropped
    all the way to number 15 the week afterward.</p>
      <p>After recording "Then Came You" Bell quoted 'that Dionne
    made a face after the session and didn't care for the songs
    very much. So, Thom ripped a dollar in two and signed each half
    and exchanged them. Bell told her that if the song doesn't go
    to number one, I'll send you my half. 'Then Came You' b/w 'Just
    As Long As We Have Love' shot straight to number one spot on
    Billboard's Top 100 list and No. 2 R&amp;B (Kool &amp; the
    Gang's 'Higher Plane' prevented it from the number one spot)
    making this Dionne's first No. 1 and the Spinners first and
    only No. 1 pop hit in October 1974. Dionne sent back the half
    torn dollar bill to Thom Bell with an apology.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
