<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Money_for_Nothing_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Money_for_Nothing_(song)</songId>
   <title>Money for Nothing</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dire_Straits</artistId>
      <artistName>Dire Straits</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1985-09-21</week>
      <week>1985-09-28</week>
      <week>1985-10-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/8c/Money_for_Nothing_single.JPG/200px-Money_for_Nothing_single.JPG</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Dire-Straits+Money-for-Nothing.JPG</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Brothers in Arms</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 1985</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Gramophone record</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>December 1984</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hard Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>8:26 (full-length)</length>
      <length>7:04 (vinyl LP edit)</length>
      <length>4:38 (official single edit)</length>
      <length>4:05 (promo single edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Vertigo (UK) , Warner Bros (US)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mark Knopfler</writer>
      <writer>Sting</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mark Knopfler</producer>
      <producer>Neil Dorfsman</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Money for Nothing" is a song recorded by British group Dire
    Straits, which first appeared on their 1985 album 
    <i>Brothers in Arms</i>and subsequently became an international
    hit when released as a single. It peaked at number one for
    three weeks in the United States, becoming their most
    successful single, and also peaked at number one for three
    weeks on the U.S. Mainstream Rock chart. In the band's native
    UK, the song peaked at number four. The recording was notable
    for its controversial lyrics, groundbreaking music video and a
    cameo appearance by Sting singing the song's falsetto
    introduction and backing chorus, "I want my MTV". The video was
    also the first to be aired on MTV Europe when the network
    started on August 1, 1987.</p>
      <p>"Money for Nothing" won the Grammy for the Best Rock
    Performance by a Duo or Group with a Vocal in 1985 at the 28th
    annual Grammy Awards.</p>
      <p>The recording of the song contains a very recognizable hook,
    in the form of the guitar riff that begins the song proper.
    (The song is also notable for its extended overture, which was
    shortened for radio and music video.) The guitar riff continues
    throughout the song, played in full during each chorus, and
    played in muted permutation during the verse.</p>
      <p>The song's lyrics are written from the point of view of a
    man watching music videos and commenting on what he sees. To
    achieve the effect of such a layman making such casual everyday
    commentary, Dire Straits' lead singer and songwriter Mark
    Knopfler used a vocal style known as 
    <i>Sprechstimme</i>.</p>
      <p>Knopfler described the writing of the song in a 1985
    interview with critic Bill Flanagan:</p>
      <p>In 2000, Knopfler appeared on Michael Parkinson's interview
    program and explained again where the lyrics originated.
    According to Knopfler, he was in New York and stopped by an
    appliance store. At the back of the store, they had a wall of
    TVs which were all tuned to MTV. Knopfler said there was a man
    working there dressed in a baseball cap, work boots, and a
    checkered shirt delivering boxes who was standing next to him
    watching. As they were standing there watching MTV, Knopfler
    remembers the man coming up with classic lines such as "what
    are those, Hawaiian noises?...that ain't workin" etc. Knopfler
    asked for a pen to write some of these lines down and then
    eventually put those words to music.</p>
      <p>The songwriting credits are shared between Mark Knopfler and
    Sting. Sting was visiting Montserrat during the recording of
    the song, and was invited to add some background vocals. Sting
    has stated that his only compositional contribution was the "I
    Want My MTV" line, which was sung to the identical melody of
    the verse of his own song "Don't Stand So Close to Me",
    originally recorded by The Police. Sting was reportedly
    embarrassed when his publishing company insisted on a
    co-writing credit (and royalties).</p>
      <p>The observations of the character included references to a
    musician "banging on the bongos like a chimpanzee" and a
    description of a singer as "that little faggot with the earring
    and the makeup", and lamenting that the artists got "money for
    nothing and chicks for free". These lyrics were widely
    criticised as sexist, racist and homophobic statements, and in
    some later releases of the song the lyrics were edited for
    airplay; "faggot" for example is often replaced with "mother":
    "little mother, he's a millionaire".</p>
      <p>When the song is included in rotation as part of a music
    feed played in stores, or restaurants "faggot" is usually
    turned backwards. The entire second verse was edited out for
    content and length for radio and video airplay, and on the 7"
    single. This edited version is included in the compilation
    albums 
    <i>Sultans of Swing: The Very Best of Dire Straits</i>and 
    <i>Money for Nothing</i>.</p>
      <p>In a late 1985 interview in 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine, Knopfler expressed mixed feelings
    on the controversy:</p>
      <p>Mötley Crüe bassist Nikki Sixx, in an interview with Blender
    Magazine, claimed that the song is actually about his band's
    excessive lifestyle, and that he heard the clerks in the store
    were commenting on Mötley Crüe videos shown on the in-store
    television sets.</p>
      <p>The music video for the song featured early computer
    animation illustrating the lyrics. The video was one of the
    first uses of computer-animated human characters and was
    considered groundbreaking at the time of its release. It was
    the second computer-generated music video shown on MTV.</p>
      <p>Originally, Mark Knopfler was not at all enthusiastic about
    the concept of the music video. MTV, however, was insistent on
    it. Director Steve Barron, of Rushes Postproduction in London,
    was contacted by Warner Bros. to persuade Knopfler to relent.
    Describing the contrasting attitudes of Knopfler and MTV, he
    said:</p>
      <p>Barron then flew to Budapest to convince Knopfler of their
    concept. Meeting together after a gig, Knopfler was reportedly
    still unimpressed, but this time his girlfriend was present and
    took a hand. According to Barron:</p>
      <p>Ian Pearson and Gavin Blair created the animation, using a
    Bosch FGS-4000 CGI system. The animators went on to found
    computer animation studio Mainframe Entertainment (today
    Rainmaker Animation), and referenced the "Money for Nothing"
    video in an episode of their 
    <i>ReBoot</i>series. The video also included stage footage of
    Dire Straits performing, with partially rotoscoped-animation in
    bright neon colours, as seen on the record sleeve.</p>
      <p>The video was awarded "Video of the Year" (among many other
    nominations) at the third annual MTV Video Music Awards in
    1986.</p>
      <p>Two other music videos are also featured within "Money for
    Nothing". A Hungarian pop band Első Emelet and their video
    "Állj Vagy Lövök" appears as "Baby, Baby" by "First Floor".
    (The name "első emelet" translates to "first floor".) Első
    Emelet was extremely popular at the time in Hungary, although
    their videos might not have appeared on Music Television. The
    other is a fictional, supposed MTV video "Sally" by the Ian
    Pearson Band (Pearson was one of the animators of the
    video).</p>
      <p>Knopfler modelled his guitar sound for the recorded track
    after ZZ Top guitarist Billy Gibbons' trademark guitar tone, as
    ZZ Top's music videos were already a staple of early MTV.
    Gibbons later told a 
    <i>Musician</i>magazine interviewer in 1986 that Knopfler had
    solicited Gibbons on how to replicate the tone, adding, "He
    didn't do a half-bad job, considering that I didn't tell him a
    thing!" Knopfler's "not a half-bad job" included his use of a
    Gibson Les Paul guitar, which he used on a couple of other 
    <i>Brothers in Arms</i>tracks, rather than his usual (at the
    time) Fender Stratocaster, plugged into a Marshall amplifier.
    Another factor in trying to recreate the sound was a Wah-wah
    pedal that was turned on, but only rocked to a certain
    position.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine listed it the 94th greatest guitar
    song of all time, noting how Mark Knopfler "traded his
    pristine, rootsy tone for a dry, over-processed sound achieved
    by running a Les Paul through a wah-wah pedal on a track that
    became one of the network's earliest hits".</p>
      <p>When Dire Straits performed "Money for Nothing" at the 1985
    Live Aid Concert at Wembley Stadium, the performance featured a
    guest appearance by Sting.</p>
      <p>Knopfler performed "Money for Nothing" using his Pensa-Suhr
    signature MK-1 model guitar with a pair of Soldano SLO-100
    tube/valve amplifier heads and Marshall speaker cabinets during
    the Nelson Mandela 70th Birthday Tribute and Prince's Trust
    concerts in 1988, as well as the Nordoff-Robbins charity show
    at Knebworth in 1990 and the On Every Street world tours in
    1991/1992. These versions featured extended guitar solos by
    Knopfler, backed by Eric Clapton and Phil Palmer.</p>
      <p>"Weird Al" Yankovic wrote a parody titled "Money For
    Nothing/Beverly Hillbillies*" for his 1989 film 
    <i>UHF</i>. As the title implies, this song merges the lyrics
    from 
    <i>The Beverly Hillbillies</i>theme song ("The Ballad of Jed
    Clampett") with "Money For Nothing"'s tune. Dire Straits
    members Mark Knopfler and Guy Fletcher perform guitar and
    keyboards respectively on the track. The famous video also got
    the "Weird Al" treatment, with the removal men replaced by
    blocky, computer-generated versions of Jed Clampett and
    Yankovic himself. The parody video was used as a dream sequence
    midway through the film.</p>
      <p>Satirical puppet show 
    <i>Spitting Image</i>also parodied this song, randomly calling
    it "Making Nice Curtains". It features puppets of Mark and
    David Knopfler singing about yuppies and that their music "can
    be played to your granny and aunts". Sting appears as he does
    in the real video to claim his "royalty", but is silenced as a
    guitar hits him in the head.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
