<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Pie_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Pie_(song)</songId>
   <title>American Pie</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don_McLean</artistId>
      <artistName>Don McLean</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1972-01-15</week>
      <week>1972-01-22</week>
      <week>1972-01-29</week>
      <week>1972-02-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/2b/Don_McLean_-_American_Pie.jpg/200px-Don_McLean_-_American_Pie.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Don-McLean+American-Pie.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>American Pie</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 1971 (first release) November 1991 (reissue)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>vinyl record (original)</format>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>cassette</format>
      <format>vinyl (reissue)</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>May 26, 1971</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Folk Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>8:33 (LP)</length>
      <length>4:11 (Single Part 1)</length>
      <length>4:31 (Single Part 2)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>United Artists</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Don McLean</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Ed Freeman for The Rainbow Collection</producer>
      <producer>Ltd.</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>American Pie part 2 (first release), Vincent (re-release,
    cassette version),</p>
      <p>"American Pie" is a folk rock song by singer-songwriter Don
    McLean.</p>
      <p>Recorded and released on the 
    <i>American Pie</i>album in 1971, the single was a number-one
    U.S. hit for four weeks in 1972. A re-release in 1991 did not
    chart in the U.S., but reached number 12 in the UK. The song is
    an oblique recounting of "" — the 1959 plane crash that killed
    Buddy Holly, Ritchie Valens, The Big Bopper (Jiles Perry
    Richardson, Jr.), and the pilot, Roger Peterson. The importance
    of "American Pie" to America's musical and cultural heritage
    was recognized by the Songs of the Century education project
    which listed the song as the number five song of the twentieth
    century. Some Top 40 stations initially played only side two of
    the single, but the song's popularity eventually forced
    stations to play the entire piece. "American Pie" is Don
    McLean's signature song.</p>
      <p>The song is well known for its cryptic lyrics that have long
    been the subject of curiosity and speculation. Although McLean
    dedicated the 
    <i>American Pie</i>album to Buddy Holly, none of the musicians
    in the plane crash are identified by name in the song itself.
    When asked what "American Pie" meant, McLean replied, "It means
    I never have to work again." Later, he more seriously
    stated,</p>
      <p>McLean has generally avoided responding to direct questions
    about the song lyrics ("They’re beyond analysis. They’re
    poetry.") except to acknowledge that he did first learn about
    Buddy Holly's death while folding newspapers for his paper
    route on the morning of February 3, 1959 (the line "February
    made me shiver/with every paper I'd deliver"). He also stated
    in an editorial published on the 50th anniversary of the crash
    in 2009 that writing the first verse of the song exorcised his
    long-running grief over Holly's death.</p>
      <p>Despite this, many fans of McLean, amongst others, have
    attempted an interpretation (see Interpretation Links); at the
    time of the song's original release in late 1971, many American
    AM and FM rock radio stations released printed interpretations
    and some devoted entire shows discussing and debating the
    song's lyrics, resulting in both controversy and intense
    listener interest in the song. Some examples are the real-world
    identities of the "Jester", "King and Queen", "Satan", "Girl
    Who Sang the Blues" and other characters referenced in the
    verses.</p>
      <p>Notable references are based on interpretations of the song
    by Bob Dearborn and Jim Fann.</p>
      <p>A few cover versions have been made over the years. The
    first English language cover version was by The Brady Bunch in
    1972, but a Spanish translation sung by voice actor Francisco
    Colmenero surfaced around Mexico in 1971. A very significant
    version, also in Spanish, was recorded in 1984 by the
    Nicaraguan singer Hernaldo Zúñiga. (Eduardo Fonseca recorded a
    cover version of the translation in 2000.) Ska punk band Catch
    22 made a ska version which became a staple of their live show,
    released in several versions. Alternative rock band Killdozer
    recorded a thrashing, ironic version of the song in 1989.</p>
      <p>As heard on 
    <i>Live</i>, Mott the Hoople opened mid-1970s concerts with
    singer Ian Hunter performing the first verse on solo piano up
    to the phrase 
    <i>the day the music died</i>. Hunter would then add "or did
    it?", and the full band would segue into the next number.</p>
      <p>Tori Amos performed the song often as a piano solo in her
    live concerts, and country singer Garth Brooks also sang this
    song during concerts in the early to mid 1990s. During Brooks'
    "Live in Central Park" concert, he performed this song as a
    duet with McLean himself at the end of the concert. The
    audience, of over 100,000 people, was also invited to sing the
    chorus near the end of the song.</p>
      <p>British a cappella group King's Singers covered the song for
    their 1993 album 
    <i>Good Vibrations</i>.</p>
      <p>Chris de Burgh covered the song in 2008 on the album 
    <i>Footsteps</i>.</p>
      <p>Pearl Jam frontman Eddie Vedder has sung the chorus of
    "American Pie" over the outro music of "Daughter" during select
    live performances.</p>
      <p>It was also Hong Kong pop superstar Leslie Cheung's
    breakthrough song.</p>
      <p>American pop star Madonna released a cover version of the
    song in March 2000 to promote the soundtrack to her film 
    <i>The Next Best Thing</i>(2000). Her cover is much shorter
    than the original (it contains only the beginning of the first
    verse and all of the second and sixth verses) and was recorded
    as a pop-dance song. Don McLean himself praised the cover,
    saying it was "a gift from a goddess", and that her version is
    "mystical and sensual."</p>
      <p>Due to the success of the single, it was included as a bonus
    track on her 2000 studio album 
    <i>Music</i>, however this was not available on the North
    American version. Madonna explained in a 2001 interview on BBC
    Radio 1 with Jo Whiley, the reason that the song was omitted
    from her 2001 greatest hits compilation 
    <i>GHV2</i>: "It was something a certain record company
    executive twisted my arm into doing, but it didn't belong on
    the (
    <i>Music</i>) album so now it's being punished".</p>
      <p>The cover was produced by Madonna and William Orbit, who had
    previously worked with her on the 1998 studio album 
    <i>Ray of Light</i>and 1999 single "Beautiful Stranger".
    Released in March 2000, the song was a big worldwide hit,
    reaching number one in many countries, including the United
    Kingdom, Canada, Australia, Italy, Germany (her first since "La
    Isla Bonita", in 1987), Switzerland, Austria and Finland. The
    song was the 19th best selling of 2000 in the UK. There was no
    commercial single release in the US, but the single still
    reached the number twenty-nine spot on s Hot 100, based on
    airplay alone.</p>
      <p>The music video, directed by Philipp Stölzl, depicts a
    diverse array of Americans, including a scene showing a lesbian
    couple kissing, which resulted in the video being censored on
    certain music shows in the United States. Two official versions
    of the video were produced, the first of which now appears on
    Madonna's greatest-hits DVD compilation, 
    <i>Celebration</i>, and was released as the official video
    worldwide. The second version was issued along with the "Humpty
    Remix", a more upbeat and dance-friendly version of the song.
    This video was aired on MTV's dance channel in the United
    States to promote the film 
    <i>The Next Best Thing</i>, starring Madonna and Rupert
    Everett; it contains totally different footage and new outtakes
    of the original and omits the lesbian kiss. Everett, who
    provides backing vocals in the song, is also featured in the
    video.</p>
      <p>Former Grateful Dead keyboardist Tom Constanten played an
    adapted version of 
    <i>American Pie</i>when opening for Jefferson Starship on
    August 9, 2005, the tenth anniversary of Jerry Garcia's death.
    Constanten altered the lyrics to allude to Jerry's death and
    how he heard the news by a phone call from Bruce Hornsby.</p>
      <p>Finnish rock musician Hector (Heikki Harma) made a Finnish
    cover of the song "American Pie" in 1971, under the name 
    <i>Suomi-Neito</i>(Maid Finland). While the original song
    covered the American issues, Hector's version was likewise
    "translated" to deal with the Finnish post WWII history and the
    loss of innocence in Finnish culture.</p>
      <p>The Swedish folksinger Lalla Hansson recorder in the 80´s a
    version in Swedish. The song is called "Nalen". The song is now
    about Swedish music and the classic club "Nalen" in Stockholm,
    Sweden.</p>
      <p>"American Diet" ("I'm too heavy for my Chevy; I belong in a
    sty..."), played on radio stations in Baltimore, MD during the
    late 1970s and early 80s.: re citation needed: cross reference
    to the "ink on dead tree" Publication MUSICAL CHAS by the
    "Capital Hill Area Science Fiction and Narcissism Society
    (CHASFANS)" Issue 4, Volume 3, Number 1, Whole Number 5: Page
    23-25. It references winter-spring of (19)77 WFBR-Baltimore,
    playing a tape which was subsequently erased. The CHASFANS
    attempted to remember it as best they could and was published
    in the aforementioned document. The original citation belongs
    to the person who sent WFBR the original tape.</p>
      <p>"The day the routers died" was written and performed by Gary
    Feldman at the conclusion of the RIPE 55 meeting to point out
    the urgency of IPv6 deployments.</p>
      <p>On 
    <i>That '70s Show</i>, In the episode "Celebration Day (AKA
    Graduation Day)", (Season 5, episode 25),the character Michael
    Kelso uses the music of "American Pie" to create a song
    dedicated to Jackie Burkhart, and later, when confronted with
    the fact that he ripped off McLean, claims that the "American
    Pie guy" stole the music from him.</p>
      <p>In 1983, Lauren Weinstein crafted "The Day Bell System Died"
    about the breakup of AT&amp;T. The song was very popular on the
    Usenet.</p>
      <p>In 1984, Ken Kaufman offered up "Network Pie" , a song about
    Usenet groups.</p>
      <p>At the 1984 Yale Law Revue, a satirical show performed by
    Yale Law Students, a parody entitled "The Year Yale Law School
    Died" featured entirely reworked lyrics, such as a reference to
    "The three men I admire least – Jay Katz, Klevorick and George
    Priest."</p>
      <p>A version of American Pie was adapted in 1997 to the first
    retirement of NHL legend, Mario Lemieux, entitled "Bye Bye,
    French-Canadian Guy". The song was written by two brothers from
    Pittsburgh, Michael Murphy and Bill Murphy. It was originally
    aired on Pittsburgh-based radio station, WDVE. Often, it is
    wrongfully credited to a Canadian parody band, The Arrogant
    Worms.</p>
      <p>In 1998, the Christian parody band ApologetiX released a
    parody of the song, entitled "Parable Guy", about Jesus'
    ministries through the use of storytelling.</p>
      <p>In 1999, "Weird Al" Yankovic did a 
    <i>Star Wars</i>inspired lyrical adaptation of "American Pie".
    Entitled "The Saga Begins", the song recounts the plot of 
    <i>Star Wars Episode I: The Phantom Menace</i>through the eyes
    of Obi-Wan Kenobi. While McLean gave permission for the parody,
    he did not make a cameo appearance in its video, despite
    popular rumor. McLean stated he was very pleased with the
    parody. He even admits to almost singing Yankovic's lyrics at
    live shows, because his children played the song so often.</p>
      <p>In late 2006, Brian Cooksey wrote an alternate version of
    Weird Al's "Saga Begins", titled "The Beginning (Y'shua Guy)".
    In this version, the verses begin with Genesis, continuing
    through the Gospels and ending with the Resurrection of Jesus.
    Though not a commercial success, the song resonates with those
    who are familiar with the source material; Don McLean's
    original and Weird Al's parody.</p>
      <p>The Jewish Summer Camp Song book, used at various Jewish
    summer camps in the Northeast USA, includes the song but
    changes the allusion to the trinity to "the three men I admire
    most, Abraham, Isaac, and Yaakov". It also changes the line
    "the church bells all were broken" to "those wacky synagogue
    bells were broken".</p>
      <p>The Center for Talented Youth has been using this song at
    their summer camps, every dance at every site, for a long time.
    It has a great meaning to all the tens-hundreds of thousands of
    people who have been there.</p>
      <p>In a season two episode of 
    <i>Roswell</i>, Colin Hanks and Nick Wechsler - trapped in an
    underground cave filled with parasitic alien crystals and
    running out of oxygen - sing the song while Max, Liz, Isabelle,
    and Tess try to prevent them from being buried alive. The
    episode, entitled "How the Other Half Lives", aired on February
    19, 2001, and was the fourteenth of the season.</p>
      <p>In the 
    <i>Futurama</i>episode "The Why of Fry", upon finding
    themselves trapped in a parallel universe for all eternity a
    race of alien 'brains' are at a loss for what to do. One brain
    suggested that they could sing "American Pie" to which a
    depressed Fry replied, "Go on, I deserve it."</p>
      <p>On season 4 on NBC's 
    <i>The Office</i>on the episode "The Chair Model" Michael and
    Dwight sing American Pie at the cemetery mourning the death of
    the chair model with whom Michael was infatuated.</p>
      <p>The final episode of series 11 of 
    <i>Bremner, Bird and Fortune</i>features a dream sequence sung
    supposedly by Tony Blair with lyrics referring to New
    Labour:</p>
      <p>In "24 Hour Propane People" of 
    <i>King Of The Hill</i>, Hank remarks that "You never realize
    how 'American Pie' is seven minutes long until your boss makes
    you sing it for karaoke."</p>
      <p>Seattle radio disc jockey Bob Rivers produced a parody
    entitled "American Pie Eulogy" in which a singer impersonating
    Don McLean's voice laments, "Why did Madonna kill "American
    Pie"? / Well, it’s tragic, but my classic has been hung out to
    dry / She might as well have poked a sharp stick in my eye /
    She’s making all the neighbor dogs cry."</p>
      <p>The Don McLean recording was used in the films 
    <i>The Next Best Thing</i>(2000) and 
    <i>Born on the Fourth of July</i>(1989).</p>
      <p>The song was parodied on the AFL Footy Show in early 2009,
    with Garry Lyon playing the part of McLean, and changing the
    lyrics to become a lament of the pending introduction of a new
    team to the Australian Football League.</p>
      <p>"Pi, Pi, Mathematical Pi" is another notable parody. Its
    lyrics revolve around the history of pi.</p>
      <p>The comedian Paul Shanklin made a parody of the version sung
    from Barack Obama's viewpoint regarding the healthcare plan for
    America.</p>
      <p>This song was featured in the music video game, 
    <i>Band Hero</i>. The word, "whiskey" was blanked out because 
    <i>Band Hero</i>was designed as a children's game, and
    therefore couldn't include references to alcohol.</p>
      <p>Transcriptions</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
