<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MacArthur_Park_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MacArthur_Park_(song)</songId>
   <title>MacArthur Park</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donna_Summer</artistId>
      <artistName>Donna Summer</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1978-11-11</week>
      <week>1978-11-18</week>
      <week>1978-11-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/bd/MacAruthurParkSingle.jpg/200px-MacAruthurParkSingle.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Donna-Summer+MacArthur-Park.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>A Tramp Shining</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1968-05-11</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <lengths>
      <length>7:21</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Dunhill</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jimmy Webb</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jimmy Webb</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"MacArthur Park" is a song written by Jimmy Webb. Originally
    written as part of an intended cantata rejected by The
    Association, it was first recorded by Richard Harris in 1968
    and then covered by many other performers. One of the best
    known covers of the song is Donna Summer's 1978 disco hit.
    Maynard Ferguson, Stan Kenton, and Woody Herman all performed
    dynamic big band jazz versions.</p>
      <p>Although it is unclear as to whether the name applies to the
    MacArthur Park in Los Angeles, California, or in Little Rock,
    Arkansas (the latter contains Douglas MacArthur's birthplace),
    in 2007, Webb gave an interview to the 
    <i>Los Angeles Times</i>and specifically named the park in Los
    Angeles as the place where he and his then girlfriend would
    meet. Unusually, the title on the disc and record cover art is
    spelled with a space between 
    <i>Mac</i>and 
    <i>Arthur</i>.</p>
      <p>The lyrics, which include the memorable line "Someone left
    the cake out in the rain", are more symbolic than descriptive,
    beginning as a poem about love, then moving into a lover's
    lament.</p>
      <p>"MacArthur Park" is unusually complex for a pop song. The
    music can be split roughly into four sections, or themes.</p>
      <p>The first theme contains the verses and chorus, and the
    lyrics begin: "Spring was never waiting for us girl." Fanfares
    in 9/8 time interrupt the 4/4 time of the song by adding an
    additional beat to the end of each phrase. This section centers
    on Dm, the fanfares center on A
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>, and the chorus centers on C major.</p>
      <p>The second theme is a slow lamenting melody, and starts:
    "There will be another song, for me." It is in F, and contains
    many Maj7 and a few M7
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>5 chords. At the end of this it briefly goes back into the
opening theme.</p>
      <p>The third theme is a fast paced instrumental, centered
    around G minor. It contains a lot of V/I style chords. The
    theme chords climb diatonically over a droning bass line. It
    then goes to an ascension of notes based on the chords G
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>, B
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>, D
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>, and resolves to F.</p>
      <p>The first and fourth themes are similar, but have some
    differences. The "MacArthur's park is melting" starts this time
    in F, not C. And instead of the line "I don't think that I can
    take it" starting on a I/III, it starts on a VI, and descends.
    The finale concludes with a phrase similar to the opening theme
    (but in A
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>instead of a Dm). The final chord is a B
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>.</p>
      <p>The song was first recorded by Richard Harris on his album 
    <i>A Tramp Shining</i>in 1968 and was released as a single. It
    was an unusual single, running for more than seven minutes,
    with a long, climactic orchestral break. Harris's topped the
    music charts in Europe and peaked at number two on the U.S.
    charts. The song peaked at #10 in Billboard's Easy Listening
    survey, and was #8 for the year on WABC's overall 1968
    chart.</p>
      <p>Harris sings the song's final chorus at an elevated pitch
    near the top of his falsetto range.</p>
      <p>Throughout his recording, Harris can be heard using the
    incorrect possessive form, "MacArthur's Park". Webb has said he
    tried correcting Harris during re-takes, but gave up when he
    simply could not (or would not) sing the correct words.</p>
      <p>This song went on to win a Grammy for Best Orchestration in
    1969.</p>
      <p>A multi-million selling disco version of the song by Donna
    Summer topped the U.S. charts for three weeks in 1978. Her
    recording, which was included as part of the "MacArthur Park
    Suite" on her double album 
    <i>Live and More</i>, ran to 8:40 in its full-length version.
    The shorter single edit of the song was Summer's first single
    to reach number one on the Billboard Hot 100. The 17:47 long
    medley "MacArthur Park Suite", which incorporates the songs
    "One of a Kind" and "Heaven Knows", was also issued as a 12"
    (30 cm) promo, which stayed at number one on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Dance Club Play chart for five weeks in
    1978. The releases on "Live and More" and the 12" promo are
    noticeably different in the editing of the two accompanying
    songs, with the 12" including more of "Heaven Knows" and less
    of "One of a Kind" than the "Live and More" version.</p>
      <p>The song was not included on the "Live and More" CD release
    due to time limitation; however it is available on "The Dance
    Collection" released in 1987.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered more than fifty times, including
    versions by:</p>
      <p>Other notable covers include the following:</p>
      <p>"MacArthur Park"'s odd metaphors and sentimentality have
    made it a frequent target of parody and ridicule over the
    years.</p>
      <p>In 1992, humorist Dave Barry conducted a poll among his
    readers (as recorded in 
    <i>Dave Barry's Book of Bad Songs</i>) of the worst songs ever.
    Barry's readers selected Harris's version of "MacArthur Park"
    as the worst song ever recorded, both in terms of "Worst
    Lyrics" and "Worst Overall Song".</p>
      <p>The song was also once parodied in a 1981 episode of 
    <i>SCTV</i>, in which Dave Thomas, playing Richard Harris, sang
    a version of the song that appears to never end.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
