<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secret_Love_(1953_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secret_Love_(1953_song)</songId>
   <title>Secret Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doris_Day</artistId>
      <artistName>Doris Day</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1954-02-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Calamity Jane</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1953-10-09</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" (45rpm)</format>
      <format>10" (78rpm)</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1953</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Traditional Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:38</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia 40108</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Sammy Fain and Paul Francis Webster</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Secret Love" is a popular song written in 1953 with music
    by Sammy Fain and lyrics by Paul Francis Webster. Its first
    performance was in the film 
    <i>Calamity Jane</i>by Doris Day. It received an Academy Award
    for Best Original Song. Doris Day also recorded the
    best-selling record of the song, which reached #1 on both the
    Billboard and Cash Box charts in 1954. The record was made on
    August 5, 1953. The recording was released by Columbia Records
    as catalog number 40108.</p>
      <p>The Moonglows recorded an R&amp;B version for Chance Records
    in January 1954, released in February, 1954.[3] Connie Francis
    recorded the song on April 27, 1962 at RCA Italiana Studios in
    Rome for her album 
    <i>Connie Francis sings Award Winning Motion Picture Hits</i>.
    The original version from the April 1962 with an arrangement by
    Geoff Love was only available in Australia (MGM Records
    S027592) and New Zealand (MGM Records MCS 5017). All other
    world wide releases that album included a version with a new
    orchestration recorded in April 1963 with an arrangement by Don
    Costa.</p>
      <p>British singer Kathy Kirby recorded an upbeat version of the
    song in 1963. It made the top 10 in the UK and in
    Australia.</p>
      <p>Bronx female group, The Chiffons recorded a Motownesque
    version for Bright Tunes in 1965, but it wasn't released until
    1969 on B.T. Puppy Records, and overseas on various labels in
    1970.</p>
      <p>Freddy Fender recorded "Secret Love" in his 2002 release La
    Musica de Baldemar Huerta. His 1975 bi-lingual version was a
    number-one hit on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Country Singles chart and a number twenty
    hit on the Billboard Hot 100. Fender's version was not the
    first time country audiences had heard the song; Slim Whitman
    had a major hit of his own in 1954 with the song.</p>
      <p>Mandy Moore covered the song on the 
    <i>Mona Lisa Smile</i>soundtrack. Doris Day's version was used
    in the actual movie.</p>
      <p>Spike Jones did a version of the song in the style of a
    Cuban Mambo band of the 1950s.</p>
      <p>It has also been covered by José Hoebee, a Dutch pop singer
    (ex-member of the girl group Luv'), who reached number 11 in
    the Dutch Top 40 with her version in the autumn of 1982.</p>
      <p>Anne Murray recorded a cover of the song for her album
    "Croonin'" (1993).</p>
      <p>John Serry, Sr. arranged and recorded this composition with
    his ensemble on Dot Records (DLP-3024) for his album entitled 
    <i>Squeeze Play</i>in 1956.</p>
      <p>Cerys Matthews recorded a cover version for the Children's
    Hospice charity album, 
    <i>Over the Rainbow</i>.</p>
      <p>Allan Sherman has a light-hearted parody called "Secret
    Code" on his 1965 LP 
    <i>My Name is Allan</i>.</p>
      <p>k.d. lang made a cover of the song, to be played during the
    closing credits of the documentary 
    <i>The Celluloid Closet</i>(1995). The song is also shown in a
    clip from the original 
    <i>Calamity Jane</i>movie, starring Doris Day.</p>
      <p>Lord Tanamo did a live version of "Secret Love" until it was
    recorded with Tommy McCook in 1997. Since then The Allstonians
    have been covering the song and plan on recording it in the
    near future.</p>
      <p>Soul singer Billy Stewart hit the Billboard Top 30 in 1966
    with his wild re-make.</p>
      <p>George Michael made a cover version for his 1999 album 
    <i>Songs from the Last Century</i>.</p>
      <p>Manuel Galbán &amp; Ry Cooder instrumental version on cd
    "Mambo Sinuendo" (2003)</p>
      <p>3. Disco-File, 3rd Ed., Gonzalez, Fernando L.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
