<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oh_My_Pa-Pa_(O_Mein_Papa) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oh_My_Pa-Pa_(O_Mein_Papa)</songId>
   <title>Oh! My Pa-Pa (O Mein Papa)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eddie_Fisher_(singer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Eddie Fisher</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1954-01-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"O mein Papa" is a German song about a beloved clown father,
    written by Swiss composer Paul Burkhard in 1939 for a musical
    called 
    <i>Der Schwarze Hecht</i>(reproduced in 1950 as 
    <i>Feuerwerk</i>(Fireworks)), lyrics by Erik Charell, Jürg
    Amstein, and Robert Gilbert.</p>
      <p>The song has been performed and recorded by numerous artists
    since then, including Alan Breeze, Billy Cotton, Billy Vaughn,
    Connie Francis, The Everly Brothers, Harry James, Lys Assia,
    Malcolm Vaughan, Muriel Smith, Ray Anthony &amp; his Orchestra,
    Russ Morgan &amp; his Orchestra, The Beverley Sisters, Björk
    (on Gling-Gló, as 
    <i>Pabbi minn</i>) and many others.</p>
      <p>Under the original German title, an instrumental version by
    trumpeter Eddie Calvert topped the UK Singles Chart in 1954,
    and was also a Top 10 hit in the U.S.</p>
      <p>It was adapted into English by John Turner and Geoffrey
    Parsons under the title "Oh! My Pa-Pa". A recording by Eddie
    Fisher became a #1 hit on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 chart in
    1954. Fisher's version also made the UK Top 10; thus, in the
    UK, Calvert's version was number one while Fisher's made the
    Top 10 but missed the top spot, and in the U.S., the roles were
    reversed. Calvert's version has a further claim to fame as the
    first UK number one to be recorded at the most successful of
    all British recording studios, Abbey Road. The song returned to
    Abbey Road when Geoff Love recorded an instrumental version in
    the summer of 1960 to be used as a backing track for Connie
    Francis' English-Yiddish recording. Francis overdubbed her
    vocals in Hollywood. In 1966, Francis recorded the song once
    more, this time with the original German lyrics for her German
    concept album "Melodien, die die Welt erobern".</p>
      <p>U.S. television viewers were re-introduced to the song via
    the television show "Gomer Pyle, U.S.M.C.". In the episode
    "Sing a Song of Papa", Jim Nabor's Private Pyle enters a talent
    contest at a nightclub. His rendition of the song wins him $25
    and the admiration of the club's owner, who is apparently
    connected to organized crime, and predictable hijinks
    ensue.</p>
      <p>The opening stanza was momentarily quoted in Frank Zappa's
    song "Billy the Mountain" (1972) in place of the word
    "fissure," a reference to Eddie Fisher.</p>
      <p>The song was also in the episode "Like Father, Like Clown"
    of 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>sung by Krusty the Clown.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
