<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keep_on_Truckin%27_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keep_on_Truckin%27_(song)</songId>
   <title>Keep on Truckin' (Part 1)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eddie_Kendricks</artistId>
      <artistName>Eddie Kendricks</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1973-11-10</week>
      <week>1973-11-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Eddie Kendricks</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 1973</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1973</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:21 (single edit)</length>
      <length>8:00 (album version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Tamla , T 54238</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Leonard Caston</writer>
      <writer>Anita Poree</writer>
      <writer>Frank Wilson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Frank Wilson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Keep on Truckin'" is a 1973 hit song recorded by Eddie
    Kendricks for Motown Records' Tamla label. The song was
    Kendricks' first major hit as a solo artist, coming two years
    after his departure from The Temptations. "Keep On Truckin'"
    reached number one on both the Billboard Hot 100 and R&amp;B
    Singles Chart upon its release, and was Kendricks' only
    number-one hit.. The song is considered by some to be the first
    disco song ever released, although that distinction is heavily
    debated. According to Dance Dance Revolution X Wil-Dog Abers'
    (of Ozomatli fame) aunt co-wrote the song.</p>
      <p>By 1973, Eddie Kendricks was two years deep into a solo
    career following his bitter split from The Temptations in 1971.
    While his former band mates went on to record hits such as
    "Superstar (Remember How You Got Where You Are)", which was a
    reported jab at Kendricks and fellow ex-Temptation David Ruffin
    and their seven-minute opus, "Papa Was a Rollin' Stone",
    Kendricks had begun to reach a cult R&amp;B fan base following
    his last two albums. Working closely with Frank Wilson, who was
    the main producer in most of Kendricks' solo efforts, the duo
    worked on a song that would aim at the dance floor rather than
    the serene ballads that Kendricks was used to recording. His
    earlier single, "Girl You Need a Change of Mind", was a cult
    favorite for club fans. With co-writers Anita Poree and Leonard
    Caston, Wilson created a song that rivaled that of the
    Temptations' Norman Whitfield-produced cinematic soul that had
    become commonplace among the group's recordings but instead of
    instigating drama, the song's grooves were clearly aimed at the
    dance floor.</p>
      <p>Upon its release in the summer of 1973, the song would
    finally bring Kendricks out of the shadow of his former band as
    the song's catchy beats and melody became a crossover hit. By
    late fall, the song had reached number-one on the US pop and
    R&amp;B singles chart ironically eclipsing singles released by
    his former group. When "...Truckin'" became a hit, the
    Temptations' hit luster was waning with "Hey Girl (I Like Your
    Style)" barely reaching the Top 40 and the follow-up funk song,
    "Let Your Hair Down", becoming only a modest hit. Much like
    their "Superstar", which would ironically be covered by David
    Ruffin, Kendricks includes a jab at his former band mates with
    the lyric:</p>
      <p>The single version of the song, entitled as "Part 1"
    features the sound of a truck going by, before the coda.</p>
      <p>The song would later be included in debates about the
    first-recorded and released disco record alongside The Hues
    Corporation's "Rock the Boat" and Barry White's "Can't Get
    Enough". The song gave Kendricks a Grammy nomination for Best
    Male R&amp;B Vocal Performance losing out to Stevie Wonder's
    "Superstition" and would remain his signature hit though he
    would score other hits such as "Boogie Down", "Shoeshine Boy",
    "Happy" and "A Friend of Mine". The song's instrumental bridge
    would later be sampled by rapper Mr. Cheeks on his 2002 single,
    Lights, Camera, Action and in the Jennifer Lopez 2007 single, 
    <i>Do It Well</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
