<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/To_Each_His_Own_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/To_Each_His_Own_(song)</songId>
   <title>To Each His Own</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eddy_Howard</artistId>
      <artistName>Eddy Howard</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1946-08-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"To Each His Own" is a popular song with music written by
    Jay Livingston and lyrics by Ray Evans. The song was published
    in 1946.</p>
      <p>In 1946, three different versions hit number one on the
    Billboard charts in the United Sates. Hit versions in 1946 were
    recorded by:</p>
      <p>Eddy Howard reached number one after debuting on the chart
    with his version of the song on July 11, 1946. Released by
    Majestic Records as catalog number 7188 and 1070, the single
    lasted nineteen weeks on the chart, reaching the top spot on
    August 10 for three weeks and returning for two more weeks on
    October 5.</p>
      <p>Freddy Martin &amp; his Orchestra, featuring vocals by
    Stuart Wade, and Tony Martin both had their versions debut on
    the chart on August 8, 1946, with each remaining on the chart
    for twelve weeks. While Freddie Martin, who version was
    released by RCA Victor Records, was able to top the chart for
    two weeks, Tony Martin's version, released by Mercury Records,
    peaked at number four.</p>
      <p>The next version to reach the 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts was performed by The Modernaires with
    Paula Kelly. Released by Columbia Records, together they
    debuted on the chart on August 15, 1946, lasting six weeks on
    the chart and peaking at number five.</p>
      <p>The final recording to reach number one was by The Ink
    Spots, which was released by Decca Records. Reaching the charts
    on August 29, 1946, it remained on the chart for eleven weeks
    on the chart, reaching its number-one peak on September 21.</p>
      <p>Other recordings: Sam Cooke recorded it for his LP, 
    <i>Try a Little Love</i>. Frankie Laine had a minor revival
    with the song in 1968, reaching number two on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Easy Listening chart.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
