<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/War_(Edwin_Starr_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/War_(Edwin_Starr_song)</songId>
   <title>War</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edwin_Starr</artistId>
      <artistName>Edwin Starr</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1970-08-29</week>
      <week>1970-09-05</week>
      <week>1970-09-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/19/Edwin-starr-war-single-1970.jpg/200px-Edwin-starr-war-single-1970.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Edwin-Starr+War.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>War &amp; Peace</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 10, 1970</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Hitsville USA (Studio A); , spring 1970</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Psychedelic Soul</genre>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:28</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Gordy , Gordy 7101</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Norman Whitfield</writer>
      <writer>Barrett Strong</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Norman Whitfield</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"War" is a soul song written by Norman Whitfield and Barrett
    Strong for the Motown label in 1969. Whitfield first produced
    the song — a blatant anti-Vietnam War protest — with The
    Temptations as the original vocalists. After Motown began
    receiving repeated requests to release "War" as a single,
    Whitfield re-recorded the song with Edwin Starr as the
    vocalist, deciding to withhold the Temptations' version so as
    not to alienate their more conservative fans. Starr's version
    of "War" was a number-one hit on the Hot 100 chart in 1970, and
    is not only the most successful and well-known record of his
    career, but is also one of the most popular protest songs ever
    recorded. Its power was reasserted when Bruce Springsteen and
    the E Street Band took their rendition into the U.S. Top 10 in
    1986. Following the terrorist attacks on September 11, 2001,
    the song was placed on the list of post-9/11 inappropriate
    titles distributed by Clear Channel.</p>
      <p>The Temptations' version of "War", featuring Paul Williams
    and Dennis Edwards on lead vocals, was much less intense than
    the Edwin Starr version. Williams and Edwards deliver the
    song's anti-war, pro-peace message over a stripped-down
    instrumental track, with bass singer Melvin Franklin chanting a
    repeated recruit training-like "hup, two, three, four" in the
    background during the verses.</p>
      <p>The song was included as a track on the March 1970 
    <i>Psychedelic Shack</i>album, which featured the title track
    as its only single. The track's direct message, summarized by
    its chorus ("War, what is it good for? Absolutely nothin'!"),
    struck a chord with the American public and resonated with
    growing public opposition to the war in Vietnam. Fans from
    across the nation, many of them college students and other
    young people, sent letters to Motown requesting the release of
    "War" as a single. The label didn't want to risk the image of
    its most popular male group, and the Temptations themselves
    were also apprehensive about releasing such a potentially
    controversial song as a single. The label decided to withhold
    "War"'s release as a single, a decision that Whitfield fought
    until the label came up with a compromise: "War" would be
    released, but it would have to be re-recorded with a different
    act.</p>
      <p>Edwin Starr, who had become a Motown artist in 1968 after
    his former label, Ric-Tic, was purchased by Motown founder
    Berry Gordy, Jr., became "War's" new vocalist. Considered among
    Motown's "second-string" acts, Starr had only one major hit,
    1968's number-six hit "Twenty-Five Miles", to his name by this
    time.</p>
      <p>He heard about the conflict surrounding the debate of
    whether or not to release "War," and volunteered to re-record
    it. Whitfield re-created the song to match Starr's James
    Brown-influenced soul shout: the single version of "War" was
    dramatic and intense, depicting the general anger and distaste
    the antiwar movement felt towards the war in Vietnam. Unlike
    the Temptations' original, Starr's "War" was a full-scale
    Whitfield production, with prominent electric guitar lines,
    clavinets, a heavily syncopated rhythm accented by a horn
    section, and with Whitfield's new act The Undisputed Truth on
    backing vocals.</p>
      <p>Upon its release in June 1970, Starr's "War" became a
    runaway hit, and held the #1 position on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Pop Singles chart for three weeks, in August
    and September 1970. It replaced "Make It With You" by Bread,
    and was replaced by another Motown single, "Ain't No Mountain
    High Enough" by Diana Ross.</p>
      <p>Notable as the most successful protest song to become a pop
    hit, earning compliments from contemporary protester John
    Lennon, "War" became Edwin Starr's signature song. Rather than
    hindering his career (as it might have done for the
    Temptations), "War" buoyed Starr's career, and he adopted the
    image of an outspoken liberal orator for many of his other
    early-1970s releases, including the similarly-themed "Stop the
    War Now" from 1971. It and another 1971 single, "Funky Music
    Sho Nuff Turns Me On," continued Starr's string of
    Whitfield-produced psychedelic soul hits. After 1971, Starr's
    career began to falter, and, citing Motown's reliance on
    formulas, he departed the label in the mid-1970s.</p>
      <p>Later in his career, after moving to the United Kingdom,
    Starr re-recorded several of his hits with British band Utah
    Saints. Starr's new version of "War" in 2003 was his final
    piece; he died on April 2 of the same year of a heart
    attack.</p>
      <p>Starr won a Grammy in 1971 for ” War” for best R&amp;B Male
    Vocal. In 1999, Edwin Starr's "War" was inducted into the
    Grammy Hall of Fame.</p>
      <p>Starr bought an extensive country house, Pooley Hall, on the
    outskirts of Polesworth in Warwickshire. Pooley Hall was built
    by Thomas Cockayne between 1506 and 1509 on the site of a much
    older house. It has an embattled tower with a stair turret, and
    is built of red brick with stone mullions and quoins. Though it
    is a highly unlikely story, there are said to be secret
    passages connecting Pooley Hall to Polesworth Abbey. It
    overlooks the Coventry canal and has its own landing stage.</p>
      <p>"War" was performed in concert by Bruce Springsteen and the
    E Street Band in 1985, added to the set list for the final few
    shows of their lengthy Born in the U.S.A. Tour. Springsteen and
    his manager Jon Landau were looking for a way to make these
    concluding shows, taking place at the Los Angeles Memorial
    Coliseum, a little different and special, and Landau suggested
    playing "War". A year earlier, he had suggested the same, as a
    loose protest against Reagan Administration foreign policy in
    Central America and elsewhere, but the band had been unable to
    come up with an effective arrangement. This time, however, they
    did. Springsteen taped the words of the song to his arm,
    prefaced the song with a spoken admonition not to blindly trust
    the government, leaders or anything else, and then he and the
    band performed a rock rendition.</p>
      <p>Springsteen released the September 30, 1985 performance as a
    part of his 1986 box set, 
    <i>Live/1975-85</i>. "War" was chosen as the first single from
    the set, and it was again a big hit, reaching #8 on the
    Billboard Hot 100 chart. The music video for the single was a
    straight concert filming of the same performance.</p>
      <p>Springsteen continued to perform "War" regularly through his
    1988 Tunnel of Love Express and Human Rights Now! Tours. He
    then retired it, until again performing it on his 2003 Rising
    Tour before and during the start of the Iraq War.</p>
      <p>"War" was also covered by Tom Jones in 1971 &amp; 1985.</p>
      <p>"War" was covered by The Jam in 1982. A studio version
    featured as one of three extra tracks on the Just Who Is the 5
    O'Clock Hero?, The Bitterest Pill (I Ever Had to Swallow), Beat
    Surrender 12" singles. It was also a live favourite.</p>
      <p>"War" was covered by influential Canadian punk band D.O.A.
    on their 1982 12" EP 
    <i>War On 45</i>.</p>
      <p>"War" was covered by Frankie Goes to Hollywood on the
    12-inch of their 1984 hit single "Two Tribes", and was included
    on the album 
    <i>Welcome to the Pleasuredome</i>.</p>
      <p>The trash-punk band Mace covered it on their 1987 album "The
    Evil in Good".</p>
      <p>An episode of the television series 
    <i>Xena: Warrior Princess</i>, "Lyre Lyre Hearts on Fire",
    includes a cover of "War".</p>
      <p>"War" was remixed by Bone Thugs-N-Harmony, along with Henry
    Rollins, Tom Morello, and Flea, for the soundtrack to the film 
    <i>Small Soldiers</i>. The song features new raps by Bone
    Thugs-N-Harmony, and a spoken word section by Rollins, while
    the chorus features the original vocal track by Starr.</p>
      <p>Slovenian band Laibach included a cover of "War" on their
    1994 album NATO. This version answers the question "War, what
    is it good for?" by listing what, in Laibach's opinion, war is
    good for: for example, science, religion, IBM, CNN, and various
    other large multi-national companies.</p>
      <p>In February 2007, the Stop the War Coalition released a
    single of the song, attributed to Ugly Rumours — the rock band
    formed by former UK prime minister Tony Blair at Oxford
    University during the 1970s. The song reached no 6 in the UK
    music charts. The accompanying video featured a Blair
    look-alike as lead singer, and appearances by George Galloway
    and Lauren Booth as police officers arresting Blair.</p>
      <p>Rock band Pearl Jam has covered parts of the song in the
    breakdown of their own song 'Daughter'.</p>
      <p>Blues singer Maria Muldaur covered the song on her 2008
    album, 
    <i>Yes We Can</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was also sung by Jackie Chan, Adrienne Bailon and
    Chris Tucker in the two Rush Hour films.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
