<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/If_I_Knew_You_Were_Comin%27_I%27d%27ve_Baked_a_Cake 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/If_I_Knew_You_Were_Comin%27_I%27d%27ve_Baked_a_Cake</songId>
   <title>If I Knew You Were Comin' (I'd've Baked a Cake)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eileen_Barton</artistId>
      <artistName>Eileen Barton</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1950-04-15</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"If I Knew You Were Comin' I'd've Baked a Cake" is a popular
    song written by Al Hoffman, Bob Merrill, and Clem Watts and
    published in 1950.</p>
      <p>The big hit version in 1950 was recorded by Eileen Barton in
    January 1950. The recording was released by National Records as
    catalog number 9103. The record first reached the Billboard
    magazine charts on March 3, 1950 and lasted 15 weeks on the
    chart, peaking at #1.</p>
      <p>Another version was recorded by Georgia Gibbs. The recording
    was made on February 16, 1950 and released by Coral Records as
    catalogue number 60169. The record first reached the Billboard
    magazine charts on March 17, 1950 and lasted six weeks on the
    chart, peaking at #21.</p>
      <p>A British version was recorded by Dame Gracie Fields in
    1950, and has since been used on a British television
    advertising campaign.</p>
      <p>Another version was recorded by Betty Harris and a choir,
    with Art Mooney's Orchestra. The recording was made on February
    15, 1950 and released by MGM Records as catalogue number
    10660.</p>
      <p>Bing Crosby and Bob Hope recorded a version together that
    expanded on the standard lyrics to include verses about making
    a meal and preparing a goose.</p>
      <p>In Australia, a version was recorded by June Hamilton in
    May, 1950 and released by Pacific Records as catalog number
    10-0030.</p>
      <p>This song was used in a skit on "Sesame Street" involving
    Ernie and Cookie Monster, when Cookie Monster wanted cookies,
    but,instead had to settle for a birthday cake, made by Ernie,
    in which he wildly eats it up. When he first sees the finished
    cake, Cookie Monster exclaims: "Oh!!,I wish it was a
    Cookie".</p>
      <p>A version was used as the opening theme to Exit 57, a sketch
    comedy series that aired on Comedy Central and starred Amy
    Sedaris, Paul Dinello, Stephen Colbert, Mitch Rouse, and Jodi
    Lennon.</p>
      <p>Manhattan band The Maxes recorded a version of the song in
    2008 as part of a 12-song Al Hoffman collection titled "The
    Maxes Sing Al Hoffman."</p>
      <p>Certain versions of the song include the lyrics If I Knew
    You Were Comin' I'd've Baked a Cake "this morning" instead of
    "how'd you do"</p>
      <p>Greggs The Bakers (a popular UK High Street bakers) is using
    this song as part of its new tv advertising campaign. This can
    be view at www.greggs.co.uk/tv</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
