<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crocodile_Rock 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crocodile_Rock</songId>
   <title>Crocodile Rock</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elton_John</artistId>
      <artistName>Elton John</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1973-02-03</week>
      <week>1973-02-10</week>
      <week>1973-02-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/0b/Elton_John_Crocodile_Rock_%282%29.jpg/200px-Elton_John_Crocodile_Rock_%282%29.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Elton-John+Crocodile-Rock.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Don't Shoot Me I'm Only the Piano Player</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>UK 27 October 1972 , US 20 November 1972</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:58 (album version)</length>
      <length>3:54 (single version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MCA (US) , DJM (UK)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Elton John</writer>
      <writer>Bernie Taupin</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Crocodile Rock" is a song written by Elton John and Bernie
    Taupin, and recorded in June 1972 at the Strawberry Studios,
    Château d'Hérouville in France. It was released on 27 October
    1972 in the UK and 20 November 1972 in the US, as a pre-release
    single from his forthcoming 1973 album 
    <i>Don't Shoot Me I'm Only the Piano Player</i>, and became his
    first U.S. number-one single, reaching the top spot on 3
    February 1973, and stayed there for three weeks. It was the
    first song released as a single on the MCA label (catalogue
    #40000) after MCA dissolved its Uni, Decca, Kapp and Coral
    labels. (John had previously been with the Uni label.)
    "Crocodile Rock" is dominated by a Farfisa organ, played by
    John. The Farfisa is instantly recognizable by its
    carnival-like sound and honky-tonk rhythm, while the lyrics
    take a nostalgic look at early rock 'n' roll, and a
    relationship with a woman named Suzie, which the writer
    instantly associates with the music of the era. Regular Elton
    John band members, such as Davey Johnstone and Nigel Olsson,
    are among the song's performers.</p>
      <p>The song was inspired by John's discovery of leading
    Australian band Daddy Cool and their hit single "Eagle Rock",
    which was the most successful Australian single of the early
    1970s remaining at #1 for a (then) record 10 weeks. John heard
    the song and the group on his 1972 Australian tour and was
    greatly impressed by it. The cover of John's 1973 album 
    <i>Don't Shoot Me I'm Only the Piano Player</i>(the album on
    which "Crocodile Rock" is included) features a photo of John's
    lyricist Bernie Taupin wearing a "Daddy Who?" promotional
    badge. The song also appears to have been strongly influenced
    by the hit "Little Darlin'", most famously recorded in 1957 by
    The Diamonds (although the original version was recorded by The
    Gladiolas.) The chorus resembles "Speedy Gonzales" by Pat
    Boone. While there was no actual "Crocodile Rock", there was a
    dance called The Alligator.</p>
      <p>Bob The Builder included a cover of this on his debut album,
    
    <i>The Album</i>in 2001.</p>
      <p>On the tribute album 
    <i>Two Rooms: Celebrating the Songs of Elton John &amp; Bernie
    Taupin</i>recorded in 1991 by a symposium of eminent performers
    as the soundtrack of the documentary film 
    <i>Two Rooms</i>, the song "Crocodile Rock" is covered by The
    Beach Boys. Their interpretation emphasises the vocal
    reminiscence of the Rock and Roll era and tones down the honky
    tonk and cha-cha-cha ambiance of the original.</p>
      <p>The Baha Men covered the song for the 2002 movie 
    <i>The Crocodile Hunter: Collision Course</i>.</p>
      <p>There are also well-known nightclubs called the "Crocodile
    Rock" in Allentown, Pennsylvania and Toronto, Ontario.</p>
      <p>Discography</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
