<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bennie_and_the_Jets 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bennie_and_the_Jets</songId>
   <title>Bennie and the Jets</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elton_John</artistId>
      <artistName>Elton John</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-04-13</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Goodbye Yellow Brick Road</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>4 February 1974</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:10</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MCA (US/Canada) , DJM Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Elton John</writer>
      <writer>Bernie Taupin</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Bennie and the Jets" is a song composed by Elton John and
    Bernie Taupin. The song is written in the key of G major and
    first appeared on the 
    <i>Goodbye Yellow Brick Road</i>album in 1973. "Bennie and the
    Jets" has been one of John's most popular songs.</p>
      <p>The song tells of "Bennie and the Jets", a fictional band of
    whom Elton John is a supposed fan. In interviews, Taupin has
    said that the song's lyrics are a satire on the music industry
    of the 1970s. The greed and glitz of the early '70s music scene
    is portrayed by Taupin's words:</p>
      <p>Taupin also goes on to describe the flashy wardrobe of
    "Bennie", the leader of the band:</p>
      <p>Elton John was set against releasing "Bennie and the Jets"
    on side one of the 
    <i>Goodbye Yellow Brick Road</i>album, and was against
    releasing it as a single, believing it would fail. The song
    peaked at number one on the singles charts in 1974." Bennie and
    the Jets" was also John's first Top 40 hit on the R&amp;B
    charts.</p>
      <p>Axl Rose of Guns N' Roses has stated that he was listening
    to "Bennie and the Jets" and that inspired him to become a
    singer.</p>
      <p>The song was recorded in France at Château d'Hérouville's
    Strawberry Studios, where John and Taupin had recorded their
    previous two albums, 
    <i>Honky Chateau</i>and 
    <i>Don't Shoot Me I'm Only the Piano Player</i>.</p>
      <p>After recording the song in the studio, John and the band
    worried that it was too plain and unoriginal. According to
    guitarist Davey Johnstone, "'Bennie and the Jets' was one of
    the oddest songs we ever recorded. We just sat back and said,
    'This is really odd'." Gus Dudgeon, who produced 
    <i>Goodbye Yellow Brick Road</i>as well as most of John's
    albums up to that point, added the "live from Playhouse
    Theatre" sound to the track. Dudgeon added applause and
    audience sounds from John's previous concerts, plus
    whistles.</p>
      <p>While John rarely plays the same song the same way, and
    often makes subtle or even drastic changes, 'Bennie' is a
    slight exception. During live renditions, the solo in the
    middle of the song is played exactly the same way live as it
    was recorded. An exception to this can be heard on the 1976
    live release, "Here and There", where John significantly
    changes the solo in the bridge. The ending is almost always
    improvised in a variety of styles (and, at times, for a number
    of minutes) including classical, swing and, perhaps most
    notably, boogie-woogie.</p>
      <p>Discography</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
