<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Go_Breaking_My_Heart 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Go_Breaking_My_Heart</songId>
   <title>Don't Go Breaking My Heart</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elton_John</artistId>
      <artistName>Elton John and Kiki Dee</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1976-08-07</week>
      <week>1976-08-14</week>
      <week>1976-08-21</week>
      <week>1976-08-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>21 June 1976</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:28</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Rocket Records , MCA Records (US/Canada)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ann Orson</writer>
      <writer>Carte Blanche</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Gus Dudgeon</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Don't Go Breaking My Heart" is a duet by Elton John and
    Kiki Dee. It was written by Elton John with Bernie Taupin under
    the pseudonym "Ann Orson" and "Carte Blanche" (a pun on the
    expression "an horse and cart, blanche"), and intended as an
    affectionate pastiche of the Tamla Motown style, notably the
    various duets recorded by Marvin Gaye and singers such as Tammi
    Terrell and Kim Weston. It is not to be confused with the Burt
    Bacharach/Hal David song of the same title recorded in 1966 by
    Dionne Warwick.</p>
      <p>Like many of Elton John's singles from the 1970s, it was
    never included on any of his original albums (though it was
    recorded during the same sessions that produced 
    <i>Blue Moves</i>). However, it was included on the original
    version of 
    <i>Elton John's Greatest Hits Volume II</i>in 1977. It has
    since been shifted to the "Volume 3" compilation, 
    <i>Greatest Hits 1976–1986</i>. In 2002, it also appeared on
    Elton John's 2-disc greatest hits album, 
    <i>Elton John's Greatest Hits 1970-2002</i>. A demo version of
    the song was recorded by John as a solo artist. This version
    has not been released commercially.</p>
      <p>"Don't Go Breaking My Heart" was also John's first No. 1
    single in the UK, topping the chart for six weeks in mid 1976.
    He would not enjoy a solo British chart-topper until
    "Sacrifice" in 1990. It also became his sixth No. 1 single in
    the US, topping the Billboard Hot 100 for four weeks.</p>
      <p>The b-side "Snow Queen" has yet to be released on CD. The
    song was supposedly inspired by Cher, with Elton's improvising
    past Sonny &amp; Cher hits I Got You Babe, and The Beat Goes On
    as well as the solo Cher song Bang Bang (My Baby Shot Me Down)
    during the fadeout of the song.</p>
      <p>In 1985, John and Dee performed the track to the crowd at
    Wembley Stadium during John's set at Live Aid (where Dee sang
    backup). In 1987, Elton appeared with Minnie Mouse on the NBC
    series 
    <i>Totally Minnie</i>performing the track. He also performed it
    with the Spice Girls on his ITV tribute programme 
    <i>An Audience With Elton John</i>.</p>
      <p>The song’s promotional film has been cited among the
    cheapest music videos ever produced. The circumstances behind
    its conception were detailed on an episode of Pop-Up Video. The
    video’s director was found in the midst of filming a Rod
    Stewart television special. He was pulled aside, located an
    unused soundstage, hastily dressed it to give the appearance of
    a recording studio, setup three cameras and had the two singers
    pretend to record their vocals. Shot in a single take while
    being told to ‘improvise’, Elton John and Kiki Dee often missed
    their cues and John’s attempt to lead Dee in a very haphazard
    dance sequence caught his companion off guard. The music video
    with RuPaul features a black grand piano, something Elton has
    not used since 1987.</p>
      <p>Hip hop music artist Ol' Dirty Bastard and R&amp;B singer
    Macy Gray recorded a loose cover version of the song which
    retained the melody but featured new rap lyrics and intentional
    off-key singing.</p>
      <p>Discography</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
