<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Are_You_Lonesome_Tonight%3F_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Are_You_Lonesome_Tonight%3F_(song)</songId>
   <title>Are You Lonesome Tonight?</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elvis_Presley</artistId>
      <artistName>Elvis Presley</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1960-11-28</week>
      <week>1960-12-05</week>
      <week>1960-12-12</week>
      <week>1960-12-19</week>
      <week>1960-12-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Are You Lonesome To-night?," now often known as "Are You
    Lonesome Tonight?," is a popular song with music by Lou Handman
    and lyrics by Roy Turk. It was first published in 1926, and
    most notably revived by Elvis Presley in 1960.</p>
      <p>A number of artists recorded "Are You Lonesome Tonight?" in
    1927. Composer Lou Handman himself played piano while his
    sister Edith provided the vocals for a recording released on
    the Gennett label. Vaughn DeLeath (also known as "The Original
    Radio Girl") recorded the song twice, first on June 13, as solo
    and later on September 21, as vocalist for The Colonial Club
    Orchestra. Around August 1927, another version was released by
    famed tenor Henry Burr.</p>
      <p>The first charting version of "Are You Lonesome Tonight?"
    was recorded by Blue Barron for MGM Records as catalog number
    10628. The record first reached the pop chart on April 7, 1950
    and lasted eight weeks there, peaking at number nineteen. Only
    a few weeks after Barron's recording, Al Jolson recorded a
    version of the song on April 28, 1950; it was released by Decca
    Records as catalog number 27043.</p>
      <p>In 1959 American songstress Jaye P. Morgan had a Billboard
    #65 hit with it on the MGM label, backed by "Miss You". Elvis
    Presley must have heard it while he was in the army in Europe,
    as he also heard and was inspired by other songs like "O Sole
    Mio" and "Return To Sorrento", which he made into hits on his
    return in 1960.</p>
      <p>This led to the best-known recording, by Elvis Presley,
    recorded on April 4, 1960, and engineered by Nashville sound
    pioneer Bill Porter. Colonel Parker (it was one of his wife's
    favorite songs) persuaded Elvis to record his own rendition of
    this song. Elvis' version was based on the Blue Barron
    Orchestra in 1950 and the spoken part of the song (like Al
    Jolson's) was loosely based on Shakespeare's using Jaques'
    speech on Act II Scene VII: "All the world's a stage, and all
    men and women merely players: they have their exits and their
    entrances; And one man in his time plays many parts." It went
    on to be one of the biggest-selling singles of 1960, peaking at
    number one on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>pop chart for six weeks and peaking at number
    three on the R&amp;B charts .</p>
      <p>Elvis, occasionally during live performances, would randomly
    change lyrics to give them humorous connotations. One popular
    instance was recorded at the International Hotel in Vegas on
    August 26, 1969. During the performance, instead of singing:
    "Do you gaze at your doorstep and picture me there", he sings
    "Do you gaze at your bald head and wish you had hair". Moments
    later, he saw a bald man in the audience (as legend has it),
    and burst into laughter which continued into the next lines.
    The audience was treated to additional laughter during the
    spoken verse singing: "You know someone said that the world's a
    stage, and each must play a part." Seeing the irony of his own
    lyrics, Elvis was again overtaken by laughter and barely
    recovered. The audience enjoyed the sincerity of the moment
    while Elvis regained his composure. Meanwhile the band and
    backup singers continued to keep the song going. It is
    speculated that much of Elvis' mirth derived from the solo
    backing singer whose falsetto remained resolute throughout. To
    this, Elvis comes back just in time for the line: "And I had no
    cause to doubt you" followed by more laughter. So overtaken,
    Elvis encourages the backup singer to "sing it, baby" drawing
    even more laughter which nearly brings the house down. In the
    end, the song is finished to a round of applause. The version
    is considered to be a popular underground classic, and was a UK
    Top 30 hit in 1982 after first being commercially released by
    RCA in the 1980 box set 
    <i>Elvis Aaron Presley</i>.</p>
      <p>According to Dr. Demento, who plays the version on his show,
    there is nothing on the label of the recording to indicate that
    it is anything other than an ordinary recording of the
    song--"People must have been surprised when they took it home
    and played it."</p>
      <p>Elvis said at the end, "That's it, man, fourteen years right
    down the drain...boy, I'll tell ya."</p>
      <p>In 1977, Presley again performed the song for the 
    <i>Elvis in Concert</i>TV special. Similarly to 1969, he also
    appears to mess up the spoken interlude, ad-libbing jokes
    throughout. Whether this was intentional or not is unknown; the
    1981 documentary film 
    <i>This is Elvis</i>uses footage of this performance to
    illustrate Presley's physical deterioration near the end of his
    life. Darrin Memmer's book "Elvis Presley - The 1977 CBS
    Television Special," published in 2001 by Morris Publishing,
    suggests it was intentional.</p>
      <p>The Lettermen recorded the song as a track on their 1964
    album 
    <i>She Cried</i>.</p>
      <p>Doris Day recorded the song on June 6, 1967, in a version
    included on 
    <i>The Love Album</i>.</p>
      <p>Mr. Saks &amp; The Blue Strings aka Tommy &amp; The Tom Toms
    recorded the song as an 
    <i>instrumental</i>single in 1960 for noted producer Major Bill
    Smith.</p>
      <p>Elvis's version was listed at #81 on 
    <i>Billboard's Greatest Songs of all time.</i>[1]</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
