<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suspicious_Minds 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suspicious_Minds</songId>
   <title>Suspicious Minds</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elvis_Presley</artistId>
      <artistName>Elvis Presley</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1969-11-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>August 26, 1969</released>
   <formats>
      <format>45 rpm record</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>January 1969</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:22 (3:28)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mark James</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Chips Moman and Felton Jarvis</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Suspicious Minds" is a song about being trapped in a
    mistrusting and dysfunctional relationship. Originally, and
    most notably, a hit for Elvis Presley in 1969, "Suspicious
    Minds" was widely regarded as the single that jump-started
    Presley's career after his successful 
    <i>'68 Comeback Special</i>. It was his eighteenth and last
    number-one single in the United States. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>later ranked it #91 on their list of the
    500 Greatest Songs of All Time.</p>
      <p>Written by Mark James aka Francis Zambon in 1968, who was
    also co-writer of "Always On My Mind", which Elvis would later
    record, the song first was recorded and released by James. Even
    though James' recording initially was not commercially
    successful, Elvis decided he could turn it into a hit on
    reviewing the song as presented to him by Memphis Soul producer
    Chips Moman, owner of American Sound Studio, in 1969.</p>
      <p>Presley recorded "Suspicious Minds" along with at least
    another two hit singles—"In the Ghetto" and "Kentucky Rain"—in
    the so-called "Memphis sessions" of February 1969 at American
    Sound Studio. He first performed the song at the Las Vegas
    Hilton on July 31, 1969, and the 45 rpm single was released in
    the fall. It reached number one in the United States in the
    week of November 1 and stayed there for that week. It would be
    Presley's final number-one single in the U.S. before his death
    ("The Wonder of You" in 1970, "Way Down" in 1977 and a
    posthumous remixed release of "A Little Less Conversation" in
    2002 all hit number one on the British charts, followed by
    re-issues of several previous chart toppers in 2005). Mark
    James' version of the song appears as the last song on the 1970
    record entitled 
    <i>Raindrops Keep Fallin' On My Head</i>by B. J. Thomas.</p>
      <p>Future Grateful Dead vocalist Donna Jean Godchaux sang
    backing vocals on the track.</p>
      <p>This song is part of the soundtrack for 2001's 
    <i>Black Hawk Down</i>. It also plays over the opening credits
    to the Coen Bros. film 
    <i>Intolerable Cruelty</i>.</p>
      <p>Notable in this song is a fadeout at about 3:52 into the
    song, which lasts for about 15 seconds before fading back in.
    This fadeout was intentional, as it helped convey a message of
    relationship in the song.</p>
      <p>It is also the sole Elvis Presley track that was released by
    Time-Life in the 1997 6-CD boxed set, "Gold And Platinum: The
    Ultimate Rock Collection".</p>
      <p>Dee Dee Warwick, Dionne's sister, covered "Suspicious Minds"
    while Elvis Presley's version was still on the charts.
    Warwick's version was a minor U.S. hit, peaking at #80 in
    1970.</p>
      <p>Waylon Jennings and Jessi Colter recorded the song for RCA
    in 1970. Their version reached No. 25 on the Billboard country
    chart in November of that year. The Jennings-Colter version was
    re-released by RCA in 1976, topping out at No. 2, and was
    included on the ground-breaking album 
    <i>Wanted! The Outlaws</i>that same year.</p>
      <p>Singer Ronnie McDowell sung the song for the 1979 film of
    the soundtrack 
    <i>ELVIS</i>.</p>
      <p>Candi Staton had a No. 31 UK hit with her revival in
    1982.</p>
      <p>In 1986, the band Fine Young Cannibals' cover version of the
    song, which featured backing vocals by Jimmy Somerville,
    reached #8 on the UK Singles chart. Six years later, country
    singer Dwight Yoakam recorded his own version of the song for
    the soundtrack to the movie 
    <i>Honeymoon in Vegas</i>, as well as a video. It was later
    released on his compilation album 
    <i>The Very Best of Dwight Yoakam</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2002, Gareth Gates released his remake as a single from
    his debut album 
    <i>What My Heart Wants to Say</i>. This version, charted as a
    double A-side with his duet with Will Young on "The Long and
    Winding Road," hit number one on the UK Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>In 2004, Pete Yorn released a live recording of the song on
    his 2 disc album 
    <i>Live From New Jersey</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2009, Rusted Root covered this on their studio album 
    <i>Stereo Rodeo</i>.</p>
      <p>In October 2009, mashup artist Marco van Bastard released a
    bootleg called "Suspicious Creep" using the Elvis Presley vocal
    and the instrumental version of Radiohead's "Creep".</p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Sitting Pretty"</span>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
