<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It%27s_Now_or_Never_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It%27s_Now_or_Never_(song)</songId>
   <title>It's Now or Never</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elvis_Presley</artistId>
      <artistName>Elvis Presley</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1960-08-15</week>
      <week>1960-08-22</week>
      <week>1960-08-29</week>
      <week>1960-09-05</week>
      <week>1960-09-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>July 5, 1960</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>April 3, 1960</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:15</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Wally Gold</writer>
      <writer>Aaron Schroeder</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"It's Now or Never" is a popular song recorded by Elvis
    Presley in 1960. The melody of the song is borrowed from the
    Italian standard, "'O Sole Mio", but the inspiration for it
    came from the song, "There's No Tomorrow", recorded by U.S.
    singer, Tony Martin, in 1949.</p>
      <p>In the late 1950s, while stationed in Germany with the U.S.
    Army, Presley heard Martin's recording and put to tape a
    private version of the song. Upon his discharge, Presley
    requested that new lyrics be written especially for him, a job
    that was undertaken by the songwriting duo of Aaron Schroeder
    and Wally Gold, with a demo by David Hill.</p>
      <p>In 1960, "It's Now or Never" was a number-one record in the
    U.S. and the UK, where it spent nine weeks at the top, and
    numerous other countries, selling in excess of 25 million
    copies worldwide, his biggest international single ever. Its UK
    release was delayed for some time because of rights issues,
    allowing the song to build up massive advance orders and to
    enter the UK Singles Chart at number one, a very rare
    occurrence at the time. "It's Now or Never" peaked at number
    seven on the R&amp;B charts .</p>
      <p>Barry White heard this song in 1960 when he was in jail for
    stealing tires. The song had such an impact on White, that it
    convinced him to pursue a career in music.</p>
      <p>A live version featuring "O Sole Mio" is available on the
    1977 live album 
    <i>Elvis in Concert</i>. "O Sole Mio" is sung by tenor Sherrill
    Nielson.</p>
      <p>In early 2005, the song was re-released along with the other
    Presley singles in the UK, and again reached number one on the
    UK Singles Chart. The song also appears in the TV mini-series 
    <i>Elvis</i>.</p>
      <p>American country music singer and actor John Schneider
    released a cover of the song as his first single and the title
    track of his debut album. Schneider's version was a Top 5 hit
    on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Country Singles chart and also peaked at
    #14 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
