<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lose_Yourself 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lose_Yourself</songId>
   <title>Lose Yourself</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eminem</artistId>
      <artistName>Eminem</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2003-01-04</week>
      <week>2003-01-11</week>
      <week>2003-01-18</week>
      <week>2003-01-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/d/d6/Lose_Yourself.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Eminem+Lose-Yourself.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Music from and Inspired by the Motion Picture 8 Mile</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 22, 2002</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hardcore Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:20</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Shady , Interscope , UMG Soundtracks</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Eminem</writer>
      <writer>L. Resto</writer>
      <writer>J. Bass</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Eminem</producer>
      <producer>Jeff Bass</producer>
      <producer>Luis Resto</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Lose Yourself" is a hip hop song by American rapper Eminem.
    It was released in 2002 as part of the soundtrack to the film 
    <i>8 Mile</i>, also starring Eminem, later released as a single
    in 2002, and re-released on Eminem's greatest hits compilation 
    <i>Curtain Call: The Hits</i>. The song was written and
    produced by Eminem and producer Louis Resto.</p>
      <p>Reaching #1 on a record 24 charts worldwide, "Lose Yourself"
    is the most successful rap song of all time. It spent a
    record-breaking 12 weeks atop the U.S. Billboard Hot 100, the
    longest-running #1 of 2002. It topped the UK and Eurocharts for
    over a month, ranking in the top 10 in several year-end sales
    charts. It won an Academy Award for Best Original Song, two
    Grammy Awards, and two other Grammy nominations, the most
    awards won by a single rap song in one year. The song is ranked
    4th in the 100 greatest songs of the past 25 years by VH1.
    "Lose Yourself" ranked #166 in 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's the 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time. It also ranked #93 on AFI's 100 Years...100 Songs. The
    song was named the fourth best song of the decade by the 
    <i>Complex Magazine</i>.</p>
      <p>In March 2009, "Lose Yourself" topped the 2 million mark in
    digital downloads in the United States, becoming the second
    oldest song to hit that sales level. It also became Eminem's
    first song to reach 2 million digital downloads as a lead
    artist. In the same year the single was named the 28th most
    successful song of the 2000s, on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade and the seventh
    most successful song of the decade in Australia.</p>
      <p>The song was written by Eminem during a break of the filming
    of 
    <i>8 Mile</i>. He recorded it in a portable studio on the set,
    recording all three verses in one take. The sheet on which he
    wrote the song appears in 
    <i>8 Mile</i>in a scene where his character is writing while
    riding the bus. This sheet was sold on eBay for $10,000.</p>
      <p>The song's lyrics explicitly sum up the background info
    about Eminem's character in 
    <i>8 Mile</i>, B. Rabbit, with the first verse summing up much
    of the plot of the movie.</p>
      <p>The song's general production style is similar in scope to
    the track "'Till I Collapse" from 
    <i>The Eminem Show</i>(released before 
    <i>8 Mile</i>). Both tracks begin with an interlude punctuated
    by a piano, followed by a gradual introduction of the beat,
    accompanied by a spoken introduction by Eminem. Both tracks
    also prominently feature a bass loop and some guitar
    elements.</p>
      <p>"Lose Yourself" is the most successful single of Eminem's
    mainstream career. It had a 12-week run at #1 in the United
    States &amp; Australia, and topped the charts in many other
    countries as well, including the United Kingdom, Ireland, New
    Zealand and Denmark among others. It debuted at number nine in
    Canada and moved up to #1 the following week. According to the
    Guinness Book Of World Records "Lose Yourself" became the
    "Longest Running Single at Number One for a Rap Song" thus
    making it the most successful rap song of all time.</p>
      <p>In the United States, "Lose Yourself" debuted on the
    Billboard Hot 100 singles chart the week of October 5, 2002, at
    #43. A week later, the single jumped to #18, and hit #1 by 
    <span class="mw-formatted-date" title="11-09">
November 9
</span>. The single spent 16 total weeks in the Top 10, and a total
of 23 weeks in the Top 50. While in the #1 spot (from 11/09/02
through 1/25/03), "Lose Yourself"'s impressive run kept several top
contenders for the #1 spot from ever reaching #1, including Jay-Z,
Nelly, Jennifer Lopez, Christina Aguilera, and especially Missy
Elliott, whose single "Work It" was at #2 for 10 weeks.</p>
      <p>The song went on to receive the Academy Award for Best
    Original Song (the first time a rap song ever won this award),
    upsetting the favored song "The Hands That Built America" by
    U2. It is rumored that Eminem, who was not present at the award
    ceremony believing he would not win for a rap song, was
    sleeping at the time the award was announced. This was the
    first time in 14 years the winner of the Best Original Song
    category was not performed at the ceremony. Luis Resto, one of
    the song's co-writers, had attended the ceremony and accepted
    the award instead. "He's creative, he has symphonies in his
    head," Resto said at the lectern about Eminem. [1] The American
    Film Institute later ranked it #93 on their list of the 100
    Greatest Songs from American Films.</p>
      <p>At the Grammy Awards of 2004, "Lose Yourself" became
    Eminem's second career nomination for Record of the Year
    (following "Without Me"), and the first rap song ever to be
    nominated for Song of the Year. It won Best Male Rap Solo
    Performance and Best Rap Song, which was a brand new category
    at the time.</p>
      <p>At #166, "Lose Yourself" is the highest ranked of the three
    songs from the 21st century featured in the 2004 List of
    Rolling Stone's 500 Greatest Songs of All Time (joining "Stan"
    at #290). Outkast's "Hey Ya!" was the other, at #180. The
    magazine later ranked the song the twelfth best of the decade
    [2]. The song was the 51st best-selling single of the 2000
    decade in UK.</p>
      <p>"Lose Yourself" was later released on Eminem's compilation
    album, 
    <i>Curtain Call: The Hits</i>, in 2005.</p>
      <p>The song was also covered by The Script for their debut
    self-titled album, released in 2008.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Lose Yourself" was filmed in Detroit,
    Michigan, and thus contains numerous shots of the city,
    including the Ambassador Bridge. The video is a mixture of
    multiple scenarios, including scenes from and reminiscent of
    the movie 
    <i>8 Mile</i>, and Eminem rapping next to the "8 Mile Rd.
    Mobile Court" sign that appears on the cover of the movie's
    soundtrack.</p>
      <p>It contains scenes focusing on Rabbit's and the real life
    Eminem's character, for example, the difficulties he has to
    face while rapping, the insult and booing of crowds as he is a
    white rapper and the trouble he has to face due to his
    alcoholic mother and people he hangs out with.</p>
      <p>He won a Much Music Video Awards in 2003 for Favourite
    International Artist with the video for "Lose Yourself".</p>
      <p>At the 2003 MTV Video Music Awards it received the award for
    Best Video from a Film in the final year this award was given
    out. It also received nominations for Video of the Year, Best
    Male Video, Best Rap Video, and Viewer's Choice.</p>
      <p>The video has been viewed over 46,414,517 times on Youtube
    making it Eminem's most popular video on that site.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
