<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crack_a_Bottle 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crack_a_Bottle</songId>
   <title>Crack a Bottle</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eminem</artistId>
      <artistName>Eminem, Dr. Dre and 50 Cent</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2009-02-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e0/Eminem_-_Crack_a_Bottle.jpg/200px-Eminem_-_Crack_a_Bottle.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Eminem-Dr-Dre-and-50-Cent+Crack-a-Bottle.jpg</albumImageUri>
   </album>
   <released>May 18, 2009</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Promo CD</format>
      <format>Digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2008</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:57 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>5:16 (Single Version)</length>
      <length>4:36 (Radio Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Aftermath , Interscope , Shady</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>M. Mathers</writer>
      <writer>C. Jackson</writer>
      <writer>A. Young</writer>
      <writer>D. Parker</writer>
      <writer>M. Batson</writer>
      <writer>T. Lawrence</writer>
      <writer>J. Renard</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Dr. Dre</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Crack a Bottle" is a hip hop song by Eminem, Dr. Dre and 50
    Cent for Eminem's album 
    <i>Relapse</i>. On February 12, 2009, the song broke the first
    week digital sales record with 418,000 downloads, topping the
    previous record held by "Live Your Life" by T.I. featuring
    Rihanna. This record was broken again the following week by
    "Right Round" by Flo Rida.The song won the Grammy award for
    Grammy Award for Best Rap Performance by a Duo or Group at the
    52nd Grammy Awards.</p>
      <p>"Crack a Bottle" initially gained attention in December
    2008, when an unfinished version of the song was initially
    leaked under the name "Number One" on the mixtape 
    <i>4th Quarter Pressure Part 2</i>, while a final working
    version was leaked on January 6, 2009. Various media outlets
    had reported that the recording was to be the first single from
    Eminem's 2009 album 
    <i>Relapse</i>, however the Italian branch of Universal Music
    Group, owner of Interscope Records, later denied this, stating
    that "Crack a Bottle" was only a promotional recording. Despite
    all this, the song was released on February 2, 2009, and made
    available for paid digital download, with 50 Cent stating that
    the song will be included on his upcoming album 
    <i>Before I Self Destruct</i>. According to Danielle Harling of
    
    <i>HipHopDX</i>—a website dedicated to hip hop music
    coverage—the song will ultimately be present on both 
    <i>Relapse</i>and 
    <i>Before I Self Destruct</i>, while in contrast, Daniel Kreps
    of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>stated that it is still unsure which rapper
    will feature this song on his upcoming album. Despite the
    confusion, Universal eventually announced that "Crack a Bottle"
    will be included in 
    <i>Relapse</i>, although it does not consider it the album's
    first single.</p>
      <p>The song samples "Mais dans la lumière" by Mike Brant,
    written by Jean Lunard, who also received songwriting credits
    for the song.</p>
      <p>The song is in the key of C-sharp minor.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Billboard</i>gave a positive review of the song: "Although
    not quite as strong as the title track to Eminem's 2004 album 
    <i>Encore</i>, the return of Eminem, Dr. Dre and 50 Cent has
    been anticipated for a long time, and it is sure to put Eminem
    back atop the marquee. His skills remain some of the best in
    hip-hop, and the accompanying contributions make the music that
    little bit more stronger." 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>commented negatively on the song, saying
    that it is one of the weakest tracks on the album, along the
    other single "We Made You". . The song won at the 52nd Grammy
    Awards in the Grammy Award for Best Rap Performance by a Duo or
    Group category.</p>
      <p>During an interview for MTV, 50 Cent originally told that
    there were plans to make an animated music video for "Crack a
    Bottle", which was to be shot along with a music video for his
    song "I Get It In". On February 25, Eminem's manager Paul
    Rosenberg posted on his blog a still frame from the music video
    illustrating a homeless person holding a bottle wrapped in a
    brown bag. According to Rosenberg, it is directed by Syndrome
    and was planned to be released within a couple of weeks. The
    music video was playing on TV in Eminem's music video "3 a.m.",
    which has been directed by Syndrome too.</p>
      <p>On May 7, 2009, an unfinished version of the video was
    released via TheRelapse.com, featuring Eminem's verse and
    chorus. Later during the same day, 50 Cent's rapped verse of
    the video was released via ThisIs50.com as well. This was added
    to the unfinished video on therelapse.com.</p>
      <p>A month later, on June 7, 2009, Cashis posted a link on
    Twitter to the full video in which he makes a cameo appearance.
    The music video portrays each rappers' style. Eminem's -
    chaotic, Dr. Dre - west coast style, 50 Cent's - more club
    oriented. None of the performers are featured in the video.</p>
      <p>Since its release, "Crack a Bottle" has mainly charted in
    the United States, entering in various charts including the Hot
    100 and the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs. The song peaked in top
    ten on the Hot Rap Tracks, at the number four. After spending
    three consecutive weeks at number seventy-eight on the Hot 100,
    on 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s edition of February 21, 2009, "Crack a
    Bottle" reached the number one position on the Hot 100 through
    sales of 418,000 downloads, thus causing the fourth-biggest
    jump to the top of the Hot 100 in the chart's history. To date,
    "Crack a Bottle" is Eminem's second number one song in the U.S.
    and the first since 2002. With this song, Dr. Dre reached the
    top of the Hot 100 for a third time, while this is 50 Cent's
    fourth. The song has also entered in various European national
    charts, including the Irish Singles Chart and UK Singles Chart,
    and also debuted at number one on the Canadian Hot 100.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
