<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bailamos 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bailamos</songId>
   <title>Bailamos</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enrique_Iglesias</artistId>
      <artistName>Enrique Iglesias</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1999-09-04</week>
      <week>1999-09-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/bd/Bailamos_1.jpg/200px-Bailamos_1.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Enrique-Iglesias+Bailamos.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Wild Wild West soundtrack and Enrique</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 17, 1999</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1998—Spring 1999</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Latin Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:38</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Fonovisa , Interscope Records , Overbrook , Universal</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Paul Barry &amp; Mark Taylor</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mark Taylor &amp; Brian Rawling</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Bailamos" is a Latin pop song from singer Enrique Iglesias,
    sung in English and Spanish. It was the debut single of
    Iglesias in the English-language market, and attained immense
    success, reaching the #1 spot in the Billboard Hot 100.</p>
      <p>The track first appeared on a limited edition of his Spanish
    studio album 
    <i>Cosas del Amor</i>and was released as a single in parts of
    Latin America and Europe.</p>
      <p>After attending one of Enrique's concerts, Will Smith asked
    Enrique to contribute to the soundtrack of his upcoming movie 
    <i>Wild Wild West</i>and Bailamos was chosen to appear.</p>
      <p>The song quickly became most requested on pop radio in New
    York, Los Angeles and Miami. Due to the song's popularity it
    was released as a single throughout the world.</p>
      <p>In English, Bailamos means "
    <i>We Dance</i>" (
    <i>We Are Dancing</i>), or in this case, "
    <i>Let's Dance</i>". The Song was dedicated to two students:
    Brandon Kimball and Marisa Bisaccia. The students rescued
    Enrique during The Running of the Bulls several years ago.</p>
      <p>In the United States, the song was seen as part of a wave of
    crossover music from Latin American singers and a general
    increase in interest in Latin music, which was started by Ricky
    Martin's release Livin' La Vida Loca. The single reached number
    one on the US pop charts, making it Iglesias' first chart
    topper on Billboard's Hot 100. The Latin song 
    <i>Smooth</i>by Carlos Santana released at the end of the year
    was one of the most successful song in chart history, and its
    immense success could, to some extent, be credited to Bailamos'
    and other Latin pop songs during the era.</p>
      <p>The success of "Bailamos" was a breakthrough for Iglesias,
    which enabled him to sign a multi-album deal with Interscope.
    The song would go on to appear on his debut English album 
    <i>Enrique</i>, though slightly altered to fit with the sound
    of the album.</p>
      <p>"Bailamos" was written and by Paul Barry and Mark Taylor and
    produced by Barry and Brian Rawling, the same team which wrote
    and produced Cher's hit 
    <i>Believe</i>.</p>
      <p>The original music video for Bailamos was shot in Miami. It
    has a montage of different scenes involving Iglesias, starting
    off with a scene of Iglesias in an apartment talking on the
    phone and later looking out of a window to the Miami skyline.
    Subsequent scenes involve Iglesias walking the streets and
    staring into a building as he watches two flamenco dancers.</p>
      <p>After the song was chosen to be part of the 
    <i>Wild Wild West</i>soundtrack, a second video was made,
    directed by Nigel Dick. A portion of this video was shot in
    Mexico, while most of it shot in the backlot at Universal
    Studios. In this video, Iglesias is depicted as a wanted man
    with the opening shot being a poster calling for his capture
    "dead or alive". Entering a sleepy Mexican town. He attracts
    several women who dance around him. Picking one out, they kiss
    until they are interrupted by people trying to claim the
    reward. Both Iglesias and the love interest manage to escape.
    The video also contains small snippets of scenes from 
    <i>Wild Wild West</i>movie.</p>
      <p>The third music video of Bailamos is directed by another
    famous music video director, Paul Hunter. The video is
    plotless, and simply features Iglesias as a barman in a night
    club as he watches flamenco dancers on stage. It is also
    intercut with shots of Iglesias interacting with the lead
    dancer played by Staci Flood. The video ends with Iglesias and
    Flood leaving the now empty club.</p>
      <p>There were also several remix videos of Bailamos, such as 
    <i>Fernando's Latin Mix</i>and 
    <i>Mijango's Club Mix</i>.</p>
      <p>The track peaked at number 1 for two weeks in the Billboard
    Hot 100 chart in the United States, also became the 11th number
    1 single for Iglesias in the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Latin Tracks chart for 1 week. It did hit
    the top spot also in Spain and Latvia. The single also peaked
    inside the Top Ten in UK, Netherlands, France and Germany.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
