<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Be_with_You_(Enrique_Iglesias_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Be_with_You_(Enrique_Iglesias_song)</songId>
   <title>Be with You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enrique_Iglesias</artistId>
      <artistName>Enrique Iglesias</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2000-06-24</week>
      <week>2000-07-01</week>
      <week>2000-07-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f7/Be_With_You2.jpg/200px-Be_With_You2.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Enrique-Iglesias+Be-with-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Enrique</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 6, 2000</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>maxi single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Fall 1999; , Hyde Park, London, UK</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>House</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:40</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Interscope</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Enrique Iglesias</writer>
      <writer>Paul Barry</writer>
      <writer>Mark Taylor</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mark Taylor</producer>
      <producer>Brian Rawling</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Be with You" is a dance/pop song performed by singer
    Enrique Iglesias. It was co-written by Iglesias and, produced
    by Mark Taylor and Brian Rawling, the team responsible for
    Cher's hit song "Believe". Iglesias once stated that he
    initially came up with the lyrics of the song while taking a
    break from recording in London's Hyde Park. The song was
    released as the second single from Iglesias' debut English
    album 
    <i>Enrique</i>in 2000. The song was successful, particularly in
    the U.S.</p>
      <p>The official music video for this single was directed by
    Dave Meyers and starts out with Enrique and a bunch of friends
    (played by Enrique's real life friends including Gerardo Mejia)
    stopping at a road side store. While messing around in the
    store Enrique makes eye contact with the shy girl working the
    counter, his love interest in the video (played by Shannon
    Elizabeth). When the group leave the store, Enrique drives
    their jeep while the others perform various stunts including
    car surfing and interacting with girls in another jeep riding
    beside them.</p>
      <p>The group stops at a foot of a some hills where Enrique
    notices Shannon, now wearing more provocative clothes and with
    a lot more confidence; he and the group follow her to a
    Nightclub (the now closed Point Night Club in Los Angeles)
    where Enrique searches the packed dance floor for his love
    interest when the music stops and changes to that of the
    popular Thunderpuss 2000 remix which builds up with shots of
    break dancers until the music turns back to the album version
    of the song. Enrique manage to find Shannon who gropes him and
    leads him out of the club. Outside, the two kiss as Fireworks
    go off. The entire video is intercut with shots of Enrique
    singing in front of a tribal background.</p>
      <p>The video debuted on MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>in February 2000. It was Enrique's
    first video to make it to number one on the popular chart show.
    Some airing of the video on MTV cut out the section of the
    video featuring the Thunderpuss 2000 remix. Music stations such
    as Much Music and various stations throughout Europe aired a
    version which featured the full album version of the song.</p>
      <p>The Spanish version of the video is exactly the same as the
    English version, with the exception of Enrique mouthing the
    words in Spanish in front of the tribal background and when he
    interacts with Shannon.</p>
      <p>"Be with You" became Iglesias' second number-one single in
    the U.S.. It also topped the 
    <i>Billboard</i>dance charts and also charted in the top ten in
    Spain. The Spanish version of the song ("Sólo Me Importas Tú")
    reached peaked at number two on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Latin Tracks.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
