<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sweet_Dreams_(Are_Made_of_This)_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sweet_Dreams_(Are_Made_of_This)_(song)</songId>
   <title>Sweet Dreams (Are Made of This)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eurythmics</artistId>
      <artistName>Eurythmics</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1983-09-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/00/Eurythmics_SDAMOT.jpg/200px-Eurythmics_SDAMOT.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Eurythmics+Sweet-Dreams-Are-Made-of-This.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Sweet Dreams (Are Made of This)</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 1983</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1982</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
      <genre>Synthpop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:35 (7" Single)</length>
      <length>4:48 (12" Single)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>David A. Stewart</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Sweet Dreams (Are Made of This)" (or simply "Sweet Dreams")
    is a song by pop music duo Eurythmics (David A. Stewart and
    Annie Lennox). It was released as a single and was the title
    track of their album 
    <i>Sweet Dreams (Are Made of This)</i>. It is notable as the
    song which provided the group with their breakthrough into
    commercial success. Its striking music video helped to propel
    the song to number two on the UK singles chart, and number one
    on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 in 1983. It was the fourth single
    released from the 
    <i>Sweet Dreams</i>album in the UK and the first single
    released by Eurythmics in the United States.</p>
      <p>"Sweet Dreams (Are Made of This)" is arguably Eurythmics'
    signature song and it is their only chart-topper in the U.S.
    Following its success, their previous single, "Love Is a
    Stranger", was re-released and also became a worldwide hit. On 
    <i>Rolling Stone's</i>The 500 Greatest Songs of All Time issue
    in 2003, "Sweet Dreams (Are Made of This)" was ranked number
    356: it was the group's only song on the list. The song is
    about sadomasochistic sex. Eurythmics have regularly performed
    the song live in all their live sets since 1982. This track is
    regularly performed on solo Lennox performances also.</p>
      <p>In 1991, the song was remixed and reissued to promote
    Eurythmics' 
    <i>Greatest Hits</i>package. It re-charted in the UK, reaching
    number 48. It was also a moderate hit in dance clubs. Another
    remix by Steve Angello was released in France in 2006, along
    with the track "I've Got a Life" (peaking at number ten).</p>
      <p>The original recording's main instrumentation featured a
    sequenced analog synthesizer riff, which Stewart discovered
    accidentally in the studio when he played a bass track in
    reverse. Apart from the synthesizer, the arrangement also uses
    Movement Systems Drum Computer, piano in the middle eight, and
    Lennox's multitracked harmony vocals.</p>
      <p>* This version is different from the one found on the album 
    <i>Sweet Dreams (Are Made of This)</i>.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Sweet Dreams" was directed by Chris
    Ashbrook and filmed on January 11, 1983 shortly before the song
    and the album was released. The video received heavy airplay on
    the then-young MTV channel and is widely considered a classic
    clip from the early-MTV era. Lennox's striking androgynous
    visual image, with close-cropped, orange-colored hair, men's
    suit and cane and detached yet soulful vocal delivery
    immediately made her a household name. Her gender-bending image
    would be further explored in other Eurythmics videos such as
    "Who's That Girl?" and "Love Is a Stranger".</p>
      <p>Marilyn Manson released a cover version of "Sweet Dreams
    (Are Made of This)" as the first single from the remix album, 
    <i>Smells Like Children</i>. This version became an MTV staple
    and helped to establish the band in the mainstream. It also
    appears on the band's greatest hits album, 
    <i>Lest We Forget: The Best Of</i>. This version is featured on
    the soundtracks to the 1999 film 
    <i>House on Haunted Hill</i>and the 2009 film 
    <i>Gamer</i>. It is also featured in the film 
    <i>Trick 'r Treat</i>. In Manson's autobiography, 
    <i>The Long Hard Road out of Hell</i>, he states that Nothing
    did not want to release this as a single. They wanted to
    release their cover of Screamin' Jay Hawkins' "I Put a Spell on
    You", which, according to Manson, "was far too dark, sprawling
    and esoteric, even for some of our fans."</p>
      <p>Marilyn Manson added some extra lines to the lyrics that are
    not present in the Eurythmics version: "I wanna use you and
    abuse you/I wanna know what's inside you." and "I'm gonna use
    you and abuse you/I'm gonna know what's inside you."</p>
      <p>The video for Manson's cover contains several clips of
    Manson and bandmates in what appears to be an old cathedral. In
    between the clips are a number are surreal shots of Manson
    wearing eccentric outfits, Manson wandering around an abandoned
    street in a tutu, and him riding a pig wearing a cowboy hat and
    covered with grease.</p>
      <p>The original version of the song was used in Everybody Hates
    Chris</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
