<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Believe_(Fantasia_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Believe_(Fantasia_song)</songId>
   <title>I Believe</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fantasia_Barrino</artistId>
      <artistName>Fantasia</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2004-07-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/07/B0002BSFQI.01._AA240_SCLZZZZZZZ_.jpg/200px-B0002BSFQI.01._AA240_SCLZZZZZZZ_.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Fantasia+I-Believe.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Free Yourself and Dreams/Don't Cry Out Loud/I Believe</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 29, 2004  (2004-06-29)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>DVD single</format>
      <format>Digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Gospel</genre>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:02 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>4:07 (Radio Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>J Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Louis Biancaniello</writer>
      <writer>Tamyra Gray</writer>
      <writer>Sam Watters</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Clive Davis</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Believe" is the debut single released by singer and 
    <i>American Idol</i>season 3 winner, Fantasia Barrino, as well
    as the 
    <i>American Idol</i>season 3 runner-up, Diana DeGarmo. The song
    significantly helped Fantasia rise to fame. The song was
    co-written by former 
    <i>American Idol</i>contestant Tamyra Gray.</p>
      <p>Fantasia sang "I Believe" on the finale of American Idol
    (season 3) as her last performance within the competition.
    Diana sang the song first, also on the finale, for her first
    performance of the night. Fantasia's final performance that
    evening is regarded by some fans and critics as one of the most
    outstanding performances in the show's history. Only her two
    performances of Summertime (which are considered by some to be
    among the best performances in the show's history) received
    more praise. Fantasia received outstanding praise and was
    declared the winner of American Idol by all three judges. The
    judges predictions came true and Fantasia was crowned American
    Idol the following evening. An ecstatic and tearful Fantasia
    performed her new single "I Believe" minutes after the
    announcement. Diana's performance was also well-received by the
    judges.</p>
      <p>The song was an instant success for Fantasia when it was
    released on June 22, 2004. It performed well on the radio and
    sales charts of the United States and Canada debuting at number
    one in both nations. This made Fantasia the first artist in the
    history of the Hot 100 to debut at number one with a first
    record. "I Believe" is also the winner of three Awards. 
    <i>I Believe</i>is noted for its inspirational lyrics.</p>
      <p>The runner up of American Idol Season 3, Diana Degarmo, also
    sang this song during the final 2 showdown and in addition sang
    it during the finale as an encore performance. Although she did
    not win the competition, she did release the song on her single
    but did not release it on her debut album.</p>
      <p>American Idol contestants, Lakisha Jones (season 6) and
    Syesha Mercado (season 7) sang this song during the
    inspirational song week.</p>
      <p>When the song was released it debuted on the Hot 100 at
    number one. The CD was a substantial success in the U.S. and in
    Canada. In its debut week the single shattered the first week
    sales record for any single in 2004 in the U.S. "I Believe" was
    certified double platinum by the CRIA in Canada selling more
    than 80,000 units. It has sold 527,000 copies in the United
    States , making it one of the most successful single of 2004.
    "I Believe" was number one on the U.S single sales chart for
    eleven consecutive weeks and ten weeks in Canada, giving it the
    longest stay at number one on the chart by any 
    <i>Idol</i>contestant. "I Believe" also spent six consecutive
    weeks at number one on the U.S. R&amp;B Single Sales chart. "I
    Believe" hit number one on more music charts than any other
    Idol contestant's debut single so far.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
