<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/London_Bridge_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/London_Bridge_(song)</songId>
   <title>London Bridge</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fergie_(singer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Fergie</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2006-08-19</week>
      <week>2006-08-26</week>
      <week>2006-09-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/8c/LondonBridge_single.jpg/200px-LondonBridge_single.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Fergie+London-Bridge.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Dutchess</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 18, 2006 (U.S.) , September 11, 2006 (UK)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2006</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:01 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>3:27 (Clean Radio Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>A&amp;M</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Stacy Ferguson</writer>
      <writer>Sean Garrett</writer>
      <writer>Mike Hartnett</writer>
      <writer>Jamal Jones</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Polow da Don</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"London Bridge" is a song co-written and performed by pop
    singer Fergie for her debut album, 
    <i>The Dutchess</i>. It contains a sample taken from "Down To
    The Night Club" by Tower Of Power. It was released as the lead
    single from the album on July 18, 2006, and was Fergie's first
    single as a solo artist. As of April 2009, "London Bridge" has
    sold over 2,000,000 copies in the United States.</p>
      <p>The song was produced by Polow da Don, with lyrics by Sean
    Garrett and Fergie. Fergie describes the song as being "kind of
    like a punch in the face to let people know I'm coming out...
    I've been getting way too into myself nowadays and I just wanna
    have fun with as many men as I can possible." The song is a
    club track that lightly touches on personal lyrics about fame
    and celebrity. This song also begins with tornado or air raid
    sirens blaring after "Oh Shit!" or "Oh Snap!"</p>
      <p>Fergie collaborated with her fellow member of the Black Eyed
    Peas, will.i.am, on the clip's concept to make it more
    distinctive. She describes the concept as follows: "We're doing
    this androgynous-type thing where my girls and I go into a
    Gentlemen's club and pull them into a bathroom and come back
    out in their clothes. They're going to be dressed up really
    dapper and looking really handsome. (sic) " Will.i.am, Taboo,
    and Apl.de.ap all made cameos in the video.</p>
      <p>For the video, which was filmed at the Woolwich Barracks in
    Woolwich, South London, she brought in backup dancers who
    double as bodyguards, dressed like cholas — tough Mexican girls
    known for wearing dark lipstick and big hair — to make the clip
    "have a bit more edge, be very distinct, be very mixed."</p>
      <p>Fergie is seen intermittently sailing down the River Thames
    just in front of Tower Bridge, which isn't the same as London
    Bridge, despite the song title.</p>
      <p>Fergie based one of her outfits for the video on her
    family's crest and tartan, with some changes as she wanted it
    to be modernized. She also wears a tiara cocked to the side of
    her head to play off the royal name of her album, as well as
    having the same surname (Ferguson) and nickname, as the Duchess
    of York (Sarah Ferguson).</p>
      <p>As of November 7, 2009 the music video for "London Bridge"
    has been viewed 2,217,623 times on the popular video-sharing
    website YouTube.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Rolling Stone</i>called the song a "total ripoff of
    Hollaback Girl", Gwen Stefani's number one single of 2005.
    Another reviewer described the song as being "Hollaback Girl"
    "slathered in puerile sexual raunch".</p>
      <p>There is a remix featuring 50 Cent called "London
    London".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
