<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glamorous_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glamorous_(song)</songId>
   <title>Glamorous</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fergie_(singer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Fergie featuring Ludacris</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2007-03-24</week>
      <week>2007-03-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/50/Fergie-Glamorous-single-cover.jpg/200px-Fergie-Glamorous-single-cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Fergie-featuring-Ludacris+Glamorous.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Dutchess</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 1, 2007</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2006</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:06 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>3:19 (Uk Radio Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>A&amp;M</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Stacy Ferguson</writer>
      <writer>Jamal Jones</writer>
      <writer>Will Adams</writer>
      <writer>Elvis Williams</writer>
      <writer>Christopher Bridges</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Polow da Don</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Glamorous" is the third single taken from pop singer
    Fergie's solo debut album, 
    <i>The Dutchess</i>. In March 2007, the song became Fergie's
    second number-one single in the United States. The single was
    released on March 19, 2007 in the UK and was the second single
    taken from the album. The single was not as successful in Latin
    America (where it wasn't officially released) as "London
    Bridge" and "Fergalicious". "Glamorous" is the fourth single
    from the album in Brazil, where "Big Girls Don't Cry" was
    released as the third single. Fergie sang this song along with
    "Big Girls Don't Cry" at the Concert for Diana. As of March
    2008, the single has sold 2,300,000 copies. The song was used
    in the promotional video for the CW television show 
    <i>Gossip Girl</i>. The song appears on the video game 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Presents: American Idol Encore</i>.</p>
      <p>The video had a World Premiere on MTV's 
    <i>TRL</i>on February 7, 2007. The video is directed by Dave
    Meyers, and was shot in an anamorphic 1.85:1 widescreen aspect
    ratio. It starts in 1994 with Fergie and Polow da Don at a keg
    party in East Los Angeles before she was famous. The camera
    then rotates upward where it is present day and Fergie is
    lounging in a Bombardier Global Express business jet, and as
    the chorus suggests, "flying first class, up in the sky". The
    flight attendant is played by Freddy Rodriguez. She is seen
    watching the music video on her LG enV for the Black Eyed Peas
    "Pump It". Fergie then lands and enters a limo waiting for her
    where she goes with her friends to a drive thru at a fast food
    restaurant. This restaurant is most likely Taco Bell as the
    lyrics suggest, though the food package appears to bear Jack in
    the Box logos. The video at this point does a transition to the
    past (1990's) where it is suggested Fergie came to this same
    restaurant with her friends before her glamorous life. The
    transition occurs as Fergie sings of the days when she had a
    Mustang. The limo transforms into a Mustang convertible. She
    and her friends are wearing clothes and have hairstyles similar
    to those of 1990s pop culture.</p>
      <p>The video then goes back to present day where Fergie and
    Ludacris are shown shooting a movie called 
    <i>Glamorous</i>, a throwback to 
    <i>Bonnie and Clyde</i>. The two are shown holding Thompson
    submachine guns while being held up by police near a canyon,
    apparently for stealing money. Ludacris raps his verse to
    Fergie telling her all the expensive things he will buy for
    her. Fergie and Ludacris are then shown shooting down the cops,
    after which the movie shoot ends.</p>
      <p>After the shoot Fergie proceeds to sit in a chair with her
    name on it, as people rush over to do her make up. While this
    is happening she thanks her fans for making her famous. Scenes
    of this are intercut with Fergie getting back on the plane she
    came on, while she flashes back to when she was a little girl,
    where her father warned her about the coldness of the showbiz
    industry. Fergie is then shown at the same kegger from earlier
    in the video, with Alfonso Ribeiro, Polow da Don, apl.de.ap and
    Cypress Hill with B-Real with whom she clinks plastic glasses,
    followed with the plane she is on in the present day flying
    into London as the sun sets.</p>
      <p>"Glamorous" debuted on the U.S. Hot 100 at number 98 in
    mid-January 2007, two weeks before its official release to
    radio stations. The song reached its initial peak at number
    nine, giving Fergie her third top 10 solo hit in six months,
    equal to her group the Black Eyed Peas' tally over the past six
    years. In the next week, the single plummeted from nine to
    thirty-three, one of the biggest drops in a single week out of
    the top 10, due to A&amp;M Records blocking the digital
    download of the single. "Glamorous" was released back in the
    iTunes Store and other digital outlets on the week of February
    28. Upon re-release of "Glamorous" as a digital single
    download, it re-entered the top 10 at the number eight position
    on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100, rising from number 55, in the charting
    week of March 17, 2007. On the March 24, 2007 edition of the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100, "Glamorous" hit number-one, giving
    Fergie her second #1 single; it remained at number one for a
    second consecutive week, but then fell to number two in the
    next week. "Glamorous" ended as the year's 10th highest seller
    there, ranked at #10 on the Billboard Year-End chart for 2007.
    "Glamorous" debuted at #10 on the Australian ARIA singles
    chart, and was the week's second highest debut behind Christina
    Aguilera's "Candyman" and Taylor Swift's "Today Was a
    Fairytale" which debuted at #6. "Glamorous" made its initial
    peak at #3 before rising to its peak at #2. "Glamorous" has
    been certified Platinum by ARIA for sales of over 70,000.
    "Glamorous" was also ranked at #13 on the Australian ARIA
    Year-End singles chart for 2007, and is one of four entries on
    this chart for Fergie, with the others being "Fergalicious",
    "Clumsy" and "Big Girls Don't Cry". The song debuted at #56 in
    the UK Singles Chart and peaked at #6, making it her second
    solo Top 10 hit. In Latin America, the song thus far has
    dubious honor of being the only single to not chart in the
    Latin America Top 40; "Big Girls Don't Cry" has already
    charted.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
