<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Girls_Don%27t_Cry_(Fergie_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Girls_Don%27t_Cry_(Fergie_song)</songId>
   <title>Big Girls Don't Cry</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>Fergie</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2007-09-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/8a/Fergie-Big_Girls_Don%27t_Cry.jpg/200px-Fergie-Big_Girls_Don%27t_Cry.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Fergie+Big-Girls-Don-t-Cry.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Dutchess</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 15, 2007 (North America) , July, 2007 (worldwide) , July 9, 2007 (United Kingdom)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2006</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:28 (Album version)</length>
      <length>4:14 (Radio edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>A&amp;M</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Stacy Ferguson</writer>
      <writer>Toby Gad</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Toby Gad</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Big Girls Don't Cry" is a song written by Fergie and Toby
    Gad for pop singer Fergie's debut solo album 
    <i>The Dutchess</i>(2006). The song was released as the album's
    fourth single in 2007 (see 2007 in music) and topped the charts
    in several countries, most notably in Australia (for nine
    consecutive weeks—also becoming the number-one single in the
    ARIA's Year End Charts for 2007), and in the United States. It
    was the most downloaded track in the U.S., with sales of more
    than 3,080,000 copies sold. In July 2007, Fergie performed the
    song at the Concert for Diana and Live Earth. By the end of
    August 2007, the song became Fergie's third number one single
    on the Billboard Hot 100 chart. It was nominated in the 'Best
    Female Pop Vocal Performance' category at the 50th Annual
    Grammy Awards, which was held February 10, 2008. The song
    appears in 
    <i>Dance Dance Revolution X</i>, 
    <i>Singstar Pop Vol 2</i>, and 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Presents American Idol Encore 2</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was listed at #89 on Billboard: All-Time Hot 100
    Top Songs and the 13th most successful song of the decade at
    the end of 2009 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade.</p>
      <p>After "Big Girls Don't Cry" was written, Fergie and her
    management felt that the song did not fit the theme of her
    album and decided not to record it. However, her management
    felt that the song was too strong to let go, so they decided to
    shop the song around to different record labels. Eventually,
    the song was sold to Bad Boy Records, where it was handed to
    Jordan McCoy. McCoy's team felt they had a huge hit on their
    hands and quickly recorded the song, assuring Fergie and her
    management that they were going to release it as a single.</p>
      <p>However, according to McCoy, after Fergie heard their
    finished version, she had a change of heart and recorded the
    song as well. Without the knowledge of Bad Boy Records, Fergie
    went ahead and tagged it on to her album at the last minute.
    Jordan and her team were upset by Fergie's decision, scrapped
    the entire project and considered suing Fergie. However,
    because Fergie co-wrote the song, she had partial ownership and
    they could not sue her.</p>
      <p>"Big Girls Don't Cry" is a moderate pop song written in the
    key of G major. The tempo is composed in common time and
    follows the major chord G/B-Csus2-D5. The song was compared to
    as an exact 2006 version of 
    <i>Wild Orchid</i>.</p>
      <p>The song has achieved high success worldwide, topping the
    charts in over ten countries, including Australia, Brazil,
    Canada, Ireland, New Zealand, Mexico, Austria, Romania, Croatia
    and the U.S. In Brazil the song was the most pleyed on the
    radio in 2007. In the UK it surpassed "London Bridge" as her
    highest charting solo single thus far, peaking at number two
    (behind only Rihanna's 10 week chart topping "Umbrella"); the
    single has spent 23 weeks on the UK Singles Chart Top 40 and 9
    weeks in the Top 10.</p>
      <p>After spending several weeks in the number two and three
    positions on the U.S. Hot 100, "Big Girls Don't Cry" finally
    ascended to number one, becoming Fergie's third Hot 100
    number-one single, and second consecutive after "Glamorous" in
    early 2007. Thanks to this achievement Fergie has become only
    the second American female solo artist in the '00s to have
    three chart-toppers from one album after Christina Aguilera in
    1999-2000. In addition to the Hot 100, the song topped the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Pop 100, Pop 100 Airplay, Hot 100 Airplay, and
    Hot Digital Songs charts. It also became her first number one
    on both the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks chart and the
    Adult Top 40, where on the later she became the first female
    artist to top that chart after 52 weeks of number ones by male
    artists. The song is one of the most successful singles of 2007
    in the U.S., as it stayed in the top ten of The Hot 100 for 21
    consecutive weeks, 18 of those in the top five.</p>
      <p>It is most played song of 2007 on U.S. Mainstream Top 40
    radio (becoming the number-one single of 2007 on the and the
    third most successful track of 2000s on the same tally), and
    the most successful song of 2007 by peak position on American
    Top 40 (eight weeks at number one). It is Fergie's most
    downloaded song in the U.S. with over 2,367,000 downloads, more
    than "Fergalicious" who has sold over 2,315,000 downloads till
    the first week of December 2007. It's the 3rd most downloaded
    song of 2007 in the U.S. behind "Crank That (Soulja Boy)"
    (+2,510,000) and "Hey There Delilah" (+2,416,000), and the 6th
    in the U.S. history. "Big Girls Don't Cry" was ranked at #4 on
    Billboard's Year-End chart for 2007.</p>
      <p>"Big Girls Don't Cry" has become Fergie's most successful
    single worldwide, surpassing "London Bridge". The song debuted
    at number thirty-two and reached number one on its thirteenth
    week, staying there for five consecutive weeks. The song stayed
    in the chart for forty-nine weeks, twenty-six of which were in
    the top ten. In Australia it was certified 2x Platinum by ARIA
    for combined sales of over 140,000 copies, and ended as the
    year's biggest hit, ranked at number-one on the ARIA Year-End
    singles chart for 2007. It was also the longest running number
    one single at the top spot with 9 consecutive weeks (10 in the
    Download Chart) and the last to do so.</p>
      <p>Also, despite only spending a week at #1 on the New Zealand
    RIANZ singles chart, "Big Girls Don't Cry" has become the
    fourth most successful single in RIANZ music history and the
    second best seller in the country for 2007. It spent a total of
    38 weeks on the chart.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by Anthony Mandler and began
    production on March 30, 2007. The video had a 'First Look' on
    MTV's 
    <i>TRL</i>on May 16, 2007 and has since peaked at #5 on May 24,
    2007. The video topped Vh1's Top 40 Videos of 2007 list. Milo
    Ventimiglia plays Fergie's love interest.</p>
      <p>The video begins with Fergie getting out of her car (a red
    1969 Mustang fastback) and going inside a warehouse where she
    meets her band and practices. Meanwhile, she is seen singing
    next to her boyfriend (Milo Ventimiglia), who is sleeping. She
    starts walking through the house, and is then watching herself
    and her boyfriend from a different point of view getting out of
    her car. They go into the house, and her boyfriend gets out a
    guitar and starts playing, while Fergie is singing. Later on,
    she sees her boyfriend out the window with several guys, one of
    whom passes him a small package, which is presumably drugs, and
    it upsets her. Fergie then starts singing the chorus while she
    is taking her clothes off a clothes line and putting them into
    a suitcase. As the third verse begins, Fergie is walking around
    a warehouse singing while wearing a tan-gray baby doll dress.
    At the end of the song, she is seen getting into her car and
    driving down the road.</p>
      <p>There are two music videos: the main version features the
    garage scene mixed with the others; the extended, in which the
    song is performed twice, the first time it was sang features
    all the scenes, excluding the garage scenes, the second time it
    only features unseen garage scenes and the normal garage
    sensual scenes.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Big Girls Don't Cry" has been viewed
    about 30 million times on popular video-sharing website
    YouTube.</p>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>The Dutchess (Japan re-issue edition) and Sean Kingston
    (Deluxe Edition)</i>
      </p>
      <p>A remix was made of the song in late 2007, which retained
    the vocals of the original, but with a new, 1980s-reminiscent
    sound, with none of the acoustic guitars present in the
    original. Titled the "Big Girls Remix", it featured reggae star
    Sean Kingston, who records his vocals over the new beat and
    after his verses, it goes into the chorus of the original and
    basically maintains Fergie's vocals for the rest of the
    song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
