<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dreams_(Fleetwood_Mac_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dreams_(Fleetwood_Mac_song)</songId>
   <title>Dreams</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fleetwood_Mac</artistId>
      <artistName>Fleetwood Mac</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1977-06-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/1/17/FleetwoodmacDreams.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Fleetwood-Mac+Dreams.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Rumours</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 24, 1977 (USA) / June 1977 (UK)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1976</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:17</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Warner Bros.</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Stevie Nicks</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Fleetwood Mac</producer>
      <producer>Richard Dashut and Ken Caillat</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Dreams" is a song written by singer Stevie Nicks, for the
    group Fleetwood Mac's 1977 album, 
    <i>Rumours</i>. The song was the only U.S. number one hit for
    the group, and remains one of their best known songs.</p>
      <p>The members of Fleetwood Mac were experiencing emotional
    upheavals while recording 
    <i>Rumours</i>. Drummer Mick Fleetwood was going through a
    divorce. Bass player John McVie was separating from his wife,
    keyboard player Christine McVie. Guitarist Lindsey Buckingham
    and Nicks were ending their eight-year relationship. "We had to
    go through this elaborate exercise of denial," explains
    Buckingham to Blender Magazine, "keeping our personal feelings
    in one corner of the room while trying to be professional in
    the other."</p>
      <p>Nicks wrote the song at the Record Plant studio in
    Sausalito, California, in early 1976. "One day when I wasn't
    required in the main studio," remembers singer Stevie Nicks to
    Blender, "I took a Fender Rhodes piano and went into another
    studio that was said to belong to Sly, of Sly &amp; the Family
    Stone. It was a black-and-red room, with a sunken pit in the
    middle where there was a piano, and a big black-velvet bed with
    Victorian drapes."</p>
      <p>"I sat down on the bed with my keyboard in front of me,"
    continues Nicks. "I found a drum pattern, switched my little
    cassette player on and wrote 'Dreams' in about 10 minutes.
    Right away I liked the fact that I was doing something with a
    dance beat, because that made it a little unusual for me."</p>
      <p>When Nicks played the song to the rest of the group, they
    decided to record it the following day. Only a basic track was
    recorded at Sausalito. Recording assistant Cris Morris
    remembers that "all (they) kept was the drum track and live
    vocal from Stevie — the guitars and bass were added later in
    Los Angeles."</p>
      <p>Christine McVie described the song as having "just three
    chords and one note in the left hand" and "boring" when Nicks
    played a rough version on the piano. McVie changed her mind,
    after Lindsey "fashioned three sections out of identical
    chords, making each section sound completely different. He
    created the impression that there’s a thread running through
    the whole thing."</p>
      <p>"Dreams" was the second single from the 
    <i>Rumours</i>album in the US, and it reached the number one
    spot on June 18, 1977, and held it for one week. It went to #24
    in the United Kingdom as the third single, following "Go Your
    Own Way" (#38) and "Don't Stop" (#32). A performance of the
    song on stage was used as the promotional video. Fleetwood Mac
    would not begin to make concept music videos until 1979.</p>
      <p>"Dreams" is a cover of the Fleetwood Mac song by The Corrs.
    "Dreams" was originally recorded for "Legacy: A tribute to
    Fleetwood Mac's Rumours" which features cover versions like
    "Don't stop" by Elton John, "You make loving fun" by Jewel and
    others from the Goo Goo Dolls and the Cranberries. It turned
    out to be the first big hit for the Corrs in the UK and the
    video won the "Best Adult Contemporary Video" award from
    Billboard magazine in 1998.</p>
      <p>The Corrs had the honor of performing "Dreams" with Mick
    Fleetwood from Fleetwood Mac in their legendary concert at the
    Royal Albert Hall, on St Patrick's Day, 1998 (incidentally,
    that was also Caroline Corr's 25th birthday).</p>
      <p>Tee's remix made "Dreams" one of the most successful Corrs
    singles ever: it reached #6 in the UK single charts and on the
    whole stayed in the charts for 10 weeks.</p>
      <p>The "Dreams" video was urgently needed, similar to the video
    for "What Can I Do." The song had made the UK Radio One
    playlist (BBC One), and needed a video to go along with it.
    Director Dani Jacobs was originally unavailable because he had
    a previously scheduled shot in Canada, but he dumped it on the
    spot and flew to Singapore to shoot "Dreams." When he arrived
    there, he found that his ideas of a "dreamy, oriental" feel for
    the video were trashed by Singapore's western looks.
    Thankfully, the crew found the Thian Hock Keng Buddhist temple
    in the Telok Ayer Street in Chinatown. The location was found,
    yet the crew had picked one of the hottest, most humid days of
    the year (April 10, 1998), so the Corrs were downing copious
    amounts of "Evian", spending time in the air-conditioned
    trailers and Andrea even filmed the entire video with her dress
    unzipped at the back to keep perspiration at bay.</p>
      <p>In 2005, Nicks contributed new vocals to a remake of the
    song by DJ and house music duo Deep Dish. The song appears on
    their album 
    <i>George Is On</i>, and was a top twenty UK Singles Chart hit
    and climbed to number 26 on the U.S. Hot Dance Club Play
    chart.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
