<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Right_Round 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Right_Round</songId>
   <title>Right Round</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flo_Rida</artistId>
      <artistName>Flo Rida</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2009-02-28</week>
      <week>2009-03-07</week>
      <week>2009-03-14</week>
      <week>2009-03-21</week>
      <week>2009-03-28</week>
      <week>2009-04-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/b/b6/Flo_Rida_-_Right_Round_Official_Cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Flo-Rida+Right-Round.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>R.O.O.T.S.</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 10, 2009  (2009-02-10)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Conway and Atlantic Studios , Hollywood , California</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hip House</genre>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:23</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Poe Boy , Atlantic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Tramar Dillard</writer>
      <writer>Lukasz Gottwald</writer>
      <writer>Allan Grigg</writer>
      <writer>Justin Franks</writer>
      <writer>Philip Lawrence</writer>
      <writer>Bruno Mars</writer>
      <writer>Aaron Bay-Schuck</writer>
      <writer>Peter Burns</writer>
      <writer>Stephen Coy</writer>
      <writer>Michael Percy</writer>
      <writer>Timothy Lever</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Dr. Luke</producer>
      <producer>Koool Kojak</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Right Round" is a dance-pop song performed by American
    rapper Flo Rida from 
    <i>R.O.O.T.S.</i>, his second studio album. It was released as
    the lead single from the album on February 10, 2009 by Poe Boy
    Entertainment and Atlantic Records. The song lyrically speaks
    of developing a crush on a woman at a strip club, while
    musically incorporating a sample of the 1984 Dead or Alive song
    "You Spin Me Round (Like a Record)" in its hook. Pop singer
    Kesha contributed uncredited guest vocals to the song.</p>
      <p>The song received mostly negative reviews from critics, who
    claimed it was cheesy and misogynistic. However, it was a
    commercial success, reaching the top ten of the charts in
    nineteen countries worldwide. In the United States, it became
    Flo Rida's second number-one single and broke the record for
    first-week sales when it was released to digital retailers. The
    single's accompanying music video was directed by Malcolm Jones
    and nominated for an MTV Video Music Award.</p>
      <p>"Right Round" was written by Flo Rida, Dr. Luke, Allan
    Grigg, Justin Franks, Philip Lawrence, Bruno Mars, Aaron
    Bay-Schuck, Pete Burns, Steve Coy, Mike Percy and Tim Lever. It
    was produced by Luke and Koool Kojak and features uncredited
    guest vocals from American pop singer Kesha. According to Flo
    Rida, the song is about "a young lady, she might be in the
    strip club and she's got my head spinning round, [...] Or any
    young lady that I might see walking past me that's getting my
    attention. She got it going on! I'm going crazy over her."</p>
      <p>The song contains a sample of Dead or Alive's 1984 single
    "You Spin Me Round (Like a Record)". Flo Rida explained that he
    listened to that and similar records growing up as a result of
    the varying music genres his seven sisters listened to.
    However, Mike Caren, his A&amp;R, was the one who brought the
    sample to his attention. As 
    <i>R.O.O.T.S.</i>was Flo Rida's second studio album, he wanted
    to show listeners musical growth by "broaden[ing] my horizons,"
    which was why he decided to record the song. After Luke
    produced the sample, the song was recorded. It was recorded
    primarily at Conway Studios in Hollywood, California, with
    additional recording at Atlantic Studios, also located in
    Hollywood.</p>
      <p>Musically, "Right Round" uses the recurring pop rap themes
    of Flo Rida's music; specifically, similarities were noted
    between the song and "Low" (2007), with Allmusic reviewer David
    Jeffries calling "Right Round" its "heir apparent". The song is
    "swaggering" and "bass-heavy", according to Leah Greenblatt of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>. The lyrics discuss being in a
    strip club with friends and tossing money at a woman performing
    a striptease. Additionally, the chorus line "You spin my head
    right round, right round / When you go down, when you go down,
    down" can be interpreted as a reference to fellatio. The song's
    sexual themes have been compared to those of "If U Seek Amy"
    (2009) by Britney Spears.</p>
      <p>Reviews for "Right Round" were mostly negative. A reviewer
    for 
    <i>The New York Times</i>called the song "[b]ionic and empty".
    In a review of 
    <i>R.O.O.T.S.</i>, Ken Capobianco of 
    <i>The Boston Globe</i>stated, "His music is pure ear candy
    that must make Britney [Spears] envious, yet he wants to come
    off as a thug." He continued that it is unlikely that "Right
    Round" would be heard on Brooklyn's streets 15 years prior to
    its release, calling it "as hard as Jell-O." Alex Fletcher of
    Digital Spy stated in his review of the song, "It's pretty
    difficult to ruin a pop classic, but Flo Rida gives it a pretty
    good stab here." He added that "Right Round" is "[f]illed with
    more misogyny than a 1970s working mens' club", and called it
    "an unpleasant affair that's only saved from the trashcan by
    its sample." Fletcher concluded, "The fuzzy synths, electro
    beats and infectious chorus hook sung by Ke$ha are almost
    enough to fool the casual listener into enjoying themselves.
    But sadly it's never too long before Flo Rida turns up again to
    spoil things." Simon Vozick-Levinson of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>called the song "a horrendous rap
    remake of Dead or Alive's 'You Spin Me Round (Like a Record).'"
    Noting that the song was, at the time, the number-one single on
    the Hot 100, he added, "What does all this say about us as a
    society? Mainly that we really, really enjoy cheesetastic '80s
    hair-pop hits in whatever form we can get 'em, I guess."</p>
      <p>There were some positive reviews, however. One such review
    came from Fraser McAlpine of BBC, who opened, "It's one of the
    fundamental laws of pop, anything which tips a nod to 'You Spin
    Me Round (Like A Record)' by Dead Or Alive is going to be worth
    a listen." He continued, "Even though this is just a song
    written from the perspective of a randy man watching a
    pole-dancer and bragging about how much money he has [...] in a
    manner which would make Akon blush, there's just something kind
    of cute about the whole thing." McAlpine attributed this to the
    song's "Tigger-beat", explaining, "How can anything too sordid
    be going on when everyone is bouncing around like they're on
    spacehoppers?" Bill Lamb of About.com commented, "You will hear
    echoes of another pop classic, but the new song stands on its
    own feet." However, he noted that while pop music fans would
    appreciate it, hip hop listeners would likely dismiss it, and
    he added that "[i]t's not groundbreaking by any means".</p>
      <p>In the United States, "Right Round" debuted at number
    seventy-four on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 based solely on airplay. The next week,
    it rose sixteen positions to chart at number fifty-eight. In
    its third chart week, issue dated February 19, 2009, it jumped
    fifty-seven positions to the top spot, becoming Flo Rida's
    second number-one hit after 2007's "Low". That week, it also
    debuted at the top of the Hot Digital Songs chart with sales of
    636,000, breaking the record of first-week sales established
    only the week before by Eminem, Dr. Dre and 50 Cent's "Crack a
    Bottle" (418,000). It remained atop the Hot 100 for six
    consecutive weeks. "Right Round" also topped the Pop 100 in the
    United States, and peaked at the third position on the Hot Rap
    Tracks chart, and appeared on the Hot 100's year-end and
    decade-end charts at positions six and eighty, respectively. By
    March 12, 2009, the song was certified gold and platinum by the
    Recording Industry Association of America, and by March 31,
    achieved double-platinum status. To date, it has been certified
    triple-platinum by the RIAA. "Right Round" made its Canadian
    debut at the seventy-fifth position, moved to the forty-seventh
    position in its second week, and peaked at the top of the
    charts—where it spent nine non-consecutive weeks—its third
    week. At the end of 2009, it was ranked the number-three song
    on the Canadian Hot 100.</p>
      <p>The song debuted at the top of the Australian ARIA Singles
    Chart and maintained its position for seven non-consecutive
    weeks. It has been certified twice-platinum by the Australian
    Recording Industry Association. It was the number-five song of
    the year and appeared on the decade-end chart at number
    eighteen. In New Zealand, "Right Round" debuted at number nine
    and moved to number five in its second week. It remained in the
    top five for four weeks before reaching a peak of number two,
    where it remained for four consecutive weeks. The Recording
    Industry Association of New Zealand has certified the song
    platinum, and it was ranked as the seventh most popular song of
    2009.</p>
      <p>"Right Round" also performed well in Europe, peaking at the
    second position on the European Hot 100 Singles chart and at
    number sixteen on the chart's year-end list. It debuted on the
    UK Singles Chart at number one, then dropped to number two in
    its second charting week. It remained in the top ten for six
    weeks. In Ireland, it debuted at number four and remained in
    the top five for four weeks. In its fifth week, it topped the
    chart and remained at the top position for three consecutive
    weeks. Elsewhere in Europe, the song reached the top ten in
    Austria (where it was certified gold by the International
    Federation of the Phonographic Industry), Belgium (number one
    in Wallonia, number two in Flanders), Denmark, the Netherlands,
    Finland, France, Norway, Spain, Sweden, Switzerland and
    Germany.</p>
      <p>The song's accompanying music video was shot in Miami,
    Florida and directed by Malcolm Jones. Kesha was asked to
    appear in the video, but declined; in an interview with 
    <i>Esquire</i>magazine, she said, "They [Flo Rida's team]
    wanted me in the video, and I said, 'Nah, I want to make my own
    name for myself.'" The video begins with Flo Rida standing on a
    revolving circular platform, while his name appears in gold on
    a screen behind him. A young woman then joins him on the
    platform, with shots alternating between the two together and
    each individually. During the first verse, the screen behind
    him alternates between images of a rotating globe and locations
    such as Tokyo, Paris and New York City. Shortly after, the
    silhouettes of three women appear behind Flo Rida while the
    clip is intercut with shots of a rotating disco ball and
    several women on a circular bed. Several women are then seen
    dancing on or around cars while Flo Rida stands in front of
    them. A waitress comes in to serve them an unidentified
    beverage. As the video ends, Flo Rida is seen once again on the
    circular platform while the screen behind him shows a red
    background with a gold Poe Boy Entertainment sticker. The video
    was nominated for Best Hip-Hop Video at the 2009 MTV Video
    Music Awards, but lost to Eminem's "We Made You" (2009).</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
