<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Want_to_Know_What_Love_Is 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Want_to_Know_What_Love_Is</songId>
   <title>I Want to Know What Love Is</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foreigner_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Foreigner</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1985-02-02</week>
      <week>1985-02-09</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/57/Foreigner-I-Want-To-Know-Wh-297484.jpg/200px-Foreigner-I-Want-To-Know-Wh-297484.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Foreigner+I-Want-to-Know-What-Love-Is.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Agent Provocateur</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November, 1984</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1984</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:58 (7" single)</length>
      <length>6:23 (12" single)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mick Jones</writer>
      <writer>Lou Gramm</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mick Jones</producer>
      <producer>Alex Sadkin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Want to Know What Love Is" is a 1984 power ballad
    recorded by the British-American rock band Foreigner. The song
    hit #1 in both the UK and the U.S. and is the band's most
    successful single. It remains one of the band's best known
    songs and most enduring radio hits, charting in the top 25 in
    2000, 2001 and 2002 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Adult Contemporary Recurrents chart.</p>
      <p>Written by Mick Jones, with some degree of uncredited
    contribution by Lou Gramm, and produced by Jones and Alex
    Sadkin, it was the first single released from the album 
    <i>Agent Provocateur</i>(1984). The song features backing
    vocals from the New Jersey Mass Choir (of the GMWA), 
    <i>Dreamgirls</i>star Jennifer Holliday, and the Thompson
    Twins. The choir appears in the song's music video.</p>
      <p>"I Want to Know What Love Is" reached number one in the 
    <i>UK Singles Chart</i>on January 15, 1985, and stayed there
    for three weeks. It reached the top of the U.S. 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 on February 2, 1985, where it stayed
    for two weeks. It was Foreigner's first and only Pop
    chart-topper in either country, although the band had four #1
    Mainstream Rock and one #1 Adult Contemporary radio hits in the
    U.S. This was the band's third of four #1 singles on the
    Mainstream Rock chart. The song spent five weeks at #1 in
    Australia, and also hit the top of the charts in Canada, Norway
    and Sweden, peaking at #2 in Switzerland and South Africa.</p>
      <p>The song was also issued as a 12" single with a slightly
    longer time length of 6:23. This version contains a slightly
    longer intro and an extended vocal chorus/ad-lib-to-fade
    ending.</p>
      <p>The single's B-Side, "Street Thunder (Marathon Theme)", is
    an instrumental track originally appearing on 
    <i>The Official Music of the XXIIIrd Olympiad—Los Angeles
    1984</i>, and later on the band's 2-CD compilation, 
    <i>Jukebox Heroes: The Foreigner Anthology</i>, in 2000.</p>
      <p>Soon after Foreigner's single topped the charts, the New
    Jersey Mass Choir released its own, similar-sounding version of
    the song, on an album also titled 
    <i>I Want to Know What Love Is</i>. Their single peaked at #37
    on the Hot Black Singles chart and #12 on the Hot Dance
    Music/Maxi-Singles Sales chart.</p>
      <p>The Foreigner song was ranked by 
    <i>Billboard</i>as the number four Hot 100 single of the year
    1985. It was the band's fourth Gold single in the U.S. and
    their first and only Gold single in the UK.</p>
      <p>In 2004 "I Want to Know What Love Is" was voted #476 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s list of the 500 greatest songs of all
    time. In 2006 this song was included on VH1's program "Top 100
    Songs of the 80's" at #65.</p>
      <p>The song was used on the 16th episode of 
    <i>Miami Vice</i>in the first season, entitled 
    <i>Rites of Passage</i>on 8 February 1985. The song was made
    part of the videogame 
    <i>Grand Theft Auto: Vice City Stories</i>soundtrack in 2006,
    and was the background music for the game's first trailer and
    intro cutscene. In 2007, the game 
    <i>SingStar '80s</i>included the song. The song was played in a
    scene in 
    <i>Larry The Cable Guy: Health Inspector</i>and in the
    "Valentine's Day" episode of the TV show 
    <i>Ed</i>. The song also features in the 1998 Swedish film 
    <i>Show Me Love</i>. The song was sung twice on 
    <i>General Hospital</i>in 2009; first by the character Spinelli
    to his girlfriend Maxie at Jake's karaoke night, and second by
    guests at a reception, to Spinelli and Maxie. The song appears
    in 
    <i>Alvin and the Chipmunks: The Squeakquel</i>.</p>
      <p>"I Want to Know What Love Is" was covered by Australian
    singer Tina Arena and her recording was released as a single in
    1998 from her album 
    <i>In Deep</i>. Arena's version of the song was produced by
    Foreigner band member Mick Jones, who was the song's
    writer.</p>
      <p>The song peaked at #13 in France and finished 60th on the
    End Of Year Chart (1999).</p>
      <p>"I Want to Know What Love Is" was covered by American singer
    Mariah Carey and released as the second single from her twelfth
    studio album, 
    <i>Memoirs of an Imperfect Angel</i>(2009). The single,
    produced by Carey, C. "Tricky" Stewart and James "Big Jim"
    Wright, was sent to European radio stations on August 28 and
    official impacted U.S. radio on September 14, 2009. Mick Jones
    said of her version: "I think she's actually retained the
    integrity of the song. You know, the arrangement is very
    similar to the original. They haven't tampered with the song
    too much. She's captured a certain emotional thing, a
    feeling."</p>
      <p>The single has garnered generally positive reviews;
    Australian magazine "Rhyme &amp; Reason" stated that "[While
    Carey stayed] [...] true to the original, this piano-led remake
    is less an overhaul of the classic '80s hit than it is a modest
    but impressive update." The UK 
    <i>Daily Star</i>gave it a 5 out of 5 rating: "[The song is]
    given the Carey treatment and [is] complete with choir and
    karaoke climax. It's a great rework." Bill Lamb from About.com
    said that "Mariah Carey's new version could leave you
    speechless. The diversity of vocal coloring expressed in this
    recording is stunning. While the single Obsessed remains
    disappointing, this single is a reminder of just how formidable
    Carey's talents are given a strong production and arrangement".
    
    <i>Los Angeles Times</i>said "[T]ackling a well-known power
    ballad seems like a safe choice. It's a comfortable fall-back
    plan after "Obsessed" performed well, but did far from
    blockbuster numbers. It will undoubtedly be a hit, but it's
    giving me more reason to fear 
    <i>Imperfect Angel.</i>The sort-of-real/sort-of-not feud with
    Eminem seemed largely a ploy to keep Carey in the headlines,
    and covering Foreigner seems just as calculated to steer Carey
    back onto familiar ground". 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>said "Mariah + Gospel Choir + "I
    Want to Know What Love Is" = Ecstasy".</p>
      <p>The single received a negative review from Alex Fletcher of
    UK-based entertainment site Digital Spy: "With its corny
    lyrics, choir backing vocals and sweeping, jumbo jet-size
    chorus, ["I Want to Know What Love Is"] may as well have been
    written for Mimi. However it's more than a little
    disappointing, that her take on the Foreigner classic is so
    timid. The singer gives an understated performance with only a
    few piano flourishes and robotic beats as backing. When she
    does finally unleash her trademark whistle for the crescendo,
    it feels too calculated and sounds like a recording studio clip
    chucked on the end. She has stripped away the much-loved
    ridiculousness and pomposity of the original, leaving a rather
    limp, lifeless number in its place.</p>
      <p>Carey filmed a music video for "I Want to Know What Love Is"
    in September 2009 in New York City. The director for the video
    is Hype Williams. The video premiered on Mariah's official
    website on November 13, 2009. The video shows Carey singing in
    a stadium whilst shots are intercut with people accompanied by
    their loved ones, or who have had tough times in their past
    (i.e. terminal illness etc) who get quite emotional watching
    her perform. A gospel choir appears at the end of the video
    singing along with Carey at the centre of the stadium. In the
    video, Mariah adopts her signature curly hairstyle that was
    present in the initial stages of her career from 1990–1993,
    maintaining the 'Memoirs' theme of the new album.</p>
      <p>"I Want to Know What Love Is" debuted on the Hot 100 at #66
    for the week ending October 3, 2009, eventually peaking at #60.
    In Brazil, it reached number one on the five-month-old
    Brazilian Airplay Chart in December and remained at the top
    spot for the next two charts, spanning all of January and
    February. The song also reached #1 on the Japanese airplay
    chart as well as #19 on the UK Official Top 40, as well as #3
    on the Japan Hot 100. The song reached the Top 10 on the U.S. 
    <i>Billboard</i>Adult Contemporary Tracks chart at #10,
    bringing Carey's total number of top ten hits on that chart to
    20, one behind Celine Dion's current record. On the UK Singles
    Chart, the song debuted at #19 on the week ending November 29,
    becoming her highest debuting and peaking song since 2008's
    "Touch My Body", which peaked at #5. The song has debuted at #6
    in France selling 1,910 copies in its first week.</p>
      <p>Laura Branigan and John Farnham performed a duet to the song
    on live television for the 1986 Logie Awards, an Australian
    awards show.</p>
      <p>In 1997 this song was also covered by slain South African
    reggae star Lucky Dube on his Taxman album. It featured strong
    South African reggae drum beats by ace drummer Mnca
    Mtshali.</p>
      <p>A Spanish-language version by The Barrio Boyzz, entitled
    "Quiero Saber Que Es Amor/I Want to Know What Love Is", hit #40
    on 
    <i>Billboard's</i>Latin Tropical/Salsa Airplay chart on April
    7, 2001.</p>
      <p>In 2001, singer Rhona covered it on her debut self-titled
    album.</p>
      <p>A cover by Gloria Gaynor appears on the 2002 K-Tel
    compilation 
    <i>Tina Turner &amp; Gloria Gaynor, Back To Back</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2002 the victims of fires in a disco in Sweden and a bar
    in The Netherlands recorded this song as a way for these young
    people to learn to cope with their memories and their injuries.
    Their single, released under the artist name Volendam meets
    Göteborg, reached #39 in the Dutch charts.</p>
      <p>In 2003 Wynonna Judd's cover of "I Want to Know What Love
    Is" was released as a single from her album 
    <i>What the World Needs Now Is Love</i>, peaking at #14 on the
    Billboard Hot Adult Contemporary chart. Later that year, the
    track was remixed for dance clubs, peaking at #12 on 
    <i>Billboard's</i>Hot Dance Airplay chart in 2005.</p>
      <p>In 2004, a cover by Sarah Geronimo from her album 
    <i>Sweet Sixteen</i>was a hit in her native Philippines.</p>
      <p>The song was one of several covers chosen by Clay Aiken to
    appear on his 2006 album 
    <i>A Thousand Different Ways</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2008 this song was covered by David Phelps on his album 
    <i>The Voice</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was also performed by Celtic Thunder's Keith Harkin
    in concert, and it appears on that band's 2008 album 
    <i>Act Two</i>.</p>
      <p>Alvin and the Chipmunks covered the song for the 2009 movie 
    <i>Alvin and the Chipmunks: The Squeakquel</i>and its
    soundtrack.</p>
      <p>Leela James covered the song on her 2009 sophomore release
    "Let's Do It Again".</p>
      <p>Other covers of this song have been recorded by familiar
    artists as diverse as Progressive rock keyboardist Geoffrey
    Downes, pop chanteuses Rita Coolidge and Shirley Bassey, Latin
    crooner Julio Iglesias, Memphis soul singer Ann Peebles and
    Christian pop artist Kathy Troccoli.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
