<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Eyes_Adored_You 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Eyes_Adored_You</songId>
   <title>My Eyes Adored You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frankie_Valli</artistId>
      <artistName>Frankie Valli</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1975-03-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"My Eyes Adored You" (original working title, "Blue Eyes in
    Georgia") is a popular song written by Bob Crewe and Kenny
    Nolan. It was originally recorded by The Four Seasons in early
    1974. After the MoWest label balked at the idea of releasing
    it, the recording was sold to lead singer Frankie Valli for
    $4000. After rejections by Capitol, Atlantic, and other labels,
    Valli succeeded in getting the recording released on Private
    Stock Records, but the owner/founder of the label wanted only
    Valli's name on the label. The single was released in the U.S.
    in November 1974 and topped the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 in March 1975.</p>
      <p>The single was Valli's first number one hit as a solo
    artist, and remained at number one for one week. Although it
    was released as a Valli solo effort, the song is sometimes
    included on Four Seasons compilation albums. It is from the
    album Closeup.</p>
      <p>The success of "My Eyes Adored You" triggered a revival of
    interest in recordings by Frankie Valli and The Four Seasons.
    The group was subsequently signed to Warner Bros. Records as
    Valli's followup single, "Swearin' to God" was climbing to the
    #6 position on the Hot 100. Three months later, The Four
    Seasons visited the Top Ten for the first time since 1967 with
    "Who Loves You".</p>
      <p>The song was recorded in 1976 by Fred Astaire with the Pete
    Moore Orchestra (United Artists Records UA-LA580-G) and in 2008
    by Australian singer Alfio for his album 
    <i>Classic Rewinds</i>which pays tribute to Frankie Valli and
    14 other popular Italian-American singers.</p>
      <p>John Barrowman covered the song in 2010 on his third studio
    album, self-titled as John Barrowman.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
