<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/That_Lucky_Old_Sun 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/That_Lucky_Old_Sun</songId>
   <title>That Lucky Old Sun</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frankie_Laine</artistId>
      <artistName>Frankie Laine</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1949-10-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"That Lucky Old Sun" is a 1949 popular song with music by
    Beasley Smith and words by Haven Gillespie. Like "Old Man
    River", its lyrics contrast the toil and intense hardship of
    the singer's life with the obliviousness of the natural
    world.</p>
      <p>The biggest hit version of the song was by Frankie Laine.
    This recording was released by Mercury Records as catalog
    number 5316. It first reached the Billboard magazine Best
    Seller chart on August 19, 1949 and lasted 22 weeks on the
    chart, peaking at #1.</p>
      <p>The recording by Vaughn Monroe was released by RCA Victor
    Records as catalog number 20-3531 (78 rpm) and 47-3018 (45
    rpm). It first reached the Billboard magazine Best Seller chart
    on September 16, 1949 and lasted 14 weeks on the chart, peaking
    at #9.</p>
      <p>The recording by Louis Armstrong was released by Decca
    Records as catalog number 24752. It first reached the Billboard
    magazine Best Seller chart on October 14, 1949 and lasted 3
    weeks on the chart, peaking at #24.</p>
      <p>Frank Sinatra released his competing version of the song on
    the Columbia label catalog number 38608. It reached the best
    sellers chart on October 29, 1949 and peaked at #16.</p>
      <p>This song was translated into Russian, and was presented to
    Soviet audiences as describing how a Western man suffers the
    hardships of capitalism. It was recorded in Russian by singer
    Mark Bernes in early 1960s.</p>
      <p>A version by Ray Charles appeared on his 1963 album 
    <i>Ingredients in a Recipe for Soul</i>. (This recording is
    also included as a bonus track on post-1988 CD reissues of
    Charles' landmark 1962 album 
    <i>Modern Sounds in Country and Western Music</i>.)</p>
      <p>Jerry Lee Lewis recorded an unreleased solo version at Sun
    Studios in 1956 or 1957. (A recorded version by Lewis can be
    found on the Great Balls of Fire album, the soundtrack for the
    movie "Great Balls of Fire" with Dennis Quaid playing the part
    of Jerry Lee Lewis.)</p>
      <p>Paul Williams recorded a version on the 1972 Album Life Goes
    On (Paul Williams album)</p>
      <p>Willie Nelson recorded a version on the 1976 Album 
    <i>The Sound in Your Mind</i>which was also released as an
    extra track on the reissued 
    <i>Stardust: 30th Anniversary Legacy Edition</i>.</p>
      <p>The Jerry Garcia Band performed a version on the Jerry
    Garcia Band live album in 1991.</p>
      <p>Johnny Cash covered it on the album American III: Solitary
    Man in 2000.</p>
      <p>Brian Wilson premiered a song cycle inspired by the song
    entitled 
    <i>That Lucky Old Sun (A Narrative)</i>at the Royal Festival
    Hall, London, England on 10 September 2007.</p>
      <p>A duet with Kenny Chesney and Willie Nelson is included on
    Chesney's 2008 album 
    <i>Lucky Old Sun</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
