<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mule_Train 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mule_Train</songId>
   <title>Mule Train</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frankie_Laine</artistId>
      <artistName>Frankie Laine</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1949-11-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Mule Train" is a popular song written by Johnny Lange, Hy
    Heath, and Fred Glickman. It is a novelty cowboy song,
    supposedly sung by an Old-West wagon driver spurring on his
    mules as he recites the goods he is delivering to far-flung
    mail-order customers.</p>
      <p>Charting versions were recorded by Frankie Laine, Bing
    Crosby, Tennessee Ernie Ford, and Vaughn Monroe.</p>
      <p>The Frankie Laine recording was recorded on October 2, 1949,
    and released by Mercury Records as catalog number 5345.The
    record first reached the Billboard magazine charts on November
    4, 1949 and lasted 13 weeks on the chart, peaking at #1.
    Laine's recording of the song was produced by Mitch Miller. It
    featured a bellowed vocal delivery (like that of a real driver
    shouting to be heard) and studio-created gimmicks such as
    whipcracking sound effects. It is often cited as an outstanding
    early example of studio production techniques.</p>
      <p>The Bing Crosby recording was recorded on October 26, 1949,
    and released by Decca Records as catalog number 24798. The flip
    side was "Dear Hearts and Gentle People." The record first
    reached the Billboard magazine charts on November 25, 1949 and
    lasted 16 weeks on the chart, peaking at #2. This recording was
    featured in an episode of the NBC radio network radio program 
    <i>Lassie Show</i>entitled Mule Train, which aired on
    12/17/1949.</p>
      <p>The Tennessee Ernie Ford recording was recorded on October
    18, 1949, and released by Capitol Records as catalog number
    40258. The record first reached the Billboard magazine charts
    on November 25, 1949 and lasted 9 weeks on the chart, peaking
    at #10. Ford's version also charted on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>country charts, reaching No. 1 in December.</p>
      <p>The Vaughn Monroe recording was released by RCA Victor
    Records as a 78rpm single (catalog number 20-3600) and a 45rpm
    single (catalog number 47-3106). The record first reached the
    Billboard magazine charts on November 18, 1949 and lasted 9
    weeks on the chart, peaking at #10. Monroe also sang the song
    in the 1950 Republic Western "Singing Guns." He played an
    outlaw who became town marshal with the intent of stealing a
    shipment of gold, and sang the song while at the reins of what
    appeared to be a stagecoach.</p>
      <p>Woody Herman and The King Cole Trio, along with Irving
    Ashby, Joe Comfort and Gene Orloff, made a recording of "Mule
    Train" on November 7, 1949 in New York City, as well as the
    track "My Baby Just Cares For Me", which were both released by
    Capitol Records as a single, catalog number 787, which gave
    label credit to Herman for "Mule Train" and to the trio for "My
    Baby Just Cares For Me".</p>
      <p>Gordon MacRae made a recording on October 1, 1949, which was
    released by Capitol Records in the United States as the flip
    side of the single "Dear Hearts and Gentle People" (which he
    recorded on October 21, 1949) as catalog number 777, and in
    England as catalog number CL 13226.</p>
      <p>Les Welch and his Orchestra made a recording in Australia in
    February, 1950, which was released by Pacific Records (in
    Australia) as catalog number 10-0019.</p>
      <p>The song was subsequently recorded in England by Frank
    Ifield in the 1960s.</p>
      <p>In 1950, a satirical version of the song, "Chinese Mule
    Train," was recorded by Spike Jones with Fladdy Morgan singing
    (RCA Victor 20-3741).</p>
      <p>A reggae version was recorded by Count Prince Miller in 1971
    and then again with Sly and Robbie in the 1980s.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
