<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Piano_Concerto_No._1_(Tchaikovsky) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Piano_Concerto_No._1_(Tchaikovsky)</songId>
   <title>Piano Concerto in B Flat</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freddy_Martin</artistId>
      <artistName>Freddy Martin</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1941-10-04</week>
      <week>1941-10-11</week>
      <week>1941-10-18</week>
      <week>1941-10-25</week>
      <week>1941-11-01</week>
      <week>1941-11-08</week>
      <week>1941-11-15</week>
      <week>1941-11-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>The Piano Concerto No. 1 in , Op. 23 was composed by Pyotr
    Ilyich Tchaikovsky between November 1874 and February 1875. It
    was revised in the summer of 1879 and again in December 1888.
    It is considered one of the most popular of Tchaikovsky's works
    and among the best known of all piano concerti.</p>
      <p>The work is scored for 2 flutes, 2 oboes, 2 clarinets in
    B-flat, 2 bassoons, 4 horns in F, 2 trumpets in F, 3 trombones
    (2 tenor, 1 bass), timpani, solo piano, and strings.</p>
      <p>The concerto follows the traditional form of three
    movements:</p>
      <p>The well-known theme of the introductory section to the
    first movement is based on a melody that Tchaikovsky heard
    performed by blind beggar-musicians at a market in Kamenka,
    near Kiev in Ukraine. This well known passage in the concerto,
    was notable for a considerable time after its composition on
    its apparent formal independence from the movement and the
    concerto as a whole. This sense of independence seemed to be
    highlighted by being not in the work's nominal key of B flat
    minor but in the relative major key of D-flat. Despite its very
    substantial nature, the theme is only heard twice, and never
    subsequently reappears in the concerto. Musicologist Francis
    Maes writes that because of its independence from the rest of
    the work,</p>
      <p>For a long time, the introduction posed an enigma to
    analysts and critics alike.... The key to the link between the
    introduction and what follows is ... Tchaikovsky's gift of
    hiding motivic connections behind what appears to be a flash of
    melodic inspiration. The opening melody comprises the most
    important motivic core elements for the entire work, something
    that is not immediately obvious, owing to its lyric quality.
    However, a closer analysis shows that the themes of the three
    movements are subtly linked. Tchaikovsky presents his
    structural material in a spontaneous, lyrical manner, yet with
    a high degree of planning and calculation.</p>
      <p>Maes continues by mentioning that all the themes are tied
    together by a strong motivic link. These themes include the
    Ukrainian folk song "Oy, kryatshe, kryatche ..." as the first
    theme of the first movement proper, the French 
    <i>chansonette</i>, "Il faut s'amuser, danser et rire."
    (Translated as: One must have fun, dance and laugh) in the
    middle section of the second movement and a Ukrainian 
    <i>vsnyanka</i>or greeting to spring which appears as the first
    theme of the finale; the second theme of the finale is
    motivically derived from the Russian folk song "Podoydi,
    podoydy vo Tsar-Gorod" and also shares this motivic bond. The
    relationship between them has often been ascribed to chance
    because they were all well known songs at the time Tchaikovsky
    composed the concerto. It seems likely, though, that he used
    these songs precisely because of their motivic connection and
    used them where he felt necessary. "Selecting folkloristic
    material," Maes writes, "went hand in hand with planning the
    large-scale structure of the work."</p>
      <p>Tchaikovsky authority Professor David Brown essentially
    agrees with Maes, further suggesting that Alexander Borodin's
    First Symphony may have given him both the idea to write such
    an introduction and to link the work motivically as he does,
    though he also mentions a four-note musical phrase ciphered
    from Tchaikovsky's own name and a three-note phrase likewise
    taken from the name of soprano Désirée Artôt, with whom the
    composer had been engaged some years before.</p>
      <p>There is some confusion as to whom the concerto was
    originally dedicated. It was long thought that Tchaikovsky
    initially dedicated the work to Nikolai Rubinstein, and Michael
    Steinberg writes that Rubinstein's name is crossed off the
    autograph score. However, Brown writes that there is actually
    no truth in the assertion that the work was written to be
    dedicated to Rubinstein. Tchaikovsky did hope that Rubinstein
    would perform the work at one of the 1875 concerts of the
    Russian Musical Society in Moscow. For this reason he showed
    the work to him and another musical friend, Nikolai Hubert, at
    the Moscow Conservatory on December 24, 1874/January 5, 1875,
    just three days after finishing its composition. Brown writes,
    "This occasion has become one of the most notorious incidents
    in the composer's biography." Three years later Tchaikovsky
    shared what happened with his patroness, Nadezhda von Meck:</p>
      <p>I played the first movement. Not a single word, not a single
    remark! If you knew how stupid and intolerable is the situation
    of a man who cooks and sets before a friend a meal, which he
    proceeds to eat in silence! Oh, for one word, for friendly
    attack, but for God's sake one word of sympathy, even if not of
    praise. Rubinstein was amassing his storm, and Hubert was
    waiting to see what would happen, and that there would be a
    reason for joining one side or the other. Above all I did not
    want sentence on the artistic aspect. My need was for remarks
    about the virtuoso piano techinque. R's eloquent silence was of
    the greatest significance. He seemed to be saying: "My friend,
    how can I speak of detail when the whole thing is antipathetic?
    I fortified myself with patience and played through to the end.
    Still silence. I stood up and asked, "Well?" Then a torrent
    poured from Nikolay Grigoryevich's mouth, gentle at first, then
    more and more growing into the sound of a Jupiter Tonana. It
    turned out that my concerto was worthless and unplayable;
    passages were so fragmented, so clumsy, so badly written that
    they were beyond rescue; the work itself was bad, vulgar; in
    places I had stolen from other composers; only two or three
    pages were worth preserving; the rest must be thrown away or
    completely rewritten. "Here, for instance, this—now what's all
    that? (he caricatured my music on the piano) "And this? How can
    anyone ..." etc., etc. The chief thing I can't reproduce is the
    
    <i>tone</i>in which all this was uttered. In a word, a
    disinterested person in the room might have thought I was a
    maniac, a talented, senseless hack who had come to submit his
    rubbish to an eminent musician. Having noted my obstinate
    silence, Hubert was astonished and shocked that such a ticking
    off was being given to a man who had already written a great
    deal and given a course in free composition at the
    Conservatory, that such a contemptuous judgment without appeal
    was pronounced over him, such a judgment without appeal was
    pronounced over him, such a judgment as you would not pronounce
    over a pupil with the slightest talent who had neglected some
    of his tasks—then he began to explain N.G.'s judgment, not
    disputing it in the least but just softening that which His
    Excellency had expressed with too little ceremony.</p>
      <p>I was not only astounded but outraged by the whole scene. I
    am no longer a boy trying his hand at composition, and I no
    longer need lessons from anyone, especially when they are
    delivered so harshly and unfriendlily. I need and shall always
    need friendly criticism, but there was nothing resembling
    friendly criticism. It was indiscriminate, determined censure,
    delivered in such a way as to wound me to the quick. I left the
    room without a word and went upstairs. In my agitation and rage
    I could not say a thing. Presently R. enjoined me, and seeing
    how upset I was he asked me into one of the distant rooms.
    There he repeated that my concerto was impossible, pointed out
    many places where it would have to be completely revised, and
    said that if within a limited time I reworked the concerto
    according to his demands, then he would do me the honor of
    playing my thing at his concert. 
    <i>"I shall not alter a single note,"</i>I answered, 
    <i>"I shall publish the work exactly as it is!"</i>This I
    did.</p>
      <p>Tchaikovsky biographer John Warrack mentions that, even if
    Tchaikovsky were restating the facts in his favor, "it was, at
    the very least, tactless of Rubinstein not to see how much he
    would upset the notoriously touchy Tchaikovsky.... It has,
    moreover, been a long-enduring habit for Russians, concerned
    about the role of their creative work, to introduce the concept
    of 'correctness' as a major aesthetic consideration, hence to
    submit to direction and criticism in a way unfamiliar in the
    West, from Balakirev and Stasov organizing Tchaikovsky's works
    according to plans of their own, to, in our own day, official
    intervention and the willingness of even major composers to pay
    attention to it."</p>
      <p>Warrack adds that Rubinstein's criticisms fell into three
    categories. First, he thought the writing of the solo part was
    bad, "and certainly there are passages which even the greatest
    virtuoso is glad to survive unscathed, and others in which
    elaborate difficulties are almost inaudible beneath the
    orchestra." Second, he mentioned "outside influences and
    unevenness of invention ... but it must be conceded that the
    music is uneven and that [it] would, like all works, seem the
    more uneven on a first hearing before its style had been
    properly understood." Third, the work probably sounded awkward
    to a conservative musician such as Rubinstein. While the
    introduction in the "wrong" key of D flat (for a composition
    supposed to be written in B flat minor) may have taken
    Rubinstein aback, Warrrack explains, he may have been
    "precipitate in condemning the work on this account or for the
    formal structure of all that follows."</p>
      <p>Brown writes that it is not known why Tchaikovsky next
    approached German pianist Hans von Bülow to premiere the work,
    although the composer had heard Bülow play in Moscow earlier in
    1874 and had been taken with the pianist's combination of
    intellect and passion, and the pianist was likewise an admirer
    of Tchaikovsky's music. Bülow was preparing to go on a tour of
    America. This meant that the concerto would be premiered half a
    world away from Moscow. Brown suggests that Rubinstein's
    comments may have deeply shaken him about the concerto, though
    he did not change the work and finished orchestrating it the
    following month, and that his confidence in the piece may have
    been so shaken that he wanted the public to hear it in a place
    where he would not have to personally endure any humiliation if
    it did not fare well. Tchaikovsky dedicated the work to Bülow,
    who described the work as "so original and noble" (although he
    later dropped the concerto from his repertoire).</p>
      <p>The first performance of the original version took place on
    October 25, 1875 in Boston, Massachusetts, conducted by
    Benjamin Johnson Lang and with Bülow as soloist. Bülow had
    initially engaged a different conductor, but they quarrelled,
    and Lang was brought in at short notice. Although the premiere
    was a resounding success, George Whitefield Chadwick, who was
    in the audience, recalled in a memoir years later: "They had
    not rehearsed much and the trombones got in wrong in the
    ‘tutti’ in the middle of the first movement, whereupon Bülow
    sang out in a perfectly audible voice, 
    <i>The brass may go to hell</i>". Interestingly, Benjamin
    Johnson Lang himself appeared as soloist in a performance of
    the concerto with the Boston Symphony Orchestra on February 20,
    1885, under Leopold Damrosch.</p>
      <p>The Russian premiere took place on November 13, 1875 in
    Saint Petersburg, with the Russian pianist Gustav Kross and
    Czech conductor Eduard Nápravník. In Tchaikovsky's estimation,
    Kross reduced the work to "an atrocious cacophony". The Moscow
    premiere took place on December 3, 1875, with Sergei Taneyev as
    soloist. The conductor was none other than Nikolai Rubinstein,
    the same man who had comprehensively criticised the work less
    than a year earlier. Rubinstein had come to see its merits, and
    he played the solo part many times throughout Europe. He even
    insisted that Tchaikovsky entrust the premiere of his Second
    Piano Concerto to him, and would have done so had he had not
    died. At that time, Tchaikovsky considered rededicating the
    work to Taneyev, who had performed it splendidly, but
    ultimately the dedication went to von Bülow.</p>
      <p>Despite his declaring to Rubinstein that he would "publish
    the concerto exactly as it stands" (something that the composer
    actually did), in 1876 Tchaikovsky happily accepted advice on
    improving the piano writing from German pianist Edward
    Dannreuther, who had given the London premiere of the work, and
    from Russian pianist Alexander Siloti several years later. The
    full chords played by the soloist at the opening of the
    concerto may in fact have been Siloti's idea, as they do not
    appear in the first two editions of the concerto. In the two
    earlier editions, the piano plays arpeggios over a limited
    range of the keyboard while the strings play the opening
    theme.</p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <strong class="selflink">
Piano Concerto No. 1 in B flat minor, Op. 23
</strong> ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Piano Concerto No. 2 in G
      major, Op. 44 ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Piano Concerto No. 3 in E
      flat major, Op. 75 ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Violin Concerto in D major,
      Op. 35</span>
      </p>
      <p>List of compositions by Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
