<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Before_The_Next_Teardrop_Falls_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Before_The_Next_Teardrop_Falls_(song)</songId>
   <title>Before the Next Teardrop Falls</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freddy_Fender</artistId>
      <artistName>Freddy Fender</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1975-05-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Before the Next Teardrop Falls</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 1975</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1974</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Country</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:33</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>ABC-Dot Records 17540</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Vivian Keith</writer>
      <writer>Ben Peters</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Huey Meaux</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Before the Next Teardrop Falls" is an American country and
    pop song written by Vivian Keith and Ben Peters, and most
    famously recorded by Freddy Fender.</p>
      <p>The song was written in the late 1960s and had been recorded
    more than two dozen times. At best, the song had achieved
    modest success by other performers. Duane Dee took a version to
    the top 10 of the Billboard Hot 100 in 1965, and Linda Martell
    sent her version to No. 33 on the country charts.</p>
      <p>In 1974, record producer Huey P Meaux approached Fender
    about overdubbing vocals for an instrumental track. Fender
    agreed, performing the song bi-lingual style — singing the
    first verse in English, then repeating the verse in
    Spanish.</p>
      <p>"The recording only took a few minutes," Fender once told an
    interviewer. "I was glad to get it over with and I thought that
    would be the last of it."</p>
      <p>However, "Before the Next Teardrop Falls" immediately took
    off in popularity when released to country radio in January
    1975. The song ascended to No. 1 on the 
    <i>Billboard magazine</i>Hot Country Singles chart in March,
    spending two weeks atop the chart. Thereafter, the song caught
    on just as strongly at Top 40 radio stations, and it wasn't
    long before Fender had a No. 1 Billboard Hot 100 hit as
    well.</p>
      <p>The song is about a man's undaunted determination to save
    his heart for the just-departed object of his deep (but
    unrequited) love, and sincere hope that should the woman's new
    relationship not work out, she will remember his love and
    return to him.</p>
      <p>A showcase of Fender's fluttering tenor and Meaux's Tex-Mex
    musical styling, "Before the Next Teardrop Falls" jump-started
    his career. (Fender's career had stalled in 1960 after his
    arrest on drug charges.) In the months and years that followed,
    Fender recorded several bi-lingual standards which became major
    hits, most notably "Secret Love."</p>
      <p>BMI Songwriter Sterling Blythe claimed that he had sold the
    rights to a portfolio of songs, among them "Before the Next
    Teardrop Falls," for $4,500 to settle debts when he left
    Nashville for the West Coast prior to Fender's recording. Until
    his death in Sacramento in 2001, Blythe carried a newspaper
    clipping about Fender's bankruptcy filing in his wallet.</p>
      <p>"Before The Next Teardrop Falls" was certified gold for
    sales of 1 million units by the Recording Industry Association
    of America. [3] The song also won the Single of the Year award
    from the Country Music Association in 1975, and was
    instrumental in Fender also winning that year's Album of the
    Year and Male Vocalist of the Year awards.</p>
      <p>"Before the Next Teardrop Falls" was one of six songs
    released in 1975 that topped both the Billboard Hot 100 and 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Country Singles charts. The other songs
    were "(Hey Won't You Play) Another Somebody Done Somebody Wrong
    Song" by B.J. Thomas, "Rhinestone Cowboy" by Glen Campbell;
    "Thank God I'm a Country Boy" and the two-sided hit "I'm
    Sorry"/"Calypso," both by John Denver; and "Convoy" by C.W.
    McCall.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
