<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/This_Diamond_Ring 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/This_Diamond_Ring</songId>
   <title>This Diamond Ring</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gary_Lewis_%26_the_Playboys</artistId>
      <artistName>Gary Lewis &amp; the Playboys</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1965-02-20</week>
      <week>1965-02-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"This Diamond Ring" is a 1965 pop song written by Al Kooper,
    Bob Brass and Irwin Levine. The song's first appearance on the
    Billboard Hot 100 chart was a bubbling-under single by Sammy
    Ambrose that reached #117 on January 9, 1965. The hit record,
    which went to number one on the Billboard chart, is attributed
    to Gary Lewis &amp; the Playboys though none of the Playboys
    played their instruments on the recording and Lewis' vocals
    were heavily supported by Ron Hicklin's overdubs. The session
    drummer was Hal Blaine, Carol Kaye played bass and Leon Russell
    both played keyboards and assisted with production. The song
    was carried through Snuff Garrett Records.</p>
      <p>Stylistically, the song's recording features the then common
    "basic 'combo' instrumentation...(electric guitar, organ, bass,
    drums), modal (dorian) inflections in the harmony and melody of
    the verse and a basic rock beat pattern." Unusually the chorus
    features timpani and the transition between verse and chorus
    creates a daring modulation from C minor (dorian) to G-flat
    major.</p>
      <p>"The musical style", writes Brackett, "skims aspects from
    contemporary rock songs, and is then produced and arranged from
    the vantage point of 'easy-listening' music." The song's
    harmonic progression resembles those of Beatles songs such as
    the G-flat/F/E-flat/D-flat descending bass line ("Bad to Me")
    and the vi-iii movement ("Please Please me", "I Want to Hold
    Your Hand", "She Loves You", "And I Love Her" and others). The
    melodic turn on "true" of "if you find someone whose heart is 
    <i>true</i>" resembles those in "Please Please Me" ("Last night
    I said these words to 
    <i>my</i>girl") and "Do You Want to Know a Secret" ("nobody
    knows, just we 
    <i>two</i>").</p>
      <p>Al Kooper has reportedly stated many times that he was
    unhappy with the record and had originally hoped the song would
    be recorded by a group like The Drifters based upon the
    original demo of the song as recorded by Jimmy Radcliffe,
    although it has been his biggest commercial success as a
    songwriter. Kooper would later re-visit the song, recording a
    funky version for his 1976 album "Act Like Nothing's
    Wrong".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
