<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Duke_of_Earl 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Duke_of_Earl</songId>
   <title>Duke of Earl</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gene_Chandler</artistId>
      <artistName>Gene Chandler</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1962-02-17</week>
      <week>1962-02-24</week>
      <week>1962-03-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>January 13, 1962</released>
   <recorded>1961</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
      <genre>Doo Wop</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Vee-Jay Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Gene Chandler</writer>
      <writer>Earl Edwards</writer>
      <writer>Bernice Williams</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Duke of Earl" is a 1962 number-one song, originally by Gene
    Chandler. It is the best known of Chandler's songs, and he
    subsequently dubbed himself 'The Duke of Earl'.</p>
      <p>"Duke of Earl" debuted on the Billboard Hot 100 chart on
    January 13, 1962, and held the number-one spot for three weeks.
    It was on the Hot 100 for a total of 15 weeks.</p>
      <p>In 1983, Youth Brigade also covered "Duke of Earl" on their
    critically acclaimed debut album 
    <i>Sound &amp; Fury"</i>
      </p>
      <p>Wayne Fontana and the Mindbenders released a cover version
    in 1964. Another cover was recorded by the UK based doo-wop
    outfit Darts in 1979. It reached #6 in the UK Singles
    Chart.</p>
      <p>Cornell Campbell did a reggae version on the Trojan Records
    label.</p>
      <p>Sha Na Na, a rock and roll revival band, performed 
    <i>Duke of Earl</i>live at the Woodstock Festival of 1969.</p>
      <p>The Beach Boys and Red Hot Chili Peppers have also played
    their version of the song whilst on tour. Cypress Hill sampled
    "Duke of Earl" into one of their own hit songs, "Hand on the
    Pump", on their 1991 self-titled album.</p>
      <p>The song has also been sung by The Nylons, The Four Tops,
    New Edition, and the Van-Dells.</p>
      <p>In his song "Keeping The Faith", Billy Joel sings 
    <i>"I thought I was the Duke of Earl / When I made it with a
    red-haired girl in a Chevrolet"</i>.</p>
      <p>Reference is made to the Duke of Earl as being a friend of
    Wolfman Jack in The Guess Who's song, "Clap for the
    Wolfman".</p>
      <p>In the Hall &amp; Oates' song "Diddy Doo Wopp (I Hear the
    Voices)" from the album 
    <i>Voices,</i>Daryl Hall sings, 
    <i>"Charlie liked the Beatles</i>/ 
    <i>Sam, he liked "Rich Girl"</i>/ 
    <i>I'm still hung up on the Duke of Earl"</i>.</p>
      <p>In the film, 
    <i>Carry on Behind</i>, Ernie (played by Jack Douglas) can be
    seen wearing a Duke of Earl T-shirt.</p>
      <p>In the film 
    <i>The Man with Two Brains</i>, a prostitute (Randi Brooks)
    sings the song (described it as her "favorite") revealing her
    unexpectedly unpleasant and squeaky voice (she pronounces it
    "Dook, Dook, Dook, Dook of Oil..."). This is also possibly
    contributed to the name of the modern-age Green Arrow villain,
    the Duke of Oil.</p>
      <p>In the film 
    <i>King Ralph</i>the titular character played by John Goodman
    sings the song as the end credits roll.</p>
      <p>In the film 
    <i>The Wrong Guys</i>, John Goodman plays the character Duke,
    leader of the Earl Gang, who are wanted by the FBI.</p>
      <p>The song was performed by the rock and roll comedy group Sha
    Na Na as part of their set at Woodstock Festival in 1969.</p>
      <p>In the 
    <i>Magnum P.I.</i>episode "Going Home", Magnum and a friend are
    seen singing a drunken a cappella of the song.</p>
      <p>The 'Duke of Earl' is mentioned in the Men Without Hats song
    "Pop Goes The World".</p>
      <p>Datamation humor columnist Chris Miksanek titled his "Over
    the Edge" online weblinks companion "The Duke of URL" which ran
    from 1998 until 2001.</p>
      <p>In the Don Henley song "They're Not Here, They're Not
    Coming", he sings 
    <i>"No place for sentiment, no room for romance"</i>/ 
    <i>"Bring back the Duke of Earl"</i>.</p>
      <p>In the episode "Kelly Does Hollywood" of the show 
    <i>Married... With Children</i>, Al Bundy attempts to get on
    Kelly's show by performing a dramatic reading of the song.</p>
      <p>A reference to this song is mentioned in an episode of 
    <i>My Name is Earl</i>entitled "Burn Victim".</p>
      <p>In his song "Window On The World", John Hiatt sings 
    <i>"The Queen of Sheba meets the Duke of Earl"</i>.</p>
      <p>In The Dead Milkmen song "Punk Rock Girl", her father is
    referred to as the Duke of Earl (as well as the Vice
    President).</p>
      <p>The song is parodied in the show The Critic referring to
    Duke Phillips and sung by parodies of U.S. Presidents Ronald
    Reagan, George H.W. Bush, Gerald Ford, Jimmy Carter, and Bill
    Clinton.</p>
      <p>The song was parodied in a 1990s commercial for Hellmann's
    Dijonnaise ("Di-di-di-Dijonnaise").</p>
      <p>At New York Ranger hockey games at Madison Square Garden,
    the song is usually played on the arena organ after the
    opposing team scores a goal.</p>
      <p>The song was also parodied from the late 1980s through to
    the early 2000s for a commercial in Australia for a hair care
    company called Decore.</p>
      <p>Steely Dan use the lyric "If you grew up in Amsterdam, then
    I'm the Duke of Earl" in the song "Slang of Ages" on their 2003
    album "Everything Must Go"</p>
      <p>In 
    <i>Doonesbury</i>Duke's Son is named Earl.</p>
      <p>{{succession box</p>
      <p>}}</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
