<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rudolph_the_Red-Nosed_Reindeer 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rudolph_the_Red-Nosed_Reindeer</songId>
   <title>Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gene_Autry</artistId>
      <artistName>Gene Autry</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1950-01-07</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>Rudolph the Red-nosed Reindeer is a character created in a
    story and song by the same name. The story was created by
    Robert L. May in 1939 as part of his employment with Montgomery
    Ward.</p>
      <p>The story is owned by The Rudolph Company, L.P. and has been
    sold in numerous forms including a popular song, a television
    special (done in stop-motion animation), and a feature film.
    Character Arts, LLC [1] manages the licensing for the Rudolph
    Company, L.P. Although the story and song are not public
    domain, Rudolph has become a figure of Christmas folklore.</p>
      <p>The song tells the tale of Santa Claus's ninth and lead
    reindeer who possesses an unusually red-colored nose that gives
    off its own light (bioluminescence), powerful enough to
    illuminate the team's path through inclement winter
    weather.</p>
      <p>Robert L. May created Rudolph in 1939 as an assignment for
    Montgomery Ward. The retailer had been buying and giving away
    coloring books for Christmas every year and it was decided that
    creating their own book would save money. In its first year of
    publication, 2.4 million copies of Rudolph's story were
    distributed by Montgomery Ward. The story is written as a poem
    in the meter of "'Twas the Night Before Christmas."</p>
      <p>Johnny Marks decided to adapt May's story into a song, which
    through the years has been recorded by many artists. It was
    first sung commercially by crooner Harry Brannon on New York
    city radio in the latter part of 1948 before Gene Autry
    recorded it formally in 1949, and has since filtered into the
    popular consciousness.</p>
      <p>The lyric "All of the other reindeer" can be misheard in
    dialects with the cot-caught merger as the mondegreen "Olive,
    the other reindeer", and has given rise to another character
    featured in her own Christmas television special, 
    <i>Olive, the Other Reindeer</i>.</p>
      <p>The song in its Finnish translation, 
    <i>Petteri Punakuono</i>, has led to Rudolph's general
    acceptance in the mythology as Joulupukki, the Finnish Santa's
    lead reindeer. However, in Finland, Santa's reindeer do not
    fly.</p>
      <p>Autry's version of the song also holds the distinction of
    being the only number one hit to fall completely off the chart
    after hitting #1 the week of Christmas 1949.. Nonetheless, it
    sold 2.5 million copies the first year, eventually selling a
    total of 25 million, and it remained the second best-selling
    record of all time until the 1980s.</p>
      <p>In 1953, Billy May recorded "Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer
    Mambo" with vocals by Alvin Stoller.</p>
      <p>Rudolph's first screen appearance came in 1944, in the form
    of a cartoon short produced by Max Fleischer for the Jam Handy
    Corporation, that was more faithful to May's original story
    than Marks's song (which had not yet been written). It was
    reissued in 1948 with the song added.</p>
      <p>On December 16, 2009, Mike Nelson featured this version in a
    live Rifftrax Christmas show in San Diego which was broadcast
    to select theaters in the United States.</p>
      <p>In 1958, Golden Books published an illustrated storybook,
    adapted by Barbara Shook Hazen and illustrated by Richard
    Scarry. The book is similar in story to the Max Fleischer
    cartoon short. Although it is one of the more memorable
    versions of the story in book form, it is apparently no longer
    in print. However, a revised Golden Books version of the
    storybook has since been issued.</p>
      <p>The reindeer made his television debut on NBC in 1964, when
    Rankin/Bass produced a stop-motion animated TV special.</p>
      <p>In 1975, a sequel to the Rankin-Bass original special was
    produced, titled 
    <i>Rudolph's Shiny New Year,</i>and then a third in 1979 titled
    
    <i>Rudolph and Frosty's Christmas in July</i>. The 2001 film 
    <i>Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer and the Island of Misfit
    Toys</i>, while it used the same characters, was produced by a
    different company, and it's unclear whether or not it should be
    considered as part of this particular canon (see the next
    section).</p>
      <p>An animated feature film remake of the story was produced in
    1998, titled 
    <i>Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer: The Movie</i>. It received
    only a limited theatrical release before debuting on home
    video. Despite this it has garnered a base of dedicated fans as
    well as criticisms of many of the songs. Its inclusion of a
    villain character, Stormella, and a love interest, Zoey, for
    Rudolph as well as a small sidekick, Slyly, and a strong
    protector character are very derivative of the Rankin-Bass
    adaptation of the story as opposed to the original tale and
    song (the characters of Stormella, Zoey, Arrow, Slyly and
    Leonard closely parallel the Rankin-Bass characters of The
    Bumble, Clarice, Fireball, Hermey the Dentist, and Yukon
    Cornelius respectively). The movie amplifies the early
    back-story of Rudolph's harassment by his schoolmates
    (primarily an older fawn named Arrow) during his formative
    years.</p>
      <p>GoodTimes Entertainment, the producers of this film, brought
    back most of the same production team for a CGI-animated
    sequel, 
    <i>Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer and the Island of Misfit
    Toys</i>in 2001. Unlike the film, the sequel licensed the
    original characters from the Rankin-Bass special.</p>
      <p>National Periodical Publications, also known as DC Comics,
    published a series of 13 annuals titled 
    <i>Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer</i>from 1950 to 1962. In
    1972, DC published a 14th edition in an extra-large format.
    Subsequently, they published six more in that format: Limited
    Collectors' Edition C-24, C-33, C-42, C-50 and All-New
    Collectors' Edition C-53, C-60. Additionally, one digest format
    edition was published as The Best of DC #4 (Mar/Apr 1980).</p>
      <p>Two BBC animations carry on the legend by introducing
    Rudolph's son, Robbie the Reindeer. However, Rudolph is never
    directly mentioned by name (references are replaced by a
    character interrupting with the phrase "Don't say that name!"
    or something similar, presumably for copyright reasons.)</p>
      <p>Rudolph is also given a brother, Rusty Reindeer, in the 2006
    American special Holidaze: The Christmas That Almost Didn't
    Happen. Unlike with Robbie, Rudolph's name is mentioned freely
    in the film.</p>
      <p>Michael Fry and T. Lewis have recently given Rudolph another
    brother in a series of 
    <i>Over the Hedge</i>comic strips; an overweight,
    emotionally-damaged reindeer named "Ralph, the Infra-Red nosed
    Reindeer", who has a red nose just like Rudolph's, but his is
    good for defrosting Santa's sleigh and warming up toast ("and
    WAFFLES!!", adds Hammy). He appeared before R.J., Verne, and
    Hammy, enviously complaining about his brother's publicity and
    his anonymity.</p>
      <p>Rudolph has a cousin, Leroy, in Joe Diffie's 1995 song
    "Leroy the Redneck Reindeer".</p>
      <p>Also, in the animated specials produced by both Rankin-Bass
    and GoodTimes Entertainment, Rudolph has been given different
    sets of parents. In Rankin-Bass's holiday special, he was
    Donner's son and his mother was a tan unnamed doe with long
    eyelashes who was simply called "Mrs. Donner." In GoodTimes's
    retelling, Rudolph's father was Blitzen, moving the reindeer up
    just a notch to probably avoid plagiarism, and Blitzen seemed
    to be somewhat younger than Donner telling by the sound of his
    voice. Also, Blitzen was married to a doe named Mitzi played by
    Debbie Reynolds. In this film, Rudolph's three uncles were the
    three reindeer Dasher, Comet, and Cupid. Arrow, Rudolph's
    rival, is Cupid's son, making the two cousins. Robert L. May's
    original book does not name Rudolph's parents.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
