<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invisible_Touch_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invisible_Touch_(song)</songId>
   <title>Invisible Touch</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genesis_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Genesis</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-07-19</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/7a/Invisible_Touch_Single.jpg/200px-Invisible_Touch_Single.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Genesis+Invisible-Touch.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Invisible Touch</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 19, 1986</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Compact Disc</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1985</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:27</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic Records , Vertigo Records</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Genesis</producer>
      <producer>Hugh Padgham</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Invisible Touch" is the title track of the 1986 Genesis
    album of the same name. It is their most successful single of
    all time and was the band's first (and, to date, only)
    number-one single in the United States. It marked the first
    instance of a group following an individual band member to the
    top of the chart. Prior to this song, Phil Collins had notched
    the first four of his seven U.S. number-one solo singles. It
    went to number four in Canada, but only reached number 15 in
    the United Kingdom. It is a meditation on intangibility,
    speaking of a woman whose qualities go beyond what only meets
    the eye.</p>
      <p>Its B-side is the second part of "Domino", titled "The Last
    Domino".</p>
      <p>The song came about during a jam for the second parts of
    another album tracks "Domino/The Last Domino," Mike apparently
    playing a riff while Phil improvises the line "She seems to
    have an invisible touch". It was recorded at the band's studio
    Fisher Lane Farm during 1985 and 1986.</p>
      <p>"Invisible Touch" was bumped out of the number one position
    on the Billboard Hot 100 by "Sledgehammer", performed by the
    former lead singer of Genesis, Peter Gabriel.</p>
      <p>A live version appears on their albums 
    <i>The Way We Walk, Volume One: The Shorts</i>, and 
    <i>Live over Europe 2007</i>. As well as on their DVD's Genesis
    Live at Wembley Stadium, The Way We Walk - Live in Concert and
    When in Rome 2007.</p>
      <p>"Invisible Touch" was performed during the 
    <i>Invisible Touch</i>, 
    <i>We Can't Dance</i>, 
    <i>Calling All Stations</i>(with Ray Wilson on vocals) and 
    <i>Turn It On Again</i>tours. On later tours the song segued
    from "Tonight, Tonight, Tonight" albeit transposed down a key
    to account for the deepening of Phil Collins's voice over the
    years. During the latest tour, the song was the finale
    featuring fireworks going off as the song ended.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Genesis Live - Invisible Touch</i>was a single by Genesis,
    released on limited edition 7" and CD near the end of their
    1991-1992 world tour in support of 
    <i>We Can't Dance</i>. Both formats were numbered and came with
    a booklet; the CD was housed in a box and the vinyl edition in
    a gatefold sleeve.</p>
      <p>The A-side was recorded during this tour, and is the same
    version found on the accompanying live album 
    <i>The Shorts</i>but for some minor edits. The B-sides "Abacab"
    and "The Brazilian" come from the 
    <i>Invisible Touch Tour</i>video.</p>
      <p>The 7" featured an edited version of "Abacab" (it faded out)
    while the CD included whole versions of both songs.</p>
      <p>Like the albums 
    <i>The Shorts</i>and 
    <i>The Longs</i>, and the home video 
    <i>The Way We Walk - In Concert</i>, the title of the record
    was prefixed by "Genesis Live", with "(Live)" appearing as a
    suffix on the back sleeve and on the disc itself.</p>
      <p>During live performances of "Invisible Touch" Phil Collins
    substituted the line 
    <i>"And though she will mess up your life"</i>with 
    <i>"And though she will fuck up your life"</i>. Consequently
    the swear word was bleeped out on the single.</p>
      <p>Unlike the original recording of the song, this live version
    was a Top 10 hit in the UK, reaching number seven. In one of
    the interview sections on the 
    <i>Way We Walk - Live in Concert</i>DVD, Phil Collins jokes
    about re-releasing the song until it finally becomes a hit.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
