<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Let_the_Sun_Go_Down_on_Me 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Let_the_Sun_Go_Down_on_Me</songId>
   <title>Don't Let the Sun Go Down on Me</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Michael</artistId>
      <artistName>George Michael and Elton John</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1992-02-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/eb/Elton7688.jpg/200px-Elton7688.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/George-Michael-and-Elton-John+Don-t-Let-the-Sun-Go-Down-on-Me.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Caribou</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>20 May 1974</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7-inch</format>
      <format>audio cassette</format>
      <format>compact disc</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Caribou Ranch</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:35</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MCA , DJM , Rocket/Phonogram</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Elton John</writer>
      <writer>Bernie Taupin</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Gus Dudgeon</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Don't Let the Sun Go Down on Me" is the first single from
    British musician Elton John's 1974 album 
    <i>Caribou</i>; it was released that year during the latter
    half of May in the United Kingdom, and on 10 June in the United
    States.</p>
      <p>In the song, Elton sings to someone he has helped and from
    whom he is now experiencing rejection:</p>
      <p>I took a chance and changed your way of life, but you
    misread my meaning when I met you, closed the door and left me
    blinded by the light, don't let the sun go down on me, although
    I search myself, it's always someone else I see.</p>
      <p>It was written with the other songs on the album during a
    ten day period in January 1974.</p>
      <p>The chorus of the song is supported with a horn arrangement
    by Del Newman, and features backing vocals of the Beach Boys'
    Carl Wilson and Bruce Johnston, and Toni Tennille. Also on the
    song are percussion accents provided by Ray Cooper and a
    mellotron played by Dave Hentschel.</p>
      <p>As successful as the 1974 record had been, it was as a duet
    with George Michael that "Don't Let The Sun Go Down on Me" had
    its greatest success. The pair had performed the song at the
    Live Aid concert in 1985. Recorded live at a concert at Wembley
    Arena, London on 25 March 1991 when Elton John was a surprise
    guest of George Michael, the duet became a massive hit on both
    sides of the Atlantic. It was released later that year and
    reached number one on the UK singles chart for two weeks in
    December 1991 and a single week on the Billboard Hot 100 in
    February 1992.</p>
      <p>The footage used for the music video of the song was taken
    from a "live" concert in Chicago with 70,000 fans. "The video
    was actually shot over several days," confirms Michael
    Pagnotta, George's publicist. "It was shot in an airline hangar
    in Burbank where George had been rehearsing; Elton came in for
    a night and they ran through the song a couple of times. Then
    the song was filmed in its entirety live in Chicago in the
    middle of October as part of that 
    <i>Cover to Cover</i>tour, and when Elton came out from the
    wings, that place went crazy." It appears on John's 
    <i>Love Songs</i>compilation. The proceeds from the single were
    divided among 10 different charities for children, AIDS and
    education.</p>
      <p>Both John and Michael performed at the Freddie Mercury
    Tribute Concert a year after the single's release.</p>
      <p>"Don't Let the Sun Go Down on Me" charted on 1 June 1974 in
    Great Britain, making it to number 16. In the United States, it
    was released while "Bennie and the Jets" was still in the Top
    40, and reached the Top 10 after four weeks. On 10 August, the
    song's two week stay at number 2 ended. It could not oust John
    Denver's "Annie's Song," Roberta Flack's "Feel Like Makin'
    Love" nor Paper Lace's "The Night Chicago Died" from the top
    spot. But a number 2 pinnacle guaranteed it further airplay. By
    September it became Elton's fourth gold single.</p>
      <p>"Don't Let the Sun Go Down on Me" has been a popular song
    for other artists to perform or record as well. Jay Chattaway
    arranged this song into a jazz version, which Maynard Ferguson
    first performed in the 1970s show "The Mark of Jazz" with host
    Sid Mark. This live version stems from around 1975; it was
    never recorded onto an album.</p>
      <p>Joe Cocker recorded his version of the song on "The Best of
    Joe Cocker".</p>
      <p>Roger Daltrey (who also appeared at the Freddie Mercury
    Tribute Concert) sang it for the 1987 soundtrack 
    <i>The Lost Boys</i>.</p>
      <p>African-American Gospel group The Winans released a version
    of the song on their album Decisions in 1987</p>
      <p>Gloria Estefan recorded it in 1989.</p>
      <p>Jazz singer Oleta Adams recorded it on the 1991 tribute
    album 
    <i>Two Rooms: Celebrating the Songs of Elton John &amp; Bernie
    Taupin</i>. Late 1990s punk cover specialty act Me First and
    the Gimme Gimmes also took it on. In December 2002 David
    Sneddon won the BBC's first Fame Academy show singing his
    version of "Don't Let The Sun Go Down On Me" and his own song
    "Stop Living The Lie". Sneddon also put his version of Elton's
    song on the B side, which was number one in the UK Singles
    Chart in January 2003.</p>
      <p>In 2003, Vanessa Carlton performed the song during the Elton
    John Tribute Concert. Also in the 2000s, "Don't Let the Sun Go
    Down on Me" has become a frequent selection of reality
    television singing contestants. Most notably, Clay Aiken's
    performance of it in the semi-final wild-card round of the
    second season of 
    <i>American Idol</i>propelled him into the finals and later a
    very successful recording career. "Don't Let" became one of
    Aiken's signature performances, and was reprised in the fifth
    season in a surprise appearance involving Michael Sandecki.
    David Archuleta's performance of it during the American Idol
    Season 7 Final received a lot of praise from all the Judges and
    even prompted Simon to proclaim it to be Archuleta's best
    performance on the show. Other such contestants who have
    performed it include 
    <i>American Idol</i>'s Justin Guarini, Jasmine Trias, Bo Bice,
    Jorge Nuñez, 
    <i>Canadian Idol</i>'s Tyler Hamilton, 
    <i>Australian Idol</i>'s Nathan Brake, 
    <i>New Zealand Idol</i>'s Clinton Randell, and 
    <i>The X Factor</i>'s Journey South and Joe McElderry, who
    received a standing ovation from all the judges, which was the
    first time in the series. Lately, it has become popular on
    Spanish show "Operación Triunfo", sung by Moritz. Forest
    Whitaker sang "Don't Let" in a comedy skit when he hosted the
    television show 
    <i>Saturday Night Live</i>on 10 February 2007.</p>
      <p>The song is covered by the company Wavegroup for the music
    video game Karaoke Revolution Presents:American Idol.</p>
      <p>Duet version</p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Careless
      Whisper" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"A Different
      Corner" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Want Your
      Sex" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Hard Day" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Faith" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Father
      Figure" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"One More Try" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Monkey" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Kissing a
      Fool" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Praying for
      Time" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Waiting for That
      Day" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Mother's
      Pride" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Freedom! '90" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Heal the
      Pain" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Cowboys and
      Angels" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Too Funky" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Killer" / "Papa Was a
      Rollin' Stone" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Jesus to a
      Child" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Fastlove" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Spinning the
      Wheel" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Older / I Can't Make You
      Love Me" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Star People
      '97" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"You Have Been Loved / The
      Strangest Thing '97" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Outside" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Freeek!" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Shoot the
      Dog" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Amazing" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Flawless (Go to the
      City)" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Round Here" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"John and Elvis Are
      Dead" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"An Easier
      Affair" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"December Song (I Dreamed of
      Christmas)"</span>
      </p>
      <p>Discography</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
