<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Midnight_Train_to_Georgia 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Midnight_Train_to_Georgia</songId>
   <title>Midnight Train to Georgia</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gladys_Knight_%26_the_Pips</artistId>
      <artistName>Gladys Knight &amp; the Pips</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1973-10-27</week>
      <week>1973-11-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/1a/Midnight_To_Geo.jpg/200px-Midnight_To_Geo.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Gladys-Knight-the-Pips+Midnight-Train-to-Georgia.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Imagination</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 1973</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" vinyl single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1973</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:38</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Buddah</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jim Weatherly</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Tony Camillo &amp; Gladys Knight &amp; the Pips</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Midnight Train to Georgia" is a 1973 number-one hit single
    by Gladys Knight &amp; the Pips, their second release after
    departing Motown Records for Buddah Records. Written by Jim
    Weatherly, and included on the Pips' 1973 LP 
    <i>Imagination</i>, "Midnight Train to Georgia" won the 1974
    Grammy Award for Best R&amp;B Vocal Performance By A Duo, Group
    Or Chorus and has become Knight's signature song.</p>
      <p>The theme of the song is how romantic love can conquer
    differences in background. The boyfriend of the song's narrator
    is a failed musician who left his native Georgia to move to Los
    Angeles to become a "superstar, but he didn't get far". He
    decides to give up, and "go back to the life he once knew."
    Despite the fact that she's settled and secure in herself, the
    narrator decides to move to Georgia with him:</p>
      <p>The song was originally recorded by singer Cissy Houston,
    and released as a single a year earlier. Jim Weatherly had
    recorded one of his own songs, "Midnight Plane to Houston," on
    Jimmy Bowen's Amos Records. "It was based on a conversation I
    had with somebody... about taking a midnight plane to Houston,"
    Weatherly recalls. "I wrote it as a kind of a country song.
    Then we sent the song to a guy named Sonny Limbo in Atlanta and
    he wanted to cut it on Cissy Houston... he asked if I minded if
    he changed the title to 'Midnight Train to Georgia.' And I
    said, I don't mind. Just don't change the rest of the song.'"
    Weatherly told Songfacts that the phone coversation was with
    Farrah Fawcett and he used Fawcett and his friend Lee Majors
    who she'd just started dating, "as kind of like characters."
    Cissy Houston took Weatherly's song into the R&amp;B chart. Her
    version can be found on the CD 
    <i>Midnight Train to Georgia: The Janus Years</i>. Also,
    Weatherly's version began with "Nashville (not L.A.) proved too
    much for the man."</p>
      <p>Weatherly's publisher forwarded the song to Gladys Knight
    and the Pips, who followed Houston's lead and kept the title
    "Midnight Train to Georgia." Their second single for Buddah, it
    debuted on the Hot 100 at number seventy-one and became the
    group's first number-one hit eight weeks later, as well as
    reaching number one on the soul singles chart, their fifth on
    that chart. On the UK Singles Chart, it peaked at number
    ten.</p>
      <p>"Midnight Train to Georgia" was inducted into the Grammy
    Hall of Fame in 1999. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>ranked it #432 on their list of the 500
    Greatest Songs of All Time.</p>
      <p>In her autobiography, 
    <i>Between Each Line of Pain and Glory,</i>Gladys Knight wrote
    that she hoped the song was a comfort to the many thousands who
    come each year from elsewhere to Los Angeles to realize the
    dream of being in motion pictures or music, but then fail to
    realize that dream and plunge into despair.</p>
      <p>The song was featured during a scene in the 1978 film 
    <i>The Deer Hunter</i>by director Michael Cimino, in which the
    character Michael (Robert DeNiro) searches for his friend Nick
    (Christopher Walken) in a strip club in Saigon as the girls
    gyrate to "Midnight Train To Georgia". The song was also
    featured in the episode "Episode 210" of the NBC sitcom 
    <i>30 Rock</i>.</p>
      <p>Initial track recorded at Venture Sound Studios,
    Hillsborough, New Jersey, 1973:</p>
      <p>Overdubs recorded at Venture Sound Studios:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
