<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rhinestone_Cowboy_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rhinestone_Cowboy_(song)</songId>
   <title>Rhinestone Cowboy</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glen_Campbell</artistId>
      <artistName>Glen Campbell</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1975-09-06</week>
      <week>1975-09-13</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/16/Rhinestone_Cowboy_Glen_Campbell.jpg/200px-Rhinestone_Cowboy_Glen_Campbell.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Glen-Campbell+Rhinestone-Cowboy.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Rhinestone Cowboy</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 1975 ( U.S. )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>February-March 1975</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Country</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:08</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Larry Weiss</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Rhinestone Cowboy" is a song written by Larry Weiss and
    most famously recorded by country-pop singer Glen Campbell. The
    song enjoyed immense popularity with both country and pop
    audiences when it was released in 1975.</p>
      <p>Weiss wrote and recorded "Rhinestone Cowboy" in 1974, and it
    appeared on his 20th Century Records album 
    <i>Black and Blue Suite</i>. Neither that version, nor a cover
    by Neil Diamond made much of an impression on audiences
    (although Diamond's version did garner adult contemporary
    airplay). In late 1974, Campbell heard the song on the radio
    and, during a tour of Australia decided to learn the song. Soon
    after his return to the United States, Campbell went to Al
    Coury's office at Capitol Records, where he was approached
    about "a great new song" — "Rhinestone Cowboy."</p>
      <p>Several music writers noted that Campbell identified with
    the subject matter of "Rhinestone Cowboy" — survival and making
    it, particularly when the chips are down — very strongly. As
    Steven Thomas Erlewine of Allmusic put it, the song is about a
    veteran artist "who's aware that he's more than paid his dues
    during his career ... but is still surviving, and someday,
    he'll shine just like a rhinestone cowboy."</p>
      <p>Released in May 1975, "Rhinestone Cowboy" immediately caught
    on with both country and pop audiences. The song spent that
    summer climbing both the 
    <i>Billboard magazine</i>Hot Country Singles and Billboard Hot
    100 charts before peaking at No. 1 by season's end - three
    non-consecutive weeks on the country chart, two weeks on the
    Hot 100.</p>
      <p>During the week of September 13 — that was the week the song
    returned to No. 1 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>country chart, after having been nudged out for
    a week by "Feelins'" by Conway Twitty and Loretta Lynn —
    "Rhinestone Cowboy" topped both the country and Hot 100 charts
    simultaneously. This was the first time a song had accomplished
    the feat since November 1961, when "Big Bad John" by Jimmy Dean
    turned the trick.</p>
      <p>"Rhinestone Cowboy" was one of six songs released in 1975
    that topped both the Billboard Hot 100 and 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Country Singles charts. The other songs
    were "Before the Next Teardrop Falls" by Freddy Fender; "(Hey
    Won't You Play) Another Somebody Done Somebody Wrong Song" by
    B.J. Thomas, "Thank God I'm a Country Boy" and "I'm
    Sorry"/"Calypso," both by John Denver; and "Convoy" by C.W.
    McCall.</p>
      <p>The song was also the sole Glen Campbell track in a
    promotional-only compilation album issued by Capitol records
    entitled "The Greatest Music Ever Sold" (Capitol
    SPRO-8511/8512), that was distributed to record stores during
    the 1976 Holiday season as part of Capitol's "Greatest Music
    Ever Sold" campaign, which promoted 15 "Best Of" albums
    released by the record label.</p>
      <p>"Rhinestone Cowboy" was certified gold for sales of 1
    million units by the Recording Industry Association of America.
    [2]</p>
      <p>The song became Glen Campbell's signature song and won
    numerous awards from the Country Music Association, Academy of
    Country Music and American Music Awards. The song also obtained
    nominations for a Grammy Award for Best Country Song as well as
    for Record of the Year, but could not win.</p>
      <p>"Rhinestone Cowboy" served as the basis for the 1984 movie 
    <i>Rhinestone</i>, starring Sylvester Stallone and Dolly
    Parton.</p>
      <p>The song also continues to be heard in movies and
    television, making the soundtracks of 
    <i>High School High</i>and 
    <i>Daddy Day Care</i>, as well as being used in an episode of
    "Desperate Housewives" and "The Jamie Foxx Show."</p>
      <p>"Rhinestone Cowboy" has been covered by Soul Asylum, Belle
    and Sebastian, Charley Pride, White Town, David Hasselhoff, DJ
    Z-Trip &amp; DJ P, Daz Sampson, Radiohead and in an episode of
    Family Guy, There's Something About Paulie, Peter Griffin
    (voiced by Seth MacFarlane) sang a brief version of the song.
    John Barrowman has made a cover version that he has sung during
    his UK concert tour. He cites it as being a favorite of his
    partner Scott.</p>
      <p>Guns N' Roses performed "Rhinestone Cowboy" live at the
    Tokyo Dome in Japan on December, 19th, 2009.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
