<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Volga_Boatmen%27s_Song 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Volga_Boatmen%27s_Song</songId>
   <title>Song of the Volga Boatmen</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glenn_Miller</artistId>
      <artistName>Glenn Miller</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1941-03-15</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>The "Song of the Volga Boatmen" (Russian: 
    <span lang="ru">Эй, ухнем!</span>) is a
    well-known traditional Russian song collected by Mily
    Balakirev, and published in his book of folk songs. It is a
    genuine shanty sung by burlaks, or barge-haulers, on the Volga
    River. Balakirev published it with only one verse (the first).
    The other two verses were added at a later date. The song was
    inspired by Ilya Repin's famous painting, 
    <i>Barge Haulers on the Volga</i>, which depicts the suffering
    of the burlaks in the depth of misery in Tsarist Russia.</p>
      <p>The song was popularised by Feodor Chaliapin, and has been a
    favourite concert piece of bass singers ever since. Glenn
    Miller's jazz arrangement took the song to #1 in the US charts
    in 1941. Spanish composer Manuel De Falla wrote an arrangement
    of the song, which was published under the name 
    <i>Canto de los remeros del Volga (del cancionero musical
    ruso)</i>in 1922. He did so at the behest of diplomat Ricardo
    Baeza, who was working with the League of Nations to provide
    financial relief for the more than two million Russian refugees
    who had been displaced and imprisoned during World War I. All
    proceeds from the song's publication were donated to this
    effort.</p>
      <p>ISO:1995 System of Russian Romanization)</p>
      <p>The catchy tune of 
    <i>The Song of the Volga Boatmen</i>has led to its being used
    in many musical situations, particularly as background music,
    often with the theme of unremitting toil (or, alternatively,
    devotion to duty) forgotten. Some uses, particularly those
    portending doom or despair, employ only the iconic four-note
    beginning; others go so far as to add new, often wryly
    humorous, lyrics, such as the "Birthday Dirge". Some of the
    uses acknowledge the tune's Russian heritage; very few use the
    original lyrics.</p>
      <p>The song, or at least the tune, was popularized in the
    mid-20th Century through a jazz version played by the Glenn
    Miller Band. A translated vocal version was sung by the leftist
    figure and singer Paul Robeson.</p>
      <p>The tune is used as the theme song for the Fremantle Dockers
    AFL teams, albeit with different lyrics.</p>
      <p>It is often used in various classic cartoons (including Tom
    and Jerry and Bugs Bunny) whenever a character is hauling
    something from one place to another. The music normally goes
    from the main (usually the chase) theme which slows down as the
    character drags the weight, and then transforms into the Song
    of the Volga Boatmen, which stops as soon as the character gets
    rid of the weight, and then the music goes back to normal.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
