<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/That_Old_Black_Magic 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/That_Old_Black_Magic</songId>
   <title>That Old Black Magic</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glenn_Miller</artistId>
      <artistName>Glenn Miller</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1943-05-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <lengths>
      <length>mm:ss</length>
   </lengths>
   <writers>
      <writer>Harold Arlen (music)</writer>
      <writer>Johnny Mercer (lyrics)</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"That Old Black Magic" is a popular song. The music was
    written by Harold Arlen, with the lyrics by Johnny Mercer. The
    song was published in 1942 and has become an often-recorded
    standard with versions by Glenn Miller, the singers Margaret
    Whiting, Frank Sinatra, Sammy Davis, Jr., Mercer himself, and
    others. Mercer wrote the lyrics with Judy Garland in mind, who
    was, on occasion, an intimate partner. Garland recorded the
    song for Decca Records in 1942.</p>
      <p>The Glenn Miller recording was released by RCA Victor
    Records as catalog number 1523. It charted in 1943, spending 14
    weeks on the Billboard magazine charts, peaking at position
    #1.</p>
      <p>The Margaret Whiting recording (with the Freddie Slack
    Orchestra, which got top billing on the label) was released by
    Capitol Records as catalog number 126. It charted in 1943,
    spending 1 week at #10 on the Billboard chart.</p>
      <p>Ella Fitzgerald recorded this on her 1961 Verve double-album
    "Ella Fitzgerald Sings the Harold Arlen Songbook".</p>
      <p>The Frank Sinatra recorded the song twice: once as a ballad
    for Columbia, and again in 1961 in a lightly swinging
    arrangement for Capitol (featured on 
    <i>Come Swing With Me</i>.) Sinatra also sang a slightly
    altered version of the song titled, "That Old Jack Magic" at
    the inaugural gala he held for John F. Kennedy the night before
    Kennedy was inaugurated as the thirty-fifth President of the
    United States.</p>
      <p>A 1950 recording on Mercury Records by Billy Daniels gave
    him the moniker "The Old Black Magic Man" for the rest of his
    career.</p>
      <p>The Sammy Davis, Jr. recording was released by Decca Records
    as catalog number 29541. It charted in 1955 and spent 6 weeks
    on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts, peaking at position #16. Sammy Davis,
    Jr. performs "That Old Black Magic" during a guest appearance
    on the television series 
    <i>I Dream of Jeannie</i>.</p>
      <p>Marilyn Monroe famously sang the song in her film 
    <i>Bus Stop</i>, in 1956. Her character Cheree is singing the
    song (somewhat out of key) to an audience who is not listening
    and talking loudly, until Don Murray quiets them all down.</p>
      <p>The duet recorded by Louis Prima and Keely Smith was
    released as a single in 1958 on the Capitol label. It reached a
    peak of eighteen on the Billboard Hot 100.</p>
      <p>Bobby Rydell had his version released as a single on Cameo
    in 1961. It reached number twenty-one on the Hot 100.</p>
      <p>Johnny Mercer recorded his version in 1974 for his album 
    <i>My Huckleberry Friend</i>.</p>
      <p>The tune was featured as background music in the movie, 
    <i>Star Trek III: The Search for Spock.</i>
      </p>
      <p>It was featured twice on 
    <i>Star Trek: Voyager</i>. It was sung by Seven of Nine during
    a simulation of World War II on the first part of the episode
    "The Killing Game". The second time it was performed by The
    Doctor and Harry Kim and his jazz band called 'Harry Kim and
    the Kimtones' in the episode "Virtuoso".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
