<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chattanooga_Choo_Choo 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chattanooga_Choo_Choo</songId>
   <title>Chattanooga Choo Choo</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glenn_Miller</artistId>
      <artistName>Glenn Miller</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1942-01-03</week>
      <week>1942-01-10</week>
      <week>1942-01-17</week>
      <week>1942-01-24</week>
      <week>1942-01-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Chattanooga Choo Choo" is a big-band/swing song which was
    featured in the 1941 movie 
    <i>Sun Valley Serenade</i>, which starred Sonja Henie, John
    Payne, Glenn Miller and his orchestra, The Modernaires, Milton
    Berle and Joan Davis. It was performed in the film as an
    extended production number, featuring vocals by Tex Beneke,
    Paula Kelly, and the Modernaires followed by a production
    number showcasing Dorothy Dandridge and an acrobatic dance
    sequence by The Nicholas Brothers. This was the #1 song across
    the United States on December 7, 1941. The Glenn Miller
    recording, RCA Bluebird B-11230-B, was no.1 for nine weeks on
    the Billboard Best Sellers chart.</p>
      <p>The 78-rpm commercial version of the song was recorded on
    May 7, 1941 for RCA Victor's Bluebird label and became the
    first to be certified a gold disc on February 10, 1942, for
    sales of 1,200,000. The transcription of this award ceremony
    can be heard on the first of three volumes of RCA's "Legendary
    Performer" compilations on Glenn released by RCA in the 1970s.
    In the early 1990s a two-channel recording of a portion of the 
    <i>Sun Valley Serenade</i>soundtrack was discovered, allowing
    reconstruction of a true-stereo version of the film
    performance.</p>
      <p>In 1996, the 1941 recording of "Chattanooga Choo Choo" by
    Glenn Miller and His Orchestra was inducted into the Grammy
    Hall of Fame.</p>
      <p>The song was written by the team of Mack Gordon and Harry
    Warren while traveling on the Southern Railway's "Birmingham
    Special" train. The song tells the story of traveling from New
    York City to Chattanooga. However, the inspiration for the song
    was a small, wood-burning steam locomotive of the 2-6-0 type
    which belonged to the Cincinnati Southern Railway, which is now
    part of the Norfolk Southern Railway system. That train is now
    a museum artifact (see below). From 1880, most trains bound for
    America's South passed through the southeastern Tennessee city
    of Chattanooga, often on to the super-hub of Atlanta. The
    Chattanooga Choo Choo did not refer to any particular train,
    though some have incorrectly asserted that it referred to
    Louisville and Nashville's Dixie Flyer or the Southern
    Railway's Crescent Limited.</p>
      <p>Today, trains have pride of place in Chattanooga's former
    Terminal Station. Once owned and operated by the Southern
    Railway, the station was saved from demolition after the
    withdrawal of passenger rail service in the early 1970s, and it
    is now part of a 30-acre (12-hectare) resort complex, including
    the Chattanooga Choo-Choo Hotel, but in 2009 joining the
    Historic Hotels of America, and numerous historical railway
    exhibits. Hotel guests can stay in half of a restored passenger
    railway car. Dining at the complex includes the Gardens
    restaurant in the Terminal Station itself, The Station House
    (which is housed in a former baggage storage room) and the
    "Dinner in the Diner" which is the complex's fine dining venue,
    housed in a restored 1941 Class A dining car. The city's other
    historic station, Union Station, parts of which predated the
    Civil War, was demolished in 1973; its site is now an office
    building housing the corporate offices of the Krystal
    restaurant chain. In addition to the railroad exhibits at "the
    Choo Choo", there are further exhibits at Tennessee Valley
    Railroad Museum, which is in the suburb of East
    Chattanooga.</p>
      <p>The reputation given to the city by the song also lent
    itself to making Chattanooga the home of the National Model
    Railroad Association. In addition, the athletic mascot of the
    University of Tennessee at Chattanooga is a rather
    menacing-looking anthropomorphized mockingbird named Scrappy,
    who is dressed as a railroad engineer and is sometimes depicted
    at the throttle of a steam locomotive.</p>
      <p>The 
    <i>Dixie Flyer</i>originally was a named train that did pass
    through and stop in Chattanooga on its run from Chicago to
    Miami. That railroad, until 1957 was the Nashville, Chattanooga
    and St. Louis Railway (NC&amp;StL). The NC&amp;StL was merged
    into L&amp;N in 1957. Now it is part of CSX.</p>
      <p>The 
    <i>Southern Crescent</i>did not go through Chattanooga, but
    there were at least three other Southern Railway trains that
    ran through Chattanooga direct to Washington and on to New York
    without changing trains.</p>
      <p>The train would not have gone through North Carolina,
    although the lyrics say "dinner in the diner, nothing could be
    finer than to have your ham 'n' eggs in Carolina." This longer
    route via Salisbury and Asheville was all on Southern rails
    from Washington, DC on southwest.</p>
      <p>Cab Calloway and His Orchestra recorded a cover version of
    "Chattanooga Choo Choo" on the Conqueror record label in 1941
    as Conqueror 9914.</p>
      <p>Bill Haley &amp; His Comets released a cover of "Chattanooga
    Choo Choo" as an Essex 45 single in 1954 as Essex 348.</p>
      <p>In 1967, the American musical group Harpers Bizarre released
    a cover version of the song "Chattanooga Choo Choo", which
    reached #45 on the U.S. pop chart while spending two weeks at
    #1 on the Easy Listening chart (which would later be renamed
    the Adult Contemporary chart).</p>
      <p>In the 1970s the tune was used in the UK on an advert for
    Toffee Crisp candy bars, starting with "Pardon me, boy, is that
    a Toffee Crisp you chew chew," and ending with the final punch
    line "Chew chew Toffee crisp, the big value bar."</p>
      <p>A cover by Steve Lucky &amp; The Rhumba Bums featured in the
    film "Be Cool" (2005).</p>
      <p>The tune was adopted twice for German songs. Both songs deal
    with trains, and both songs start with (different) translations
    of "pardon me". The first was created and performed in 1947 by
    the German pop singer Bully Buhlan (
    <i>Zug nach Kötzschenbroda</i>). The second, created by the
    German rock musician Udo Lindenberg in 1983 became very popular
    because of its political implications. The ironic text of this
    song 
    <i>Sonderzug nach Pankow</i>("Special Train To Pankow")
    appealed personally to GDR's Chairman of the Council of State
    Erich Honecker. Therefore, the song was widely propagated
    (though forbidden) in East Germany, it is now considered an
    early contribution towards the fall of the Berlin Wall.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
