<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Will_Survive 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Will_Survive</songId>
   <title>I Will Survive</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gloria_Gaynor</artistId>
      <artistName>Gloria Gaynor</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1979-03-10</week>
      <week>1979-03-17</week>
      <week>1979-04-07</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/4/45/Iwillsurvive.gif</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Gloria-Gaynor+I-Will-Survive.gif</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Love Tracks</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 27, 1978</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:18 (45)</length>
      <length>4:20.6 (CD)</length>
      <length>8:01 (12"/LP)</length>
   </lengths>
   <writers>
      <writer>Freddie Perren</writer>
      <writer>Dino Fekaris</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Will Survive" is a song first performed by Gloria Gaynor,
    released in October 1978. It was written by Freddie Perren and
    Dino Fekaris.</p>
      <p>The song's lyrics describe a narrator who finds personal
    strength while recovering from a breakup; it has often been
    used as an anthem of female empowerment,, gay empowerment and
    HIV/AIDS awareness - and is a firm favorite on the karaoke
    circuit. It is one of the most famous disco songs of all time
    and Gaynor's biggest hit. It received massive airplay in 1979,
    reaching number one on the Billboard Hot 100, also reaching
    number one in the UK the next day.</p>
      <p>The song was originally released as the B-side to a song
    first recorded by The Righteous Brothers called "Substitute", a
    track thought to have more potential for mainstream success by
    her record label. It became a worldwide hit for Clout in 1978,
    instead. Disc jockeys began flipping the single over and
    eventually copies of the record were pressed with "I Will
    Survive" as the A-side ("Substitute" managed to peak at number
    107 on Billboard's Bubbling Under Hot 100 Singles chart).</p>
      <p>The song was rated number nine on George Carlin's 10 Most
    Embarrassing Songs of All Time.</p>
      <p>It received the Grammy Award for Best Disco Recording in
    1980, the only year that the award was given. It is ranked #489
    on the 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's list of "The 500 Greatest Songs
    of All Time". The Song was also listed at #97 on 
    <i>Billboard's Greatest Songs of all time.</i>[1] In 2000 the
    song was ranked #1 in VH1's list of the 100 greatest dance
    songs.</p>
      <p>After the success of fellow '70s stars Sister Sledge's
    remixed singles in the UK in 1993, this song was also released
    in a remixed form there in about June/July 1993. Also meriting
    success, this remix reached number five on the UK Singles Chart
    (while the original version had topped the chart in 1979), but
    was her only successful remix single in the UK.</p>
      <p>Sheila Reid of Harlem, NY is the featured skater in the
    video from the skating group, The Village Wizards. They formed
    at The Village Skating Rink located in Greenwich Village which
    was the first rollerskating rink to open in Manhattan and was
    owned by the late Richard "Dick" Clammer. The video remains
    popular and can be seen on VH-1 and You Tube.</p>
      <p>Cake covered the song in a rock style in 1996 on the album 
    <i>Fashion Nugget</i>. This is Gloria Gaynor's least favorite
    version of the song, due to its use of profanity: lead singer
    John McCrea altered the line "I should have changed that stupid
    lock" to "I should have changed my fucking lock."</p>
      <p>The Cake Version song is also the goalmusic of the Turkish
    football club Galatasaray SK.</p>
      <p>The music video for Cake's version features John McCrea as a
    parking control officer who is writing tickets in San
    Francisco, often at the expense of normally happy people (such
    as a newly wed couple). This is combined with footage of Todd
    Roper playing in the streets, Victor Damiani playing on top of
    a car, and Greg Brown playing in a crowded courtyard.</p>
      <p>R&amp;B singer Chantay Savage scored a Gold selling single
    with her cover of the song. It is the only cover version of the
    song to be certifed Gold by the RIAA</p>
      <p>Second Run: April 14, 1979</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
