<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goodnight,_Irene 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goodnight,_Irene</songId>
   <title>Goodnight, Irene</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gordon_Jenkins</artistId>
      <artistName>Gordon Jenkins and The Weavers</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1950-08-19</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Goodnight, Irene" or "Irene, Goodnight," is a 20th century
    American folk standard, written in 3/4 time, first recorded by
    American blues musician Huddie 'Lead Belly' Ledbetter in
    1932.</p>
      <p>The lyrics tell of the singer's troubled past with his love,
    Irene, and express his sadness and frustration. Several verses
    make explicit reference to suicidal fantasies, most famously in
    the line "sometimes I take a great notion to jump in the river
    and drown," which was the inspiration for the 1964 Ken Kesey
    novel Sometimes a Great Notion.</p>
      <p>In 1950, US folk group The Weavers recorded a version which
    became a US #1. Although generally faithful, the Weavers chose
    to omit some of Lead Belly's more controversial lyrics, leading
    Time magazine to label it a "dehydrated" and "prettied up"
    version of the original.</p>
      <p>Due to the recording's popularity, however, The Weavers'
    lyrics are the ones generally used today.</p>
      <p>Subsequent to 1950, the song was recorded by numerous
    artists across several genres. In 2002, Lead Belly's 1936
    Library of Congress recording received a Grammy Hall of Fame
    Award.</p>
      <p>The song has also come to fame as being the terrace song for
    Bristol Rovers FC who play in the English Football League
    1.</p>
      <p>In 1950, one year after Lead Belly's death, the American
    folk band The Weavers recorded a version of "Goodnight, Irene".
    The single first reached the Billboard Best Seller chart on
    June 30, 1950 and lasted 25 weeks on the chart, peaking at
    #1.</p>
      <p>The Weavers' enormous success inspired many other artists to
    release their own versions of the song, many of which were
    themselves commercially successful.</p>
      <p>Frank Sinatra's cover, released only a month after The
    Weavers', lasted nine weeks on the Billboard magazine Best
    Seller chart on July 10, peaking at #12. Later that same year,
    Ernest Tubb &amp; Red Foley had a #1 country music record with
    the song , and both Dennis Day and Jo Stafford released
    versions which made the Best Seller chart, peaking at #22 and
    #26 respectively.</p>
      <p>On the Cash Box chart, where all available versions were
    combined in the standings, the song reached a peak position of
    #1 on September 2, 1950, and lasted at #1 for 10 weeks.</p>
      <p>The song was basis for the 1950 parody called "Please Say
    Goodnight to the Guy, Irene" by Ziggy Talent. It also inspired
    the 1954 "answer" record "Wake Up, Irene" by Hank Thompson, a
    top ten hit on Billboard's country chart.</p>
      <p>Band From TV did a cover of the song, with Hugh Laurie doing
    piano and vocals.</p>
      <p>The Dixie Chicken in College Station plays this song at
    closing time, 2 a.m. every night of the week.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
