<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/We%27re_an_American_Band_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/We%27re_an_American_Band_(song)</songId>
   <title>We're an American Band</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grand_Funk_Railroad</artistId>
      <artistName>Grand Funk</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1973-09-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>We're an American Band</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1973</released>
   <recorded>1973</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hard Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Capitol Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Don Brewer</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Todd Rundgren</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"We're an American Band" (from the album of the same name)
    is a 1973 song by the band Grand Funk Railroad. It was the
    group's first number one single. Written by Don Brewer and
    produced by Todd Rundgren, the huge chart success of this
    single broadened Grand Funk's appeal to a much wider
    audience.</p>
      <p>It is the 99 song on VH1's 100 Greatest Hard Rock Songs.</p>
      <p>Brewer's lyrics are somewhat autobiographical, detailing the
    band's recent tour and their energetic live performances. In
    the song, the band mentions traveling through Little Rock,
    Arkansas, as well as stopping to party with four groupies that
    sneak into their hotel in Omaha, Nebraska. The lyrics also
    mention "sweet sweet Connie", which is the first name of
    legendary groupie Connie Hamzy.</p>
      <p>According to rock critic/writer Dave Marsh in his book, 
    <i>The Heart of Rock and Soul</i>, Grand Funk was touring with
    the British group Humble Pie in early 1973. After one
    performance, the two groups were drinking in a bar when the two
    groups began arguing over the merits of British versus American
    rock. Grand Funk drummer Don Brewer stood up and after bragging
    about American rock heroes such as Jerry Lee Lewis, Fats
    Domino, Little Richard and Elvis Presley, proudly announced,
    "We're an American band!" Thus inspired, Brewer wrote the song
    the next morning, and it was the top selling song in the world
    by September of 1973. A video was also made, showing the band
    playing the song as well as engaging in activities such as
    basketball, dirtbike riding and watersports.</p>
      <p>The original single was released on gold transparent
    vinyl.</p>
      <p>The song is played as backdrop music during a high school
    football game in the film 
    <i>Radio</i>.</p>
      <p>This song was used on ABC's 
    <i>Life on Mars</i>with Sam Tyler (Jason O'Mara) impersonating
    Michael Jackson while dancing to it.</p>
      <p>The band Americade covered the song for their 1982 album
    release 
    <i>American Metal</i>and the corresponding video won "Best New
    Video" (one of six nominated summer rock videos) on MTV July
    3rd/4th, 1983 announced by Lindsay Buckingham and VJ Alan
    Hunter.</p>
      <p>Autograph covered the song in November, 1985 and had it
    added to their second album 
    <i>That’s the Stuff</i>in early 1986, replacing the original
    track #6, which was released in October, 1985. The "Up all
    night with Freddie King, I got to tell you poker's his thing"
    portion early in the song is replaced by "Up all night, sleep
    all day, I got to tell you that's how we play" for unknown
    reasons, possibly because of King's death ten years
    earlier.</p>
      <p>Poison covered the song and released it as a single for
    their 
    <i>The Best of Poison: 20 Years of Rock</i>compilation which
    peaked at number 17 on the Billboard 200 The song was slightly
    changed replacing the line "And we proceeded to tear that hotel
    down" with the line "And Poison tore that hotel down." It was
    also on the Poison cover album 
    <i>Poison'd</i>.</p>
      <p>Kid Rock covered the song during one year's MTV Video Music
    Awards, substituting "We'll help you party down" with "We'll
    take your panties down".</p>
      <p>All-accordion rock band Those Darn Accordions parodied this
    song as "We're An Accordion Band", substituting many of the
    lyrics with references to famous accordion players such as
    Myron Florin and Flaco "The King" Jimenez". They replace "We'll
    help you party down" with "We'll help you polka down".</p>
      <p>Jackyl covered the song for their 1998 compilation release 
    <i>Choice Cuts</i>utilizing Jesse Dupree's unique vocal
    style.</p>
      <p>The Village People, as well as Phish, cover the song as part
    of their live repertoire.</p>
      <p>The Hardcore Punk Band Verbal Abuse covered the song on
    their 
    <i>Just An American Band</i>LP in 1983.</p>
      <p>Singers Aly &amp; AJ have covered this song for 
    <i>Randy Jackson’s Music Club: Volume One.</i>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
