<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sweet_Child_o%27_Mine 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sweet_Child_o%27_Mine</songId>
   <title>Sweet Child o' Mine</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guns_N%27_Roses</artistId>
      <artistName>Guns N' Roses</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1988-09-10</week>
      <week>1988-09-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a7/Sweetchildomine.jpg/200px-Sweetchildomine.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Guns-N-Roses+Sweet-Child-o-Mine.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Appetite for Destruction</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 18, 1988</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
      <format>10" vinyl</format>
      <format>12" vinyl</format>
      <format>CS</format>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1987</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hard Rock</genre>
      <genre>Heavy Metal</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:12 (Radio Edit) 5:56 (Album Version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <descr>
      <p>"Sweet Child o' Mine" is the third single by American hard
    rock band Guns N' Roses, and the third from their 1987 debut
    studio album, 
    <i>Appetite for Destruction</i>. Released on August 18, 1988,
    the song topped the Hot 100 chart, becoming the band's first
    and only number-one single, and reached number six on the UK
    Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>Slash has been quoted as having a disdain for the song due
    to its roots as simply a 'string skipping' exercise and a joke
    at the time. In a VH1 special, it was stated that Slash played
    the riff in a jam session as a joke. Drummer Steven Adler and
    Slash were warming up and Slash began to play a "circus" melody
    while making faces at Steven. Izzy asked Slash to play it
    again, meanwhile Axl was upstairs to in his room and heard the
    'jam session' going on downstairs and couldnt help but write
    lyrics. He based it on his girlfriend Erin Everly. With Steven
    Adler's added drum part, the harmony became the core of the
    song. Originally, there was a third verse to the song. However,
    this verse was later cut from recording as the band's producer,
    Spencer Proffer, felt the song would carry on for too long. The
    final dramatic breakdown was not added until Proffer suggested
    the band add one. They agreed, but weren't sure what to do. Axl
    started saying to himself, "Where do we go? Where do we go
    now?" Spencer suggested that he sing that, and "Sweet Child o'
    Mine" was born. In an interview with 
    <i>Hit Parader</i>magazine in 1988, bassist Duff McKagan
    noted:</p>
      <p>The "Sweet Child o' Mine" video depicts the band rehearsing
    in an abandoned theater, surrounded by crew members. All of the
    band members' girlfriends at the time were shown in the clip.
    Izzy Stradlin's dog was also featured. The video was extremely
    successful on MTV, and helped launch the song to success on
    mainstream radio.</p>
      <p>In an effort to make "Sweet Child o' Mine" more marketable
    to MTV and radio stations, the song was cut from 5:56 minutes
    to 4:12, with much of Slash's guitar solo removed. This move
    drew the ire of the band members, including Axl Rose, who
    commented on it in a 1989 interview with 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>: "I hate the edit of 'Sweet Child o'
    Mine.' Radio stations said, "Well, your vocals aren't cut." "My
    favorite part of the song is Slash's slow solo; it's the
    heaviest part for me. There's no reason for it to be missing
    except to create more space for commercials, so the
    radio-station owners can get more advertising dollars. When you
    get the chopped version of 'Paradise City' or half of 'Sweet
    Child' and 'Patience' cut, you're getting screwed."</p>
      <p>On an interview on Eddie Trunk's New York radio show in May
    2006, Axl Rose stated that his original concept for the video
    focused on the theme of drug trafficking. According to Rose,
    the video was to depict an Asian woman carrying a baby into a
    foreign land, only to discover at the end that the child was
    dead and filled with heroin. This concept was rejected by
    Geffen Records.</p>
      <p>There is also an alternative video for "Sweet Child o' Mine"
    with different shots, all in black and white. It can be watched
    in Guns N' Roses/VEVO official channel on YouTube.</p>
      <p>"Sweet Child o' Mine" placed #37 on 
    <i>Guitar World</i>'s list of the "100 Greatest Guitar Solos."
    It also came in at number three on 
    <i>Blender</i>'s 500 Greatest Songs Since You Were Born, and at
    number 196 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s The 500 Greatest Songs of All Time. In
    March 2005, magazine placed it at number 6 in its list of the
    100 Greatest Guitar Tracks. The introduction's famous riff was
    also voted number-one riff of all-time by the readers of 
    <i>Total Guitar</i>magazine. It was also in 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s 40 Greatest Songs that Changed the
    World. It places number 7 in VH1's "100 Best Songs of the 80s",
    and placed #210 on the RIAA Songs of the Century list. On a
    recent BBC poll, the song was voted to have the "greatest
    guitar riff ever".</p>
      <p>The song came 1st in 
    <i>Kerrang!</i>'s Slash's top 30 guitar anthems. The song is
    currently ranked as the 91st greatest song of all time, as well
    as the best song of 1987, by Acclaimed Music. Recently, it was
    again popularized by its appearance in 
    <i>Guitar Hero II</i>, spreading the song to a younger
    generation of listeners. The famous intro makes the song one of
    the most easily recognizable tunes of all time. In October 2009
    it came first in 
    <i>Kerrang!</i>'s 100 greatest riffs.</p>
      <p>The first time this song appeared in a movie was in 1988, it
    played as the credits were rolling for the movie Bad
    Dreams.</p>
      <p>"Sweet Child o' Mine" is featured in the 2008 film 
    <i>The Wrestler</i>. The song is played when Randy "The Ram"
    Robinson (played by Mickey Rourke) makes his entrance to the
    ring at the end of the film. Rourke, who is friends with Axl
    Rose, convinced him to allow the song to be played in the film
    for a fraction of what would have been normally charged. Rourke
    himself used the song as his entrance music during his boxing
    career.</p>
      <p>It is also sung a capella by Derek's family in the 2008 film
    
    <i>Step Brothers</i>.</p>
      <p>The song is also in the Sean Penn, Gary Oldman film 
    <i>State of Grace</i>.</p>
      <p>An extract of this song was also featured in the Adam
    Sandler film, 
    <i>Big Daddy</i>.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by many artists including Texas,
    Most Precious Blood, Akasha featuring Neneh Cherry, DJ Dougall,
    Schmoof, Flat Pack, Luna, Chester the Pup, Bumblefoot, Dead
    Tongues, DJ Dex &amp; A, The Aluminium Group and DZK. The song
    was also performed in many live concerts by country singer
    Carrie Underwood, opening with her alone on acoustic guitar and
    using her voice to reference Slash's intro guitar tones before
    launching into a full band rock-out. Bonnie Tyler performed it
    on the for Charity DVD 
    <i>Rock for Asia</i>in 2005.</p>
      <p>Occasionally, as a joke, Linkin Park performs parts of the
    song during some concerts. The Manic Street Preachers also
    frequently play it as an introduction to their song "Motown
    Junk" in live concerts. The main riff is replayed by Red Hot
    Chili Peppers at the end of the song "Punk Rock Classic". The
    intro is also sampled in a song on the 
    <i>Fort Minor</i>mixtape, titled "S.C.O.M."(Sweet Child o'
    Mine). Avenged Sevenfold frequently use the opening riff as a
    segue between songs during live concerts.</p>
      <p>In 1999, the song was covered by Sheryl Crow and re-recorded
    by the then-new Guns N' Roses members for the film 
    <i>Big Daddy</i>. Crow's version earned her a Grammy Award for
    Best Female Rock Vocal Performance. The new Guns N' Roses
    version which morphed into a live version half way through was
    not featured on the original soundtrack album of the movie, but
    can be heard during the movie's ending credits. The song was
    also featured in the 1990 film 
    <i>State of Grace</i>, in a bar during a brawl.</p>
      <p>It was performed on December 2, 2006 at the Nokia Theatre
    Times Square in New York City by jam band Umphrey's McGee.</p>
      <p>Black Eyed Peas usually performs the first verses of this
    song as well during their live shows. Turbonegro uses the intro
    as Introlick for the Song Bad Mongo played live.</p>
      <p>A cover of the song is featured as a special encore in the
    music video game 
    <i>Guitar Hero II</i>.</p>
      <p>Part of the song is featured at the beginning of the episode
    "Witch Hunt" of the hit CBS show 
    <i>NCIS</i>. Part of the song is used in scenes of a little
    girl. The song ends when a sound of a gunshot is heard
    indicating that the girl in the scenes is the deceased daughter
    of the show's main character Leroy Jethro Gibbs.</p>
      <p>"Sweet Child o' Mine" was also covered in 2005 by
    Flatpack/Mylo.</p>
      <p>The song "Homecoming Queen" by Hinder bears a strong
    resemblance to "Sweet Child o Mine."</p>
      <p>Slash performed "Sweet Child o' Mine" with Fergie at his
    recent 43rd birthday party in Las Vegas at the Mirage Hotel
    &amp; casino on July 23, 2008.</p>
      <p>During the 2008 Reading Festival, band Tenacious D announced
    they were going to perform a cover of one of Metallica's most
    well known songs as a tribute. They then proceeded to play the
    opening riff to "Sweet Child o' Mine".</p>
      <p>Swedish music artist Johan Darius released a version of the
    song through his website in December 2008.</p>
      <p>Irish dance act The Lazy Boyz recorded a trance version in
    2004. It went on to appear on two Ministry of Sound
    compilations, 
    <i>Big Tunes</i>and 
    <i>The Annual 2005</i>.</p>
      <p>Australian vocal group Human Nature performed a cappella
    version on 
    <i>Andrew Denton's Musical Challenge</i>
      </p>
      <p>SR-71's song, "Axl Rose", contains part of the opening
    riff.</p>
      <p>Indie pop artist Victoria Bergsman, under the name Taken by
    Trees, also covered the song. Her version was used in the
    trailer for the remake of the Wes Craven film 
    <i>The Last House on the Left</i>, and in a 2009 UK advert for
    department store John Lewis and announced would be released as
    their next UK single. This cover peaked at #23 on the UK
    Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>A version of this song was performed by Lucie Jones on the
    sixth series of (UK) in 2009.</p>
      <p>During the Use Your Illusion Tour, Axl Rose would sometimes
    sing a few lines from songs by other artists as an
    'introduction' to the song. The songs used were:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
