<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hollaback_Girl 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hollaback_Girl</songId>
   <title>Hollaback Girl</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gwen_Stefani</artistId>
      <artistName>Gwen Stefani</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2005-05-07</week>
      <week>2005-05-14</week>
      <week>2005-05-21</week>
      <week>2005-05-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/3a/Hollaback_Girl.png/200px-Hollaback_Girl.png</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Gwen-Stefani+Hollaback-Girl.png</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Love. Angel. Music. Baby.</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 15, 2005  (2005-03-15)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download (U.S.)</format>
      <format>CD single (worldwide)</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>New York City , New York , United States</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Dance</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:20</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Interscope</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Gwen Stefani</writer>
      <writer>Chad Hugo</writer>
      <writer>Pharrell Williams</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>The Neptunes</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Hollaback Girl" is a song written by singer Gwen Stefani
    and Pharrell for Stefani's debut solo album 
    <i>Love. Angel. Music. Baby.</i>As part of Stefani's vision of
    creating "a silly dance record", the song is influenced by
    1980s dance and pop music. They wrote the song as a response to
    Courtney Love's statement that Stefani was a "cheerleader" in
    an interview with 
    <i>Seventeen</i>magazine.</p>
      <p>The song was released as the album's third single in early
    2005 (see 2005 in music) and was one of the year's most popular
    songs, peaking inside the top ten on the majority of the charts
    it entered. It reached number one in Australia and the United
    States, where it became the first digital download to sell one
    million copies. "Hollaback Girl" received many award
    nominations, including Best Female Pop Vocal Performance and
    Record of the Year at the 48th Grammy Awards, yet it divided
    pop music critics. The CD single has a "Parental Advisory:
    Explicit Content" label, while the album, 
    <i>Love. Angel. Music. Baby.</i>, does not.</p>
      <p>The song was listed at #180 on Pitchfork Media's top 500
    songs of the 2000s. Hollaback Girl is 41st most popular song of
    the decade according to Billboard Magazine.</p>
      <p>Stefani had worked with The Neptunes (Pharrell Williams and
    Chad Hugo) during the early stages of writing 
    <i>Love. Angel. Music. Baby.</i>; however, a case of writer's
    block resulted in reportedly uninspired collaborations. As the
    album neared completion, Stefani regained her confidence and
    booked another session with The Neptunes. Stefani flew to New
    York City to meet up with Williams, and after finishing two
    songs within a week, Stefani ended the session early and
    prepared to return home. A few minutes later, Williams called
    her back into the studio to write another song. Stefani said,
    "I was tired. I wanted to go home, but he was like, 'Don't
    leave yet.
    <span style="padding-right:.2em;">"</span>'</p>
      <p>When she returned to the studio, Williams began to play
    Stefani his first solo album, and she became envious. Excited
    by his material, she decided to write another song with
    Williams, despite her opinion that the album already contained
    far too many tracks.</p>
      <p>To search for inspiration, Stefani and Williams had a
    lengthy discussion in which Stefani said that she had yet to
    write a song about her intentions for pursuing a solo career.
    She remarked how the album was missing an "attitude song", and
    she recalled a derogatory comment that grunge musician Courtney
    Love had made about her in an interview with teen magazine 
    <i>Seventeen</i>.</p>
      <p>Stefani responded in the March 2005 issue of 
    <i>NME</i>:</p>
      <p>Stefani believed that some of the fans of No Doubt would be
    upset with her solo effort, commenting, "[They] were probably
    like, 'Why is she doing this record? She's going to ruin
    everything'." She revealed that she too did not know why she
    was recording a solo album. For the remainder of the evening,
    Stefani and Williams incorporated this inspiration into the
    lyrics that eventually became "Hollaback Girl". The two decided
    that Stefani did not have to have an answer for her intentions
    and that the choices she made were based on what she felt was
    wrong or right. On its creation, Stefani said, "to me, it is
    the freshest attitude song I've heard in so long." Williams was
    pleased with the song, commenting, "Gwen is like the girl in
    high school who just had her own style."</p>
      <p>Because Stefani never disclosed the song title's meaning,
    reviewers came up with various interpretations. In a satirical,
    line-by-line analysis of the song's lyrics, 
    <i>OC Weekly</i>critic Greg Stacy humorously speculated that
    "Gwen is apparently the captain of the cheerleader squad; she
    is the girl who 'hollas' the chants, not one of the girls who
    simply 'hollas' them back". The most commonly accepted meaning
    is that a hollaback girl responds to a confrontation with words
    but that Stefani would rather take initiative and "step it
    up".</p>
      <p>"Hollaback Girl" is a moderately fast song, being 110bpm, in
    the key of B major. It combines old school hip hop with dance
    music, and—like the majority of pop music—is set in common
    time. The main chord pattern of the song alternates between B
    major and D sharp minor triads. Most of the harmonic content of
    the song revolves around a two-chord alternation which music
    theorists may regard as an L (leading tone) transformation, in
    which the root of the major chord is lowered by a half-step to
    form a second inversion minor chord on the third scale degree
    (see image to right). This stepwise motion between B and
    A-sharp highlights this chord change. It is in verse-chorus
    form with a bridge before the fourth and final chorus. The song
    features sparse instrumentation, primarily a minimal beat
    produced by drum machine. A guitar plays the song's riff, a
    six-note pattern as Stefani repeats "this my shit" during the
    chorus, and a brass section joins during the second chorus. In
    part because of its cheerleading motif, it drew comparisons to
    Toni Basil's "Mickey" (1982).</p>
      <p>"Hollaback Girl" had a polarizing effect on music critics.
    LAUNCHcast's Jennifer Nine described it as a "stomping,
    stripped-back track", and Allmusic said that it had the
    "thumping, minimal beats of The Neptunes." Richard Smirke
    called it "a trademark Neptunes hip-hop stomp." In its review
    of 
    <i>Love. Angel. Music. Baby.</i>, 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>gave the song a positive review, writing
    that "Stefani's gum-snapping sass brings out the beast in her
    beatmasters, especially the Neptunes in 'Hollaback Girl'." 
    <i>Blender</i>listed it as the eleventh best song of 2005, and
    the song tied with Damian Marley's "Welcome to Jamrock" for
    number five on the 2005 Pazz &amp; Jop, a survey of several
    hundred music critics conducted by Robert Christgau.</p>
      <p>On the other hand, Jason Damas, in a review for 
    <i>PopMatters</i>, described the song as sounding "almost
    exactly like Dizzee Rascal", and added, "lyrically, this is
    where Gwen sinks the lowest here, especially on a breakdown
    where she repeats, 'This shit is bananas / B-A-N-A-N-A-S!'
    several times". Eric Greenwood of 
    <i>Drawer B Media</i>called the song "moronic and
    embarrassingly tuneless. I'd quote the lyrics, but they're so
    bad, I almost feel sorry for her. A 35-year-old woman singing
    about pom-poms and 'talking shit' in high school betrays such a
    delusional self-image that it's hard not to be taken aback. And
    on top of that, The Neptunes' beats are clunky and the
    production is senselessly bombastic." Nick Sylvester of 
    <i>Pitchfork Media</i>also criticized the track, referring to
    it as a "Queen pastiche...which has about as much club
    potential as a 13-year old with a milk moustache and his dad's
    ID". However, despite this initial review Pitchfork Media would
    later list the track #35 on their top singles of 2005, and #180
    on the top 500 songs of the 2000s. 
    <i>Maxim</i>was unimpressed with the song, and in its October
    2005 issue, published a list of the "20 Most Annoying Songs
    Ever" with "Hollaback Girl" in first place.</p>
      <p>"Hollaback Girl" was mocked on an episode of the animated
    television series 
    <i>Family Guy</i>titled "Deep Throats"; after watching a VH1
    special about Gwen Stefani, Brian Griffin states, "I don't know
    what a Hollaback Girl is—all I know is that I want her dead."
    In another episode of 
    <i>Family Guy</i>the song was mocked again, this time in the
    guise of a parody of the feature film 
    <i>The Shawshank Redemption.</i>In the film, Red (played by
    Morgan Freeman), upon hearing "Canzonetta sull'aria" (from
    Mozart's 
    <i>The Marriage of Figaro</i>) for the first time, states that
    he has no idea what the women are singing about, but imagines
    it must be something beautiful. In the parody, Cleveland
    (playing the role of Red) hears "Hollaback Girl" and likewise
    claims to have no idea what Stefani is singing about—even
    though the lyrics are not in a foreign language (as is the
    issue in the film). Cleveland imagines it is "a foul,
    disease-ridden thing, that wears too much makeup to cover up
    the fact that it's a 47 year-old fish-dog".</p>
      <p>The song's bridge, in which Stefani exclaims "This shit is
    bananas" and then proceeds to spell 
    <i>bananas</i>, was later parodied in an episode of the
    claymation television show 
    <i>Celebrity Deathmatch</i>, in which Stefani spells out 
    <i>bananas</i>, 
    <i>broccoli</i>, and 
    <i>kumquat</i>during an interview with Tally Wong.</p>
      <p>The single was officially solicited to radio in North
    America on 5 April 2005, although the music video had been
    released two weeks earlier, on 21 March. "Hollaback Girl"
    entered the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100, the main U.S. chart, at number
    eighty-two, and within six weeks of its release, it had reached
    the top of the chart, making it the fastest-rising single to
    reach the top in 2005; it also became Stefani's first U.S.
    number one. It maintained the number one position for four
    weeks. The single spent thirty-one weeks on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100, twenty-nine of which were in the top
    fifty. It was removed from the Hot 100 for the week ending 29
    October 2005. On the year-end chart, the song was the second
    most successful, beaten by Mariah Carey's "We Belong
    Together".</p>
      <p>"Hollaback Girl" held the record for most U.S. radio
    airplays in one week, with 9,582 plays, and maintained this
    feat for over a year before Shakira and Wyclef Jean's "Hips
    Don't Lie" overtook the position. It peaked at number one on
    the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Pop 100 for eight weeks, and was a small
    success in the dance clubs, peaking at number fifteen on the
    Hot Dance Music/Club Play chart. The song was a crossover
    success, and reached number four on the Rhythmic Top 40, and
    number eight on the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Singles &amp; Tracks
    chart.</p>
      <p>The song was noted for having a large number of digital
    downloads, becoming the first single to sell more digital
    downloads than CDs. In October 2005, "Hollaback Girl" was the
    first single to ever sell one million digital downloads and
    later went on to sell a total of 1.2 million downloads; it was
    certified quintuple platinum. Due to its downloads, it reached
    number one on both digital sales charts concurrently, and it
    topped the year-end Hot Digital Songs chart.</p>
      <p>"Hollaback Girl" was a successful single in Canada, where
    the song debuted at number twelve on the Canadian Singles
    Chart; however, it fell from there and was unable to reach a
    higher position. It remained in the top fifty for six months.
    However, the Canadian Recording Industry Association later
    argued that based on Canada's population relative to the U.S.,
    the single should have sold around 120,000 copies and that the
    comparatively lower sales of 25,000 were a sign that Canadian
    copyright law should be tightened to discourage non-commercial
    peer-to-peer filesharing. Columnist Michael Geist disputed the
    comparison, arguing that the Canadian online music market was
    still developing.</p>
      <p>In the rest of the world, reaction to "Hollaback Girl" was
    generally positive, though not as overwhelming as in North
    America. It was released in Australia on 23 May 2005, debuting
    at number one, and in Europe on 6 June 2005, debuting at number
    twenty-two and eventually reaching number five. In the United
    Kingdom, however, "Hollaback Girl" did not perform as well as
    Stefani's previous releases. The song's predecessors, "What You
    Waiting For?" and "Rich Girl", had both reached number four,
    while "Hollaback Girl" debuted at number eight, and stalled at
    the same position the following week. Although its UK success
    was limited, it remained in the top forty for an additional
    eleven weeks and sold more than Rich Girl. The single largely
    was successful across Europe and Asia, and reached the top five
    in Austria, Germany, Ireland, and China, and the top ten in
    Finland, Italy, the Netherlands, Norway, Sweden, and
    Switzerland.</p>
      <p>The single had moderate success in Latin America. The single
    debuted 19 June 2005 at number thirty-three on the Latin
    America Top 40, a weaker debut than Stefani's previous singles.
    After eight weeks on the chart, it peaked at number nine.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by Paul Hunter and filmed in
    Van Nuys and Reseda, California, United States. The video opens
    with a scene of Stefani spending time with her Harajuku Girls,
    when a crowd of students appears. Stefani and the Harajuku
    Girls then drive down Sherman Way past Magnolia Science Academy
    to Birmingham High School in a 1961 Chevrolet Impala,
    accompanied by the crowd. Stefani and the group cause a
    commotion when they disrupt a football game by walking onto the
    field and when they go to a 99 Cents Only Store and throw
    cereal and other food products down an aisle. Throughout the
    video, there are intercut sequences of choreographed dancing
    filmed in a sound stage, intended to represent Stefani's
    imagination. Stefani and the Harajuku Girls are outfitted in
    cheerleading uniforms, accompanied by several Californian
    spirit groups: the Orange Crush All Stars, a cheerleading squad
    from Orange County; a marching band from Fountain Valley High
    School in Fountain Valley; a pep flag team named the Carson
    High School Flaggies from Carson; and a drill team from Stephen
    M. White Middle School in Carson. To visualize the song's
    bridge, the Harajuku Girls spell the word "bananas" with cue
    cards. The video ends with a close-up frame of Stefani with her
    arms in the air.</p>
      <p>The Chevy Impala convertible from the video includes a
    painting by artist J. Martin. The design includes Gwen Stefani
    as seen on the album cover of 
    <i>Love. Angel. Music. Baby.</i>with the words "Hollaback Girl"
    in calligraphy. Eventually, the car was sold on eBay. Pharrell,
    one of the song's co-producers, makes a cameo appearance. The
    complete version of "Hollaback Girl" featured in the music
    video has been released commercially through CD singles and
    digital downloads, and some include remixes by Diplo and Tony
    Kanal.</p>
      <p>The video debuted on 21 March 2005 and proved successful on
    video-chart programs. It debuted on MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>on 31 March at number ten and remained
    on the program for a total of fifty days, becoming what 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>called "a staple of MTV's TRL". The video
    reached the top of the chart and was retired at number four on
    23 June, becoming Stefani's first video to retire. It also
    reached the top of MuchMusic's 
    <i>Countdown</i>three months after its debut, and remained
    there for two weeks. VH1 listed the song at number five on its
    Top 40 Videos of 2005, and at the 2005 MTV Video Music Awards,
    the music video received four nominations but only won the
    award for Best Choreography. Stefani did not attend the 2006
    MTV Video Music Awards, prompting rumors that she was
    protesting her lack of nominations the previous year, her
    multiple losses to Kelly Clarkson, and her not having been
    asked to perform. Stefani denied the rumors, responding, "the
    only reason I am not attending the MTV Video Music Awards is
    because I will be recording and spending time with my
    family."</p>
      <p>Diplo made a remix for the track after M.I.A. turned down an
    offer to produce one. Tony Kanal, Stefani's ex-boyfriend and
    fellow No Doubt member, produced a remix titled the
    "Dancehollaback Remix". The track features reggae singer Elan
    Atias, whose debut album Kanal produced, and appears as a
    single on iTunes, on the CD single for "Cool", and on a remix
    CD of 
    <i>Love. Angel. Music. Baby.</i>Stefani later requested to
    contribute vocals on "I Wanna Yell" from Atias's debut album 
    <i>Together as One</i>, and was featured on his song
    "Allnighter". The female rapper Ak'sent released a mixtape with
    the song as well. The band Cobra Starship also recorded a
    parody of this song titled "Hollaback Boy".</p>
      <p>The single was first released in Australia and New Zealand
    on March 15, 2005. Releases followed in Canada and the United
    States on April 5, 2005, Ireland and the United Kingdom on June
    21, 2005, and July 2, 2005 in continental Europe.</p>
      <p>Discography
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Awards and
    nominations · 
    <span style="white-space:nowrap">No Doubt ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">L.A.M.B. ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Harajuku Lovers ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Harajuku Girls ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Gavin Rossdale</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span id="interwiki-ro-fa"/>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
