<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sleepy_Lagoon_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sleepy_Lagoon_(song)</songId>
   <title>Sleepy Lagoon</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_James</artistId>
      <artistName>Harry James</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1942-06-20</week>
      <week>1942-06-27</week>
      <week>1942-07-04</week>
      <week>1942-07-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Sleepy Lagoon" is a popular song, based on an orchestral
    'valse serenade' originally written by British composer Eric
    Coates, with lyrics by Jack Lawrence.</p>
      <p>Lawrence heard the music and wrote a song lyric, then took
    the lyric to Chappell, the publisher of Coates' original
    melody. The head of Chappell's New York office, Max Dreyfuss,
    was concerned that this lyric had been added without consulting
    the composer, who was a famous British classical composer and
    "may resent your tampering with his melody." Dreyfuss also
    didn't think the melody belonged in the popular genre, and was
    better suited to treatment as a light classical piece.</p>
      <p>After some time during which Lawrence attempted to contact
    Coates (this was 1940, and Britain was in the middle of World
    War II, making communication difficult) communication was
    established, and contrary to Dreyfuss' fears, Coates thought
    the lyric fitted so well that one could hardly believe it had
    been written to a pre-existing melody. The resulting song was
    published as a collaboration of Lawrence and Coates, and when
    Lawrence showed the song to bandleader Harry James, it was
    recorded for a major hit (again counter to Dreyfuss' thoughts).
    Other hit versions were recorded by Dinah Shore, David Rose,
    Fred Waring, Glenn Miller and others.</p>
      <p>The recording by James was released by Columbia Records as
    catalog number 36549. It first reached the Billboard magazine
    Best Seller chart on April 17, 1942 and lasted 18 weeks on the
    chart, peaking at #1.</p>
      <p>In 1942, the original version was recorded (with added
    seagulls) for introducing the BBC radio series 
    <i>Desert Island Discs</i>, and the theme is still in use
    today.</p>
      <p>The song made the Billboard Hot 100 in 1960, in a version by
    the Platters, found originally on the flipside of the 1960 top
    ten "Harbor Lights".</p>
      <p>The song is used at one of the rides (The Magic Clock) in De
    Efteling in The Netherlands, one of Europe's largest theme
    parks.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
