<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cat%27s_in_the_Cradle 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cat%27s_in_the_Cradle</songId>
   <title>Cat's in the Cradle</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_Chapin</artistId>
      <artistName>Harry Chapin</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-12-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Verities &amp; Balderdash</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1974</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Folk Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:02</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Elektra Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Harry Chapin</writer>
      <writer>Sandra Chapin</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Paul Leka</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Cat's in the Cradle" is a 1974 folk rock song by Harry
    Chapin from the album 
    <i>Verities &amp; Balderdash</i>. The single topped the
    Billboard Hot 100 in December 1974. As Chapin's only #1 hit
    song, it became the best known of his work and a staple for
    folk rock music.</p>
      <p>The lyrics to the verses of the song were originally written
    as a poem by Chapin's wife, Sandy Chapin, who is credited as
    the song's co-writer. The poem itself was inspired by the
    awkward relationship between Sandy Chapin's first husband,
    James Cashmore, and his father, a New York City politician. She
    was also inspired by a country song she heard on the radio.
    More than a year later, after the birth of his own son, Harry
    added the music and the chorus. Label executive David Geffen
    selected the song as a single, over Chapin's objections.</p>
      <p>The song is told in first-person by a father who is too busy
    to spend time with his son. Though the son repeatedly asks him
    to join in childhood activities, the father always responds
    with little more than vague promises of spending time together
    in the future, peppered with images from nursery rhymes. While
    the son longs to spend time with his father, he continues to
    admire his father. This shapes the son's future behavior, as
    shown in the slightly-altered line 
    <i>"But we'll get together then dad"</i>. The Ugly Kid Joe
    cover version does not make this lyrical change but rather
    alters the grammatical structure of the chorus from 
    <i>"When you coming home?" / "Son, I don't know when ..."</i>to
    the final 
    <i>"When you coming home, son?" / "I don't know when
    ..."</i>The final verse is a reverse of the roles; where the
    father asks his now grown-up son to visit, but the son responds
    with his father's line. The father then reflects that they are
    both alike.</p>
      <p>The chorus refers to the following nursery rhymes:</p>
      <p>"Cat's in the Cradle" is widely mistakenly credited to
    artist Cat Stevens, in part due to a mistitled MP3 version of
    the song widely circulated on the internet. As well the style
    and vocals sound akin to a Cat Stevens song, and the song and
    the singer both contain the word, 'Cat'. In 1977, Stevens'
    former label, Deram Records released a compilation album, 
    <i>Cat's Cradle</i>. Jack Black contributed to this confusion,
    playing part of the song in a 
    <i>Saturday Night Live</i>sketch where Black's character
    claimed the song was by Yusuf Islam, a.k.a. Cat Stevens. There
    are no known verifiable recordings of Cat Stevens performing
    the song, however, and a Cat Stevens fan web site assures
    readers that Stevens has never performed the song, "not live,
    not in the studio, and not even privately".</p>
      <p>The cover of the song by Ugly Kid Joe is furthermore often
    confused for a cover by Guns n' Roses, a band which never
    recorded the song. This is due to an incorrect MP3 circulating
    on P2P networks; which contains the Ugly Kid Joe version even
    though the file credits it to Guns n' Roses.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
