<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It%27s_Been_a_Long,_Long_Time 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It%27s_Been_a_Long,_Long_Time</songId>
   <title>It's Been a Long, Long Time</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_James</artistId>
      <artistName>Harry James</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1945-11-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"It's Been A Long, Long Time" is a 1945 popular song that
    became a major hit at the end of World War II. The lyrics are
    written from the perspective of a person welcoming home his or
    her spouse or lover at the end of the war.</p>
      <p>The music was written by Jule Styne, the lyrics by Sammy
    Cahn. A recording by Harry James with vocal by Kitty Kallen
    reached #1 on the Billboard Hot 100 chart on November 24, 1945.
    An alternate version by Bing Crosby accompanied by The Les Paul
    Trio was also working its way up the charts. It replaced the
    James' version at #1 on December 8, 1945. Crosby's lasted a
    week at #1, ousted by Sammy Kaye's "Chickery Chick." The Harry
    James recording then returned to the top spot on December 22
    for another week.</p>
      <p>In 1945 it was standard practice in the record industry for
    labels to release "competing" versions of hit songs. Other
    recordings of "It's Been A Long, Long Time" that charted in
    1945 were recorded by Charlie Spivak &amp; His Orchestra (with
    vocal by Irene Daye) and Stan Kenton &amp; His Orchestra (vocal
    by June Christy).</p>
      <p>Crosby's version features some memorable guitar by Les Paul,
    who recalled in an interview printed in 
    <i>Mojo</i>magazine: "Bing was a sucker for guitar and that
    particular song was a case of you don't have to play a lot of
    notes, you just have to play the right notes."</p>
      <p>The song quickly became a pop standard, with well received
    versions recorded by June Haver &amp; Dan Dailey (1950), Perry
    Como (1956), Al Hibbler (1956), Peggy Lee(1959), Keely Smith
    (1959), Louis Armstrong (1964), and Tom Jones (1966). Frank
    Sinatra did not make a studio recording of the song, but sang a
    version on his radio show that has appeared on many Sinatra
    compilation albums.</p>
      <p>Other artists who have recorded it include Guy Mitchell,
    Sammy Cahn, Shelley Fabares, Sammy Kaye, The Ink Spots, Tina
    Louise, Jimmy Roselli, Brook Benton, Rosemary Clooney, Chet
    Atkins (with Les Paul on their album Chester and Lester) and
    Star Trek: The Next Generation's Brent Spiner on his 1991
    album, 
    <i>Ol' Yellow Eyes Is Back</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
