<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alone_(Heart_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alone_(Heart_song)</songId>
   <title>Alone</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heart_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Heart</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-07-11</week>
      <week>1987-07-18</week>
      <week>1987-07-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/c/cb/Heart_Alone.jpg/200px-Heart_Alone.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Heart+Alone.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Bad Animals</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 16, 1987</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:39</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Billy Steinberg</writer>
      <writer>Tom Kelly</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Ron Nevison</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Alone" is a song composed by Billy Steinberg and Tom Kelly.
    It first appeared on via Steinberg and Kelly's pet project,
    1983's I-Ten, 
    <i>Taking a Cold Look</i>. It was later recorded by John Stamos
    in his role as Gino Minelli, on the original soundtrack of the
    CBS sitcom 
    <i>Dreams</i>in 1984. American rock band Heart made it a hit in
    1987. Twenty years later, Céline Dion recorded it for her album
    
    <i>Taking Chances</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was given to Heart and released as the first single
    from their ninth studio album 
    <i>Bad Animals</i>. Heart's version is a power ballad that
    begins with a piano line and a subdued vocal from Ann Wilson,
    only to build to a dramatic love song. According to a Songfacts
    interview with Steinberg, Kelly, who was an experienced session
    singer, sung high harmony parts on the record. "Alone" is
    Heart's biggest hit, spending three weeks at number 1 on the
    U.S. Billboard Hot 100 and ranking number 2 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Year-End Top Pop Singles of 1987. It is also
    their most successful single in the United Kingdom, where it
    peaked at number 3 on the UK Singles Chart.The song's vieo
    featured the band live.</p>
      <p>Céline Dion covered "Alone" for her 2007 album 
    <i>Taking Chances</i>. It was released as the second single in
    Europe and North America, and third in the United Kingdom.
    "Eyes on Me" was released as the second single in the United
    Kingdom instead.</p>
      <p>"Alone" was produced by Ben Moody, ex-member of
    Evanescence.</p>
      <p>Dion performed it in various TV shows, during her
    promotional tour for the 
    <i>Taking Chances</i>album, in November and December 2007.
    Because of that and due to music download sales, the song
    debuted in November 2007 at number 85 on the UK Singles Chart.
    For the same reason, after selling 12,535 copies, it entered
    the U.S. Bubbling Under Hot 100 Singles at number 24 and
    Canadian Hot 100 at number 57.</p>
      <p>Officially "Alone" debuted on radio in Sweden in December
    2007. The next month it entered the Swedish Singles Chart, due
    to strong digital sales, and peaked at number 52.</p>
      <p>The song premiered on other European radio sations in
    January 2008. Céline Dion promoted "Alone" at that time in
    France, performing it on 
    <i>Star Academy</i>. In France, the song was released
    simultaneously with "A cause," featured on 
    <i>D'elles</i>. "Alone" was also serviced to radio at the end
    of March in Canada and in mid-April in the United States.</p>
      <p>The digital single release in the UK on May 5, 2008 was
    coincided with the British leg of the Taking Chances Tour.</p>
      <p>The music video was taken from Dion's CBS TV special 
    <i>That's Just the Woman in Me</i>and released in early March
    2008.</p>
      <p>In October 2008, "Alone" was included on the European
    version of 
    <i>My Love: Essential Collection</i>.</p>
      <p>UK digital single</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
