<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/These_Dreams 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/These_Dreams</songId>
   <title>These Dreams</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heart_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Heart</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-03-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/5/52/Heart_These_Dreams.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Heart+These-Dreams.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Heart</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 18, 1986</released>
   <formats>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>7'" (picture sleeve)</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>The Record Plant, Sausalito, CA (January-April 1985)</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Powerpop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:15</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Martin Page</writer>
      <writer>Bernie Taupin</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Ron Nevison</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"These Dreams" is a popular song released in 1986 by the
    rock band Heart from their 1985 self-titled album. It was the
    first song by the band to become a number one hit on the
    Billboard Hot 100.</p>
      <p>In 1985, Martin Page (who co-wrote several other pop hits,
    including "We Built This City" and "King of Wishful Thinking")
    and Bernie Taupin (longtime collaborator of Elton John) wrote
    the music and lyrics to the song now known as "These Dreams."
    At the time, Page and Taupin were under contract to Columbia
    Records and the record company offered the song to Stevie
    Nicks, who expressed no interest in recording it. Heart had
    just recently signed with Capitol Records. While the band had
    previously recorded their own material, they were impressed by
    "These Dreams" and agreed to use it on their upcoming
    album.</p>
      <p>"These Dreams" differed from past Heart hits in that it was
    a polished, pop power ballad. The song also marked the first
    Heart single on which lead vocals were performed by Nancy
    Wilson instead of Ann Wilson. According to 
    <i>The Billboard Book of Number One Hits</i>by Fred Bronson,
    when it came time for Nancy Wilson to record her vocal, she was
    suffering from a cold and her voice sounded somewhat raspy and
    gravelly. After the song reached its peak of success, producers
    reportedly wanted Nancy to recreate the gravelly sound on
    future recordings, asking her, "Can't you just get sick
    again?"</p>
      <p>"These Dreams" was released as the third single from Heart's
    1985 album 
    <i>Heart</i>. Following two consecutive US top-ten singles, the
    song elevated the band's success even further, becoming Heart's
    first single to hit number one on the Billboard Hot 100 on
    March 22, 1986. It also became Heart's first (and, to date,
    only) number one song in the US Adult Contemporary chart and
    peaked at number sixty-two in the UK Singles Chart; however, a
    re-issue released in 1988 reached number eight.</p>
      <p>The music video for "These Dreams" received heavy airplay
    from MTV and was the third of four US top-ten singles from the 
    <i>Heart</i>album. The single's B-side, "Shell Shock", was also
    the B-side of Heart's previous single "Never".</p>
      <p>The petite sail-shaped electric guitar Nancy played in the
    music video was the creation of Nashville luthier David
    Petschulat, which had been purchased years earlier.</p>
      <p>This song was dedicated (on the album) to Nancy Wilson's
    good friend Sharon Hess, who died of leukemia shortly before
    the song was made. The lyrics of the song describe the fantasy
    world a person enters when faced with a difficult situation in
    real life. The final verse seemingly suggests that, moments
    before awakening, what one desires the most is exactly that
    which is out of reach in a dream: "In a wood full of princes,
    freedom is a kiss. But the prince hides his face from dreams in
    the mist."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
