<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Am_Woman 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Am_Woman</songId>
   <title>I Am Woman</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Helen_Reddy</artistId>
      <artistName>Helen Reddy</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1972-12-09</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/d1/Reddy.jpg/200px-Reddy.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Helen-Reddy+I-Am-Woman.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>I Am Woman</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 1972</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1972</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:04</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ray Burton</writer>
      <writer>Helen Reddy</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jay Senter</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Am Woman" is a song cowritten by Helen Reddy and
    singer/songwriter/guitarist Ray Burton and performed by Reddy.
    Released in its most well-known version in 1972, the song
    became an enduring anthem for the women’s liberation
    movement.</p>
      <p>The song reached #1 on the Billboard charts in December
    1972. It was the first #1 on the Billboard chart by an
    Australian artist and the first Australian-penned song to win a
    Grammy Award (in her acceptance speech for Best Female
    Performance, Reddy famously thanked "God, because 
    <i>She</i>makes everything possible"). It sold more than a
    million copies, and has been played more than a million times
    on US radio, and helped propel Reddy to a successful pop career
    which made her more than $40 million in America. As an example
    of the endurance of the song, it was played at the 2010 Academy
    Awards as the exit music for Kathryn Bigelow after she won the
    Best Director Oscar for "The Hurt Locker," the first time a
    woman won the award.</p>
      <p>After securing a recording contract in 1971 with Capitol
    Records that yielded the hit "I Don't Know How to Love Him",
    Reddy – then living in Los Angeles -- was asked for an album.
    She gave the label a set of 10 jazz-tinged pop songs. Nestled
    among the Leon Russell, Graham Nash and Van Morrison songs were
    two Reddy originals. "I Am Woman" was one of them. The
    composition was the result of Reddy’s search for a song that
    would express her growing passion for female empowerment. In a
    2003 interview in Australia’s 
    <i>Sunday Magazine</i>(published with the 
    <i>Sunday Herald Sun</i>and 
    <i>Sunday Telegraph</i>), she explained:</p>
      <p>The only songs were 'I Feel Pretty' or that dreadful song
    'Born A Woman'." (The 1966 hit by Sandy Posey had observed that
    if you're born a woman "you're born to be stepped on, lied to,
    cheated on and treated like dirt. I'm glad it happened that
    way".) These are not exactly empowering lyrics. I certainly
    never thought of myself as a songwriter, but it came down to
    having to do it.</p>
      <p>Reddy’s own long years on stage had also fuelled her
    contempt for men who belittled women, she said. "Women have
    always been objectified in showbiz. I'd be the opening act for
    a comic and as I was leaving the stage he'd say, 'Yeah, take
    your clothes off and wait for me in the dressing room, I'll be
    right there'. It was demeaning and humiliating for any woman to
    have that happen publicly."</p>
      <p>Reddy credits the song as having supernatural inspiration.
    She said: "I remember lying in bed one night and the words, 'I
    am strong, I am invincible, I am woman', kept going over and
    over in my head. That part I consider to be divinely inspired.
    I had been chosen to get a message across." Pressed on who had
    chosen her, she replied: "The universe." The next day she wrote
    the lyric and handed it to Australian guitarist Ray Burton to
    put it to music.</p>
      <p>Burton, 26 at the time and playing in Los Angeles with
    Australian rock band The Executives (and later a member of
    Ayer's Rock), was a friend who had often worked with Reddy in
    live venues across Australia. He has a different recollection
    of the song's beginning. He told 
    <i>Sunday Magazine</i>he spoke to Reddy after she attended a
    series of regular women's meetings at which he says they would
    "sit around and whinge about their boyfriends".</p>
      <p>Reddy insists Burton didn't change a word of the lyrics. Yet
    she admits she had no expectations for the track. More than a
    year later, however, the song was picked to run behind the
    opening credits of 
    <i>Stand Up And Be Counted</i>, a lightweight Hollywood women's
    lib comedy starring Jacqueline Bisset, Loretta Swit and Steve
    Lawrence. On the strength of this, Capitol decided to release
    the song as a single. Because in its initial form 
    <i>I Am Woman</i>ran to little more than two minutes, Reddy was
    asked to write an additional verse and chorus. The extra verse
    inserted the song's only reference to men ("Until I make my
    brother understand"). More importantly, the new version would
    add significant punch to a song that, in its initial form, was
    simple, bouncy and unconfronting.</p>
      <p>Reddy told 
    <i>Sunday Magazine</i>she remembered nothing of the second
    recording session and did not know which musicians played on
    the song. In fact, she had one of the best line-ups in LA
    backing her:</p>
      <p>According to Mike Deasy, the session, at Sun West Studio on
    Hollywood Boulevard, was neither typical nor cheerful. Producer
    Jay Senter quit as soon as the track was complete, allegedly
    because he could not tolerate the attitude of Reddy’s famously
    hot-tempered husband, Jeff Wald. Deasy told 
    <i>Sunday Magazine</i>:</p>
      <p>As the single was released, Wald – who had worked the phones
    for 18 hours a day when her first single was released, urging
    radio stations to play it – once more put his formidable
    promotional skills to use. He won gigs for Reddy - by now
    heavily pregnant with son Jordan - to sing on 19 TV talk and
    variety shows, which in turn triggered phone calls from female
    viewers to radio stations begging them to play it. "It was
    through television that we forced them to play it," said Reddy.
    And as radio played it, women bought it, driving the song
    higher in the charts until it hit No.1 on December 9, 1972, the
    week Reddy gave birth. "It was my first No.1," said Reddy, "and
    it was the first No.1 Capitol Records had in five years. They
    were chuffed."</p>
      <p>In the year that Gloria Steinem's Ms. magazine was launched
    in the US and Cleo in Australia, the song quickly captured the
    imagination of the burgeoning women's movement. National
    Organization for Women founder Betty Friedan was later to write
    that in 1973, a gala entertainment night in Washington DC at
    the NOW annual convention closed with the playing of "I Am
    Woman". "Suddenly," she said, "women got out of their seats and
    started dancing around the hotel ballroom and joining hands in
    a circle that got larger and larger until maybe a thousand of
    us were dancing and singing, 'I am strong, I am invincible, I
    am woman.' It was a spontaneous, beautiful expression of the
    exhilaration we all felt in those years, women really moving as
    women."</p>
      <p>To Reddy, the song's message reaches beyond feminism. "It's
    not just for women," she said. "It's a general empowerment song
    about feeling good about yourself, believing in yourself. When
    my former brother-in-law, a doctor, was going to medical school
    he played it every morning just to get him going."</p>
      <p>The song brought greater exposure to Reddy, paving the way
    for a succession of hit singles. It also generated tremendous
    wealth, which the couple flaunted with a gaudy lifestyle of
    mansions, limousines, jewelry and speedboats. In her tell-all
    Hollywood book, 
    <i>You'll Never Eat Lunch in This Town Again</i>, Julia
    Phillips claimed that by the time the couple completed their
    acrimonious divorce in 1982 they had blown most of the $40
    million they had made. When Reddy’s performance of the song at
    the 1981 Miss World contest infuriated feminists, she
    responded: "Let them step forward and pay my rent and I'll stay
    home. What I'm doing is advertising a product I wouldn't
    use."</p>
      <p>Expelled from the US in 1971 because of work-permit
    problems, Ray Burton was forced to watch the song's stellar
    rise in the US from a distance. Things became so bad he was
    forced to live on unemployment benefits. "It could have been
    the launching pad for a writing and singing career," he said.
    "They took advantage of the fact I wasn't there."</p>
      <p>He claimed he was forced to take legal action against the
    singer in 1998 to recover a portion of songwriter royalties
    that had been withheld from him since 1972. He said: "I got
    some money out of it, but nothing like it would have been in
    the '70s when it was riding high."</p>
      <p>Reddy disputes Burton's claims. "There was a buyout 25 or 30
    years ago," she told 
    <i>Sunday Magazine</i>. "Neither of us had any idea the song
    would become what it became. About 10 years ago he got in touch
    with me because he was in financial difficulties. I felt sorry
    for him and reinstated his songwriter royalties. His passport
    problems ended any hope he had of a career in the States and
    somehow that bitterness got transferred to me. I wish him well.
    I bear him no animosity."</p>
      <p>Today he performs again in venues on the Queensland Gold
    Coast, where he lives. Sometimes he includes it in his set,
    raising a laugh from audiences by saying, "Here's a song I
    wrote in the '70s, with a twist." He sings it as, "She is
    woman, hear her roar".</p>
      <p>Interest in the song has been revived by its use in the 1997
    Julia Roberts film 
    <i>My Best Friend’s Wedding</i>and a Jessica Williams dance
    version from a 1999 film, 
    <i>Trick</i>. It was covered by The Dan Band on their CD 
    <i>The Dan Band Live</i>and also inspired a one-hour music
    special by the group, 
    <i>Dan Finnerty &amp; The Dan Band: I Am Woman</i>. It has been
    used in TV commercials for a sports footwear chain and a
    female-oriented cable TV network, but a pitch about 2003 by
    Coors beer ("with a gigantic amount of money," Reddy says) was
    rebuffed. "I'm not in the drug-dealing business," she says. "I
    don't care how much money they offer me." For some years Reddy
    tired of talking about the song, frustrated that out of her
    35-year music career it was all the media remembered her for.
    In recent years a hint of revisionism has crept in, prompted by
    the discovery that her lyrics had been included in history
    textbooks in US schools. Reddy, who says her singing career is
    over, last performed the song in October 2002, using it to
    conclude a world farewell concert in Edmonton. It was an
    emotional night. "I had no idea what the song was destined to
    become," she said. "If I'd known, I would have been far too
    intimidated to have written it."</p>
      <p>The song was recorded by Paul Weston and Jo Stafford, in the
    guise of untalented duo Jonathan &amp; Darlene Edwards. The
    couple gave the song their characteristic treatment--deliberate
    wrong notes, shifting tempo and style, and mismatched
    percussion.</p>
      <p>In 2006, Burger King reworked the lyrics for a commercial
    titled "Manthem" extolling the virtues of large burgers over
    small "chick food" plates. [1] [2]</p>
      <p>In March 2007, Rush Limbaugh starting using this song in a
    parody form for his "John Edwards Update" on his radio show
    after a New York Times reporter said that Edwards could be the
    first woman president.</p>
      <p>On July 3, 2008, the song was played in the fifth episode of
    the CBS series 
    <i>Swingtown</i>and on September 2, 2008 it was played by the
    school band in episode 10 of 
    <i>The Secret Life of the American Teenager</i>.</p>
      <p>The style of the title has become iconic and has inspired
    other songs, such as 'I Am Cow' by The Arrogant Worms and poems
    including 'I Am Pigeon' by Flying Lemming.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
