<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Angie_Baby 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Angie_Baby</songId>
   <title>Angie Baby</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Helen_Reddy</artistId>
      <artistName>Helen Reddy</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-12-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Free and Easy</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1974</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Easy Listening</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:29</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Alan O'Day</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Joe Wissert</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Angie Baby" is a popular song that was a number-one U.S.
    hit for Australian singer Helen Reddy. It hit #1 on the
    Billboard Hot 100 chart at the end of December of 1974 and
    became one of Reddy's biggest-selling singles. The song also
    topped the U.S. adult contemporary chart, the singer's fifth #1
    on this chart.</p>
      <p>The song's cryptic lyrics have inspired a number of listener
    theories as to what the song is really about, and Reddy has
    refused to comment on what the true storyline of the song is,
    partly because she has said she enjoys hearing other listeners'
    interpretations. Reddy has also said that "Angie Baby" was the
    one song she never had to push radio stations into playing.</p>
      <p>Singer/songwriter Alan O'Day finally revealed in 1998 that
    the "crazy" heroine in the song had "magic power" and "special
    abilities", and that he had deliberately blurred the lines
    between fantasy and reality. However, he still declined to give
    a detailed explanation of what happened to the boy in the song.
    Reddy herself had joked that the boy had become "a sound wave",
    an explanation that O'Day later refuted.</p>
      <p>In an article he wrote in 2006, O'Day said the song took
    three months to write. Originally it was loosely based on the
    character in the Beatles’ "Lady Madonna". In order to make the
    character more interesting, he decided to make her abnormal,
    and he thought of a young next door neighbor girl he had known
    who had seemed "socially retarded." O'Day said he also thought
    to his own childhood, since as an only child who was often ill,
    many of his days were spent in bed with a radio to keep him
    company. He named the character Angie, probably inspired by the
    Rolling Stones' song "Angie". Originally the character was just
    supposed to be mentally "slow," but while writing the song,
    O'Day showed it to his therapist, who pointed out that the
    character's reactions in the song were not those of a retarded
    person, so O'Day changed the lyric from "slow" to "touched,"
    and the character switched from retarded to "crazy." This
    expanded to her living in a dream world of lovers, inspired by
    the songs on her radio. When a "neighbor boy with evil on his
    mind" tries to enter her room to take advantage of the girl, he
    is instead drawn into her reality, with weird and unexpected
    consequences. The intent was to show that the Angie character
    had more power than he or the listener expected; she literally
    shrank him down into her radio, where he remained as her slave
    whenever she desired him to come out.</p>
      <p>Not everyone understood the meaning of O'Day's lyrics, and
    when the song was released, it inspired a great deal of
    speculation as to its true meaning. The song was compared to
    Bobbie Gentry’s "Ode To Billie Joe" (which had a mystery about
    "something" thrown off the Tallahatchie Bridge). Some also
    thought of it as a "Women's Lib" song along the line of Reddy's
    other hits, like her other #1's, "I Am Woman" and "Delta Dawn,"
    though O'Day says that that was not his intent, and that he was
    not consciously making a public statement.</p>
      <p>The song was also featured as the sole Helen Reddy track as
    part of a promotional-only compilation album issued by Capitol
    Records entitled "The Greatest Music Ever Sold" (Capitol
    SPRO-8511/8512), which was distributed to record stores during
    the 1976 Holiday season as part of Capitol's "Greatest Music
    Ever Sold" campaign, promoting 15 "Best Of" albums that were
    released by the record label.</p>
      <p>"Angie Baby" became Helen Reddy's first charting single in
    the British Isles reaching #5 in both the UK and Ireland in
    February 1975; Reddy would chart again once in both nations
    with "I Can't Say Goodbye to You" - (#43 UK/ #16 Ireland) - in
    1981. [1] "Angie Baby" was also Reddy's final major hit in her
    native Australia at #13.</p>
      <p>Alan O' Day recorded his composition for his 1977 album 
    <i>Appetizers</i>. "Angie Baby" has also been recorded by
    Barbara Dickson.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
