<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Delta_Dawn 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Delta_Dawn</songId>
   <title>Delta Dawn</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Helen_Reddy</artistId>
      <artistName>Helen Reddy</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1973-09-15</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Delta Dawn</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1972</released>
   <recorded>1972</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Country</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:09</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Larry Collins</writer>
      <writer>Alex Harvey</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Delta Dawn" is a song written by former child rockabilly
    star Larry Collins and songwriter Alex Harvey (who more often
    goes by the name Alexander Harvey today, and is not to be
    confused with the late Glaswegian rocker Alex Harvey), best
    known as a 1972 Top Ten C&amp;W hit for Tanya Tucker and a #1
    hit for Helen Reddy in 1973.</p>
      <p>The title character of "Delta Dawn" is a faded southern
    belle from Brownsville, Tennessee who at forty-one is obsessed
    to unreason by the long ago memory of an errant suitor. The
    song's lyrics describe how the woman regularly "walks downtown
    with a suitcase in her hand/ Looking for a mysterious dark
    haired man" who she says is "meeting her…today/ To take [her]
    to his mansion in the sky".</p>
      <p>The song is said to have been inspired by a woman named Dawn
    Parsworth who waited aimlessly for days for a man who had stood
    her up after promising to marry her. She would walk up to the
    bus-stop every day slowly becoming more and more mentally-ill.
    She was later admitted to a Brownsville asylum where she died
    in a ward cell.</p>
      <p>The song's composer Alex Harvey made the first recording of
    "Delta Dawn". Tracy Nelson, who sang backup on Harvey's
    recording, performed "Delta Dawn" in her live act and after
    hearing Nelson sing "Delta Dawn" at the Bottom Line in New York
    City Bette Midler added the song to her repertoire.
    Nashville-based producer Billy Sherrill heard Midler sing
    "Delta Dawn" on 
    <i>The Tonight Show</i>and wanted to sign her to Epic Records
    and have her record the song. Finding out that Midler was
    already signed to Atlantic Records, Sherrill cut the song with
    Tanya Tucker who was newly signed to Epic and Tucker's version
    reached #6 C&amp;W in the spring of 1972. Record producer Tom
    Catalano prepped an instrumental track of "Delta Dawn",
    virtually replicating that of Tucker's single, and - despite
    Catalano having worked with Helen Reddy - the track was first
    offered to Barbra Streisand, upon whose refusal Catalano had
    Reddy add her vocals to the track.</p>
      <p>In the meantime Bette Midler had recorded "Delta Dawn" for
    her 
    <i>The Divine Miss M</i>debut album from which her bluesy
    version was planned as the lead single. The June 1973 single
    release of Reddy's version was two days prior to Midler's
    necessitating the amendment of the latter's single so that the
    original B-side "Boogie Woogie Bugle Boy" was shopped to radio,
    becoming a Top Ten hit. Reddy's version of "Delta Dawn" entered
    the Top Ten in August 1973 to spend two weeks at #1 that
    September, becoming Reddy's second #1 hit after "I Am Woman";
    Reddy would subsequently reach #1 with "Angie Baby". "Delta
    Dawn" also became the first of Reddy's six consecutive - and
    eight overall - #1 hits on the Easy Listening chart in 
    <i>Billboard</i>.</p>
      <p>In Reddy's native Australia, where she'd reached #2 with
    both "I Don't Know How to Love Him" and "I Am Woman", "Delta
    Dawn" became Reddy's first #1 hit, spending five weeks atop the
    chart in August and September 1973. The follow-up single "Leave
    Me Alone (Ruby Red Dress)" gave Reddy a second consecutive -
    and final - Australian #1.</p>
      <p>"Delta Dawn" also marked Reddy's only chart appearance in
    South Africa, reaching #13 in the autumn of 1973.</p>
      <p>"Delta Dawn" has been recorded by a number of C&amp;W
    artists: Bob Luman, Loretta Lynn, the Statler Brothers, Waylon
    Jennings, Kitty Wells and Dottie West. The song was also
    recorded by Teresa Brewer and Scott Walker.</p>
      <p>"Delta Dawn" has been popular across college campuses in the
    southeastern United States since the late 1980s, as New Orleans
    based cowpunk band Dash Rip Rock has made it one of their
    signature live tunes. The song has also been released on the
    Dash Rip Rock album 
    <i>Boiled Alive</i>. Punk rock band Me First and the Gimme
    Gimmes recorded "Delta Dawn" for their 2004 live album 
    <i>Ruin Jonny's Bar Mitzvah</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
