<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rise_(Herb_Alpert_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rise_(Herb_Alpert_song)</songId>
   <title>Rise</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Herb_Alpert</artistId>
      <artistName>Herb Alpert</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1979-10-20</week>
      <week>1979-10-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Rise</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1979</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12-inch single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>7:35</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>A&amp;M</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Andy Armer</writer>
      <writer>Randy Badazz Alpert</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Herb Alpert</producer>
      <producer>Randy Badazz Alpert</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Rise" is a song written by Andy Armer and Randy Badazz
    Alpert, and first recorded by trumpeter Herb Alpert. The
    instrumental track was included on Alpert's solo album 
    <i>Rise</i>and released as a single in 1979. It reached number
    one on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 in October of that year and
    remained in the top position for two weeks. Herb Alpert thus
    became the first (and only) artist to reach the top of the Hot
    100 with a vocal performance ("This Guy's in Love with You",
    1968) as well as an instrumental performance. "Rise" also spent
    one week atop the adult contemporary chart. "Rise" was
    successful on the other charts: It peaked at number four on the
    soul chart. . and number seventeen on the disco chart. .The
    recording also received a Grammy Award for Best Pop
    Instrumental Performance.</p>
      <p>"Rise" was originally recorded as an uptempo dance song,
    however, Herb and Randy tried slowing the tempo down to 100bpm.
    Upon release, the song received an unexpected burst of
    promotion: Jill Phelps, musical director of the ABC soap opera 
    <i>General Hospital</i>, decided to use "Rise" as the musical
    backdrop for the rape of Laura Webber by Luke Spencer. For
    several weeks afterward, the recording was played on the show
    to evoke the memory of Luke's act. The added exposure in an
    extremely popular program boosted sales to the point of selling
    more than one million copies.</p>
      <p>Shortly after "Rise" became a hit in the United States, it
    became a hit in the United Kingdom when British disk jockeys
    were playing import copies of the record at the wrong speed
    (American 12-inch singles are played at 33 revolutions per
    minute, the same as an LP, while British and European 12-inch
    singles are played as 45 RPM).</p>
      <p>In the 1981 Hindi movie 
    <i>Yaarana</i>starring Amitabh Bachchan and Neetu Singh, Neetu
    Singh teaches Amitabh some dance moves to this song. The song
    almost plays full length as Amitabh masters disco dancing.</p>
      <p>A sample of "Rise" is the entire musical groove of the 1997
    #1 world-wide hit song, "Hypnotize", recorded by The Notorious
    B.I.G. and co-produced by Sean "Puffy" Combs. The sample is
    credited on both the single, "Hypnotize" and in the liner notes
    for the Notorious B.I.G's album, "Life After Death".</p>
      <p>In 1999, Brazilian saxophonist Leo Gandelman did a remake of
    "Rise" for his album "Brazilian Soul".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
