<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27m_Henery_the_Eighth,_I_Am 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27m_Henery_the_Eighth,_I_Am</songId>
   <title>I'm Henry VIII, I Am</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Herman%27s_Hermits</artistId>
      <artistName>Herman's Hermits</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1965-08-07</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"I'm Henery the Eighth, I Am" (also "I'm Henery the VIII, I
    Am" or "I'm Henry VIII, I Am"; spelled "Henery" in references
    to the Herman's Hermits version) is a 1910 British music hall
    song by Fred Murray and R. P. Weston. It was a signature song
    of music hall star Harry Champion and became the
    fastest-selling song in history to that point when revived in
    1965 by Herman's Hermits, becoming the group's second
    number-one on the Hot 100 chart. The lead solo on the Hermits'
    version was played by the group's lead guitarist Derek "Lek"
    Leckenby.</p>
      <p>In the well-known chorus, Henery explains that his wife had
    been married seven times before:</p>
      <p>
         <i>I'm Henery the Eighth, I am,,</i>
         <i>Henery the Eighth I am, I am!</i>, 
    <i>I got married to the widow next door,</i>, 
    <i>She'd been married seven times before.</i>, 
    <i>And every one was an Henery</i>, 
    <i>She wouldn't have a Willie or a Sam</i>, 
    <i>I'm her eighth old man named Henery</i>, 
    <i>Henery the Eighth, I am!</i>,</p>
      <p>According to one source, Champion "used to fire off [the
    chorus] at tremendous speed with almost desperate gusto, his
    face bathed in sweat and his arms and legs flying in all
    directions." In later versions recorded by Champion, "Willie"
    is changed to "William" because the former is a slang term for
    the penis in Britain.</p>
      <p>The song is often sung in a Cockney accent.</p>
      <p>The Herman's Hermits version consists of the chorus sung
    three times. Between the first two choruses, Peter Noone calls
    out, "Second verse, same as the first!"</p>
      <p>This song was recorded (in 1961) and extensively performed
    live by the british star Joe Brown, who revived the song and
    made it largely known in the pop world. His version has two
    choruses either side of his guitar solo. He performs it live
    still today.</p>
      <p>Earlier sources usually spell the name "Henery" (as do some
    old sources when referring to the historical King of England),
    and the music requires the name "Henery" to be pronounced as
    three syllables. The sheet music for the 1965 Herman's Hermits
    revival, however, presented the name as "Henry", as do sources
    referring to this version.</p>
      <p>In the 1990 movie 
    <i>Ghost</i>, the ghost Sam (Patrick Swayze) pesters Oda Mae
    Brown (Whoopi Goldberg) into taking a message to his girlfriend
    by singing this song over and over again in a bad English
    accent all night long, keeping her awake. His girlfriend Molly
    (Demi Moore) later reveals that Sam used this tactic to get her
    to agree to go out with him.</p>
      <p>Homer Simpson sings this song in the 
    <i>Simpsons</i>episode 
    <i>Margical History Tour</i>, but with much different lyrics.
    Homer is playing King Henry VIII of England and substituting
    many words to state he is eating multiple course meals.</p>
      <p>In the comic book 
    <i>Spike vs. Dracula</i>, Spike threatens to haunt Dracula with
    an endless singing of the song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
