<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wake_Up_Little_Susie 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wake_Up_Little_Susie</songId>
   <title>Wake Up Little Susie " Everly Brothers</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Honeycomb_(song)</artistId>
      <artistName>"Honeycomb" Jimmie Rodgers</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1957-10-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Wake Up Little Susie" is a popular song written by Felice
    and Boudleaux Bryant and published in 1957.</p>
      <p>The song is best known in a recording by The Everly
    Brothers, issued by Cadence Records as catalog number 1337. The
    song reached number one on the Pop chart and the Cash Box Best
    Selling Records chart, despite having been banned from Boston
    radio stations for lyrics that, at the time, were considered
    suggestive. "Wake Up Little Susie" also spent seven weeks atop
    the 
    <i>Billboard</i>country chart and got to number two on the UK
    Singles Chart. The song was ranked at #311 on the 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's list of The 500 Greatest Songs
    of All Time.</p>
      <p>In an appearance on The Oprah Winfrey Show during the 2000
    U.S. presidential election, Governor George W. Bush named "Wake
    Up Little Susie" as his favorite song.</p>
      <p>The song is written from the point of view of a high school
    boy to his girlfriend, Susie. In the song, the two go out on a
    date to a drive-in movie theater, only to fall asleep during
    the movie. They do not wake up until 4 o'clock in the morning,
    well after the 10 o'clock curfew. They then contemplate the
    reactions of her parents and their friends.</p>
      <p>Although banned in such places as Boston, the song does not
    state that Susie and her boyfriend had sexual relations.
    Indeed, it strongly implies that they did not; the couple
    simply fell asleep because they were bored by the movie. One
    line in the lyrics states that the movie 
    <i>"didn't have much of a plot."</i>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
