<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rock_the_Boat_(Hues_Corporation_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rock_the_Boat_(Hues_Corporation_song)</songId>
   <title>Rock the Boat</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hues_Corporation</artistId>
      <artistName>Hues Corporation</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-07-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Rock the Boat" is a disco song by the group Hues
    Corporation in 1974. It is sometimes considered the first disco
    record to reach number one on the Billboard Hot 100 in the
    United States, though some consider this distinction to go to
    "Love's Theme" by Love Unlimited Orchestra (earlier that same
    year) or even The Sound Of Philadelphia (TSOP) by MFSB. "Rock
    the Boat" was written by Waldo Holmes, who also wrote the
    Blacula songs.</p>
      <p>"Rock the Boat" was first featured on the Hues Corporation's
    1973 album, 
    <i>Freedom for the Stallion</i>(an edited version later
    appeared on certain editions of the band's follow-up album,
    1974's 
    <i>Rockin' Soul</i>). and was released as the second single
    from the album in early 1974 to follow-up 
    <i>Stallion'</i>s title song, which had peaked at #63 on the
    Hot 100. Initially, "Rock the Boat" appeared as though it would
    flop, as months went by without any radio airplay or sales
    activity. Not until the song became a disco/club favorite in
    New York did Top 40 radio finally pick up on the song, leading
    the record to finally enter the Hot 100 and zip up the chart to
    #1 in July of 1974. The record also reached the top 10 in the
    United Kingdom. It is a heavy airplay favorite on oldie and
    adult-contemporary stations today.</p>
      <p>The song features a lead vocal by Fleming Williams, who left
    the Hues Corporation shortly after the song was recorded.
    According to 
    <i>The Billboard Book of Number One Hits</i>by Fred Bronson,
    the lone female member of the group, H. Ann Kelly, had
    originally been pegged to sing lead, but this idea was
    discarded out of fear that groups with female lead singers were
    less commercially viable. The song also features an important
    post-Motown performance of James Jamerson.</p>
      <p>"Rock the Boat" was covered in 1982 by the Dutch/American
    singer Forrest Thomas. His version also made the U.K. top five
    and the top 10 of the American Dance/Disco chart. Jacob Miller
    and the Inner Circle cut a Reggae version of the song in
    1974.</p>
      <p>0</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
