<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Need_You_Tonight 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Need_You_Tonight</songId>
   <title>Need You Tonight</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/INXS</artistId>
      <artistName>INXS</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1988-01-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/d9/Need_you_tonight.jpg/200px-Need_you_tonight.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/INXS+Need-You-Tonight.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Kick</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 23, 1987 , June 1, 2005 (remixes)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>12" single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>Cassette</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:00</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic records , Mercury Records , WEA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Andrew Farriss</writer>
      <writer>Michael Hutchence</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Chris Thomas</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Need You Tonight" is the fourth song on INXS's 1987 album 
    <i>Kick</i>as well as the first single from the album released
    worlwide. It was also the only single of the band's to reach #1
    on the Hot 100. It also achieved their highest peak at number
    two on the UK Singles Chart, however this peak was only reached
    after a re-release of the single in November 1988. On its first
    run on the UK Charts in October 1987, it stalled at No. 58.
    While it would arguably become the band's signature song, it
    was one of the last songs recorded for the album.</p>
      <p>In INXS's official autobiography, 
    <i>INXS: Story to Story</i>, Andrew Farriss said that the
    famous riff to the song appeared suddenly in his head while
    waiting for a cab to go to the airport to fly to Hong Kong. He
    asked the cab driver to wait a couple of minutes while he
    grabbed something from his motel room. In fact, he went up to
    record the riff and came back down an hour later with a tape to
    a very annoyed driver. This riff was later described as
    sounding like a cross between Keith Richards and Prince.</p>
      <p>The song is a much more electronic track than most of the
    band's material before or after, combining sequencers with
    regular drum tracks and a number of tracks of layered guitars.
    To approximate the sound on the recorded track, the band often
    utilizes click tracks for a frequent synthesizer chord as well
    as rim shots heard throughout the song.</p>
      <p>On the 
    <i>Kick</i>album, the song is linked to the next song, entitled
    either "Mediate" or "Meditate" depending on the pressing of the
    album. On some compilations, the two tunes appear together and
    on others, only "Need You Tonight" appears (rarely, if ever,
    has "Mediate" appeared on its own).</p>
      <p>The song is also notable for its promotional music video
    which combined live action and different kinds of animation.
    Directed by Richard Lowenstein, the video was actually "Need
    You Tonight / Mediate", as it combined two songs from the
    album. Lowenstein claimed that the particular visual effects in
    "Need You Tonight" were created by cutting up 35mm film and
    photocopying the individual frames, before re-layering those
    images over the original footage.</p>
      <p>For "Mediate", it segues into a tribute to Bob Dylan's
    "Subterranean Homesick Blues". The members flip cue cards with
    words from the song, followed by a Kirk Pengilly saxophone
    solo. Beneath the lyric "a special date" in the "Mediate"
    portion of the video, the cue card shown reads "9-8-1945". This
    refers to the date 9 August 1945 which was the date the atomic
    bomb was dropped on Nagasaki, Japan. As the date is in the
    Australian format, with the day first and month second,
    American observers sometimes confuse the date for 8 September
    1945.</p>
      <p>The video won five MTV Video Music Awards including Video of
    The Year and was ranked at number twenty-one on MTV's countdown
    of the 100 greatest videos of all time.</p>
      <p>Static Revenger/Koishii &amp; Hush Mixes, Remixes</p>
      <p>Rogue Traders covered and remixed "Need You Tonight" and
    released it as a single in Australia. The song was renamed "One
    of My Kind", where it reached #10 on the Australian Top 100
    Singles Chart, becoming their first top-10 hit. "One of My
    Kind" is the second single released by the Rogue Traders for
    their debut album 
    <i>We Know What You're Up To</i>. Because it was the only hit
    single from the album, the band was publicly considered one-hit
    wonders until "Voodoo Child" reached #4 in 2005.</p>
      <p>The music video is set in a dance party where the lizard on
    the single cover wanders around looking for a girl of his kind.
    He finds one looking lonely. The two sit together and he
    singles the line 'you're one of my kind' before the video
    ends.</p>
      <p>Maxi CD single</p>
      <p>12" vinyl</p>
      <p>The single spent 15 weeks in the charts, 9 of which were in
    the top 50. The single also topped the ARIA Dance chart.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
