<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theme_from_Shaft 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theme_from_Shaft</songId>
   <title>Theme from Shaft</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isaac_Hayes</artistId>
      <artistName>Isaac Hayes</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1971-11-20</week>
      <week>1971-11-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/4d/Theme-from-shaft-1971.jpg/200px-Theme-from-shaft-1971.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Isaac-Hayes+Theme-from-Shaft.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Shaft</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 1971</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>45 RPM</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
      <genre>Proto Disco</genre>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:15 (single edit)</length>
      <length>4:34 (album version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Stax , STXS-2010</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Isaac Hayes</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Isaac Hayes</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Theme from Shaft", written and recorded by Isaac Hayes in
    1971, is the soul- and funk-styled theme song to the
    Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer film 
    <i>Shaft</i>. The theme was released as a single (shortened and
    edited from the longer album version) two months after the
    movie's soundtrack by Stax Records' Enterprise label. "Theme
    from 
    <i>Shaft</i>" went to number one on the Billboard Hot 100 in
    the United States in November 1971. The song was also
    well-received by adult audiences, reaching number six on
    Billboard's Easy Listening (later Adult Contemporary)
    chart.</p>
      <p>The following year, "Theme from 
    <i>Shaft</i>" won the Academy Award for Best Original Song,
    with Hayes becoming the first African American to win that
    honor (or any Academy Award in a non-acting category). Since
    then, the song has appeared in numerous television shows,
    commercials, and other movies, including the 2000 remake of ,
    for which Hayes re-recorded the song without making any changes
    to it. "Theme from 
    <i>Shaft</i>" is sometimes considered more iconic than the
    movie for which it was written.</p>
      <p>In 2000, Hayes told National Public Radio that he had only
    agreed to write and record the 
    <i>Shaft</i>score after 
    <i>Shaft</i>producer Joel Freeman promised him an audition for
    the lead role. He never got the chance to audition, but kept
    his end of the deal anyway. Director Gordon Parks also had a
    hand in composing the theme, describing the character of John
    Shaft (the "black private dick/who's a sex machine/to all the
    chicks") to Hayes and explaining that the song had to
    familiarize the audience with him. Hayes recorded the rhythm
    parts on the theme first, scored the entire rest of the film,
    then returned to the theme song.</p>
      <p>The song begins with a sixteenth-note hi-hat ride pattern,
    played by Willie Hall, which was drawn from a break on Otis
    Redding's "Try A Little Tenderness", a Stax record on which
    Hayes had played. Also featuring heavily in the intro is
    Charles Pitts' guitar, which uses a wah-wah effect common in
    1970s funk; the riff had originally been written for an
    unfinished Stax song. The synthesized keyboard is played by
    Hayes. Even on the edited single version, the intro lasts for
    more than two and a half minutes before any vocals are
    heard.</p>
      <p>The lyrics describe John Shaft's coolness, courage, and sex
    appeal, and Hayes' lead vocals are punctuated by a trio of
    female backup singers. At one famous moment, Hayes calls Shaft
    "a bad mother—" before the backup singers (one of whom is Tony
    Orlando &amp; Dawn's Telma Hopkins) interrupt the implied
    profanity with the line "Shut yo' mouth!" Hayes immediately
    defends himself by replying that he's "only talking about
    Shaft," with the back-up vocalists replying, "We can dig it."
    Other well-known passages include "You're damn right!" also
    uttered by Hayes, and "He's a complicated man/but no one
    understands him/but his woman/John Shaft."</p>
      <p>The song was considered very racy for its time; as late as
    1990, censors at the Fox Network thought it too risqué to be
    sung on 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>(until it was demonstrated that the song had
    indeed been played on television before).</p>
      <p>The song was not intended to be a single, but the success of
    the film and the popularity of the track in nightclubs led to a
    45 record of the theme being released on Enterprise Records two
    months after the soundtrack. Within two months, it hit #1 on
    the Billboard Hot 100 and stayed there a second week. The song
    had an enormous influence on the disco and soul music of the
    decade.</p>
      <p>In 1972, Hayes performed "Theme from 
    <i>Shaft</i>" as part of the Academy Awards ceremony in his
    trademark chainmail vest, but accepted the award later that
    night wearing a tuxedo. Hayes dedicated his historic win to his
    grandmother, Rushia Wade, who joined him onstage to accept the
    award. In addition, Hayes, Rev. Jesse Jackson, and the Stax
    staff dedicated Hayes' win to the black community at an
    Operation PUSH rally following the Academy Awards.</p>
      <p>Later that year, Hayes performed "Theme from 
    <i>Shaft</i>" live at the Wattstax concert in Los Angeles Film
    footage of this performance was recorded for Mel Stuart's
    documentary film of the concert, but was cut before the film's
    release due to legal complications with MGM, who would not
    allow Hayes to perform his 
    <i>Shaft</i>songs in any other film until 1976. A 2003
    remastered version of the 
    <i>Wattstax</i>film reinstates Hayes' performance of "Theme
    from 
    <i>Shaft</i>".</p>
      <p>When John Singleton directed an updated version of 
    <i>Shaft</i>, starring Samuel L. Jackson, in 2000, Hayes
    rerecorded the theme for the new film.</p>
      <p>(the rerecorded version was based on the 1978 disco 12" mix
    titled Shaft II).</p>
      <p>The song has been played or parodied in television shows
    including 
    <i>The Fresh Prince of Bel-Air</i>, 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>, 
    <i>Sesame Street</i>, 
    <i>Scrubs</i>, 
    <i>The X-Files</i>, 
    <i>Mystery Science Theater 3000</i>, 
    <i>Father Ted</i>, 
    <i>Histeria!</i>, and 
    <i>The Wire</i>. On 
    <i>Sesame Street</i>a parodied version of the song, "Cookie
    Disco", was about Cookie Monster, dressed as Isaac Hayes, who
    ends up eating the set. The song was featured in the film 
    <i>I'm Gonna Git You Sucka</i>, where the lead character Slade
    is a parody on Shaft (Issac Hayes was in the film in a
    different role). The 1989 comedy film 
    <i>UHF</i>(co-written by and starring "Weird Al" Yankovic)
    features a mock trailer segment on television parodying the
    movie 
    <i>Gandhi</i>called 
    <i>Gandhi II</i>, set to music meant to resemble the 
    <i>Shaft</i>theme. A 1998 Burger King marketing campaign
    featured Hayes singing a retooled version of the song, with
    lyrics now alluding to Mr. Potato Head, who is seen dancing on
    the piano that Hayes plays. In the series Two and a Half Men,
    there are references occainsionally of the song, including one
    episode where Alan, Herb, Gordon, and another guy are seen
    singing the song as a barbershop quartet.</p>
      <p>Sammy Davis Jr recorded a cover version of this song with
    extended lyrics, and a version by Eddy &amp; The Soul Band was
    a hit in the 1980s.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
