<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You%27re_Beautiful 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You%27re_Beautiful</songId>
   <title>You're Beautiful</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Blunt</artistId>
      <artistName>James Blunt</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2006-03-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/66/You%27re_Beautiful.png/200px-You%27re_Beautiful.png</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/James-Blunt+You-re-Beautiful.png</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Back to Bedlam</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 30, 2005  (2005-05-30) , (See release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single (worldwide)</format>
      <format>7" single ( UK )</format>
      <format>Digital download ( U.S. )</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
      <genre>Folk Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:34 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>3:22 (Single Version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>James Blunt</writer>
      <writer>Sacha Skarbek</writer>
      <writer>Amanda Ghost</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Tom Rothrock</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"You're Beautiful" is a pop rock song co-written by British
    singer James Blunt, Sacha Skarbek and Amanda Ghost for Blunt's
    debut album 
    <i>Back to Bedlam</i>(2004). It was released as the third
    single from the album in 2005. In the UK and Australia the song
    reached number one and number two respectively. When released
    as the debut single from 
    <i>Back to Bedlam</i>in Canada and the U.S., it reached number
    one on both charts and received widespread airplay. In 2006,
    the song won an Ivor Novello Award for airplay, and it holds
    the honour of being the only song by a British artist to top
    the Latin America Top 40. The song has sold 625,000 copies in
    the UK as stated by the Official UK Charts Company.</p>
      <p>Newspapers have claimed that "You're Beautiful" is about a
    former girlfriend of Blunt's, Dixie Chassay, casting director
    for the 
    <i>Harry Potter</i>films, although Blunt refuses to confirm or
    deny this. On 8 March 2006 episode of the Oprah Winfrey
    program, Blunt said of the song, "It's kind of miserable. It
    was about seeing my ex-girlfriend on the Underground in London
    with her new man, who I didn't know existed. She and I caught
    eyes and lived a lifetime in that moment, but didn't do
    anything about it and haven't seen each other since." Several
    versions of the song exist. One lyrical version has an explicit
    word in it ("
    <i>She could see from my face that I was fucking high</i>")
    which was released on 
    <i>Back to Bedlam</i>and most of the "You're Beautiful"
    singles. The radio edit of the song replaces the explicit
    lyric, changing it to "
    <i>She could see from my face that I was flying high</i>".
    Acoustic, live and DVD versions have also been released.
    However, because of the word in question, the album was given a
    Parental Advisory sticker.</p>
      <p>When asked about the song, Blunt responded, "It's probably
    one of the least meaningful songs on the album and by no means
    people's favourite. The album is like a book covering various
    aspects of life in a specific order."</p>
      <p>In an interview with HitQuarters, co-writer Sacha Skarbek
    said their collaboration on the song began when Blunt brought
    the title and the approach of the chorus to a songwriting
    session. Skarbek's contribution largely focused on the music
    aspect to the track, contributing chord ideas for the verses,
    honing the melodies, and making sure the song stuck to, "a
    couple of key hooks rather than making it too complicated."</p>
      <p>The music video for "You're Beautiful" was directed by Sam
    Brown. The video shows Blunt committing suicide, following a
    Japanese tradition of removing one's shoes and contents of
    clothing prior to jumping from a great height. Blunt removes
    the upper portion of his clothing in a cold, bare, snowy
    setting and places all of his personal belongings on the
    ground. Whilst he does this, seagulls circle overhead like
    buzzards. At the end of the video, he jumps off a cliff and
    lands into the depths of icy water while he sings the lyrics:
    "But it's time to face the truth, I will never be with
    you".</p>
      <p>In a poll conducted by 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>to identify the 10 most annoying songs,
    this song was ranked seven. In another poll by the British
    tabloid 
    <i>The Sun</i>it was voted the most irritating song of all
    time.</p>
      <p>"You're Beautiful" is Blunt's most successful single release
    to date. It was also his first successful single, and reached
    number one in ten countries across the world, including the
    United Kingdom, the United States, Spain, Canada, and the
    Netherlands. The song peaked within the top five in Australia,
    France, and Germany.</p>
      <p>"You're Beautiful" accomplished a feat rarely seen on the
    modern UK Singles Chart by ascending the chart following its
    début. Released on 30 May 2005, it entered at number twelve on
    5 June and reached number one six weeks later where it remained
    for five consecutive weeks. The last song to début outside of
    the top ten and climb to number one was The Outhere Brothers'
    "Boom Boom Boom" (1995). The highest position "You're
    Beautiful" reached in Australia was number two, where it stayed
    for two consecutive weeks.</p>
      <p>In November 2005, "You're Beautiful" was released in North
    America where it achieved widespread success. In Canada, it
    ascended to number one (where it remained for four consecutive
    weeks) twenty-two weeks following its début on the BDS Airplay
    chart. In the United States, it débuted at number eighty-eight
    before reaching number one seventeen weeks later. It replaced
    Beyoncé's "Check on It" and itself was replaced by Ne-Yo's "So
    Sick". The song became the first non-urban or 
    <i>American Idol</i>song to reach the top of the U.S. Billboard
    Hot 100 since Nickelback's "How You Remind Me" in 2001.
    However, "Hollaback Girl" by Gwen Stefani has also been
    credited for that accomplishment, but due to its hip-hop based
    influences, it's been disputed. This also became the first
    single by a British artist to reach number one since Elton
    John's "Candle in the Wind 1997" (1997). It achieved success on
    the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Pop 100, Hot Digital Songs, Adult Contemporary,
    and Adult Top 40 formats.</p>
      <p>It has been certified six-fold platinum in the U.S. for
    digital sales of 1,200,000 copies.</p>
      <p>At the 2007 Grammy Awards this single received three
    nominations: Record of the Year, Song of the Year and Best Male
    Pop Vocal Performance [2] winning none. For the video the
    singer won the MTV Award for Best Male Video and Best
    Cinematography.</p>
      <p>A parody of the song was made by the British sketch-show 
    <i>Dead Ringers</i>. Titled "It's Bloody Cold", it featured Jon
    Culshaw as Blunt sitting in the snow and jumping into a
    swimming pool in an attempt to be seen as cool by the other
    major British singers (Robbie Williams, Noel Gallagher, Liam
    Gallagher, Morrissey and Craig David are explicitly named among
    these). It also claimed that the name "James Blunt" is Cockney
    rhyming slang.</p>
      <p>"Weird Al" Yankovic composed and recorded a parody of
    "You're Beautiful" entitled "You're Pitiful", intended for
    release on his twelfth album. Yankovic had done so with
    permission from Blunt himself. However, Blunt's label, Atlantic
    Records, chose to forbid Yankovic from releasing his parody.
    Yankovic removed the song from his album to avoid conflict with
    the record label, and in June 2006 posted it as a free download
    on his own website. [3]</p>
      <p>The Internet Sketch Comedy show 
    <i>Moron Life</i>did a parody of the song titled "My
    Testicles".</p>
      <p>The song and video were parodied on the sketch show, 
    <i>MADtv</i>. Nicole Parker played a narcissistic James Blunt
    and wore a prosthetic male torso when it came time to strip off
    her shirts during the song. 
    <i>MADtv</i>renamed the song to "I'm Beautiful".</p>
      <p>The song has also been parodied in an office setting: "My
    Cubicle", created by comedy website Morning Sidekick. Several
    versions are circulating, one audio-only, one with a video
    showing the lyrics on a blank background, and several
    fan-created music videos in which an actor acts out the actions
    in the lyrics. [4]</p>
      <p>The Amateur Transplants performed a parody to the song for
    their album Unfit to Practise, titled "Beautiful Song".</p>
      <p>Jared Leto and Shannon Leto of 30 Seconds to Mars joked
    around with the song in a clip for MTV2 while inside a car.
    Jared sang the song as "I'm Beautiful"</p>
      <p>Blunt has recorded an appearance for Season 38 of Sesame
    Street, in which he sings a parody titled "My Triangle."</p>
      <p>Music video by Kevin Sage named "She Was Beautiful" is a
    parody of the song.</p>
      <p>A parody of the song titled 'You're Beauteous' appeared on
    Cartoon Network. It uses scenes from The Marvelous
    Misadventures of Flapjack.</p>
      <p>These are the formats and track listings of major single
    releases of "You're Beautiful".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
