<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miami_Vice_Theme 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miami_Vice_Theme</songId>
   <title>Miami Vice Theme</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jan_Hammer</artistId>
      <artistName>Jan Hammer</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1985-11-09</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/2b/MiamiViceThemejap.jpg/200px-MiamiViceThemejap.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Jan-Hammer+Miami-Vice-Theme.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Miami Vice soundtrack</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1985</released>
   <recorded>1984</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Electronic</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:26</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MCA Records</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jan Hammer</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>The musical piece Miami Vice Theme was created and performed
    by Jan Hammer as the theme to the television series 
    <i>Miami Vice</i>. It was first presented as part of the
    television broadcast of the show in September 1984 and released
    as a single in 1985, peaking at the number one spot on the
    Billboard Hot 100. It is the last instrumental to have topped
    the chart to date. It also peaked at number 5 in the UK. In
    1986, it won Grammy Awards for "Best Instrumental Composition"
    and "Best Pop Instrumental Performance." This song, along with
    Glenn Frey's number-two hit "You Belong to the City", put the 
    <i>Miami Vice</i>soundtrack on the top of the U.S. album chart
    for eleven weeks in 1985, making it the most successful TV
    soundtrack of all time until 2006 when Disney Channel's 
    <i>High School Musical</i>beat its record.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Miami Vice's</i>pilot episode, made as a two-hour TV movie,
    did not originally have a theme, but the musical sounds and
    notation that would become the theme were present as background
    score. When the series got picked up, Hammer created the sixty
    second version of the theme. The synth-guitar lead was missing
    in the aired version of the pilot and the first batch of
    episodes, and this unfinished version of the theme has remained
    attached to those episodes, even on the DVD video box set
    released in 2005.</p>
      <p>The theme is also remembered as the song played during the
    first few three-point competitions at the NBA All-Star Weekend,
    including the one in 1986 where Larry Bird famously walked into
    the locker room and told all his competitors they were playing
    for second place.</p>
      <p>From 1992 until 1997, it was used as the theme music for
    Westwood One's 
    <i>Radio Free D. C.: The G. Gordon Liddy Show</i>. (From 1992
    until 1996, an announcer would introduce the show during the
    music bed, saying, "From Washington D. C., Radio Free D.C.,
    with G. Gordon Liddy".)</p>
      <p>The music video of the theme is a mini-episode of the TV
    series with Hammer as a fugitive on the run from James "Sonny"
    Crockett and Ricardo Tubbs. Throughout majority of the video,
    Hammer performs the theme in front of a projector screen
    playing footage from the TV series - including scenes of the
    Vice duo chasing him. In the end of the video, he boards a
    helicopter and escapes from Crockett's sight.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
