<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/When_I_Think_of_You 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/When_I_Think_of_You</songId>
   <title>When I Think of You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Janet_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Janet Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-10-11</week>
      <week>1986-10-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/3f/Janet_Jackson_-_When_I_Think_Of_You_US_and_EU.jpg/200px-Janet_Jackson_-_When_I_Think_Of_You_US_and_EU.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Janet-Jackson+When-I-Think-of-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Control</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 28, 1986 (U.S.) , July 1986 (UK) , November 4, 1986 (South Africa)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>October 1985</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:57</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>A&amp;M</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>James Harris III</writer>
      <writer>Terry Lewis</writer>
      <writer>Janet Jackson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"When I Think of You" is the third single from Janet
    Jackson's third studio album, 
    <i>Control</i>(1986). The song—written by Jackson and Jimmy Jam
    and Terry Lewis and produced by Jam and Lewis—is about a person
    who finds relief and fun in a lover. It is Jackson's first
    number-one hit on the Hot 100, and also became a top ten hit
    (peaking at #10) in the United Kingdom.</p>
      <p>The song was resurrected in 1995 when released on two
    limited-edition CD single formats in the United Kingdom, one
    containing remixes by Deep Dish and Heller &amp; Farley, and
    the other containing remixes by David Morales. That same year
    the remixes were included on certain releases of "Runaway".</p>
      <p>The song has been performed on all of Jackson's tours.</p>
      <p>The single became Jackson's first number-one hit on the Hot
    100 chart. After "When I Think of You" reached number one, it
    made Jackson and her brother Michael Jackson the first, and so
    far, only siblings to both have solo number-one hits on the Hot
    100. At the time she was twenty years old, making Jackson the
    youngest artist since Stevie Wonder to top the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100. It also reached number three on the
    Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs and number one on the Hot Dance Club
    Play in 1986. "When I Think of You" was the thirty-second
    biggest Hot 100 single of 1986, as well as the forty-seventh
    biggest Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs single of 1986 and the
    twenty-second biggest Hot Dance Club Play single of 1986.</p>
      <p>Jackson has performed the song on the Rhythm Nation 1814
    Tour, janet. Tour, The Velvet Rope Tour, All for You Tour, and
    Rock Witchu Tour.</p>
      <p>The music video finds Jackson going around a neighborhood.
    Each location she visits has the same mysterious man in
    different costumes saying a brief statement to her and then
    vanishing as she turns around. The director of "When I Think of
    You", Julien Temple, would later direct Jackson's "Alright"
    video, and both videos have a similar style. "When I Think of
    You" has only five cuts. The video is quite similar to the
    opening segment of Temple's 1986 film 
    <i>Absolute Beginners</i>, which stars David Bowie and Sade
    Adu. The style is that the video is assumed to be one long
    take, but in fact it is five smaller takes. Although fluid in
    nature, obvious mistakes can be seen in the edits, especially
    when she comes out of the back door of the club, and a
    photographer takes her picture. The flash acts as an edit, but
    the people in the background are in quite different positions
    before and after the flash. Two of Jackson's nephews, TJ and
    Taryll Jackson make an cameo in the video.</p>
      <p>The Dance Remix was used for the video. The video was made
    available on the iTunes Store on February 1, 2007. Jackson
    would later repeat the same type of format for her video "Rock
    with U" from 2008's 
    <i>Discipline</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
