<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_Will_Never_Do_(Without_You) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_Will_Never_Do_(Without_You)</songId>
   <title>Love Will Never Do (Without You)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Janet_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Janet Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1991-01-19</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/34/LWNDWY_single_cover.jpg/200px-LWNDWY_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Janet-Jackson+Love-Will-Never-Do-Without-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Janet Jackson's Rhythm Nation 1814</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 2, 1990 (UK) , November 5, 1990 (U.S.)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1988-1989 , Flyte Tyme Studios , ( Minneapolis , Minnesota )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>New Jack Swing</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:30 (Single Version)</length>
      <length>5:50 (Album Version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>A&amp;M</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>James Harris III</writer>
      <writer>Terry Lewis</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Love Will Never Do (Without You)" is the seventh single
    from American R&amp;B-pop singer Janet Jackson's fourth studio
    album, 
    <i>Janet Jackson's Rhythm Nation 1814</i>(1989). It topped the
    Hot 100 chart for one week.</p>
      <p>The song became Jackson's fifth number-one single on the Hot
    100, the final of seven top five singles from the album, making
    her the only artist to achieve seven top five singles from one
    album. The success of "Love Will Never Do (Without You)" also
    helped the album to become the only in history to produce
    number one hits on the Billboard Hot 100 in three separate
    calendar years—"Miss You Much" in 1989, "Escapade" and "Black
    Cat" in 1990, and "Love Will Never Do (Without You)" in
    1991—and the only album in the history of the Hot 100 to have
    seven top 5 hit singles.[25][26]</p>
      <p>In 1996, the song was remixed by Roger Sanchez. The Single
    Edit was included on the international release of Jackson's
    1996 greatest hits compilation 
    <i>Design of a Decade 1986/1996</i>. Although being one of the
    album's last singles, it was one of the first songs recorded
    for 
    <i>Janet Jackson's Rhythm Nation 1814</i>. The song's
    background vocals were recorded in late 1988, while Jackson
    recorded the lead vocals in January 1989.</p>
      <p>Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis tooled on the idea of making this
    song a duet. According to Fred Bronson's 
    <i>The Billboard Book of Number 1 Hits</i>, they thought about
    possibly getting Prince, Johnny Gill, Ralph Tresvant, or anyone
    else working with them at the time. However, there was no
    concrete plan. During the recording of the first verse, Jimmy
    Jam tells Jackson, "Sing it low like some guy would sing it."
    As a result, they kept the idea of her singing the first verse
    in a low octave but go an octave up on the second verse.</p>
      <p>Jackson has performed the song on most of her tours
    including the janet. Tour, The Velvet Rope Tour, All for You
    Tour, and Rock Witchu Tour.</p>
      <p>Singer Macy Gray sang the song live as a tribute to Janet
    Jackson during MTV's Icon special in 2002.</p>
      <p>The video was directed by photographer Herb Ritts in
    September 1990. Jackson originally planned to wear a dress for
    the video, but Ritts envisioned Jackson in nothing more than a
    black top and a pair of jeans. The video features cameos by
    Calvin Klein underwear models Antonio Sabàto, Jr.(no longer
    models for Calvin Klein) and Djimon Hounsou.</p>
      <p>The video won for Best Female Video and was nominated for
    Best Choreography and Best Art Direction at the 1991 MTV Video
    Music Awards. It ranked thirteen on 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s The 100 Top Music Videos, seventy-two on
    VH1's 100 Greatest Videos, and eighty-eight on MTV's 100
    Greatest Videos Ever Made.</p>
      <p>Two versions of the video were produced, one in
    black-and-white, and the other colorized, both of which appear
    on the 
    <i>Design of a Decade 1986/1996</i>video compilation. On April
    27, 2007, the video was made available on iTunes.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
