<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miss_You_Much 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miss_You_Much</songId>
   <title>Miss You Much</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Janet_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Janet Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1989-10-07</week>
      <week>1989-10-14</week>
      <week>1989-10-21</week>
      <week>1989-10-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/df/Janet-Jackson-Miss-You-Much-314328.jpg/200px-Janet-Jackson-Miss-You-Much-314328.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Janet-Jackson+Miss-You-Much.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Janet Jackson's Rhythm Nation 1814</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 22, 1989</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1988–1989 , Flyte Tyme Studios , ( Minneapolis , Minnesota )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>New Jack Swing</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:12</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>A&amp;M</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>James Harris III</writer>
      <writer>Terry Lewis</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Miss You Much" is the lead single from American R&amp;B-pop
    singer Janet Jackson's fourth studio album, 
    <i>Janet Jackson's Rhythm Nation 1814</i>(1989). The song was
    written and produced by Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis.</p>
      <p>Much was riding on the song, as it would either prove or
    disprove detractors of Jackson, who thought she was a fluke and
    a one-hit-album wonder. As it happened, it became one of
    Jackson's biggest-selling singles to date, hitting number one
    on both the Hot 100 and Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs charts, and
    becoming her second number-one hit on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100, where it stood for four weeks. The
    song sold over four million copies, becoming the
    biggest-selling song of 1989. Apart from the United States, the
    song peaked at number one in Canada and managed to reach the
    top twenty in Australia and many European countries.</p>
      <p>Jackson was honored with two American Music Awards for
    Favorite Soul/R&amp;B Single and Favorite Dance Single for
    "Miss You Much", and was nominated for Favorite Dance Artist
    and a Grammy Award for Best Female R&amp;B Vocal Performance.
    The single also won a Soul Train Music Award for Best
    R&amp;B/Soul Single, Female. The single contains a B-side
    called "You Need Me", an outtake from 
    <i>Janet Jackson's Rhythm Nation 1814</i>. The song is about
    Jackson's personal feelings about her father, and how the
    tables are turned, that now he needs her. At the time of its
    release there were reports that the B-side was the product of
    Jackson's record labels pressure on her in an attempt to
    produce specifically "Control Part 2" which reportedly was to
    address the rumors that remained in the press regarding her
    personal life and family. Jackson never caved in and followed
    the alleged orders to produce the project beyond this single
    track and therefore it is considered autobiographical and a
    collectors' item.</p>
      <p>Jackson has performed the song on all of her tours,
    including the Rhythm Nation 1814 Tour, janet. Tour, The Velvet
    Rope Tour, All for You Tour, and Rock Witchu Tour.</p>
      <p>Heavy anticipation and pre-retail-single radio airplay
    during the late summer of 1989 allowed "Miss You Much" to debut
    at number forty-two on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 the week of September 2, 1989, and
    basically soar to the number-one spot in five weeks, by October
    7, 1989, where it remained for four weeks, easily becoming the
    biggest hit of 1989 in terms of weeks at number one. (Phil
    Collins would match this feat the week of December 23, 1989
    with "Another Day in Paradise".)</p>
      <p>The video for "Miss You Much" was directed by Dominic Sena
    and is a part of the 
    <i>Rhythm Nation 1814 Film</i>. The black-and-white video
    begins with dancers hanging out at a pool hall gossiping about
    Jackson and her boyfriend. Jackson enters the room and her
    dancers look at her. One dancer asks Jackson what she has been
    up to. She calls them nosey, and then demonstrates her love
    through song and dance. The end of the video cuts out a final
    dance routine performed with chairs. The chair routine can be
    found on the 
    <i>Rhythm Nation Compilation</i>CD and DVD.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
