<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/That%27s_the_Way_Love_Goes 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/That%27s_the_Way_Love_Goes</songId>
   <title>That's the Way Love Goes</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Janet_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Janet Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1993-05-15</week>
      <week>1993-05-22</week>
      <week>1993-05-29</week>
      <week>1993-06-05</week>
      <week>1993-06-12</week>
      <week>1993-06-19</week>
      <week>1993-06-26</week>
      <week>1993-07-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/59/Ttwlg.jpg/200px-Ttwlg.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Janet-Jackson+That-s-the-Way-Love-Goes.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>janet.</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 20, 1993</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>CD maxi single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>December 1992 – January 1993 , Flyte Tyme Studios , ( Edina , Minnesota )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>New Jack Swing</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:25</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Virgin</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Janet Jackson</writer>
      <writer>James Harris III</writer>
      <writer>Terry Lewis</writer>
      <writer>James Brown</writer>
      <writer>Fred Wesley</writer>
      <writer>John Starks</writer>
      <writer>Charles Bobbit</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Janet Jackson</producer>
      <producer>Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"That's the Way Love Goes" is a song by American singer
    Janet Jackson from her fifth studio album, 
    <i>janet.</i>(1993). Released as the album's lead single in
    April 1993, the Grammy Award-winning song became Jackson's
    biggest number-one single ever in the United States, staying
    atop the Hot 100 for eight weeks.</p>
      <p>"That's the Way Love Goes", written and produced by Jackson
    and Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis, contains a sample of James
    Brown's 1974 number-one R&amp;B hit "Papa Don't Take No Mess".
    As the lead single from 
    <i>janet.</i>, the mood was a stark contrast to her previous
    album 
    <i>Janet Jackson's Rhythm Nation 1814</i>. Jackson was not
    excited about the track the first time she heard it, so Jam and
    Lewis gave her a tape of it just as she was leaving for a
    Christmas vacation in 1992 and asked her to listen to it for a
    couple of weeks. When she returned in January 1993, she told
    the producers, "You know that track you did? I love it. It's
    absolutely the bomb", according to 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine. Jackson came up with the title, and
    the first draft had the lovelorn tone one would expect from
    such a title. Then she called Jam at two in the morning to tell
    him she was taking a different direction, casting the lyrics in
    a more seductive light. "If" was the original choice for the
    lead single by Virgin. However, Jam and Lewis argued otherwise.
    "Everybody was talking about", says Jam. "To me, your first
    single should say, 'Welcome to the album. If you like this,
    check out the rest.' And we really felt 'That's the Way Love
    Goes' was in keeping with the spirit of the rest of the album.
    And since it went to number one, we proved that we were right!"
    "If" was eventually released as the second single from the
    album.</p>
      <p>In 1994, the track earned Jackson her second Grammy Award
    for Best R&amp;B Song, and was also nominated for Best Female
    R&amp;B Vocal Performance.</p>
      <p>Since then, the song has been covered by Norman Brown, 'N
    Sync, Chantay Savage, Deborah Cox, and Brownstone.</p>
      <p>Jackson performed the song as a medley with "If" at the 1993
    MTV Video Music Awards; the audio recording of which appears on
    the limited edition double disc edition of 
    <i>janet.</i>A remix of the song entitled CJ FXTC Club Mix
    appears on her 1995 remix album 
    <i>janet. Remixed</i>.</p>
      <p>Jackson has performed the song on all of her tours,
    including the janet. Tour, The Velvet Rope Tour, All for You
    Tour, and Rock Witchu Tour.</p>
      <p>"That's the Way Love Goes" was ranked number 427 on 
    <i>Blender'</i>s list of The 500 Greatest Songs Since You Were
    Born.</p>
      <p>"That's the Way Love Goes" is set in common time with a key
    of G minor. Jackson's vocal chords ranges between the tonal
    nodes of high-tone F
    <sub>3</sub>to low-tone Bb
    <sub>4</sub>. The song is in a medium tempo of 100 beats per
    minute with the chord progression being set like Am–E–Gb.</p>
      <p>"That's the Way Love Goes" debuted at number fourteen on the
    U.S. Hot 100. Two weeks later, a day before Jackson's
    twenty-seventh birthday, May 16, 1993 it became Jackson's sixth
    number one on the Hot 100, eleventh number one on the Hot
    R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs, and ninth number one on the Hot Dance
    Club Play. The single is also Jackson's biggest hit on the Hot
    100 Airplay, where it spent ten weeks at number one. This song
    is Jackson's most successful single in the U.S. to date.
    Internationally, it reached number one in Canada, Australia,
    and New Zealand; the top five in the United Kingdom, the
    Netherlands, and Finland; and the top ten in Germany, Sweden,
    Denmark, and Ireland. The song also went on to top the European
    Hot 100 Singles chart because of its high peaks across
    Europe.</p>
      <p>The video was directed by Jackson's ex-husband René
    Elizondo, Jr. in March 1993. Set in a loft, Jackson is depicted
    amongst her friends who persuade her to play her new song.
    Jackson performs the song, being interrupted by Tish who pauses
    it to tell her, "Yo, this is slamming!" Tish plays the tape and
    everyone there begins to dance along to it. The video also
    features then-unknown Jennifer Lopez as Jackson's backup
    dancer. "That's the Way Love Goes" was nominated for three MTV
    Video Music Awards in 1993: Best Female Video, Best Dance
    Video, and Best Choreography. The video is featured on the 1994
    compilation 
    <i>janet.</i>, the 1996 compilation 
    <i>Design of a Decade</i>, the limited bonus-DVD edition of
    2001's 
    <i>All for You</i>, and 2004's 
    <i>From janet. to Damita Jo: The Videos</i>.</p>
      <p>An alternate version of the video, the One Take Version, is
    set in the same hotel room and is a single take focusing solely
    on Jackson. It appears exclusively on the 1994 VHS video
    compilation 
    <i>janet.</i>
      </p>
      <p>N*SYNC paid tribute to the video exclusively on MTV Icon,
    where they covered a shortened version of the song in a similar
    setting.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
