<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Together_Again_(Janet_Jackson_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Together_Again_(Janet_Jackson_song)</songId>
   <title>Together Again</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Janet_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Janet</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1998-01-31</week>
      <week>1998-02-07</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/89/Togetheragain.jpg/200px-Togetheragain.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Janet+Together-Again.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Velvet Rope</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 2, 1997</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>CD maxi single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>cassette maxi single</format>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1997</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>House</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:01 (album version)</length>
      <length>4:07 (radio edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Virgin</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Janet Jackson</writer>
      <writer>James Harris III</writer>
      <writer>Terry Lewis</writer>
      <writer>René Elizondo</writer>
      <writer>Jr.</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Janet Jackson</producer>
      <producer>Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Together Again" is a song by American singer Janet Jackson
    from her sixth studio album, 
    <i>The Velvet Rope</i>(1997). Produced by Jackson and Jimmy Jam
    and Terry Lewis, it was released as the album's second single,
    and achieved commercial success worldwide by selling over 6
    million copies, and to date, the song is Jackson's best selling
    single.</p>
      <p>The song was a tribute from Jackson to friends who had
    recently passed from AIDS, as stated on album booklet of 
    <i>The Velvet Rope</i>. Originally written as a ballad, the
    track was re-arranged as a dance song. The song became
    Jackson's eighth number one on the Hot 100—the only U.S.
    chart-topper from 
    <i>The Velvet Rope</i>—and peaked at number eight on the Hot
    R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs chart. The single sold nearly six million
    copies worldwide, and became one of the biggest-selling singles
    from a female artist in the history of the UK Singles Chart,
    where it peaked at number four. The song is Jackson's biggest
    international single, reaching the top five and the top ten in
    many countries.</p>
      <p>Jackson has performed the song on all of her tours since its
    release, as the closing number, The Velvet Rope Tour and All
    for You Tour while the Rock Witchu Tour saw it moved to the
    middle of the setlist. Also, this song was in the ending of
    "Janet Megamix 04".</p>
      <p>"Together Again" is set in common time with a key of C
    major. Jackson's vocal chords ranges between the tonal nodes of
    high-tone A
    <sub>3</sub>to low-tone D
    <sub>5</sub>. The song is in a moderate tempo of 120 beats per
    minute with the chord progression being set like
    C–Gm6–Bm–A–Dm–Gm–Dm.</p>
      <p>As the first official single from her album 
    <i>The Velvet Rope</i>(after the radio-only U.S. single "Got
    'til It's Gone"), the single was highly anticipated. Before its
    official release it was enjoying heavy airplay in North
    America. Some weeks after its release it debuted at number nine
    on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 chart dated December 20, 1997, before
    becoming her eighth number-one single on January 31, 1998,
    spending two weeks at number one, fourteen weeks inside the top
    ten, and a total of forty-six weeks on the chart. In Canada it
    peaked at number two and stayed in the top ten for many weeks,
    becoming one of her biggest hits there, even surpassing the
    success of some of her six Canadian number-one singles, due to
    its staying power on the chart.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom the song entered the UK Singles Chart
    in December 1997 at number four and spent ten weeks inside the
    top ten; it is Jackson's biggest hit to date in the UK, with
    sales of over three quarters of a million. It achieved massive
    success in the rest of Europe as well, topping the Dutch Top 40
    and the European Hot 100 Singles and charting inside the top
    five and the top ten of most of the European countries. The
    single's massive commercial and radio success helped 
    <i>The Velvet Rope</i>to top the charts of several countries
    throughout Europe and worldwide. It is her best-selling single
    to date.</p>
      <p>Two videos were produced for the song. The one for the album
    version was directed by Seb Janiak and is a dance video that
    shows Jackson and her dancers performing in a futuristic
    African paradise where people are seen living side by side with
    wild animals such as elephants, giraffes, and wildcats. In the
    scene where Jackson appears to be hugging herself, dancer Nikki
    Pantenburg served as Jackson's body double. This version
    received a nomination for Best Dance Video at the 1998 MTV
    Video Music Awards. The one for the Deeper Remix was directed
    by René Elizondo, Jr. and depicts Jackson in an apartment
    remembering a friend in the video. Both videos are featured on
    the DVD edition of 2001's 
    <i>All for You</i>and the 2004 video compilation 
    <i>From janet. to Damita Jo: The Videos</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
