<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Me_and_Bobby_McGee 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Me_and_Bobby_McGee</songId>
   <title>Me and Bobby McGee</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Janis_Joplin</artistId>
      <artistName>Janis Joplin</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1971-03-20</week>
      <week>1971-03-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Me and Bobby McGee" is a song written by Kris Kristofferson
    and Fred Foster, originally performed by Roger Miller. Janis
    Joplin notably covered the song on the album 
    <i>Pearl</i>. The song was recorded only a few days before her
    death in October 1970.</p>
      <p>Some sources state that Gordon Lightfoot issued the first
    recorded version. Another story tells how Kristofferson popped
    his head into the studio with freshly written verses as Roger
    Miller was recording the song. Regardless, Miller was the first
    artist to have a hit with the song, peaking with it at #12 on
    the US country charts in 1969. Lightfoot's version hit #13 pop,
    and #1 country in his native Canada in 1970. In a 2008
    autobiography, Don Reid and Harold Reid of the Statler Brothers
    say Kristofferson promised it to them, but when they later
    inquired about recording it, they learned Miller had already
    cut the song. The Reids say there were no hard feelings, and
    were happy about Miller's success with the song. The song was
    later included on a Statler Brothers album, but was not
    released as a single.</p>
      <p>Janis Joplin also covered the song on her 1971 
    <i>Pearl</i>album. Kristofferson had sung the song for Joplin,
    and singer Bob Neuwirth taught it to her. Kristofferson,
    however, did not know she had covered it until after her death
    (the first time he heard it was the day after she died).
    Joplin's version topped the charts to become her only number
    one single and only the second posthumous number one single in
    rock &amp; roll history (the first was "(Sittin' on) the Dock
    of the Bay" by Otis Redding). In 2004, the Janis Joplin version
    of this song was ranked #148 on Rolling Stone's list of the 500
    Greatest Songs of All Time.</p>
      <p>Kristofferson performed the song live at the Isle of Wight
    Festival 1970 and a CD and DVD of the event were issued 30
    years later as 
    <i>Message to Love: The Isle of Wight Festival 1970</i>. The
    Janis Joplin version was used prominently in the epilogue of
    Rainer Werner Fassbinder's epic film of 
    <i>Berlin Alexanderplatz</i>.</p>
      <p>In the original version of the song, Bobby is a woman; Janis
    Joplin, who was a lover and a friend of Kristofferson's from
    the beginning of her career to her death, changed the sex and a
    few of the lyrics in her cover. Kristofferson states he did not
    write this song for her, but the song is associated with her.
    Especially, he has said, in the line, "Somewhere near Salinas,
    Lord, I let her slip away."</p>
      <p>The line about "Bobby and I Sang the Blues", was adopted by
    Don Mcclean for the song "American Pie" when he met a girl who
    "Sang the Blues", hoping for some "Happy News", but "She just
    smiled and turned away".</p>
      <p>The line: "Freedom is just another word for nothing left to
    lose/ But nothing ain't worth nothing but it's free", is listed
    in Bartlett's Familiar Quotations under Kris Kristofferson's
    name.</p>
      <p>Other artists</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
