<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Down_(Jay_Sean_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Down_(Jay_Sean_song)</songId>
   <title>Down</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jay_Sean</artistId>
      <artistName>Jay Sean featuring Lil Wayne</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2009-10-17</week>
      <week>2009-10-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/91/Jay_Sean_Ft._Lil_Wayne_-_Down.jpg/200px-Jay_Sean_Ft._Lil_Wayne_-_Down.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Jay-Sean-featuring-Lil-Wayne+Down.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>All or Nothing</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 31, 2009 ( U.S. Airplay) , (see release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Dec. 2008 – Mar. 2009</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:32 (Single version/Album version)</length>
      <length>3:15 (Without Rap)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Cash Money / Universal Republic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>K. Jhooti</writer>
      <writer>D. Carter</writer>
      <writer>J-Remy</writer>
      <writer>Bobby Bass</writer>
      <writer>Jared Cotter &amp; J Perkins</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>J-Remy &amp; Bobby Bass</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Down" is a song by British artist Jay Sean. The song was
    released in North America as his debut single from his debut
    album there, 
    <i>All or Nothing</i>. In other markets, including the UK, the
    song serves as Jay Sean's lead single from what will be his
    third studio album there. The single features American rapper
    and label mate Lil Wayne and is produced by J-Remy and Bobby
    Bass. "Down" is the seventh-best selling single of 2009, having
    sold more than three million digital copies in the United
    States alone, and has been certified Platinum in several
    countries. The song has sold six million copies worldwide, and
    also received a large airplay of two billion listener
    impressions on radio worldwide.</p>
      <p>The track was released to US radio on May 31, 2009 and on
    iTunes on June 30, 2009. "Down" hit #1 on the Billboard Hot 100
    chart in the issue dated October 17, 2009, knocking The Black
    Eyed Peas off the top of the chart after their 26 week reign at
    #1. This made Jay Sean the first British act to score a
    Billboard Hot 100 number-one single since Coldplay's "Viva la
    Vida" in 2008, and the fourth British act overall this decade.
    The song has also made him "the first UK Urban act ever to top
    Billboard's Hot 100", the ninth (second British) male solo
    performer to top the US charts with his debut single in the US,
    and the first British act to have reached #1 in the US and not
    in the UK with a song since Seal's "Kiss From A Rose" in 1995.
    It is also the best-selling single by a British/European male
    artist in North America since Elton John's "Candle in the Wind"
    in 1997, the first single by a solo artist of Asian origin to
    top the US charts, and the first by an British Asian artist in
    general since Freddie Mercury in 1980.</p>
      <p>On October 15, 2008, at the MOBO Awards, Jay Sean announced
    that he had signed with the American hip hop record label Cash
    Money Records. He explained, “It’s always been a dream for me
    to sign to an American label. And it’s great to be accepted by
    the best in the game.”</p>
      <p>It was rumoured that his first single in the US would be a
    remix of the single, "Tonight" featuring Lil Wayne. In fact, a
    remix had not been produced but the song "Down" which was
    originally recorded in December 2008. The song was written by
    Jay Sean with Jared Cotter, J Perkins and producers J-Remy and
    Bobby Bass. The track was originally for 
    <i>My Own Way: Deluxe Edition</i>without Lil Wayne, alongside
    "War". The CEO of Cash Money Ronald "Slim" Williams liked the
    track, played it to Wayne and wanted Wayne to be on the track;
    Wayne loved it and added a new verse on the track.</p>
      <p>Sean told MTV News that he recorded this song in 90 minutes,
    after which he received a call from Ronald "Slim" Williams. He
    recalled: "Slim called me up and was like, 'Yo, man, there's
    something wrong on the second verse that just doesn't sound
    right.' I was like, 'Really? What?' He played the song. All of
    a sudden I heard Wayne's Auto-Tune stuff, and I'm like, 'OK.
    What's going on? Right! That's Lil Wayne on my song right now!'
    That day was brilliant."</p>
      <p>"The news was on, everything was depressing and we were like
    'look at this man — everything's so down in the dumps. Why
    don't we write a song to take everyone's mind away from being
    down?'" explains Sean about how the track came about during a
    late night recording session in Miami's Hit Factory studio.
    According to Sean, "Wayne heard it, fell in love and dropped a
    verse on it," which resulted in the up-tempo summer record
    peppered with Wayne's gritty pipes.</p>
      <p>Of the song, Jay Sean said, "I'm a very positive, optimistic
    person and thought let me write a song about the idea that if
    you've got someone special in your life then nothing else
    really matters, how you need to appreciate the little things.
    The title is a play on the word 'down.' That's why Lil Wayne
    says, 'Are you down like the economy.' It's a fun, very easy
    track something to pump in your car". Lil Wayne said,
    "Everybody is used to what Cash Money is, and that’s why he has
    a new sound. It’s for the ladies. We’re used to getting in your
    face... and now we are getting more mature here".</p>
      <p>The BBC reports that Jay Sean is "The Most Successful Male
    U.K. Urban artist in U.S chart history". "I want to do my best
    to represent the UK in America and let people really understand
    that it doesn't matter if we're from a little place called
    Hounslow. As long as you work hard and strive to do you best
    and make good music, and of course with a bit of luck, it is
    possible," Jay told the BBC. The success of "Down" has also led
    to Sean being considered the most successful European urban
    artist in North America.</p>
      <p>When the track topped the Billboard Hot 100, Jay Sean was on
    stage with labelmate Lil Wayne, on the first night of the US
    rapper's London concert tour. Before he returned to the US, Jay
    Sean was asked, "How does it feel to have the top song of the
    week?", and replied, "This is insane. It's just incredible to
    have reached #1 with my first release in America. It's
    difficult for me to put into words. My head is spinning. I've
    been grinding hard for the last seven years releasing records
    independently and now to have the biggest record in the USA
    this week. It's just a dream come true." The second time the
    song hit #1, he was performing at 
    <i>"The Justin Timberlake and Friends Concert Benefiting
    Shriners Hospitals For Children"</i>on October 17, 2009 with
    Justin Timberlake.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Down" was produced alongside the video
    for "Written On Her". The "Down" video was first shot in London
    on April 24, 2009, with Cash Money crew without Lil Wayne. The
    video was shot over two days. The Buckinghamshire mansion
    featured is Hedsor House, an enormous private mansion and park
    where Mark Ronson hosted his 33rd birthday and where scenes for
    the feature film 
    <i>The Golden Compass</i>were filmed. The video was completed
    in Miami, with Jay Sean heading to the US to finish the video
    with Lil Wayne on May 20, 2009. The video features Hispanic
    American model Korrina Rico as the lead lady, dancers, bright
    blue lights and bottles. The video was produced by Shurwin
    Beckford and directed by Richard Pengelley for Jayded
    Entertainment/Guerilla Hype/Hey Buddy and edited by Jamie Mac
    and Adam Wood. During the rap break, Lil Wayne is seen wearing
    a red t-shirt with the word 'COMMUNIST' in white capitalized
    letters. The prelude of his previous single "Ride It" can be
    heard in the music video as the introduction to this song.</p>
      <p>On July 23, 2009, the video premiered on Jay Sean's YouTube
    page; it was the #1 most viewed music video on YouTube for its
    first two weeks and had over 5 million views as of December 24,
    2009. During the week of August 10, 2009, the music video was
    featured as iTunes' Free Music Video of the Week. The video was
    added to MTV's rotation on August 5, 2009 include MTV Hits and
    MTV America. The video was also added to the Universal Music
    Group's channel where the video had more than 20 million views
    as of November 23, 2009. The video was added to the Island
    Records channel where his UK fans can see the video, which had
    around 5 million views as of December 20, 2009. The video was
    also added to the Jay Sean Vevo channel, where it has more than
    46 million views as of March 15, 2010.</p>
      <p>Ginger Clements from 
    <i>Billboard</i>gave the song a positive review, stating that
    Jay Sean's "melodic vocals [...] resonate with impressive tonal
    clarity". 
    <i>Billboard</i>gave the song a score of 91/100. Alex MacGregor
    of UK Mix gave the song 4 out of 5 stars, stating that it "is
    actually a creditable offering of world beating R&amp;B pop
    that reminds the listener of some of the better moments in
    Usher's back catalogue."</p>
      <p>"Down" has been included in various compilation albums,
    including 
    <i>Now That's What I Call Music! 32</i>(US), which debuted at
    #5 on the 200. It has also been included in 
    <i>Now That's What I Call Music! 74</i>(UK), 
    <i>Clubland 16</i>and the Australian compilation 
    <i>So Fresh: The Hits of Summer 2010 &amp; The Best Of
    2009</i>. The song has also been featured in the "Canon"
    episode of 
    <i>Melrose Place</i>.</p>
      <p>According to data released by Google, "Down" is one of the
    top five most searched-for songs of 2009 on the internet.
    "Down" has been used and covered in numerous user videos on
    YouTube, including a breast cancer awareness video by the
    Providence St. Vincent Medical Center. A cover version of the
    song was also performed on Episode 2 of 
    <i>The Sing-Off</i>by the a capella group Nota. After Nota went
    on to win the contest during the finale, Sean himself made an
    appearance, performing "Down" with the group in the show's
    ending. DJ Bikram Keith and DJ Vix made a "Desi Remix" to
    "Down". The single was also include on DJ Earworm's mash-up of
    all the Top 25 Billboard hits of the year. The title "Urban
    Desi Boy of 2009" was given to Jay Sean by DesiHits. On Grammy
    Awards 2010 where Jay Sean was, told Taylor Swift that "Down"
    was her favorite song of 2009.</p>
      <p>In early December 2009, the song appeared at #20 on the
    Year-End Hot 100 singles of 2009 and at #14 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Year-End Pop Songs of 2009. Later in the month,
    it appeared at #4 on Z100's Top 100 Songs of 2009. It also
    appeared on VH1's Top 40 Music Videos of 2009 List at #20.
    Having sold more than three million digital copies in the
    United States alone, "Down" is the seventh-best selling single
    of 2009, in a year noted for having the highest record sales of
    all time. To date, it has sold six million copies
    worldwide.</p>
      <p>After the track leaked on web 21 May 2009 did Jay Sean
    perform the "Without Rap" version of the track for the first
    time live in Chicago. He has also performed the track on Macy's
    Thanksgiving Day Parade, in Toronto, on Jimmy Kimmel Live, on
    Madison Square Garden, alongside "Do You Remember", on The
    Wendy Williams Show, on BBC 1Xtra Live 2009, a "Acoustic
    version" for Billboard.com and Yahoo! Music, and the "Candle
    Light Remix" for BBC Radio 1.</p>
      <p>"Down" debuted at #72 on the Billboard Hot 100 for the chart
    week of August 6, 2009, and stayed at #2 for three weeks. After
    fourteen weeks on the chart, the song reached number one for
    the chart week ending October 17, 2009, making Jay Sean the
    first Indian-origin (and Asian-origin in general) solo artist
    to achieve a #1 single in the US. "Down" ended the Black Eyed
    Peas' 26-week reign at the #1 spot on the Hot 100. Furthermore,
    "Down" had managed to top one of the most competitive weeks in
    the US charts this decade, with the top five titles (Sean's
    "Down", Miley Cyrus' "Party in the U.S.A.", Jay-Z's "Run This
    Town", Jason DeRulo's "Whatcha Say", and Black Eyed Peas' "I
    Gotta Feeling") being "separated by the tightest point margin
    in more than six years." After spending a week at the top spot,
    "Down" was succeeded by Britney Spears' "3", but the following
    week, it reached #1 again. On the 
    <i>American Top 40</i>, "Down" debuted at #27 on August 22,
    2009, and reached #1 on October 24, 2009, his first AT40 entry
    to peak at the top. On the Canadian Hot 100, it debuted at #40
    for the week of August 17, 2009, and peaked at #3 in the week
    of October 15, 2009. The song also peaked at #1 on Pop Songs,
    #1 on Radio Songs, #1 on Rhythmic Top 40, #2 on Digital Songs,
    #3 on Ringtones, and, one week before it was charted on the Hot
    100, debuted-peaked at #4 on Heatseekers Songs.</p>
      <p>On the 
    <i>Recording Industry Association of New Zealand</i>singles
    chart, "Down" debuted at #18, and after six weeks the song
    peaked at #2 (where it spent four weeks) for the week of
    November 5, 2009. On 
    <i>Sverigetopplistan</i>, "Down" debuted at #52 and, in its
    second week, peaked at #29 beginning November 5, 2009, where it
    spent ten weeks at that position. In Switzerland, for the week
    of October 8, 2009, the song debuted on the Swiss Music Charts
    at #65 and peaked at #57 five weeks later. The single debuted
    at #9 on October 22, 2009 on the Norwegian Singles Chart, and
    after two weeks the song peaked at #5. In the UK, although
    "Down" charted highly, it did not reach the same level of
    success as it did in the US market. "Down" entered and peaked
    at #3 on the UK Singles Chart and spent one week at #1 on the
    UK R&amp;B Chart. It is his highest charting single in the UK
    since "Stolen" charted at #4 in 2004.</p>
      <p>On Austrian Singles Chart debuted the song at #70, for the
    week beginning of November 5, 2009, and peaked at #52. On the
    Australian ARIA Charts, the song debuted at #9 that same week
    and peaked at #2 three weeks later. On the Belgian Singles
    Chart, the song peaked at #2. The song debuted at #9 on the
    European Hot 100 and at #94 on the Japan Hot 100 during the
    week dated November 9, 2009. It has so far peaked at #79 on the
    Japan Hot 100 on the week dated March 6, 2010. The song debuted
    on the French SNEP chart at #19 on February 27, 2010.</p>
      <p>Jay Sean knocked the Black Eyed Peas out of the top spot on
    the U.S. Hot 100 for the week ending October 7, 2009. That
    makes him the first Indian-origin solo artist to top the U.S.
    charts with a debut single. His first single (American-debut
    single) with Cash Money Records and Universal Music Group
    became his first #1 on U.S. Billboard Hot 100 and first single
    to sell more than two million copies in America, and the second
    for featured artist Lil Wayne who first led for five weeks last
    year with "Lollipop" at #1 on Billboard Hot 100.</p>
      <p>"Down" entered the UK Singles Chart on 1 November 2009 at
    #3, and #1 on the R&amp;B Chart becoming Sean's highest
    charting positions on both charts.</p>
      <p>The song has sold 6,000,000 copies worldwide.</p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"
      <strong class="selflink">
Down
</strong>" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Do You
      Remember" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"War"</span>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
