<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Empire_State_of_Mind 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Empire_State_of_Mind</songId>
   <title>Empire State of Mind</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jay-Z</artistId>
      <artistName>Jay-Z and Alicia Keys</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2009-11-28</week>
      <week>2009-12-05</week>
      <week>2009-12-12</week>
      <week>2009-12-19</week>
      <week>2009-12-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/b2/Esom-single-cover.jpg/200px-Esom-single-cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Jay-Z-and-Alicia-Keys+Empire-State-of-Mind.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Blueprint 3</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 20, 2009 (Single)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2009 ; Roc The Mic Studios, Oven Studios , ( New York City , New York )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:37 (album version)</length>
      <length>3:18 (radio edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Roc Nation , Atlantic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>S. Carter</writer>
      <writer>A. Shuckburgh</writer>
      <writer>A. Keys</writer>
      <writer>A. Hunte</writer>
      <writer>J. Sewell-Ulepic</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Al Shux</producer>
      <producer>Janet "Jnay" Sewell-Ulepic</producer>
      <producer>Angela Hunte</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Empire State of Mind" is a song by hip hop artist Jay-Z,
    featuring guest contribution of R&amp;B and soul
    singer-songwriter Alicia Keys. The song was released as the
    third single from Jay-Z's eleventh studio album 
    <i>The Blueprint 3</i>on his Roc Nation label. The song is an
    anthemic ode to both artists' native New York City, featuring a
    sample of "Love on a Two-Way Street" by The Moments. Jay-Z and
    Keys performed the song at the 2009 MTV Video Music Awards, as
    well as the American Music Awards of 2009. It is also the plate
    music for New York Yankees shortstop Derek Jeter, and it was
    used in the trailer for 
    <i>Sex and the City 2</i>.</p>
      <p>The single has been commercially successful in the United
    States. It peaked at number one on the Hot 100 for five weeks,
    becoming Jay-Z's first number-one single on the chart as a lead
    artist. "Empire State of Mind" reached number 2 on the UK
    Singles Chart on October 4, 2009. The song also reached number
    2 on the Irish Singles Chart on September 25, 2009 with no
    official release. The song was named "Song of The Year" at The
    Village Voice's 
    <i>Pazz &amp; Jop</i>and was ranked the second best song of
    2009 by Rolling Stone.</p>
      <p>Alicia Keys has recorded an answer song to 'Empire State of
    Mind' titled 'Empire State of Mind (Part II) Broken Down', it
    features on the album 
    <i>The Element of Freedom</i>and peaked at number 4 on the UK
    Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>"Empire State of Mind" is an anthemic hip hop song with
    influences of electropop and orchestra pop. It features a
    sample of "Love on a Two-Way Street" by The Moments. The title
    is a reference to New York's eponym "The Empire State", and may
    also be a reference to Billy Joel's "New York State of Mind".
    Jay-Z's former rival Nas titled a song on his 1994 debut album,
    Illmatic, "N.Y. State of Mind". The song is an anthem to
    Jay-Z's hometown, New York City. The song also mentions NBA
    superstars LeBron James and Dwyane Wade and teams New York
    Knicks and New Jersey Nets. It states that New York is "the
    home of the hip hop", namechecking Afrika Bambaataa, a DJ from
    the South Bronx, New York who was instrumental in the early
    development of hip hop throughout the 1970s &amp; 80s.</p>
      <p>"Empire State of Mind" was originally created by
    singer-songwriter-producer Angela Hunte, a Brooklyn native,
    along with writing partner Jane't "Jnay" Sewell-Ulepic. Hunte
    grew up in the same building — 560 State Street, an address
    which is mentioned in the song — where Jay-Z lived, but they
    had never collaborated on a song before.</p>
      <p>The track's creation was inspired during an overseas trip
    Hunte and Sewell-Ulepic made to London in February, both
    feeling nostalgic. Hunte was sick during that summer while
    Sewell-Ulepic's mother was ill. Hunte recalls, "We said to
    ourselves, 'we complain so much about New York -- about the
    busy streets, about the crowds and the pushing, about the
    subway system -- but I would trade that for anything right
    now.' Before we left the hotel that night, we knew we would
    write a song about our city."</p>
      <p>It was reported that fellow New York MC Nas, who himself has
    a song called "N.Y. State of Mind", was supposed to be featured
    on the song but declined because of a busy touring schedule, an
    ongoing divorce case with his ex-wife Kelis, and his continuing
    work with Damian Marley on their collaboration album titled 
    <i>Distant Relatives</i>.</p>
      <p>Jay-Z stated in an interview that after hearing the piano
    loops, he immediately thought of Keys and wanted her to be
    featured. Keys recalls, "There was a first phone call, and Jay
    hit me up like, 'I feel like I have this record that's going to
    be the anthem of New York.'" Keys later recorded the sequel to
    the song called "Empire State of Mind (Part II) Broken Down",
    which is included on Keys' fourth studio album, 
    <i>The Element of Freedom</i>. Contrary to previous reports,
    the sequel does not feature Jay-Z.</p>
      <p>In February 2010, Jay-Z has revealed that Mary J. Blige was
    initially considered for Alicia Keys' feature on 'Empire State
    Of Mind'. He has admitted that he was "two seconds away" from
    phoning Blige to appear on the record's chorus. He said that
    the second choice for the track's vocals was Keys. He said that
    using Blige on the song would have been a safe move but said
    that that the combination of Keys' sound and piano talent had
    struck a chord with him.</p>
      <p>The song is played in the key of F# Major at a tempo of
    87bpm. The vocal range is A#3-C#5.</p>
      <p>The song received airplay from numerous radio stations and
    gained a huge number of downloads, especially after the 2009
    MTV Video Music Awards. The song was released as the third
    single from the album to Rhythmic Airplay on October 19, 2009,
    the same day as Alicia Keys's single "Doesn't Mean Anything".
    The song was featured on episode 12 of the third season of 
    <i>Gossip Girl</i>titled "The Debarted". It was also featured
    on 
    <i>WWE Raw</i>for a Madison Square Garden episode shot
    there.</p>
      <p>"Empire State of Mind" received generally positive reception
    from most music critics. Allmusic stated "The king of the
    crossovers here is 'Empire State of Mind,' a New York
    flag-waver with plenty of landmark name-dropping that turns
    into a great anthem with help on the chorus from Alicia Keys. 
    <i>Los Angeles Times</i>writer Greg Kot commended Jay-Z for his
    ability to perform with cameos, and called the song "Empire
    State of Mind" "the sound of Jay-Z cruising for pop hits". 
    <i>Newsday</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s Glenn Gamboa said
    that Jay-Z declares "'I'm the new Sinatra' - and when he pushes
    for change" on the song. 
    <i>NME</i>described Alicia Keys's cameo as "lusty bellowing".
    Pitchfork Media stated "the piledriver hooks of 'Run This Town'
    and 'Empire State of Mind' are content to annoy their way to
    ubiquity". PopMatters called the song "yet another chance for
    Jay to show love for his city, but it remains interesting
    thanks to a fantastic Al Shux beat and celebratory hook from
    Alicia Keys . Above all, it’s a chance for the Marcy emcee to
    show off shades of a new flow while not losing you for a
    second". 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s Jody Rosen called
    it a "pallid New York shout-out".</p>
      <p>Steve Jones of 
    <i>USA Today</i>perceived a maturity by Jay-Z in the song, and
    wrote that "The upper-crust landmarks he now references are a
    far cry from the grimy Marcy Projects sights that he once
    detailed, something that perhaps is to be expected from the
    self-described 'new Sinatra.'" Alluding to the classic "Theme
    from New York, New York" anthem, Hip Hop Is Read similarly
    commented: "Frank Sinatra, move ova, make room for Hova. This
    is by far the best offering on The Blueprint 3". 
    <i>The Daily Telegraph</i>described the song's sound as
    "anthemic club pop" and called Keys's chorus line "singalong".
    About.com called "Empire State of Mind" the album's apex, while
    commending Alicia Keys for her "excellent display of some
    unusually strong vocals". Slant Magazine
    <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s William McBee
    described it as a "glittering paean to the Big Apple with
    Alicia Keys soaring skyscraper-level on the hook and Jay
    putting on for his city". Smoking Section called "Empire State
    of Mind" an "antithesis to Nas’ 'NY State Of Mind,'&#x9d;as he
    presents the city that never sleeps as the ultimate proving
    ground for those who can escape it’s trappings". 
    <i>The Times</i>called it an "orchestral rap ballad"., and 
    <i>The Guardian</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s Alexis Petridis
    described its chorus as "incredible, breezy pop".</p>
      <p>The song was ranked 8th best song of 2009 by MTV,
    second-best song of 2009 by 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>, the Best Hip Hop Single by iTunes, and
    the best single of 2009 by The Village Voice's 37th annual Pazz
    &amp; Jop critics' poll. Pitchfork Media ranked it #44 in its
    year-end recap.</p>
      <p>"Empire State of Mind" was first performed at Jay-Z's
    "Answer the Call" benefit concert in Madison Square Garden on
    September 11, 2009, where it was the opening song. The song was
    then performed live at the 2009 MTV Video Music Awards on
    September 13, 2009, where it closed the awards. Also, Jay-Z
    performed the song on September 18, 2009 during a live
    performance on 
    <i>Friday Night with Jonathan Ross</i>. Because of scheduling
    conflicts, Roc Nation singer Bridget Kelly performed in Alicia
    Keys' place (with the exception of the MTV Video Music
    Awards).</p>
      <p>The song became an anthem for the New York Yankees during
    their championship run in 2009. Yankee shortstop and captain,
    Derek Jeter, used the song as his entrance music before every
    at-bat. It was performed live by Jay-Z and Alicia Keys in
    Yankee Stadium before Game 2 of the 2009 World Series. Jay-Z
    also performed the song with Bridget Kelly at the Yankees'
    World Series victory ceremonies in New York City Hall on
    November 6, 2009.</p>
      <p>The song is used by World Wrestling Entertainment in video
    packages highlighting their Madison Square Garden appearances.
    Jay-Z and Bridget Kelly also sang "Empire State of Mind" at the
    MTV EMA in Berlin, Germany in November 2009. The song was also
    performed by Jay-Z and Alicia Keys at the American Music Awards
    on November 22, 2009. While accepting an American Music Award
    for the song, Jay-Z finished off his thank you speech with the
    phrase "Men lie, Women lie, Numbers don't" and then laughed,
    which many believed to be a shot at fellow rap artist 50
    Cent.</p>
      <p>On November 29, 2009 Keys performed the song's chorus in a
    medley alongside "Doesn't Mean Anything" and "No One" on the UK
    TV show 
    <i>The X Factor</i>.</p>
      <p>On December 15, 2009 Keys appeared on 
    <i>The Colbert Report</i>as a guest. Following an interview
    with host Stephen Colbert, she performed the song with Colbert
    taking Jay-Z's place. The lyrics to Jay-Z's rap were rewritten
    into a tribute to the upper middle class area, which Colbert
    had accused Keys of ignoring during the interview.</p>
      <p>On February 16, 2010 Jay-Z and Keys performed the song
    together at the UK Brit awards.</p>
      <p>The music video was filmed on October 1, 2009, in Harlem,
    Times Square, and around Ground Zero of New York City, and
    shows Yankee Stadium, the Empire State Building, the Chrysler
    Building and Ebbets Field. The video was directed by Hype
    Williams. It premiered on Jay-Z's official YouTube channel on
    October 30, 2009. It ranked at #6 on BET's 
    <i>Notarized: Top 100 Videos of 2009</i>countdown.</p>
      <p>The song debuted on the Hot 100 at number 50, with more than
    40,000 downloads. Leaping from 23 to 1 on the Hot Digital Songs
    the following week, it hit number 5 on the Hot 100 in its
    second week on the chart. With that big jump, the song became
    Jay Z's sixteenth top 10 hit and Keys's ninth top 10 hit. The
    song was the first single on which Jay-Z performed as a lead
    artist to hit number one on the Hot 100, though he has had
    previous Hot 100 number ones as a featured artist. Overall, it
    is the fourth "Hot 100" number one hit for both artists. The
    song stayed at number one for five weeks, and was the final
    number-one single of the 2000s.</p>
      <p>"Empire State of Mind" entered the UK Singles Chart at #15
    on 20 September, 2009. In the next week, it climbed to #3, and
    then one further place to #2, held off the top spot by Taio
    Cruz with "Break Your Heart". The song also peaked at #2 on the
    UK R&amp;B Chart based on downloads alone, no promotion and, at
    that time, no music video. As of March 28, 2010 it has spent 28
    weeks inside the UK top 40.</p>
      <p>After the release of Keys's album, 
    <i>The Element of Freedom</i>, the acoustic version of the song
    debuted at #55 in the U.S.</p>
      <p>The Song has so far sold over 3.000.000 units and remains in
    the Top 20 Digital songs</p>
      <p>Source:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
