<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harper_Valley_PTA 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harper_Valley_PTA</songId>
   <title>Harper Valley PTA</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeannie_C._Riley</artistId>
      <artistName>Jeannie C. Riley</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1968-09-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Harper Valley PTA</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1968</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Country</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:16</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Plantation</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Tom T. Hall</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Shelby Singleton</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Harper Valley PTA" is a country music song written by Tom
    T. Hall. It was a major hit single for country singer Jeannie
    C. Riley in 1968, and crossed over to the pop charts as well,
    eventually selling over six million copies as a single, making
    Riley the first woman ever to top the U.S. pop and country
    singles charts with the same song. (Her accomplishment would
    not be repeated until 1981, when Dolly Parton topped the
    country and pop singles charts with "9 to 5".)</p>
      <p>The song tells the story of a junior high student who is
    sent home with a note to her widowed single mother from the
    Parent-Teacher Association (PTA) of the school decrying her
    scandalous behavior by small-town standards. The mother decides
    to speak to a meeting of the PTA where she addresses various
    episodes of misbehavior on the part of several of its members,
    concluding, "This is just a little 
    <i>Peyton Place</i>/ And you're all Harper Valley
    hypocrites."</p>
      <p>In an interview, Hall admitted his inspiration for the song
    was passing by the Harpeth Valley Elementary School in
    Bellevue, Tennessee, not far from his then-home in Franklin. He
    liked the sound of the name and decided to write a song using a
    similar place name. He also reportedly wrote the song about
    Olive Hill, Kentucky where Hall grew up.</p>
      <p>The song was later the inspiration for a 1978 motion picture
    and a 1981 television series, both starring Barbara Eden,
    playing the heroine of the song, Stella Johnson.</p>
      <p>Other songs on the album tell more about some of the people
    who are members of the Harper Valley P.T.A., including Mayor
    Harper and Widow Jones.</p>
      <p>Jeannie C. Riley's recording of the song won her a Grammy
    for the Best Country Vocal Performance, Female.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
