<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27m_Real_(Jennifer_Lopez_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27m_Real_(Jennifer_Lopez_song)</songId>
   <title>I'm Real</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jennifer_Lopez</artistId>
      <artistName>Jennifer Lopez featuring Ja Rule</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2001-09-08</week>
      <week>2001-09-15</week>
      <week>2001-09-22</week>
      <week>2001-10-20</week>
      <week>2001-10-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/8b/Jennifer_Lopez_-_I%27m_Real_-_CD_single_cover.jpg/200px-Jennifer_Lopez_-_I%27m_Real_-_CD_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Jennifer-Lopez-featuring-Ja-Rule+I-m-Real.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>J.Lo</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 16, 2001</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2000 , Sony Music Studios , ( New York City , New York )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:57</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jennifer Lopez</writer>
      <writer>Troy Oliver</writer>
      <writer>Cory Rooney</writer>
      <writer>L.E.S</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Tory Oliver</producer>
      <producer>Cory Rooney</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I'm Real" is the name of two songs by Jennifer Lopez. One
    is the song taken from her second studio album, 
    <i>J.Lo</i>(2001), and the other is "I'm Real (Murder Remix)",
    which features rapper Ja Rule of The Inc. Records (formerly
    known as Murder Inc. Records), included on the special edition
    of 
    <i>J.Lo</i>, Lopez's remix album, 
    <i>J to tha L-O!: The Remixes</i>(2002), and Ja Rule's third
    studio album, 
    <i>Pain Is Love</i>(2001). The remix contains an interpolation
    of the Mary Jane Girls' 1983 song "All Night Long" written by
    Rick James. Both versions reached number one on the U.S. Hot
    100 on September 8, 2001 (the U.S. number-one single during the
    September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks), and remained there for
    five non-consecutive weeks. Ja Rule had been brought in after
    the moderate U.S. performance of "Play", the second single from
    
    <i>J.Lo</i>. Singer Ashanti (also on The Inc.) also provided
    backing vocals on the Murder Remix. The two songs are
    essentially different songs with the same title.</p>
      <p>The music video for "I'm Real" followed the release of the
    single in the U.S. It depicts Lopez driving a motorcycle
    throughout the highway. The video also featured a cameo
    appearance by underwear model Travis Fimmel and a dance-break
    (to "More Bounce to the Ounce" by Zapp) with Lopez's soon-to-be
    husband Cris Judd appearing as the lead dancer. The video for
    the "I'm Real (Murder Remix)" featured Ja Rule and Irv Gotti,
    and won the award for Best Hip-Hop Video at the 2002 MTV Video
    Music Awards.</p>
      <p>Despite the success of "I'm Real", there was a bit of
    controversy over the use of the single's sample and the
    structure of the song. The song contains an uncredited sample
    from Yellow Magic Orchestra's 1978 version of Martin Denny's
    1959 song "Firecracker" (while the remix on the other hand
    officially interpolates the Mary Jane Girls' 1983 song "All
    Night Long"). There have been reports that the "Firecracker"
    sample was originally planned to be used for Mariah Carey's
    "Loverboy". According to the music publisher of "Firecracker",
    Carey called to license a sample of the song which had never
    been sampled before and within a month Lopez called to do the
    same. Carey felt that former husband and music executive at
    Sony Music (Columbia Records), Tommy Mottola, was interfering
    with her career by arranging for the sample to go to Lopez.
    Upset by the conduct of Lopez and her ex-husband, Carey
    featured a reference to the song on her single "Loverboy", her
    first single released by her then-record company, Virgin
    Records. The verse can be heard in Da Brat's rap section, where
    she sings, "Hate on me, much as you want to, you can't do what
    the fuck I do, bitches be, emulating me daily" over the melody
    of "Firecracker". The word "bitch" was used in the song, but
    when the song aired on the radio, the word "bitch" was deleted
    and the song was cut down to three minutes and fifteen seconds
    long.</p>
      <p>Irv Gotti, who produced the remix of "I'm Real" featuring Ja
    Rule, openly admitted during an interview with 
    <i>XXL</i>magazine that Mottola contacted him with instructions
    to create a song that sounded exactly like a song he had made
    with Carey for the soundtrack entitled "If We" also featuring
    Ja Rule.</p>
      <p>Furthermore, some in the African American community were
    outraged by Lopez's use of the word "nigga" in the Murder
    Remix.</p>
      <p>"I'm Real (Murder Remix)" debuted on the U.S. Hot 100 at
    number sixty-six the week of July 7, 2001. By its fourth week,
    the song had reached the top twenty, fueled by increasing
    airplay of the single. By September 8, 2001, the single topped
    the chart, dislodging Alicia Keys' "Fallin'" from a three-week
    stint at number one. "I'm Real" spent the next three charting
    weeks at the summit, and was subsequently knocked out of the
    top spot by "Fallin'", which boasted an additional three
    consecutive weeks at number one. After three weeks stalled at
    number two, "I'm Real" returned to number one again for a final
    two weeks, through October 27, 2001. "I'm Real (Murder Remix)"
    was a staple on R&amp;B/hip hop and pop radio during the summer
    and fall of 2001, spending fifteen weeks on the top five of the
    
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100. In 2009 the single was named the 30th
    most successful song of the 2000s, on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade.</p>
      <p>, The chart position of the Murder Remix was boosted by
    radio play of the album track, which led to complaints of
    unfairness and change of 
    <i>Billboard</i>policy in 2002. Afterwards, airplay of
    identically named songs but with substantially different
    melodies was not combined when computing chart positions.
    Lopez's follow-up was "Ain't It Funny (Murder Remix)", another
    Ja Rule-featured remix, which also reached number one on the
    Hot 100.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
