<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/If_You_Had_My_Love 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/If_You_Had_My_Love</songId>
   <title>If You Had My Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jennifer_Lopez</artistId>
      <artistName>Jennifer Lopez</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1999-06-12</week>
      <week>1999-06-19</week>
      <week>1999-06-26</week>
      <week>1999-07-03</week>
      <week>1999-07-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/21/Jennifer_Lopez_-_If_You_Had_My_Love_-_CD_single_cover.jpg/200px-Jennifer_Lopez_-_If_You_Had_My_Love_-_CD_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Jennifer-Lopez+If-You-Had-My-Love.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>On the 6</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 11, 1999</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>CD maxi single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>January 1999, New York City, NY</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:25</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Rodney Jerkins</writer>
      <writer>Fred Jerkins III</writer>
      <writer>LaShawn Daniels</writer>
      <writer>Cory Rooney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Darkchild</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"If You Had My Love" is the lead single from Jennifer
    Lopez's debut album, 
    <i>On the 6</i>(1999). Released in 1999, the single peaked at
    number one in the United States, becoming Lopez's first
    number-one single; it also peaked at number four in the United
    Kingdom. The song is well-known for its voyeuristic music
    video.</p>
      <p>The song was written by Rodney Jerkins, Fred Jerkins III,
    LaShawn Daniels, and Cory Rooney and produced by Rodney
    Jerkins. In her debut single, Lopez is on the brink of sealing
    a relationship with a man she is interested in. However, before
    they can become a couple, she lays out some ground terms: she
    won't tolerate cheating and she needs to feel true love or it's
    "got to end". She also wonders if he knew if his love was
    untrue, would he lie to her and still call her "baby". Her
    insecurities build up to the point where Lopez questions, "If
    you had my love, and I gave you all my trust, would you comfort
    me?".</p>
      <p>"If You Had My Love" debuted on the U.S. Hot 100 the week of
    May 15, 1999, jumping from number sixty-four to number eight
    two weeks later. The single reached the top spot on June 12,
    1999, and stayed there for five consecutive weeks. The single
    was one of the most popular dance-pop singles of the summer of
    1999, remaining in the top ten for fifteen weeks.</p>
      <p>The music video, directed by Paul Hunter in April 1999,
    begins with a man (Adam Rodriguez) logging onto his personal
    computer. When prompted by a search bar, he enters the term
    "Jennifer Lopez" and is redirected to a website, "Jennifer
    Lopez Online". Clicking on the link, he is then transported
    through the Internet (which is displayed by special effects
    emulating binary numbers). After arriving, a figure in white
    walks across a room filled with cameras recording action: it
    turns out to be Lopez in a hallway. From the privacy of his
    computer, the man then redirects to a new page where Lopez is
    now seen in the living room and crawling over a table.</p>
      <p>The man is not alone in his voyeuristic actions as patrons
    of an Internet cafe and a little girl logging in from her own
    computer, watches Lopez, streaming live, on "Internet TV". The
    man then clicks on a room showing Lopez in the bathroom,
    singing whilst checking her reflection in the mirror.
    Worldwide, Lopez's feed is being streamed live to a nightclub
    and to other users with laptops. The man then clicks on the
    dance option and is once again entered through the special
    effect binary. Lopez then proceeds to perform a series of
    dances (including jazz, house, and Latin soul) as the song
    moves into a remixed (Pablo Flores Remix) portion. The man then
    zooms in on Lopez's skirt, as she dances to Latin music.</p>
      <p>He then raises the sexual intonation again by requesting a
    scene in which Lopez is taking a shower (although she is never
    seen nude). Garage workers who had been watching this soon turn
    their heads to Lopez and pay no attention to their burning car
    as they glue their eyes to the screen. A new user is
    introduced, and it is implied that he throws his computer
    underwater to "turn down the heat" (so to speak). He then
    continues to watch her there.</p>
      <p>The video received four nominations at the 1999 MTV Video
    Music Awards: Best Female Video, Best Dance Video, Best Pop
    Video, and Best New Artist.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
