<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_I_Have_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_I_Have_(song)</songId>
   <title>All I Have</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jennifer_Lopez</artistId>
      <artistName>Jennifer Lopez featuring LL Cool J</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2003-02-08</week>
      <week>2003-02-15</week>
      <week>2003-02-22</week>
      <week>2003-03-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/13/Jennifer_Lopez_-_All_I_Have_-_CD_single_cover.jpg/200px-Jennifer_Lopez_-_All_I_Have_-_CD_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Jennifer-Lopez-featuring-LL-Cool-J+All-I-Have.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>This Is Me... Then</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 11, 2003</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>October 16-17, 2002</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:14</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jennifer Lopez</writer>
      <writer>Makeba Riddick</writer>
      <writer>Curtis Richardson</writer>
      <writer>Ron G</writer>
      <writer>Lisa Peters</writer>
      <writer>William Jeffrey</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Cory Rooney</producer>
      <producer>Ron G</producer>
      <producer>Dave McPherson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"All I Have" is a song by American singer Jennifer Lopez,
    featuring American rapper LL Cool J. Written by Lopez, Makeba
    Riddick, Curtis Richardson, and Ron G and produced by Cory
    Rooney, Ron G, and Dave McPherson, it was released in early
    2003 as the second single from Lopez's third studio album, 
    <i>This Is Me... Then</i>(2002). The song reached number one in
    the United States and New Zealand, and entered the top five and
    the top ten in several countries. After the success of "All I
    Have" with LL Cool J, the track was later included on the
    re-issue of his album 
    <i>10</i>.</p>
      <p>The song is based around a sample from Debra Laws' 1981 song
    "Very Special", written by Lisa Peters and William Jeffrey. It
    was originally intended to be titled "I'm Good", but was
    changed because it sounded too similar to her 2001 hit "I'm
    Real".</p>
      <p>The music video for the single was shot in New York City in
    November 2002 and released in January 2003. It features Lopez
    and LL as former lovers now broken up. The two recall the good
    and bad times while dealing with being alone for the holidays.
    Lopez shows up to LL's house with a gift. With him not there,
    she puts the gift under the tree. He later sees the gift under
    the tree and realizes it was from Lopez. He opens the gift and
    sees a golden key. Upset at the relationship being over, he
    throws the key in the fireplace while a tearful Lopez gets help
    from her friends with her things. The video was shot right
    before Thanksgiving, but did not premiere on television until
    after Christmas.</p>
      <p>On the U.S. Hot 100, "All I Have" debuted at number
    twenty-five the last charting week of 2002, which was December
    28, easily becoming the highest-debuting song of that year.
    "All I Have" made impressive strides on the survey, reaching
    the penthouse by February 8, 2003, where it remained for four
    weeks, becoming Lopez's fourth Hot 100 number-one single and
    the first for LL. The single was one of the most popular pop
    and R&amp;B singles of the spring of 2003, remaining in the top
    ten for twelve weeks, nineteen weeks on the top thirty, and
    twenty-one weeks on the top fifty. Moreover, it charted inside
    the top five in the United Kingdom, the Netherlands,
    Switzerland, and Australia and the top ten in Canada and
    Ireland.</p>
      <p>In March 2003, Debra Laws sued Sony Music Entertainment/Epic
    Records in the United States District Court for the Central
    District of California, claiming that the use of samples from
    "Very Special" without her consent (even though the writers of
    "Very Special" and Elektra Entertainment Group—successor to
    Elektra/Asylum Records, which had released the original
    recording of "Very Special"—had given their consent to the use
    of the samples) violated her statutory and common law right of
    publicity under California law. In November 2003, Judge Lourdes
    Baird granted Sony Music's motion for summary judgment on the
    ground that Laws's state law claims were preempted by Section
    301 of the United States Copyright Act. In 2006, that decision
    was affirmed by the United States Court of Appeals for the
    Ninth Circuit.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
