<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ain%27t_It_Funny_(Murder_Remix) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ain%27t_It_Funny_(Murder_Remix)</songId>
   <title>Ain't It Funny</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jennifer_Lopez</artistId>
      <artistName>Jennifer Lopez featuring Ja Rule</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2002-03-09</week>
      <week>2002-03-16</week>
      <week>2002-03-23</week>
      <week>2002-03-30</week>
      <week>2002-04-06</week>
      <week>2002-04-13</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/75/Jennifer_Lopez_-_Ain%27t_it_Funny_Remix_-_CD_single_cover.jpg/200px-Jennifer_Lopez_-_Ain%27t_it_Funny_Remix_-_CD_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Jennifer-Lopez-featuring-Ja-Rule+Ain-t-It-Funny.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>J to tha L-O!: The Remixes and Exodus</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 11, 2001</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2001; Sony Music Studios , ( New York City , New York )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:52 [Album Version]</length>
      <length>3:42 [Video Mix]</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ashanti</writer>
      <writer>Cory Rooney</writer>
      <writer>Irv Gotti</writer>
      <writer>7 Aurelius</writer>
      <writer>Ja Rule</writer>
      <writer>Caddillac Tah</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Irv Gotti</producer>
      <producer>7 Aurelius</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Ain't It Funny (Murder Remix)" is a song by American singer
    Jennifer Lopez, featuring American rappers Ja Rule and
    Caddillac Tah. Written by Lopez, Cory Rooney, Ja Rule,
    Caddillac Tah, Ashanti, and 7 Aurelius, it was released in 2002
    as the lead single from Lopez's remix album, 
    <i>J to tha L-O!: The Remixes</i>(2002). The song was also
    included on the 2002 compilation album 
    <i>Irv Gotti Presents: The Inc.</i>as well as on Ja Rule's
    greatest hits album 
    <i>Exodus</i>.</p>
      <p>The single topped the U.S. Hot 100 becoming Lopez's third
    number-one single and Ja Rule's third number-one single; it
    also peaked at number four in the United Kingdom. Caddillac Tah
    also performs on the song and appears on the song's music
    video, and even has a longer part than Ja Rule. The remix
    samples Craig Mack's 1994 hit "Flava in Ya Ear". The song spent
    six weeks at the top of the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 from March 9, and followed another Ja
    Rule duet, "Always on Time" with Ashanti. Ashanti's "Foolish"
    replaced it at the number-one spot. Ashanti also appears in the
    video alongside Lopez, Ja Rule, Irv Gotti, Caddillac Tah, and
    other Inc. members.</p>
      <p>The original version of the song, "Ain't It Funny", appears
    on Lopez's second studio album, 2001's 
    <i>J.Lo</i>, and was also a single of its own. It was written
    by Cory Rooney for the soundtrack to Lopez's film 
    <i>The Wedding Planner</i>, but it was felt that the timbales
    gave it too much of a Latin sound, and the song was not used
    for the soundtrack. After the success of "I'm Real (Murder
    Remix)", a previous Lopez–Ja Rule collaboration, they decided
    to remix "Ain't It Funny" as a duet and release it as a
    follow-up. Unlike "I'm Real", the two versions of "Ain't It
    Funny" were released on different dates, and so charted
    separately. The songs also charted separately because 
    <i>Billboard</i>instituted a new chart policy.</p>
      <p>In the Murder Inc. studio then-upcoming artist Ashanti
    dropped by the studio. "Everyone was there and Ja (Rule) was on
    the floor playing video games, and they had the beat playing in
    the background. Chris Gotti, Irv Gotti's brother, said 'Ja's
    supposed to be writing this record for J-Lo, but it doesn't
    look like he's going to be doing anything tonight. Why don't
    you go in there and see what's happening?' So that's exactly
    what I did", says Ashanti, who wrote two verses and demoed the
    new "Ain't It Funny" for Lopez. Ashanti recalled, "I got a call
    from Gotti in Los Angeles. He asked me to write another
    verse[...] I had to write it over the phone and two-way Irv the
    lyrics."</p>
      <p>The video is in two parts which frequently interchange back
    and forth throughout the song. The first part of the video
    shows Lopez having a small party in her home with guests
    including Ja Rule and Ashanti. This part of the video is from
    the point of view of the guy who is being mentioned in the
    song. His face is not seen, and Lopez addresses the camera
    throughout this section of the video. This section begins with
    the guy knocking on the door, Lopez inviting him in, and then
    eventually showing him the door when she sees him attempting to
    look/flirt with other women at the party. As he leaves, she
    goes on entertaining the other guests.</p>
      <p>The second part of the video involves scenes with Lopez and
    Ja Rule in a white room, Ja Rule in a recording studio in
    Lopez's home, Lopez sitting in a chair singing bits of the
    song, and Lopez and Ja Rule singing the parts of the final
    verse against a gold backdrop.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
