<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bad,_Bad_Leroy_Brown 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bad,_Bad_Leroy_Brown</songId>
   <title>Bad, Bad Leroy Brown</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jim_Croce</artistId>
      <artistName>Jim Croce</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1973-07-21</week>
      <week>1973-07-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/8b/Bad%2C_Bad_Leroy_Brown.jpg/200px-Bad%2C_Bad_Leroy_Brown.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Jim-Croce+Bad-Bad-Leroy-Brown.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Life and Times</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 1973</released>
   <formats>
      <format>45</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1972</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Folk</genre>
      <genre>Folk Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:02</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>ABC Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jim Croce</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Bad, Bad Leroy Brown" is the title of a song written by
    American folk rock singer Jim Croce. Released as part of his
    1973 album 
    <i>Life and Times</i>, the song was a Number One pop hit for
    him, spending two weeks at the top of the Billboard Hot 100 in
    July 1973. Croce was nominated for two 1973 Grammy awards in
    the Pop Male Vocalist and Record of the Year categories for
    "Bad, Bad Leroy Brown".</p>
      <p>The song is about a man from the south side of Chicago who,
    due to his size and attitude, has a reputation as the "baddest
    man in the whole damn town." One day, in a bar, he makes a pass
    at a pretty, married woman, whose jealous husband proceeds to
    beat Leroy brutally in the ensuing brawl.</p>
      <p>Croce tells a nearly identical story (tough guy who
    everybody fears is brutally beaten when he meets an even
    tougher guy) in his hit single "You Don't Mess Around With
    Jim."</p>
      <p>His inspiration for the song was a friend he met in his
    brief time in the Army:</p>
      <p>Croce explained the chorus reference to Leroy Brown being
    "meaner than a junkyard dog":</p>
      <p>Pro wrestler Junkyard Dog is said to have got his ring name
    from this song.</p>
      <p>The song inspired Queen vocalist Freddie Mercury (who cited
    Croce as one of his artistic inspirations) to write the song
    "Bring Back That Leroy Brown" for the band's third album, 
    <i>Sheer Heart Attack</i>, released a year after Croce
    died.</p>
      <p>"Bad, Bad Leroy Brown" was released in April 1973 and peaked
    at number one on the American charts three months later. It was
    still on the charts on September 20 when Croce died in a plane
    crash in Natchitoches, Louisiana. It also reached #19 on the
    Australian (Go-Set) Singles Chart in 1973.</p>
      <p>Frank Sinatra recorded a cover version of the song, which
    reached number 83 on the pop charts. Country music artist
    Anthony Armstrong Jones released a cover on Epic Records in
    1973, reaching #33 on the U.S. country charts with it. Dolly
    Parton performed the song twice on her 1976-77 TV series 
    <i>Dolly!</i>(though in her version she changed the song's
    locale from Chicago to Nashville). The song was also covered by
    punk rock band The Max Levine Ensemble.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
