<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Bad_John 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Bad_John</songId>
   <title>Big Bad John</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jimmy_Dean</artistId>
      <artistName>Jimmy Dean</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1961-11-06</week>
      <week>1961-11-13</week>
      <week>1961-11-20</week>
      <week>1961-11-27</week>
      <week>1961-12-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Big Bad John" is a country song originally performed by
    Jimmy Dean and composed by Dean and Roy Acuff. Released in
    September 1961, by the beginning of November it went to number
    one on the Billboard Hot 100 and won Dean the 1962 Grammy Award
    for Best Country &amp; Western Recording.</p>
      <p>The song and its sequel tell a story typical of American
    folklore, reminiscent of Paul Bunyan or John Henry.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Big Bad John</i>was also the title of a 1990 television
    movie starring Dean.</p>
      <p>The song tells the story of a mysterious and quiet miner who
    earned the nickname Big John because of his height, weight and
    muscular physique ("
    <i>He stood six foot six and weighed two forty-five</i>"). He
    supposedly came from New Orleans, where he killed a man over a
    Cajun woman.</p>
      <p>One day, a support timber cracked at the mine where John
    worked. The situation looked hopeless until John "
    <i>grabbed a saggin' timber, gave out with a groan / and like a
    giant oak tree just stood there alone</i>", then "
    <i>gave a mighty shove</i>", opening a passage and allowing the
    other miners to escape the mine. Although the miners were about
    to reenter the mine with the equipment necessary to save John,
    the mine fully collapsed and John died in the depths of the
    mine. The mine itself was never reopened, but a marble stand
    was placed in front of it, with the words "
    <i>At the bottom of this mine lies one hell of a man - Big
    John</i>" written on it. (Some versions of the song change the
    last line to "lies a big, big man" to replace what was at the
    time considered to be borderline profane language.)</p>
      <p>Its 1962 sequel, "The Cajun Queen", describes the arrival of
    "Queenie", Big John's Cajun Queen, who rescues John from the
    mine and marries him. Eventually, they have "
    <i>one hundred and ten grandchildren</i>". The sequel's events
    are more exaggerated than the first, extending the story into
    the realm of tall tales.</p>
      <p>In June 1962, the story continued (and evidently concludes)
    with the arrival of "Little Bitty Big John", (the flip side to
    "Steel Men" on Columbia 4-42483), learning about his Father's
    act of heroism.</p>
      <p>"Big Bad John" was at number one on the pop chart for five
    weeks, on the country chart for two, and on the adult
    contemporary music chart for ten in the U.S. It was also a
    number-two hit in the United Kingdom. The song was nominated
    for the Grammy Award for Record of the Year and Best Male Solo
    Vocal Performance.</p>
      <p>Dean's LP 
    <i>Big Bad John and Other Fabulous Songs and Tales</i>, where
    the song first appeared, reached number twenty-three in the pop
    charts. The song was the B-side of "I Won't Go Huntin' with You
    Jake", but ended up becoming much more popular than the
    latter.</p>
      <p>Columbia Records was considering dropping Dean before the
    release of this million-selling single, as he hadn't had a hit
    in years. Dean wrote the song on a flight from New York to
    Nashville because he realized he needed a fourth song for his
    recording session.</p>
      <p>There are varying accounts as to who was the inspiration for
    the character of Big John. The fact is an actor he met in a
    summer stock play, John Minto (born in San Francisco) who was
    6'5" was the inspiration for the song.</p>
      <p>Country pianist Floyd Cramer, who was hired to play piano on
    the song, came up with the idea to use a hammer and a piece of
    steel instead. This became a distinctive characteristic of the
    recording.</p>
      <p>There are several known recordings of the song by Dean.
    Notably, there are two different versions of the inscription on
    the marble stand in front of the mine. The original, "
    <i>At the bottom of this mine lies one hell of a man - Big
    John</i>", was deemed too controversial, so in the version that
    was most often heard on the radio, one could hear "
    <i>At the bottom of this mine lies a big, big man - Big
    John</i>" instead.</p>
      <p>The refrain was also used to end the Jimmy Dean song
    "PT-109", referring to John F. Kennedy.</p>
      <p>Political candidates have run ads that parody Big Bad John,
    retaining the music while substituting lyrics that support
    their particular political bids.</p>
      <p>In Texas Senator John Cornyn's 2008 parody, he presented
    himself as a maverick politician, seeking a return to the
    Senate to fight to set things right. "You see I'm from Texas
    and we do things quick / And the way this place [the Senate] is
    run is about to make me sick", the ad states. Several ads were
    released by Democrats refuting some of the claims made in the
    song about John.</p>
      <p>In the same year, the Democratic National Committee parodied
    the song in an ad that targeted presidential candidate John
    McCain. The ad dubbed McCain "Exxon John" while highlighting
    U.S. $2-million in contributions by Exxon-Mobil to McCain's
    campaign, as well as the supposed role of Big Oil lobbyists in
    his campaign.</p>
      <p>Artists that have covered the song include:</p>
      <p>Michigan-based a cappella quartet Three Men and a Tenor also
    covered the song on their 2002 album 
    <i>Listen to the Music</i>. Three Men and a Tenor's version is
    notable in that the verses are sung instead of recited.</p>
      <p>San Diego-based Deadbolt's cover of the song includes an
    extra verse following the traditional ending.</p>
      <p>Québécois talk-show host Réal Giguère recorded a joual
    version of this song, renamed Gros Jambon which has become a
    quasi-folkloric song in Quebec.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
