<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Belong_to_Me_(1952_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Belong_to_Me_(1952_song)</songId>
   <title>You Belong to Me</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jo_Stafford</artistId>
      <artistName>Jo Stafford</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1952-09-13</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"You Belong to Me" is a pop music ballad from the 1950s. The
    singer reminds his/her lover that, whatever exotic locales and
    sights he/she experiences, "you belong to me". It is credited
    to three writers: Pee Wee King, Chilton Price, and Redd
    Stewart. Price wrote most of the song, and ceded equal credit
    to the other two in exchange for their work in promoting it.
    King and Stewart did rearrange the song because it was written
    as a war song during World War II and changed the title to "You
    Belong To Me" along with arranging the music. Price had
    previously had success with another hit which she had written,
    "Slow Poke", under a similar arrangement with the two men.</p>
      <p>The original version of the song was recorded by Sue
    Thompson on Mercury's country label. It was soon covered by
    Patti Page, whose version was issued by Mercury as catalog
    number 5899, with "I Went to Your Wedding" (a bigger Patti Page
    hit, reaching #1) on the flip side. It entered the Billboard
    chart on August 22, 1952, and lasted 12 weeks on the chart,
    peaking at #4.</p>
      <p>A cover version by Jo Stafford became the most popular
    version. Issued by Columbia Records as catalog number 39811, it
    was Stafford's greatest hit, topping the charts in both the
    United States and the United Kingdom (the first song by a
    female singer to top the UK chart). It first entered the US
    chart on August 1, 1952 and remained there for 24 weeks. In the
    UK, it appeared in the first ever UK chart of November 14, 1952
    (then a top 12) and reached number 1 on January 16, 1953, being
    only the second record to top such chart, remaining in the
    chart for a total of 19 weeks. Another cover version, by Dean
    Martin, released by Capitol Records as catalog number 2165, was
    also in play at that time. This version first entered the chart
    on August 29, 1952, and remained on the chart for 10 weeks,
    reaching #12. All the versions were combined in the rankings on
    the Cash Box charts, and the song reached #1 on those charts as
    well, lasting on the chart for more than half a year.</p>
      <p>In 1958 the song crossed over into rock for the first time
    on the Capitol album "Gene Vincent Rocks and the Blue Caps
    Roll." A later version of the song, by The Duprees, also made
    the Billboard Top 10, reaching #7 in 1962. It was recorded by
    many other pop vocalists, including Patsy Cline and Bing
    Crosby. A solo acoustic version was recorded by Bob Dylan for
    the 1992 album 
    <i>Good as I Been to You</i>but was eventually left off as an
    outtake, the recording only surfacing two years later in the
    soundtrack for the 1994 movie 
    <i>Natural Born Killers</i>.</p>
      <p>The song has also appeared on many soundtracks. Vonda
    Shepard's cover was used frequently on the TV series 
    <i>Ally McBeal</i>alongside romantic scenes of Ally McBeal and
    Billy Thomas. A version by Jason Wade was part of the
    soundtrack to the 2001 animated film 
    <i>Shrek</i>. Rocker Tori Amos also sang the classic for the
    Julia Roberts film 
    <i>Mona Lisa Smile</i>in 2003. Actress Rose McGowan sang it on
    the soundtrack for the 
    <i>Planet Terror</i>segment of the 2007 movie 
    <i>Grindhouse</i>. While onscreen, Bette Midler sings a
    fragment of the song (to Nick Nolte) in the 1986 comedy 
    <i>Down and Out in Beverly Hills</i>.</p>
      <p>On February 1, 2007, a short rendition of the song was sung
    by 64-year-old Sherman Pore as an audition piece for the
    television show 
    <i>American Idol</i>, as a tribute to his wife who had died
    from cancer two days before.</p>
      <p>Mary Higgins Clark references the song throughout her novel
    of the same name which was published by Pocket on April 1st
    1999.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
