<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Love_Rock_%27n%27_Roll 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Love_Rock_%27n%27_Roll</songId>
   <title>I Love Rock 'n' Roll</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joan_Jett</artistId>
      <artistName>Joan Jett and the Blackhearts</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1982-03-20</week>
      <week>1982-03-27</week>
      <week>1982-04-03</week>
      <week>1982-04-10</week>
      <week>1982-04-17</week>
      <week>1982-04-24</week>
      <week>1982-05-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1975</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1975</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:48</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RAK Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Alan Merrill</writer>
      <writer>Jake Hooker</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mickie Most</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Love Rock 'n Roll" is a rock song written in 1975 by Alan
    Merrill and Jake Hooker of The Arrows, who recorded the first
    released version. The song was later made famous by the hit
    version recorded by Joan Jett &amp; the Blackhearts in
    1981.</p>
      <p>The song was originally recorded and released by the Arrows
    in 1975 on RAK Records, with lead vocals by Alan Merrill and
    produced by Mickie Most. In an interview with Songfacts,
    Merrill said he wrote it as "a knee-jerk response to The
    Rolling Stones' It's Only Rock 'n Roll (But I Like It).'" This
    version was first released as a B-side, but was soon
    re-recorded and flipped to A-side status on a subsequent
    pressing of the record. Although not a chart hit in its
    original version as a result of non-existent promotion by the
    band's label, the song has come to worldwide prominence due to
    very successful cover versions that have been recorded.</p>
      <p>Joan Jett saw the Arrows perform "I Love Rock 'n Roll" on
    their weekly television series 
    <i>The Arrows Show</i>when she was touring England with The
    Runaways in 1976. She first recorded the song in 1979 with two
    of the Sex Pistols: Steve Jones and Paul Cook. This first
    version was not released until 1993 in Flashback. In 1981, Jett
    re-recorded the song, this time with her band, The Blackhearts.
    Early copies of the album, which was released just before
    Christmas 1981, featured the Christmas song "Little Drummer
    Boy" but, since it made little sense to have such a song on an
    album outside the holiday period, it was quickly replaced with
    "Oh Woe is Me". This recording became a U.S. Billboard Hot 100
    number-one single for seven weeks, effectively launching Jett's
    solo career. The single was certified platinum by the Recording
    Industry Association of America, representing two million
    records shipped. This success propelled Jett's 
    <i>I Love Rock 'n Roll</i>album to number two on the Billboard
    200.</p>
      <p>"I Love Rock 'n Roll"'s gritty, black-and-white music video
    received heavy play from the then-young MTV network. In it,
    Jett and the Blackhearts travel to a small, dingy bar and
    proceed to excite the drunken crowd by performing the song and
    yelling out its famous chorus. A snippet of Jett's 1981 hit,
    "Bad Reputation," is featured at the beginning of the video.
    Jett followed "I Love Rock 'n Roll" up with another cover — her
    version of Tommy James and the Shondells' "Crimson and Clover"
    was a top-ten U.S. hit. The video was originally in color, but
    it was converted to black and white due to the way Joan Jett
    felt her red leather jacket looked in color.</p>
      <p>In 1983, "Weird Al" Yankovic released a parody of Jett's
    version, titled "I Love Rocky Road", which appeared on his
    self-titled debut album. Besides the song using Jett's version
    for the music, a music video was also released modeled after
    Jett's video.</p>
      <p>Jett's version has received many accolades, including:</p>
      <p>Also, cover versions of Jett's version have appeared in two
    music video games: 
    <i>Guitar Hero</i>and 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Party</i>. The original version made an
    appearance in 
    <i>Guitar Hero: Greatest Hits</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1993 Joan Jett &amp; The Blackhearts made another music
    video for the song as part of the Wayne's World 2 soundtrack.
    In the video appear several scenes from the movie with Mike
    Myers and Dana Carvey mixed with Joan and her band playing in a
    concert.</p>
      <p>"I Love Rock 'n' Roll" is the fourth European single
    released internationally by pop singer Britney Spears from the
    album 
    <i>Britney</i>during the second quarter of 2002, except in the
    USA. The song was used in her 2002 movie 
    <i>Crossroads</i>. Spears's character, Lucy, performs it in a
    karaoke bar. Spears said of the song, "They asked me to sing
    karaoke in the movie 
    <i>Crossroads</i>and I've actually sung I Love Rock 'n' Roll in
    a lot of clubs that I've been to."</p>
      <p>Spears has publicly admitted the original song to be one of
    her favorites. Spears listened to The Arrows' original Mickie
    Most-produced version just before she recorded the song,
    according to her Jive A&amp;R man Steve Lunt. When promoting
    the single's release she infamously attributed the hit version
    of the song to Pat Benatar instead of Jett, although she claims
    this was a remark made in sarcasm rather than a mistake.</p>
      <p>Directed by Chris Applebaum, the music video for "I Love
    Rock 'n' Roll" features Spears in a tight-fitting leather
    getup. Straightforward, it features Spears jamming in a large
    red room, complete with her own band, a stack of speakers, and
    flashing lights. She crawls along on the floor, and plays air
    guitar before smashing the speakers with a real guitar. Spears
    also dances on a rotating motorcycle and gets covered with
    confetti. The Director's Cut version of the video was later
    leaked; it included previously unseen scenes from the video.The
    Bar where it was shot is called The Inn, in Long Beach , New
    York.</p>
      <p>"I Love Rock 'n' Roll" failed to make the top ten in most
    countries. However, the track was not a total flop as it made
    at least top forty placement in most regions. The song was
    moderately successful in the UK, where it peaked at number
    thirteen (which, at the time, was her lowest peak for a single
    released there, until "Break the Ice" only managed to reach
    number fifteen in 2008). The single sold a total of 51,000
    copies. The single also got Gold certification in Australia
    despite missing the top ten.</p>
      <p>"I Love Rock 'n Roll" is an often-covered song, and has been
    notably recorded by such artists as:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
