<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wooden_Heart 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wooden_Heart</songId>
   <title>Wooden Heart (Muss I Denn)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_Dowell</artistId>
      <artistName>Joe Dowell</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1961-08-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/eb/Woodenheartcover.jpg/200px-Woodenheartcover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Joe-Dowell+Wooden-Heart-Muss-I-Denn.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>G.I. Blues</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1960</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>45rpm</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>April 28, 1960</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Blues</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:03</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Fred Wise</writer>
      <writer>Ben Weisman</writer>
      <writer>Kay Twomey</writer>
      <writer>Bert Kaempfert</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Wooden Heart (Muss I Denn)" is a song best known for
    featuring in the 1960 Elvis Presley film 
    <i>G.I. Blues</i>. The song was a hit for Presley in the United
    Kingdom, making number one for six weeks, but wasn't released
    as a single in the USA until November 1964 (as B-side to "Blue
    Christmas"). Presley was pipped to the post in the U.S. by Joe
    Dowell's cover version, which made number one at the end of
    August 1961, knocking Bobby Lewis' Tossin' and Turnin' off the
    number one chart after 7 weeks. Elvis performed the song live
    during his Dinner Show concert at the Hilton Hotel in Las Vegas
    in 1975. The recording is available on the Elvis Presley live
    album, Dinner At Eight.</p>
      <p>"Wooden Heart", created by Fred Wise, Ben Weisman, Kay
    Twomey and German bandleader Bert Kaempfert, was based on a
    German folk song, "Muß i' denn zum Städtele hinaus". "Wooden
    Heart" features several lines from the original folk song,
    written in the German dialect Swabian. Bobby Vinton recorded
    his version in 1975 with those lines translated into
    Polish.</p>
      <p>The Elvis Presley version featured two parts in German, the
    first one is the first four lines of "Muß i' denn zum Städtele
    hinaus", whereas the second part appears towards the end and is
    based on a translation of the English version (therefore not
    appearing in the original German folk lyrics). This part being
    "Sei mir gut, Sei mir gut, Sei mir wie du wirklich sollst, Wie
    du wirklich sollst...." This literally means "Be good to me, Be
    good to me, Be to me how you really should, How you really
    should...."</p>
      <p>"Wooden Heart" was covered by Tom Petty and the
    Heartbreakers in 1993. It was released in their 1995 Playback
    box set on disc six, "Nobody's Children".</p>
      <p>Another Elvis song from the same session, this one a track
    from 
    <i>G.I. Blues</i>, "The first album I ever owned," Petty says.
    In 1995 Petty arranged for his family to take a private tour of
    Graceland, and for the Heartbreakers to record at Sun Studios.
    "I am the true Elvis fan. The music meant so much to me. I
    really have to give him credit for saving my life on so many
    levels.</p>
      <p>-Tom Petty, 
    <i>Playback box set liner notes</i>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
