<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Running_Bear 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Running_Bear</songId>
   <title>Running Bear</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johnny_Preston</artistId>
      <artistName>Johnny Preston</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1960-01-18</week>
      <week>1960-01-25</week>
      <week>1960-02-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:39</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Mercury Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>J. P. Richardson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bill Hall</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Running Bear" is a song written by J. P. Richardson (aka
    The Big Bopper) sung most famously by Johnny Preston in 1959.
    Preston first sang the song in 1959 with background vocals by
    Richardson and George Jones, and it was number one for three
    weeks in January 1960 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 in the United States. The song also
    reached number one in the UK in 1960.</p>
      <p>Richardson was a friend of Preston and offered "Running
    Bear" to him after hearing him perform in a club. Preston
    recorded the song at the Gold Star Studios in Houston, Texas in
    1958. The session's producer was Bill Hall with Preston on
    vocals, Link Davis on saxophone. Richardson, Hall, and Jones
    performed the song's Indian chants.</p>
      <p>Preston was signed to Mercury Records, and "Running Bear"
    was released in August 1959, seven months after Richardson's
    death in the plane crash that also killed Buddy Holly and
    Ritchie Valens.</p>
      <p>"Running Bear" tells the story of Running Bear, a "young
    Indian brave", and Little White Dove, an "Indian maid". The two
    are in love but are separated by two factors:</p>
      <p>The two, desiring to be together despite their obstacles and
    the risks for navigating the river, dive into the raging river
    to unite. After sharing a passionate kiss, they are pulled down
    by the swift current and drown. The lyrics tell the rest: "
    <i>Now they'll always be together / In their happy hunting
    ground</i>."</p>
      <p>During the late 1960s and early 1970s, Sonny James enjoyed
    an unprecidented streak of success with his commercially
    released singles, many of them covers of previous pop hits. One
    of his 16 consecutive No. 1 singles on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Country Singles chart was a cover version
    of "Running Bear."</p>
      <p>Released in April 1969, "Running Bear" topped the Hot
    Country Singles chart in mid-June and spent three weeks at No.
    1. The song soon became one of James' most popular recordings
    of his career.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
