<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Can_See_Clearly_Now 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Can_See_Clearly_Now</songId>
   <title>I Can See Clearly Now</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johnny_Nash</artistId>
      <artistName>Johnny Nash</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1972-11-04</week>
      <week>1972-11-11</week>
      <week>1972-11-18</week>
      <week>1972-11-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/08/I_can_see_clearly_now_%28Johnny_Nash%29.jpg/200px-I_can_see_clearly_now_%28Johnny_Nash%29.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Johnny-Nash+I-Can-See-Clearly-Now.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>I Can See Clearly Now</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1972</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop   Reggae</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:45</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Johnny Nash</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Can See Clearly Now" is a song written and recorded by
    Johnny Nash. It was a single from the album of the same name
    and achieved success in the United States and the United
    Kingdom when it was released in 1972. It was covered by many
    artists throughout the years, including a 1993 hit version by
    Jimmy Cliff.</p>
      <p>The song's extremely optimistic lyrics, an unabashedly
    upbeat tempo in D-major, and a quick, sustained midway
    crescendo, contrasted against minor key hits popular at the
    same time, such as "Nights In White Satin," "I'll Be Around,"
    "Witchy Woman," and "Papa Was A Rolling Stone." Nash thus
    joined Elvis Presley, Chuck Berry, and Rick Nelson as 1950s
    rock pioneers each having his last Hot 100 top 10 success in
    late 1972.</p>
      <p>It is a common misconception that the song was written
    and/or previously performed by Bob Marley, possibly based on
    the fact that The Wailers were the backing band on Nash's
    original recording. Marley wrote Nash's next single, "Stir It
    Up". Nash wrote this song himself and recorded it in London
    with members of The Average White Band.</p>
      <p>After making modest chart advances for a month, the RIAA
    certified gold single unexpectedly took only two weeks to vault
    from #20 to #5 to #1 on the Billboard Hot 100 on November 4,
    1972, remaining atop this chart for four weeks, and also spent
    four weeks atop the adult contemporary chart.</p>
      <p>Reggae singer Jimmy Cliff recorded a cover of the song for
    the 1993 movie 
    <i>Cool Runnings</i>. It was released as a single in 1994,
    becoming a comeback hit for him, reaching #18 on the Billboard
    Hot 100.</p>
      <p>The song experienced a revival in popularity again in 1993
    when Jimmy Cliff recorded a version for the soundtrack of the
    film 
    <i>Cool Runnings</i>. The song also appears in various other
    films, such as 
    <i>Grosse Pointe Blank</i>, 
    <i>The Break-up</i>, 
    <i>Thelma &amp; Louise</i>, 
    <i>Antz</i>, 
    <i>Deep Blue Sea</i>, 
    <i>Envy</i>, 
    <i>Hitch</i>, 
    <i>Shrek 2'</i>s Far Far Away Idol, and Jennifer's body, as
    well in a 2009 advertisement for Lipton in the Middle East and
    Russia.</p>
      <p>It has also been covered by</p>
      <p>It is also a perennial favorite for several a cappella
    groups, including The Coats and University of Oregon's On the
    Rocks, or the European a cappella formation "Klapa Sinj &amp;
    Ida Ajdukovic".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
