<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/(Just_Like)_Starting_Over 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/(Just_Like)_Starting_Over</songId>
   <title>(Just Like) Starting Over</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Lennon</artistId>
      <artistName>John Lennon</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1981-01-03</week>
      <week>1981-01-10</week>
      <week>1981-01-17</week>
      <week>1981-01-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/57/JustLikeStartingOver.jpg/200px-JustLikeStartingOver.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/John-Lennon+Just-Like-Starting-Over.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Double Fantasy</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>24 October 1980</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>Cassette</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1980</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:54</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Geffen Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>John Lennon</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>John Lennon</producer>
      <producer>Yoko Ono</producer>
      <producer>Jack Douglas</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"(Just Like) Starting Over" is a song written and performed
    by John Lennon for his 
    <i>Double Fantasy</i>album. The B-side was Yoko Ono's "Kiss
    Kiss Kiss". It was released as a single on 24 October 1980 and
    reached number one in both the USA and UK two weeks after he
    was murdered. It is his biggest solo American hit, staying at
    #1 for five weeks. (When Lennon was shot in New York City on 8
    December 1980 the single was at #3 in the US and the following
    week reached the summit.) In the UK it had peaked at #8 in the
    charts and had fallen out of the Top 20 before Lennon's death
    propelled it to #1, making an unprecedented #21 to #1 move. By
    6 January 1981 there were 3 Lennon songs in the UK top 5, a
    feat never achieved before or since.</p>
      <p>This was the first single released from 
    <i>Double Fantasy</i>, and the first new recording Lennon had
    released since 1975. It was chosen by Lennon not because it was
    the best track on the album, but because it was the most
    appropriate following his five year absence from the recording
    industry. He referred to it during production as the "Elvis /
    Orbison" track, as he "tongue in cheek" impersonated their
    vocal styles. The uplifting bell at the intro of the song
    serves as the antidote to the morose bell sound which opens
    Lennon's first solo album, Lennon seeing it as him having come
    full circle.</p>
      <p>Although its origins were in unfinished older compositions
    like "Don’t Be Crazy" and "My Life", it was one of the last
    songs to be completed in time for the 
    <i>Double Fantasy</i>sessions. “We didn’t hear it until the
    last day of rehearsal,” producer Jack Douglas said in 2005.
    Lennon finished the song while on holiday in Bermuda, and
    recorded it at The Hit Factory in New York City just weeks
    later. The original title was to be "Starting Over". "(Just
    Like)" was added at the last minute because a country song of
    the same title was recently released by Tammy Wynette.</p>
      <p>While commercial releases of the song (original 45rpm
    singles, LP's and Compact Discs) run a length of 3 minutes and
    54 seconds, promotional 12" vinyl singles originally issued to
    radio stations feature a longer version, officially running at
    4 minutes and 17 seconds. This version extends the coda
    fadeout, and is highly desired by collectors, as it has not
    appeared on any CD reissue or compilation.</p>
      <p>It is listed at #53 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top Songs.</i>The Flaming Lips recorded
    a version for the benefit album 
    <i>Instant Karma: The Amnesty International Campaign to Save
    Darfur</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
