<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annie%27s_Song 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annie%27s_Song</songId>
   <title>Annie's Song</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Denver</artistId>
      <artistName>John Denver</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-07-27</week>
      <week>1974-08-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e7/Annies_song.jpg/200px-Annies_song.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/John-Denver+Annie-s-Song.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Back Home Again</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June, 1974</released>
   <formats>
      <format>vinyl record</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Singer/Songwriter</genre>
      <genre>Adult Contemporary</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:58</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>John Denver</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Milt Okun</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Annie's Song" is a song recorded and written by
    singer-songwriter John Denver. It was his second number one
    song in the USA, occupying that spot for two weeks in July
    1974. It also went to number one in the UK, where it was
    Denver's only major hit single (many of Denver's American hits
    were more familiar in the UK through cover versions by other
    artists).</p>
      <p>"Annie's Song" was written as an ode to Denver's then-wife,
    Annie Denver (née Martell). Denver "wrote this song in about
    ten-and-a-half minutes one day on a ski lift" to the top of
    Bell Mountain in Aspen, Colorado, as the physical exhilaration
    of having "just skied down a very difficult run" and the
    feeling of total immersion in the beauty of the colors and
    sounds that filled all senses inspired him to think about his
    wife.</p>
      <p>The song has since become a wedding standard and an
    expression of love for many people, due to its grand imagery
    and the fact it could apply to anyone (Annie is not mentioned
    by name in any part of the song).</p>
      <p>Monty Python did a send-up of the song on their 
    <i>Monty Python's Contractual Obligation Album</i>in 1980,
    called "Farewell to John Denver". The track contained a few
    bars of Eric Idle impersonating John Denver singing "Annie's
    Song" with joke lyrics: "you came on my pillow..." (followed by
    the sound of the singer being strangled) and was removed from
    subsequent pressings of the album on legal advice (reports
    differ as to whether it had to do with the licensing of
    "Annie's Song" or the depiction of the popular singer being
    murdered), and was replaced by an apology spoken by Terry
    Jones. Later CD releases of the album, however, reinstated the
    John Denver track.</p>
      <p>Its tune is used in the UK by "The Greasy Chip Butty Song",
    the main chant of fans of Sheffield United football club.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
