<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_and_Diane 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_and_Diane</songId>
   <title>Jack and Diane</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Mellencamp</artistId>
      <artistName>John Cougar</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1982-10-02</week>
      <week>1982-10-09</week>
      <week>1982-10-16</week>
      <week>1982-10-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/00/John_cougar-jack_diane_s.jpg/200px-John_cougar-jack_diane_s.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/John-Cougar+Jack-and-Diane.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>American Fool</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1982</released>
   <formats>
      <format>45 Record</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1982</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Heartland Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:45 (Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Riva Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>John Mellencamp</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Jack &amp; Diane" is a 1982 hit song written and performed
    by American singer-songwriter, John Mellencamp, then performing
    as "John Cougar". It appears on Mellencamp's album 
    <i>American Fool</i>. It was chosen by RIAA as one of the Songs
    of the Century. The single spent four weeks at number one on
    the Billboard Hot 100 in 1982, and, to date, is the biggest hit
    single ever for Mellencamp, especially with its accompanying
    music video directed by Bruce Gowers.</p>
      <p>According to Mellencamp, "'Jack &amp; Diane' was written
    after watching 
    <i>Splendor in the Grass,</i>(a 1961 movie starring Natalie
    Wood and Warren Beatty). "'Jack &amp; Diane' was a terrible
    record to make. When I play it on guitar by myself, it sounds
    great; but I could never get the band to play along with me.
    That's why the arrangement's so weird. Stopping and starting,
    it's not very musical." Mellencamp has also stated that the
    clapping wasn't supposed to be included in the finished song.
    It was recorded with the clapping in order to help keep tempo
    and then it was to be removed. However, he realized the song
    didn't work without it.</p>
      <p>The song's tone and lyrics are evocative of a nostalgia for
    the novelty of youth, influenced in part by Mellencamp's own
    life experiences. Mellencamp has stated in interviews that
    "Jack and Diane" was originally about an interracial couple,
    but he realized that in the early '80s there could be backlash
    over such a song. Later on, he would make the title track on
    his 2001 album 
    <i>Cuttin' Heads</i>about an interracial couple.</p>
      <p>In 1982, Mick Ronson worked with John Mellencamp on his 
    <i>American Fool</i>album, and in particularly the song "Jack
    &amp; Diane". "I owe Mick Ronson the hit song, 'Jack &amp;
    Diane'. Mick was very instrumental in helping me arrange that
    song, as I'd thrown it on the junk heap. Ronson came down and
    played on three or four tracks and worked on the American Fool
    record for four or five weeks. All of a sudden, for 'Jack &amp;
    Diane', Mick said 'Johnny, you should put baby rattles on
    there.' I thought, 'What the @$%&amp;! does put baby rattles on
    the record mean? So he put the percussion on there and then he
    sang the part 'let it rock, let it roll' as a choir-ish-type
    thing, which had never occurred to me. And that is the part
    everybody remembers on the song. It was Ronson's idea."</p>
      <p>A very similar riff is in Tracy Chapman's song "Fast Car" as
    in "Jack and Diane."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
