<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/What_Goes_Around.../...Comes_Around 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/What_Goes_Around.../...Comes_Around</songId>
   <title>What Goes Around.../...Comes Around</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Justin_Timberlake</artistId>
      <artistName>Justin Timberlake</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2007-03-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/8a/WhatGoesAroundSingleCover.jpg/200px-WhatGoesAroundSingleCover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Justin-Timberlake+What-Goes-Around-Comes-Around.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>FutureSex/LoveSounds</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 8, 2007</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2006</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>7:28 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>5:13 (Radio Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Jive</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Tim "Timbaland" Mosley</writer>
      <writer>Nate "Danja" Hills</writer>
      <writer>Justin Timberlake</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Timbaland</producer>
      <producer>Danja</producer>
      <producer>Justin Timberlake</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"What Goes Around.../...Comes Around" is a song by American
    singer Justin Timberlake. The track was created after
    Timberlake and collaborators Timbaland and Nate "Danja" Hills
    were fooling around Timbaland's studio in Virginia Beach. They
    produced the song for Timberlake's second solo studio album, 
    <i>FutureSex/LoveSounds</i>. The song has similarities to "Cry
    Me a River"; although Timberlake disclosed to whom he wrote the
    song, the public had generated their lyrical
    interpretation.</p>
      <p>The track was released as the third single from the album
    early in 2007. It became Timberlake's third consecutive
    number-one single on the Hot 100. The international chart
    performance of the single failed to match its domestic success,
    never reaching the top spot. The single's music video features
    "real" artists and is considered a short film. "What Goes
    Around.../...Comes Around" was certified multi-platinum.</p>
      <p>The song received mostly positive responses from critics. It
    was nominated for Record of the Year and won Best Male Pop
    Vocal Performance at the 50th Annual Grammy Awards.</p>
      <p>After the release of his debut solo album, 
    <i>Justified</i>, in 2002, Timberlake thought he "lost his
    voice" in the sense of "not liking what he was doing". He felt
    "burnt out" after 
    <i>Justified'</i>s release; this partly changed his career's
    direction, opting to work in films and took a break from the
    recording industry.</p>
      <p>When he felt inspired to compose music again, he did not
    choose to reunite with his former band 'N Sync, which he
    considered doing after his first record. Instead, he went to
    former 
    <i>Justified</i>collaborator Timbaland's studio in Virginia
    Beach, Virginia in November 2005. However, no one of them had
    an idea of what the album would be; no plan for it and even a
    title. Timberlake revealed: "I thought if I could put something
    together that lived up to the first record, I would have." He
    told Timbaland if he could remake his previous single, "Cry Me
    a River", five or six times. Nate "Danja" Hills, a protégé of
    Timbaland, stated: "We had no direction at all other than 'Cry
    Me a River,' and not in the sense of mimicking the track, but
    in how big the song was. There was no direction for how he
    wanted the song to sound, because there was no direction for
    how he wanted [his album 
    <i>FutureSex/LoveSounds</i>] to sound."</p>
      <p>While in the studio, Timberlake, Danja and Timbaland were
    just "fooling around" and "freestyling". When Danja begun
    playing a guitar riff, it caught Timberlake's attention. He
    started humming the melody of "What goes around comes around",
    and then the lyrics came. Timbaland was at his keyboards,
    besides Danja, adding drums to the melody. Danja commented that
    "everything was coming together at the same time." After coming
    up with the music, Timberlake never wrote down the lyrics and,
    in an hour, he was ready to record it. By the time Timberlake
    was in the vocal booth, the basic track was done, then
    Timbaland produced a prelude of the song. Timberlake sang the
    song in a couple of takes and went back line by line to fill up
    the gaps. During the recording sessions, Timbaland and Danja
    added everything else, including the basses and strings. Danja
    considered the process scoring to a film and referred to the
    song a horror flick.</p>
      <p>After finishing the song, Timbaland teased Timberlake.
    Timberlake responded: "Let's do something we would never do.
    Let's go far left and just see what happens." His answer
    motivated them, and they ended up producing ten songs for the
    album.</p>
      <p>"What Goes Around.../...Comes Around" is a pop-R&amp;B song
    performed in a slow manner. It is composed in the key of A
    dorian, in common time. With a gentle and midtempo beat, the
    tempo is pacing to seventy-two beats per minute. The song
    features a two-minute interlude titled "Comes Around",
    featuring the album's producer Timbaland, spanning to a seven
    minutes and twenty-eight-second track. Timberlake's voice
    ranges from B
    <sub>3</sub>to C
    <sub>6</sub>. Musically, the song is similar to the type of
    music produced on Timberlake's 
    <i>Justified</i>album; however, it is the only link from 
    <i>FutureSex/LoveSounds</i>to 
    <i>Justified</i>.</p>
      <p>In the beginning of the song, there is a five-second harmony
    line of two bağlamas (one each panned far left and far right on
    respect octaves), a Greek folk instrument. The beat is then
    changed to a more upbeat version of the same melody with more
    percussion. Timbaland used the oud to mellow out the guitar
    riff. The chord series follows the Am-C-G-D keys. Following the
    instrumental, Timberlake begins the verse at thirteenth bar.
    The original track had a bridge, including the pre-verses, the
    verses and the choruses. After hearing the vocals of
    Timberlake, they decided to remove the bridge and follow a
    simple flow, because they felt its "too much" to have it and a
    break at the end of the song. Timbaland provides backing vocals
    on the song.</p>
      <p>"What Goes Around.../...Comes Around" is about betrayal and
    forgiveness. Timberlake revealed that the song was written for
    the experience his friend went through. However, the public
    came up with different lyrical interpretations and speculated
    "What Goes Around.../...Comes Around" a sequel to "Cry Me A
    River" in content. Bill Lamb wrote that the song has a
    "cautionary tale in the lyrics". According to him, after
    hearing the lyrics, many fans and critics insisted that the
    song is similar to "Cry Me a River", which is allegedly about
    his relationship with former girlfriend pop singer Britney
    Spears. Spence D. of IGN commented that the song presents "some
    intriguing ambiance".</p>
      <p>"What Goes Around.../...Comes Around" was released as the
    third single from 
    <i>FutureSex/LoveSounds</i>, following "Sexyback" and "My
    Love", in various dates and formats. The single was released in
    the United Kingdom on February 26, 2007. On March 5, 2007, the
    single was released in the United States. In Australia, a maxi
    single was released on March 17, featuring the radio edit and
    two remixes of the track and the explicit main version of
    "Boutique In Heaven", another song from the album. The single
    was followed with the released of "LoveStoned", the fourth
    single from the album.</p>
      <p>The song received generally positive reviews from critics. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>called the single "a soaring ballad
    featuring Timberlake's falsetto, with verses and choruses that
    pile on top of one another with dizzying effect." About.com
    reviewer Bill Lamb stated that the song "is one of the most
    gorgeous pop melodies of the year." He complimented the
    string-based arrangement of the song. Chris Willman of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>called it "superior", along with
    "LoveStoned". Zach Baron of Pitchfork Media referred to it
    "some real can't-let-go shit that'll save you the repeat stabs
    on the bad night." Spence D. of IGN called it "annoying" but he
    complimented the use of echo vocals and swirling synths.</p>
      <p>"What Goes Around.../...Comes Around" placed at number
    twenty-four on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s list of the 100 Best Songs of 2007. The
    song was nominated twice at the 50th Annual Grammy Awards,
    winning Best Male Pop Vocal Performance but lost to Amy
    Winehouse's "Rehab" for Record of the Year.</p>
      <p>"What Goes Around.../...Comes Around" was commercially
    successful in the United States. The single debuted at number
    64 on December 23, 2006 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100, prior to its physical release. From
    number eight on February 24, 2007, it propelled to number one
    the following week. "What Goes Around.../...Comes Around"
    became Timberlake's third consecutive number one hit on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 from his 
    <i>Futuresex/Lovesounds</i>album, becoming the first male
    artist since Usher in 2004 to have three or more consecutive
    number-one hits from one album. The single charted on Hot 100
    for 25 weeks. "What Goes Around.../...Comes Around" was
    certified platinum by the Recording Industry Association of
    America on June 7, 2007.</p>
      <p>Internationally, the single failed to match its domestic
    chart performance. In the United Kingdom, "What Goes
    Around.../...Comes Around" debuted at number 59 on the UK
    Singles Chart on January 29, 2007. The digital download sales
    helped propel the single to number eleven on February 26, 2007.
    "What Goes Around.../...Comes Around" peaked at number four on
    March 12, to become his sixth top five hit in the United
    Kingdom. It stayed on the chart for 22 weeks. The single
    entered the top five in Austria, Belgium, Denmark, Finland,
    France, Germany, Ireland, Norway, Romania, Sweden, Switzerland.
    In Australia, the single debuted and peaked at number three on
    the Australian ARIA singles chart on March 26, 2007, gaining
    the Highest Debut certification. It spent a total of 22 weeks
    on the chart. "What Goes Around.../...Comes Around" was
    certified two-times platinum by the Australian Recording
    Industry Association for selling over 30,000 units. The single
    peaked at number three in the New Zealand on April 9, 2007, and
    spent 16 weeks on the chart. "What Goes Around.../...Comes
    Around" was certified gold by the Recording Industry
    Association of New Zealand.</p>
      <p>The music video for the "What Goes Around.../...Comes
    Around" was produced as a short movie. The video was directed
    by Samuel Bayer, who had first directorial works with Nirvana's
    1991 single "Smells Like Teen Spirit". The video features
    dialogues written by 
    <i>Alpha Dog</i>writer and director Nick Cassavetes, who had
    previously worked with Timberlake in the film. Timberlake and
    Bayer enlisted American actress Scarlett Johansson after
    deciding on using "real" actors. The shooting went for three
    days between Christmas and New Year's Eve in Los Angeles. The
    dawn scene was shot on January 8, after the original sessions
    were done.</p>
      <p>The video starts off with Timberlake flirting with Scarlett
    Johansson on the rooftop of a 1950's 
    <i>Moulin Rouge</i>circus-style club. She rejects with a tease
    at first but eventually leaves with him to go back to his
    place. In between cuts, they are shown in bed caressing each
    other. Johansson jumps into a pool outside the house, and
    floats below the surface as if she is drowning. Timberlake runs
    out and pulls her up; she laughs at Timberlake and kisses him.
    Timberlake introduces her to a drunk Shawn Hatosy at the club
    calling her "The One". Hatosy seems to be interested in
    Johansson, despite Timberlake asking him to "look out for her".
    Timberlake returns and finds them kissing in the stairway.
    After punching Hatosy he chases after Johansson, who speeds off
    in her 1967 Chevrolet Corvette C2 Sting Ray; Timberlake follows
    in his Porsche Carrera GT. Johansson runs into a fiery car
    crash pile up and is thrown from the car landing several feet
    away. Timberlake notices a body (presumably a dead one) lying
    supine on the ground. He gets out and kneels over her while the
    camera view moves toward the sky and ends the video.</p>
      <p>The music video of "What Goes Around.../...Comes Around" was
    exclusively premiered on February 9, 2007 on the iTunes store.
    The music video debuted on MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>at number nine on February 13, 2007.
    "What Goes Around..." retired on May 7 at number seven. In
    Canada, the music video debuted on Muchmusic's Top 30 countdown
    at number 22 on January 26, 2007. It peaked at number one on
    April 27 and stayed on the chart for seven non-consecutive
    weeks. The video was commercially successful, becoming the
    fastest selling pop promo on iTunes. It has sold 50,000 in
    downloads for four days. Timberlake was the first major artist
    to release a video on the download platform.</p>
      <p>In September 2007, "What Goes Around.../...Comes Around" won
    an MTV Video Music Award for Best Direction. It was also
    nominated for Video of the Year but lost to pop singer
    Rihanna's 2007 video "Umbrella".</p>
      <p>In 2007, C-pop singer Nicholas Teo (張棟樑; 
    <i>Zhang Dong Liang</i>) covered the song, retitled to You Xi
    (遊戲; 
    <i>Game</i>) and lyrics completely rewritten in Mandarin
    Chinese, for his album Wang Zi (王子; 
    <i>Prince</i>).</p>
      <p>On May 23, 2007, Marilyn Manson and Tim Skold appeared on UK
    radio station BBC Radio 1's program 
    <i>Live Lounge</i>to promote Marilyn Manson's 2007 album 
    <i>Eat Me, Drink Me</i>. They performed an acoustic version of
    "Heart-Shaped Glasses (When the Heart Guides the Hand)",
    followed with an acoustic cover of "What Goes
    Around.../...Comes Around". The Manson cover does not include
    the interlude.</p>
      <p>French singer Myriam Abel, the winner of Nouvelle Star 3,
    also recorded a non-commercial cover of "What Goes
    Around.../...Comes Around" with a Raï influence, accessible
    through her official MySpace page [1]</p>
      <p>An a cappella rendition was recorded by Overboard for their
    2007 album, "Stranded".</p>
      <p>American post hardcore band Alesana recorded a cover for the
    most recent of the Punk Goes... compilation series, Punk Goes
    Pop 2, released March 10, 2009.</p>
      <p>American country singer Taylor Swift covered the song on her
    Fearless tour 2009 in between the song "You're Not Sorry" from
    her second album, 
    <i>Fearless</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
