<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SexyBack 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SexyBack</songId>
   <title>SexyBack</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Justin_Timberlake</artistId>
      <artistName>Justin Timberlake</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2006-09-09</week>
      <week>2006-09-16</week>
      <week>2006-09-23</week>
      <week>2006-09-30</week>
      <week>2006-10-07</week>
      <week>2006-10-14</week>
      <week>2006-10-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/88/Sexyback.jpg/200px-Sexyback.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Justin-Timberlake+SexyBack.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>FutureSex/LoveSounds</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 7, 2006  (2006-07-07)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>Electropop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:02 (Album version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Jive</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Justin Timberlake</writer>
      <writer>Timbaland</writer>
      <writer>Nate "Danja" Hills</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Timbaland</producer>
      <producer>Justin Timberlake</producer>
      <producer>Danja</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"SexyBack" is a song by American singer–songwriter Justin
    Timberlake from his second studio album, 
    <i>FutureSex/LoveSounds</i>(2006). It was released on July 7,
    2006, by Jive Records as the lead single from the album. The
    song was co-written and produced by Timberlake, Timbaland, and
    Nate "Danja" Hills.</p>
      <p>Discussing "SexyBack", Timberlake revealed that he went
    "left", singing the song in a rock style, not an R&amp;B style.
    He described the song as musicians David Bowie and David Byrne
    "covering" James Brown's 1970 song "Sex Machine". The track
    features Timbaland on backing vocals, while Timberlake's voice
    is processed with distorted vocals. The instrumentation used in
    the song includes a pounding bass beat, electronic chords, and
    beat box sounds. "SexyBack" received mixed reception from
    critics.</p>
      <p>"SexyBack" became Timberlake's first number one single on
    the Hot 100, staying seven weeks at the top spot. It also
    topped several of 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine's other component charts, including
    the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Pop 100, Hot Dance Airplay, and Hot Digital
    Songs charts, and entered the top ten on most singles charts.
    Internationally, it became Timberlake's first single to reach
    number one in the UK Singles Chart. In Australia, the track was
    Timberlake's second number one single, spending two consecutive
    weeks at the top. "SexyBack" was certified three-times platinum
    by the Recording Industry Association of America (RIAA) and
    six-times platinum by Canadian Recording Industry Association
    (CRIA).</p>
      <p>The track won Best Dance Recording at the 2007 Grammy
    Awards. In addition, the song won Timberlake the People's
    Choice Award for Favorite R&amp;B song and the Male Artist of
    the Year at the 2007 MTV Video Music Awards. The music video
    was filmed in June 2006; Timberlake decided to work with
    director Michael Haussman based on the latter's work on
    Madonna's 1994 music video "Take a Bow".</p>
      <p>"SexyBack" was written and produced by Justin Timberlake,
    Timbaland, and Nate "Danja" Hills. In December 2005, Timberlake
    began working on his second album, 
    <i>FutureSex/LoveSounds</i>, the follow-up to his 2002 album 
    <i>Justified</i>. Within three weeks, "SexyBack" was one of
    several songs that were recorded. In September 2006, Timberlake
    told 
    <i>The Weekend Mail</i>that "SexyBack" was the "second or third
    song" he did with Timbaland in a list of 10 songs they recorded
    for the album. "It was just an experiment gone right from the
    sort of synthesizer influence to the distorted vocals", said
    Timberlake. "It's one of the songs that the more you listen to
    it its just hook after hook after hook. Its just one of those
    'flow off the top of your head' tracks, in terms of melody. We
    wanted to keep it lose and not too rehearsed, it's one of those
    very experimental records though." Timberlake revealed to MTV
    News that he went "left", regarding going more rock, not in how
    he developed the song, but in the way he sang the song. "I
    wanted to sing the song like a rock and roll singer, not an
    R&amp;B singer. That's the approach."</p>
      <p>In another interview, Timberlake said that he modeled
    himself on musicians David Bowie and Prince, and described the
    song as Bowie and David Byrne "covering" James Brown's 1970
    song "Sex Machine" and concluded with, "That's all of my
    influences for that song." Timberlake himself said that the
    song "doesn't qualify as rock or straight funk" and that he was
    happy with the description "club funk". In another interview he
    said he was "keen for a new musical direction" following the
    release of his first album, 
    <i>Justified</i>. "I listened to the radio for a few months and
    thought, 'All this sounds like shit, what do I want to hear?'.
    That's really all I did. Everything's [
    <i>sic</i>] got so repetitive, everything sounds the same. I
    had to create something unique otherwise there's no point
    putting it out."</p>
      <p>"SexyBack" is an "urgent, pulsing track, a cocktail of
    soaring, distorted vocals and heavy, electronic chords threaded
    together with rap", according to Camilla Long from 
    <i>The Observer</i>. The song is composed in the key of C major
    and is set in time signature of common time with a tempo of 116
    beats per minute. The song features an unabashed 4/4 beat, a
    pounding bass beat and electronic sounds, and does not include
    Timberlake's "famous falsetto". The song's musicscape includes
    two-note dirty electronic riffs, "leapfrogging keyboards", beat
    box sound, and incorporates the "same leaky faucet" sounds of
    musician Obie Trice's 2004 song "The Setup". In addition, the
    track features Timbaland on backing vocals.</p>
      <p>Timberlake's voice in the song is processed, slowed down to
    where his voice is unrecognizable, with muffled vocals. The
    song also features Timberlake's "low register distorted
    vocals." Timberlake revealed that the vocals in the song were
    influenced by Prince. In further discussion of the song,
    Timberlake said that the chorus was "very James Brown-ish, call
    out and repeat, like 'Sex Machine'." He wrote the track "from
    top to bottom. 'I'm bringing sexy back, yeah! I'm bringing. .
    .' It's a very physical song, meant to provoke ... sexual
    dance. 'Sex Machine' is the closest reference." Timberlake said
    that the lyric, "bringing sexy back", was one of the first
    lines he came up with. In addition, he admitted that the song
    was not going to be titled "SexyBack", saying, "We weren't
    originally going to call it 'SexyBack'. I definitely didn't
    think it would become the most worn-out phrase of 2006. It just
    sounded like a nice opening to the song."</p>
      <p>Adam Graham of 
    <i>The Detroit News</i>noted that Timberlake sings about whips
    and chains, while Bill Lamb of About.com said the song has a
    "bit of s&amp;m tease about shackles and whips". Furthermore, 
    <i>The Georgia Straight</i>'s Martin Turenne said that
    Timberlake is "shackled to the bedpost, invites the crack of
    his mistress's whip." Ben Williams of 
    <i>New York</i>magazine wrote that Timberlake had been working
    on his pickup lines, with "You see these shackles baby I'm your
    slave / I'll let you whip me if I misbehave." Jason Bracelin of
    the 
    <i>Las Vegas Review-Journal</i>reported that Timberlake sings
    about "threatening to steal your girl." Charlie Brooker for 
    <i>The Guardian</i>, in regards to the lyric, "them other
    fuckers don't know how to act", wrote that Timberlake's
    translation is of him telling everyone in the world that they
    are a "clueless fornicator". Further in his report, Brooker
    opined that Timberlake "threatens us" by using "language so
    offensive" with the line, "You motherfuckers, watch how I
    attack". In addition, Brooker noted that the line, "If that's
    your girl you'd better watch your back", as Timberlake stating
    his intention to meddle in the private affairs of others. Barry
    Schwartz of 
    <i>Stylus</i>noted that the song features "pillow talk", in
    reference of the song's "sex-crazed lyrics".</p>
      <p>In the 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine review of the album, contributor Katy
    Kroll wrote that Timberlake "claims to be bringing 'sexy' back
    to pop music, and indeed he is. You can almost feel beads of
    sweat rolling off the title track and 'SexyBack' featuring
    Timbaland". Chris Willman of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>was complimentary towards Timbaland,
    producer of the song, writing that Timbaland offers "tougher,
    trickier rhythms, minimal live playing, a plethora of hip-hop
    cameos, and a self-consciously hard, edgy club sensibility" to
    "SexyBack". Russell Baillie of 
    <i>The New Zealand Herald</i>noted, "The producer's angular
    synthesizer crunch is all over it – at best on the single
    'SexyBack' where they dispense with a chorus, leaving the song
    sustained by its vocal fireworks, electrofunk and Timberland's
    repeated declaration that 'I'm bringing sexy back.
    <span style="padding-right:.2em;">'</span>" PopMatters'
    contributor Quentin B. Huff wrote that "SexyBack" was the
    "fraternal twin" to Nelly Furtado's 2006 song "Promiscuous".
    Andrew Murfett of 
    <i>The Age</i>wrote that the song was a "raunchy club banger
    that slyly suppresses" Timberlake's customary falsetto. He
    continues, "it's introduced a new phrase into the pop cultural
    lexicon". Glenn Gamboa of 
    <i>Newsday</i>was complimentary towards the song, writing that
    it was "Timberlake at his best, mainstreaming a combination of
    the wild, edgy dance-pop style of Basement Jaxx with Missy
    Elliott's more experimental hip-hop to create a boldly
    inventive sound that still pleases the masses."</p>
      <p>Kelefa Sanneh of 
    <i>The New York Times</i>wrote: "...'SexyBack', a twitchy,
    emaciated track that shot to the top of the charts and also
    became an irritating catchphrase. (Suddenly everyone was
    bringing AdjectiveBack.)" Dagny Salas of 
    <i>North by Northwestern</i>commented that Timberlake and
    Timbaland trade ridiculous lines, with "Get your sexy on/Go
    ahead, be gone with it" and "Dirty babe/You see these
    shackles/Baby I’m your slave/I’ll let you whip me if I
    misbehave." Salas continued in her review that it was not a
    song that should be good, "but does that really matter when
    it’s Good in the way that songs are during the summer [...]
    That kind of good makes songs like 'SexyBack' completely
    irresistible." Matt Burns of 
    <i>The Post</i>wrote, "Take the polarizing summer single
    'SexyBack', a repetitive song with little structure that
    doesn't know when to stop, all centered on a ridiculous
    declaration. Somehow, it works." 
    <i>The Diamondback</i>'s Michael Greenwald reported that
    "SexyBack" was "lyrically, musically and vocally the weakest
    song" on the album. A writer of 
    <i>The State Journal-Register</i>was not impressed with the
    song and concluded, with 
    <span style="padding-right:.2em;">"</span>'SexyBack' is the
    most annoyingly dumb song to hit 
    <i>Billboard</i>'s No. 1 since 'Hollaback Girl'". Guy Blackman
    of 
    <i>The Sunday Age</i>wrote: "The distorted vocals and stilted
    production of first single 'Sexyback' make Timberlake's claim
    to be 'bringing sexy back' ... seem almost laughable." 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>put it on its end-of-the-decade,
    "best-of" list, saying, "Justin Timberlake We didn't even know
    that sexy was missing until 2006. We're just happy Justin
    brought it back safe and sound."</p>
      <p>Upon the song's release, it received divided opinions, which
    pleased Timberlake. "This is such a departure from the first
    record," said Timberlake. "More people might like it, less
    people might like it, but you can't call me a chicken."
    Timberlake performed "SexyBack" and "My Love" as a medley for
    the opening of the 2006 MTV Video Music Awards. In addition, he
    performed the song at the Victoria's Secret Fashion Show. The
    song won the People's Choice Award for Favorite R&amp;B song at
    the 2007 awards ceremony. At the 49th Grammy Awards, "SexyBack"
    won a Grammy Award in the category of Best Dance Recording. At
    the 2007 MTV Video Music Awards, Timberlake won Male Artist of
    the Year for "SexyBack", "Let Me Talk To You / My Love", and
    "What Goes Around.../...Comes Around".</p>
      <p>"SexyBack" was commercially successful in the United States.
    The single debuted at number 90 in July 2006, on the Hot 100.
    From number 31, it propelled to number one the following week.
    "SexyBack" became Timberlake's first consecutive number one hit
    on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 from his 
    <i>Futuresex/Lovesounds</i>album. The single spent seven
    consecutive weeks at the number one position on the Hot 100. In
    addition to the Hot 100, "SexyBack" also topped the following 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts: Hot Dance Airplay, Hot Dance Club Play,
    Hot Dance Singles Sales, Pop 100 Airplay, Pop 100, and Top 40
    Mainstream mainstream charts. "SexyBack" was certified
    three-times Platinum by the Recording Industry Association of
    America (RIAA). This song made the then-seventh-biggest jump to
    number one in the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 history, climbing thirty spots from
    number 31 landing it at the summit of the chart on September 9,
    2006. In a Nielsen SoundScan report, the song sold 250,000 as a
    digital download.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom, "SexyBack" debuted at number 13 on
    the UK Singles Chart based solely on download sales one week
    prior to its physical release, and ascended to the top of the
    chart the following week, becoming Timberlake's first UK number
    one single. On the Australian ARIA Charts, "SexyBack" debuted
    at number one and spent two consecutive weeks at the top
    becoming Timberlake's second number one single there (after
    "Rock Your Body" reached the summit in 2003), and has been
    certified two-times Platinum by ARIA Charts. Also, in Canada
    and Austria, the single has peaked at number three and number
    five respectively, becoming his most successful single tied
    with his third released single "What Goes Around.../...Comes
    Around" in both nations. It has also been certified six-times
    Platinum in Canada.</p>
      <p>In Sweden, "SexyBack" peaked at number four, while in France
    it peaked at number eight becoming Timberlake's first top ten
    hit from the album, and would later score two more top ten
    singles with "My Love" and "What Goes Around.../...Comes
    Around". The song has also peaked at number one in Germany,
    Ireland, New Zealand and Norway, and has peaked at number two
    in Switzerland and Belgium.</p>
      <p>The music video for "SexyBack" was directed by Michael
    Haussman and features Spanish actress Elena Anaya. The video
    was filmed in June 2006 and shot in a luxury building in
    Barcelona, Spain. In discussion of the video filmed in
    Barcelona, Timberlake said: "Obviously we went for the
    architecture, the exteriors, the interiors — the vibe in Spain
    is different than anywhere else in the world. It's so cool to
    shoot there, but the girls are also pretty hot, so that doesn't
    hurt either."</p>
      <p>Timberlake decided to work with director Michael Haussman,
    following his work on Madonna's 1994 music video for "Take a
    Bow". "It's one of my favorite videos Madonna's ever done,"
    Timberlake said. "Even today, I still remember the visuals, the
    images, how he captured her. A lot of times, Madonna seems like
    she's the person in control, and in that video, she seemed
    vulnerable. It was a cool thing to see." The video was first
    shown on MTV's 
    <i>Making the Video</i>on July 25, 2006.</p>
      <p>The video starts off with a cable car looking over a large
    city (Barcelona, from the West looking East) and switches to a
    luxurious-looking hotel in Plaça de Catalunya with Elena Anaya
    taking off her sweater. It then cuts to Timberlake in a
    different room; then to a club scene and Timberlake in front of
    a white background. The video alternates between those four
    viewpoints, with Timberlake and Anaya seeming to be spies in
    the hotel room and strangers in the club. At a certain point,
    Timberlake goes over to Anaya's room by jumping over to her
    balcony. Then when Anaya goes to check it out, Timberlake traps
    her and they have sex. In the club, it ends with Timberlake
    cornering Anaya in a bathroom stall. In the hotel room scene,
    Timberlake leaves by the same way he entered and moments later
    jumps back to the balcony before an explosion ensues. It ends
    with the figure of Anaya sitting in a chair beside a small
    television in which a kiss is frozen on the screen.</p>
      <p>The indie rock band Rock Plaza Central, favored by Pitchfork
    Media, gained attention for their radically different cover of
    "SexyBack", with brass-and-banjo roots-rock stylings. It was
    released as a promotional single and a bonus track on the
    Wal-Mart version of the 2007 cover album 
    <i>Poison'd!</i>by American rock band Poison. British soul
    singer Corinne Bailey Rae recorded a jazz/swing version whilst
    appearing on BBC Radio 1's Live Lounge in 2007.</p>
      <p>UK CD1</p>
      <p>UK CD1</p>
      <p>CD Single</p>
      <p>CD - Dance Mixes</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
