<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Love_(Justin_Timberlake_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Love_(Justin_Timberlake_song)</songId>
   <title>My Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/T.I.</artistId>
      <artistName>Justin Timberlake featuring T.I.</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2006-11-11</week>
      <week>2006-11-18</week>
      <week>2006-11-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/92/My_Love_-_Single_low.jpg/200px-My_Love_-_Single_low.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Justin-Timberlake-featuring-T-I+My-Love.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>FutureSex/LoveSounds</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 12, 2006  (2006-09-12) , (See release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>6:10 (Album version)</length>
      <length>4:36 (Main version/without prelude)</length>
      <length>3:54 (No-rap version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Jive</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Justin Timberlake</writer>
      <writer>Timbaland</writer>
      <writer>Nate "Danja" Hills</writer>
      <writer>T.I.</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Timbaland</producer>
      <producer>Timberlake</producer>
      <producer>Danja</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"My Love" is a song by American singer–songwriter Justin
    Timberlake from his second studio album, 
    <i>FutureSex/LoveSounds</i>(2006). It was released on September
    12, 2006, by Jive Records as the second single from the album.
    The song was co-written by Timberlake, Timbaland, Nate "Danja"
    Hills, and T.I., and produced by Timberlake, Timbaland, and
    Danja.</p>
      <p>Timberlake revealed that the song's creating process took
    time to image and execute. He also stated that "My Love" was
    less about marriage and a more humble approach to love. The
    song features synthesizer chords with a slow beat and includes
    a beatboxing, percussion, and staccato sounds. The single
    features a rap verse from rapper T.I. Timberlake described the
    track as "a rock-techno ballad". "My Love" was well-received by
    music critics, although some criticized Timberlake for some of
    the lyrics and sounds.</p>
      <p>The track entered the top ten on most charts, topping
    several of 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine's component charts, including the Hot
    100, Pop 100, 
    <i>Hot Dance Airplay</i>, and Hot Digital Songs charts. "My
    Love" also became Timberlake's second consecutive number one
    single on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100. Internationally, the single peaked in
    the number two position, becoming Timberlake's fourth single to
    reach number two. In New Zealand, the track peaked at number
    one for five non-consecutive weeks, to become Timberlake's
    second number one single.</p>
      <p>Pitchfork Media named "My Love" as their number one song of
    2006. Many have cited that the song is similar to Timberlake's
    2002 song "Cry Me a River". The track won Best Rap/Sung
    Collaboration at the 2007 Grammy Awards. "My Love" also won
    Timberlake the Male Artist of the Year and Best Choreography in
    a Video at the 2007 MTV Video Music Awards.</p>
      <p>In December 2005, Justin Timberlake began working on his
    second album, 
    <i>FutureSex/LoveSounds</i>, the follow-up to 
    <i>Justified</i>(2002). Within three weeks, "My Love" was one
    of several songs that were recorded. In September 2006,
    Timberlake told 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>that the song was "a rock-techno ballad"
    and that the process of creating "took two hours to imagine and
    execute". While promoting the album in an interview with MTV
    News, Timberlake revealed that the second half of the album
    (including "My Love") focuses on anthems of love. In another
    interview, he revealed that "My Love" was a "contradiction of
    sounds. You've got this operatic thing going on. If you take
    all the staccato sounds out, the essence of the song is it's a
    ballad, but the way the beat is inlaid underneath the vocals,
    it becomes a percussive ballad."</p>
      <p>In discussion of T.I.'s participation in the track,
    Timberlake said: "The second hook finished and I said, 'Oh, a
    rapper would sound good on this'." Timbaland, who co-wrote and
    produced the song, agreed to the idea and suggested T.I.
    Timberlake agreed to the idea, although he doubted that T.I.
    would say yes, and said that he was thankful that T.I. agreed
    to take part.</p>
      <p>"My Love" is a hip hop R&amp;B song. The song is composed in
    the key of E minor and is set in time signature of common time
    with a tempo of 121 beats per minute. The music begins with a
    stop-start trance-style synthesizer. The song also includes
    Timbaland beatboxing and adding "toy sounds", as well as
    Timberlake's falsetto. The track features a rap verse from
    rapper T.I. It also carries a slower beat, with an
    electro-Southern hip hop sound. 
    <i>The Guardian</i>described the song as a "languid love
    ballad, prickling with dark emotion", while MTV News described
    the beat as "slow and saucy". Ben Williams of 
    <i>New York</i>magazine wrote that it has "stabbing techno
    riff, crunched-together mouth-popping noises, and wailing opera
    singer". Alexis Petridis of 
    <i>The Guardian</i>said that the single is "a twitching mass of
    rave synthesizers and [agonizingly] slow beats". Jacqui Swift
    of 
    <i>The Sun</i>wrote that the song "begins with a tinny
    percussion sound before launching into a frantic repetitive
    chorus".</p>
      <p>In July 2006, 
    <i>The Observer Music Monthly</i>interviewed Timberlake and
    stated that the track "is arguably the album's 'Cry Me a
    River'." In response, Timberlake said, "It is similar. You go
    back to Aaliyah's biggest record, 'Are You That Somebody' –
    it's similar to that too because it's that percussive ballad."
    When asked about the lyrics, "There's just one thing I need
    from you: say I do", being autobiographical, he said no, adding
    that the line before that, "this ring here represents my
    heart", is about marriage and love. Timberlake stated, "It's
    not specifically about marriage, but about a humble approach to
    love. None of it is autobiographical, though obviously I have
    experience to draw from."</p>
      <p>Williams stated that the song is "an obvious sequel" to
    Timberlake's 2002 song "Cry Me a River". 
    <i>The Georgia Straight</i>'s Martin Turenne interprets the
    song's background as Timberlake lowering himself on bended
    knee, proposing long walks on the beach and asking, "Would you
    date me on the regular?". Dagny Salas of 
    <i>North by Northwestern</i>considered it a more romantic song,
    about Timberlake professing his love to a woman. Others have
    opined that "My Love" is a marriage proposal.</p>
      <p>In 
    <i>The New York Times</i>review of the album, critic Kelefa
    Sanneh wrote: "...'My Love', a sumptuous collaboration with the
    rapper T.I. It starts with a 90-second 'prelude', a clattering
    rhythm track with a bit of rapping and snippets of melody. Then
    the real thing hits: sleek synthesizer chords punctuated by
    tiny bursts of silence." Sal Cinquemani of Slant Magazine wrote
    that the track "mixes Timberlake's proud beatboxing talent with
    colossal, futuristic synth swirls and a cartoonish, maniacal
    giggle that's looped ad infinitum a la the crying baby from
    Aaliyah's 'Are You That Somebody?'". Matthew Gasteier of 
    <i>Prefix</i>magazine noted that the song "is probably the
    standout triumph here, with stuttering synths and a
    fade-in-fade-out shimmering beat that may be the best ever from
    Timbaland". Lauren Murphy of entertainment.ie stated that the
    single is "undeniably fluid and features some of the niftiest
    slo-mo effects around". Jonah Weiner of 
    <i>Blender</i>magazine cited the song as the "standout" song
    from the album and wrote that the single "...straddles the
    album's up-tempo 
    <i>FutureSex</i>and balladeering 
    <i>LoveSounds</i>halves — one coos about puppy love over the
    other's stroboscopic, salivating beat, and both trade
    devotionals on the chorus".</p>
      <p>"My Love" was criticized for some of the lyrics and sounds
    that were featured. Sanneh reported that Timberlake "exhales
    his clumsy pickup lines" with the lyrics "If I told you you
    were beautiful / Would you date me on the regular?". Murphy
    contemplated that the song is "ultimately ruined" by a "bizarre
    Crazy Frog-meets-Laughing-Policeman underlay". Emily Vaughan of
    
    <i>North by Northwestern</i>commented that Timberlake claims to
    have gone around the world twice in "My Love" and "Damn Girl"
    and that he is also "running out of creative ways to say he
    would like you to go to bed with him". Vaughan, however, was
    positive towards "My Love", stating that the song, along with
    "What Goes Around.../...Comes Around", sounded considerably
    different from the rest of the album.</p>
      <p>The song was picked by Pitchfork Media as their number one
    song of 2006. Timberlake performed "My Love" and "SexyBack" as
    a medley for the opening of the 2006 MTV Video Music Awards,
    and again for the MTV Europe Music Awards 2006, which he also
    hosted. He also performed the song on 
    <i>Saturday Night Live</i>(
    <i>SNL</i>). Timberlake, alongside Robyn Troup and T.I.,
    performed the song live at the 49th Grammy Awards. At the
    awards ceremony, "My Love" won a Grammy Award in the category
    of Best Rap/Sung Collaboration. The song was covered by Irish
    band The Coronas, and by British group Klaxons on BBC Radio 1's
    
    <i>Live Lounge</i>and was included in the B-side of their song
    "It's Not Over Yet", which was released in June 2007.</p>
      <p>"My Love" was commercially successful in the United States.
    The single debuted at number 89 on September 23, 2006, on the
    Hot 100, prior to its physical release. From number five on
    November 11, 2006, it propelled to number one the following
    week. "My Love" became Timberlake's second consecutive number
    one hit on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 from his 
    <i>Futuresex/Lovesounds</i>album, becoming the first male
    artist since Usher in 2004 to have three or more consecutive
    number one hits from one album. The single charted on the Hot
    100 for three weeks. In addition to the Hot 100, "My Love" also
    reached number one on the following 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts: Pop 100, 
    <i>Hot Dance Airplay</i>and Top 40 mainstream charts, and has
    peaked at number three on the Rhythmic Top 40. Also, on the Hot
    R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs, "My Love" peaked at number two to become
    Timberlake's most successful single on this chart. The song
    also charted on the Hot Dance Club Play and Hot Adult Top 40
    Tracks charts, peaking at number 15 and number 29,
    respectively.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom, "My Love" debuted at number 14 on the
    UK Singles Chart on November 18, 2006, one week prior to its
    physical release, and ascended to its peak the following week
    at number two, to become Timberlake's fourth single to reach
    number two. The digital download sales helped propel the single
    to number two on November 20, 2006. The song spent nineteen
    weeks within the top 75, retiring on March 24, 2007, spending
    four of those within the top ten. The single entered the top
    five in Germany, Switzerland, Sweden, and Finland, and entered
    the top ten in France and Austria. In Australia, "My Love"
    debuted and peaked at number four on the Australian ARIA
    singles chart on November 26, 2006, gaining the Highest Debut
    certification. It spent a total of twenty-four weeks on the
    chart. "My Love" was certified Gold by Australian Recording
    Industry Association (ARIA). In New Zealand, the single debuted
    at number 25 and eventually peaked at number one for five
    non-consecutive weeks, to become Timberlake's second number one
    single.</p>
      <p>The music video for "My Love" was directed by Paul Hunter
    and premiered on October 12, 2006. The video includes the
    prelude to the song ("Let Me Talk to You"), which includes the
    song's producer, Timbaland and features T.I. The video
    incorporates a black-and-white background and dancing,
    choreographed as the steps are in synch with the beat of the
    song.</p>
      <p>The video starts with "Let Me Talk to You" as the background
    is surrounded by faulty fluorescent lighting, turning on and
    off in a programmed pattern. It also begins with Timberlake and
    Timbaland chanting "hey" to one another. The video proceeds
    with Timberlake dancing to the beat of the song. Timbaland then
    begins singing the first verse of the song, which then is
    proceeded by Timberlake. This is immediately followed with "My
    Love" playing; the first verse of the song, "Ain't another
    woman that could take your spot my", plays. Timberlake comes
    floating toward the camera, down the faulty fluorescent tube.
    Once Timberlake stops floating, he begins singing the main
    verse of the song, which violins begin to float swirling gently
    around him, for "If I wrote you a symphony / Just to say how
    much you mean to me". The scene then changes with Timberlake
    and various dancers dancing accordingly in a choreographed
    style. When Timberlake begins the second verse, "Now if I wrote
    you a love note / And made you sign up every word I wrote",
    pens and paper begin to float. This later exceeds with
    Timberlake singing "This ring here represents my heart" with a
    ring swirling into the camera. T.I. is then seen in the shot.
    T.I. begins rapping his lines in the song. After T.I. finishes
    his verse, Timberlake is then seen dancing with a female
    back-up dancer. Though, as they continue dancing, the female
    then leaves the shot, leaving Timberlake to dance to the end of
    the song. In the closing moments, the camera swirls around him,
    proving, conclusively, from every angle, that everyone has
    gone.</p>
      <p>At the 2007 MTV Video Music Awards, Timberlake won Male
    Artist of the Year for "Let Me Talk To You/ My Love",
    "SexyBack", and "What Goes Around.../...Comes Around". He,
    alongside choreographer Marty Kudelka, won Best Choreography in
    a Video for "My Love".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
