<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stronger_(Kanye_West_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stronger_(Kanye_West_song)</songId>
   <title>Stronger</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanye_West</artistId>
      <artistName>Kanye West</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2007-09-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/d7/KW-Stronger.jpg/200px-KW-Stronger.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Kanye-West+Stronger.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Graduation</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 31, 2007  (2007-07-31)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2006  (2006)</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
      <genre>Electro Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:12 (album version)</length>
      <length>4:08 (radio edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Roc-A-Fella , Island Def Jam</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Kanye West</writer>
      <writer>Thomas Bangalter</writer>
      <writer>Guy-Manuel de Homem-Christo</writer>
      <writer>Edwin Birdsong</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Kanye West (additional drum programming by Timbaland</producer>
      <producer>extended outro co-produced by Mike Dean )</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Stronger" is a song by American hip hop artist Kanye West,
    released as the second single from his third studio album 
    <i>Graduation</i>. It was produced by West and contains an
    extended outro co-produced with Mike Dean. The song contains a
    sample of "Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger" by French house
    duo Daft Punk, who received songwriting credit and had their
    costumes appear in its accompanying music video. The single was
    first released digitally on July 31, 2007 and soon became
    West's third number-one single. It won a Grammy Award for Best
    Rap Solo Performance at the 50th Grammy Awards.</p>
      <p>A portion of "Stronger" was first released in May 2007 on
    West's 
    <i>Can't Tell Me Nothing</i>mixtape. Shortly afterwards, on May
    31, 2007, Brendon Joshua played the full-length song on his
    podcast. On June 27, 2007, "Stronger" was put onto the BBC
    Radio 1 Up-Front playlist and was later upgraded to the A-List
    a month prior to its release. The single's cover art was
    released on West's website on June 28, 2007. It was designed by
    Japanese artist Takashi Murakami, who West collaborated with to
    produce the artwork for 
    <i>Graduation</i>. The cover features a cartoon version of
    West's mascot "Dropout Bear" wearing sunglasses similar to the
    those West wears in the music video, as well as the small,
    robotic heads of Thomas Bangalter and Guy-Manuel de
    Homem-Christo of Daft Punk. West performed a partial version of
    "Stronger" live at the Concert for Diana held at Wembley
    Stadium on July 1, 2007 to a crowd of 63,000 people. An
    estimated 500 million people watched the event in over 140
    countries worldwide.</p>
      <p>The single was released to iTunes on July 31, 2007. It
    debuted on the Hot 100 at number forty-seven and eventually
    peaked at the number-one position, the same week his album 
    <i>Graduation</i>took the number one spot. It is West's third
    number-one single in the United States, following "Slow Jamz"
    and "Gold Digger." After becoming West's first number one
    single in the UK, "Stronger" went on to be met by widespread
    international success, reaching number-one in Canada, Turkey,
    and New Zealand. The song was also met by critical recognition
    and was the recipient of multiple awards, including a Grammy
    Award for Best Rap Solo Performance. Daft Punk themselves made
    a surprise appearance at the 50th Grammy Awards on February 10,
    2008 to join West in performing a reworked version of the song
    on stage at the Staples Center in Los Angeles. A press release
    specified that this was the very first televised live
    performance by Daft Punk in their career.</p>
      <p>"Stronger" is an electronica-infused hip-hop song composed
    in the key of E-flat minor. It is written in common time and
    moves at 104 beats per minute. The song is built around vocal
    sample of the 2001 house song "Harder, Better, Faster,
    Stronger" by Daft Punk. Following the introduction, where a
    chopped sample of Daft Punk's robotic vocals expressing a
    decreased tempo is played continuously in the background, West
    raps the refrain, which expresses Friedrich Nietzsche's famous
    dictum, "What does not kill him, makes him stronger", as well
    as the hook twice and enter the first verse. He repeats this
    process three more times, making slight alterations to the
    chorus each time. He injects a "me likely" ad-lib after the
    hook in the second, repeats a line within the verse six times
    on the third, and recites the hook four times on the fourth. It
    is also within the fourth that the song breaks down and enters
    an extended outro passage where the vocal sample is repeatedly
    played over a layered, complex patchwork of synth-beats and
    grooves before finally bring itself to a close.</p>
      <p>West collaborated with Timbaland to rework the drum
    programming and percussion for the final version of the song,
    which appears on the 
    <i>Graduation</i>album. This version contains a master use of
    Edwin Birdsong's "Cola Bottle Baby," the song that had been
    previously sampled by Daft Punk themselves to produce "Harder,
    Better, Faster, Stronger". The pre-album version of "Stronger",
    known to the public and being used by radio, television and
    other outlets, was the version used as the single. On October
    4, 2007, a previously unreleased version of "Stronger" was
    revealed. This version retains a singular, unused verse from
    West, while the structure features less synthesizer chords and
    percussion. It is believed that this version was an early draft
    of the final song.</p>
      <p>On July 3, 2007, West told Zane Lowe on BBC Radio 1 that
    although he believes "Stronger" is a great song, it does not
    compare to the sampled original. Daft Punk were delighted upon
    first hearing the new song on Power 106 while on a San
    Francisco flight. As Guy-Manuel de Homem-Christo of the duo
    stated, "Our song had a good sound, but when [the radio DJ] put
    Kanye's record on, the sound was really fat. It sounds really
    big." The use of "Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger" was
    requested through Pedro Winter, Daft Punk's manager at the
    time, and approved by the duo. De Homem-Christo also clarified
    that "It's not a collaboration in the studio, but the vibe of
    the music we do separately connected in what [West] did with
    the song." In a later interview, de Homem-Christo specified
    that the live performance of "Stronger" at the 50th Grammy
    Awards was "truly a collaboration from the start. We really did
    it all hand in hand."</p>
      <p>The song was also named the number one record of 2007 in the
    January 2008 issue of 
    <i>Spin</i>magazine with Kanye West and Daft Punk presiding on
    the cover. This song was number 11 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s list of the 100 Best Songs of 2007. This
    song was also number 96 on 
    <i>MTV Asia</i>'s list of Top 100 Hits of 2007.</p>
      <p>"Stronger" entered the Hot 100 on the charting week of
    August 11, 2007 at number forty-seven, the highest debut single
    on the chart that week. Over the next eight weeks, the song
    steadily climbed upwards, reaching the number one position on
    the charting week of September 29, 2007, pushing the previous
    week's chart topper, Soulja Boy Tell 'Em's "Crank That (Soulja
    Boy)" into the number two position. However, the following
    week, "Crank That (Soulja Boy)" replaced "Stronger" atop the
    charts, making West's single reach its peak for only one week.
    The song debuted on the UK Singles Chart at number three and
    rose to become West's very first number one single in the
    United Kingdom. Climbing on downloads alone, it surpassed the
    prior week's number one single, Robyn's "With Every Heartbeat".
    It has also topped the Canadian Hot 100, New Zealand, and the
    Turkish Singles charts. The song ended 2007 as the 19th
    biggest-selling single in the UK of that year.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Stronger" was directed by Hype Williams
    and shot over nine days in Japan. It include shots filmed in
    Aoyama-based clothing store A Bathing Ape as well as Harajuku
    clothing store Billionaire Boys Club/Ice Cream. The video took
    over three months to complete. West first premiered a rough cut
    at the Tribeca Studios in New York City on June 19, 2007. It
    made its public premiere on June 26, 2007, on MTV Germany's 
    <i>TRL</i>. The video was also shown on the BET countdown show 
    <i>106 &amp; Park</i>on June 28, 2007.</p>
      <p>The video features appearances by singer and model Cassie
    Ventura, a real-life Japanese motorcycle gang, and the two
    principal actors from the film 
    <i>Daft Punk's Electroma</i>dressed as Daft Punk. The video
    also features multiple scenes which pay homage to the 1988
    anime film 
    <i>Akira</i>. These include the light effects on the
    motorbikes, the hospital scenes and West being scanned by
    machines. Both West and Williams had originally planned to
    integrate scenes from the film into the video. West also wears
    a pair of Alain Mikli sunglasses, which he requested from the
    designer specifically for the video. The sunglasses have since
    become a signature of West, who for a period of time often
    donned them during performances. The video was nominated two
    2007 MTV Video Music Awards for Video of the Year and Best
    Editing in a Video. It won Best Hip-Hop Video at the BET
    Hip-Hop Awards as well as Best Video at the MOBO Awards.</p>
      <p>The JabbaWockeeZ performed to this song in the finale of
    America's Best Dance Crew (season 1) as their victory
    performance for being crowned champions. 30 Seconds to Mars
    performed a cover version of "Stronger" on BBC Radio 1, which
    is featured on 
    <i>Radio 1's Live Lounge – Volume 2</i>and a UK release of the
    single "From Yesterday". The cover features a slower tempo on
    guitar and omits the profanity, which was reworded by their
    lead singer Jared Leto. Leto said that he "hoped that Kanye
    [was] okay" with the editing. The song can be heard for the
    promo of the 2007 film 
    <i>The Kingdom</i>. It can also be heard as the introductory
    song of the Baltimore Orioles, Toronto Raptors, New York Mets,
    Texas Longhorns, Washington Wizards, Cincinnati Reds and Tampa
    Bay Rays. Also, the New York Giants entered the field to this
    song at Super Bowl XLII and during most of their home games
    during the season. The New York Rangers play it at every home
    game as well. The song won the Grammy Award for Best Rap Solo
    Performance for the 50th Grammy Awards. It is also Featured in
    Season 4 Ep 4 of Entourage as background music in a night club.
    The A-Trak remix of the song is used in an advert for the
    short-lived American TV show 
    <i>Bionic Woman</i>. This song is also used by Animal Planet to
    promote their new show 
    <i>Jockeys</i>, appearing in commercials as well as being the
    series' opening theme.</p>
      <p>CD single (International)</p>
      <p>Promo 12" single</p>
      <p>CD single (UK)</p>
      <p>12" picture disc (UK)</p>
      <p>iTunes Remixes single</p>
      <p>Information taken from 
    <i>Graduation</i>liner notes.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
