<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Kissed_a_Girl 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Kissed_a_Girl</songId>
   <title>I Kissed a Girl</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Katy_Perry</artistId>
      <artistName>Katy Perry</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2008-07-05</week>
      <week>2008-07-12</week>
      <week>2008-07-19</week>
      <week>2008-07-26</week>
      <week>2008-08-02</week>
      <week>2008-08-09</week>
      <week>2008-08-16</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/5c/I_Kissed_a_Girl.png/200px-I_Kissed_a_Girl.png</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Katy-Perry+I-Kissed-a-Girl.png</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>One of the Boys</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 6, 2008</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2007–2008</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop/Rock</genre>
      <genre>Electropop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:01</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Katy Perry</writer>
      <writer>Dr. Luke</writer>
      <writer>Max Martin</writer>
      <writer>Cathy Dennis</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Dr. Luke</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Kissed a Girl" is a song by pop singer Katy Perry,
    written by Perry, Dr Luke, Max Martin and Cathy Dennis (not to
    be confused with the earlier song with the same title by Jill
    Sobule). It was produced by Dr. Luke for Perry's 2008 album 
    <i>One of the Boys</i>. Perry says the song is "about the
    magical beauty of a woman".</p>
      <p>Released as the album's lead single, "I Kissed a Girl" was a
    commercial success. It topped the Hot 100 chart, becoming the
    1000th chart-topper of the Rock Era. The song has since become
    a major worldwide hit, and along with the United States, it has
    topped the charts in more than 30 countries, including
    Australia, Canada, Ireland and the United Kingdom.</p>
      <p>"I Kissed a Girl" was performed and a nominee at the 51st
    Grammy Awards (Grammy Award for Best Female Pop Vocal
    Performance). It was also nominated for Favorite Song at the
    2009 Kids' Choice Awards.</p>
      <p>Perry has stated that "I Kissed A Girl is just a way for me
    to seem edgy and cool, I think it's worked." She says:</p>
      <p>"Everyone takes the song and relates it to their situation,
    they can see it however they want to see it. Love it, hate it,
    for me it was about us girls. When we're young, we're very
    touchy-feeley. We have slumber party sing-a-longs, we make up
    dance routines in our pajamas. We’re a lot more intimate in a
    friendship than guys can be. It’s not perverse but just sweet,
    that's what the song is about..."</p>
      <p>The song was partially inspired by Scarlett Johansson.</p>
      <p>Perry has also stated that the song was inspired by a
    particular person,</p>
      <p>"The song was inspired by a friendship I had with a girl
    when I was 15, but I didn't kiss her. I was totally obsessed
    with her. She was beautiful – porcelain skin, perfect lips –
    and I still talk to her, but I've never told her the song is
    about her."</p>
      <p>A music video for the song was released on May 16, 2008 on
    Perry's personal website and on MySpace. The video was directed
    by Kinga Burza and features a Moulin Rouge and burlesque-type
    setting with scenes of Perry, along with many other
    flamboyantly-dressed women dancing to the song. Towards the end
    of the video, she wakes up next to a male companion called
    Derek (DJ Skeet Skeet). Despite the song's title, there is no
    depiction of same-sex kissing. Katy features her real life
    friend and DJ, Mia Moretti and her main guy, Markus Molinari's
    cat Bella and the singer Ke$ha in the music video.</p>
      <p>The video made its television debut on June 12 on TRL with
    the visit and interview by Perry in set show. On June 24, 2008
    it became #1 on TRL. The video obtained high airplay on this
    music video channel, as well as on VH1. It debuted at #20 on
    VH1's VH1 Top 20 Video Countdown on June 28, 2008. On June 30,
    2008 the video was premiered on MTV Latin America. On July 6,
    2008, it rose to #4 on VH1's VH1 Top 20 Video Countdown. The
    video received five nominations for the 2008 MTV Video Music
    Awards, including Best Female Video and Best New Artist. The
    video has had over 24 million views on YouTube. Due to the
    video and the song's popularity around the world, there are
    videos on YouTube which imitate and parody the song.</p>
      <p>"I Kissed a Girl" has drawn mixed reviews from critics.
    Blogcritics Magazine called it "an instantly catchy number",
    and About.com said, "fueled by an instrumental wallop provided
    courtesy of producer Dr. Luke, 'I Kissed a Girl' is the perfect
    breakthrough". However, 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine, while giving her album 2/5 stars,
    described the song as a "New Wave-y club single", saying the
    supposedly rebellious "attention-grabbing" lyrics are "a
    vanilla recounting of her chick-on-chick exploits" and that
    this "acting out" is "just to get a dude's attention". This
    song was number 20 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s list of the 100 Best Songs of 2008.
    Allmusic praises "the stomping Gary Glitter beat" before
    criticizing the producers for turning it "into a leaden stumble
    and burying Perry's voice underneath Pro Tools overdubs so it
    all winds up as a faceless wash of sound designed to be placed
    in TV shows, movie trailers, and malls".</p>
      <p>Sal Cinquemani of 
    <i>Slant</i>magazine wrote, Perry's "lead single "I Kissed a
    Girl" features a throbbing beat and an infectious, bi-curious
    hook, but its self-satisfied, in-your-face posturing rings
    phony in comparison to the expertly constructed ambiguities of
    "Justify My Love" or practically anything in the first decade
    of Ani DiFranco's catalog; it's like a tween version of
    DiFranco's tortured bisexual confession "Light of Some Kind"". 
    <i>Hiponline.com</i>wrote that the song is "not nearly as
    interesting or exciting as you’d expect. It’s not even half as
    good as Jill Sobule’s song 'I Kissed a Girl'". 
    <i>Glitterati Gossip</i>agrees Sobule's song "was ten times
    better, because there was actual emotional content to her
    lyrics".</p>
      <p>Sobule shared her feelings about Perry's song and use of the
    title in a July 2009 interview with The Rumpus:</p>
      <p>As a musician I have always refrained from criticizing
    another artist. I was, 'Well, good for her.' It did bug me a
    little bit, however, when she said she came up with the idea
    for the title in a dream. In truth, she wrote it with a team of
    professional writers and was signed by the very same guy that
    signed me in 1995. I have not mentioned that in interviews as I
    don't want to sound bitter or petty...</p>
      <p>Okay, maybe, if I really think about it, there were a few
    jealous and pissed-off moments. So here goes, for the first
    time in an interview: Fuck you, Katy Perry, you fucking stupid,
    maybe 'not good for the gays,' title-thieving, haven't heard
    much else, so not quite sure if you're talented, fucking little
    slut.</p>
      <p>
         <i>AllMusic</i>concluded "the problem is not with Katy's
    gender-bending, it's that her heart isn't in it; she's just
    using it to get her places, so she sinks to crass, craven
    depths". 
    <i>Slant Magazine</i>agrees, saying the song "isn't problematic
    because it promotes homosexuality, but because its
    appropriation of the gay lifestyle exists for the sole purpose
    of garnering attention — both from Perry's boyfriend and her
    audience".</p>
      <p>Adam Holz of 
    <i>PluggedinOnline</i>, a division of Focus on the Family,
    wrote an article entitled "A Tale of Two Katys" about the
    singer's image transformation from a Contemporary Christian
    Music artist to one of the "girls gone wild". He criticizes the
    song for being the latest, "high-profile message to young women
    and men that our sexuality is a malleable commodity that can be
    reshaped at will". Holz also argues that Perry's message
    carries with it "no need to worry about who might get used or
    objectified in the process", causing Perry to live "down to a
    damaging, demeaning stereotype".</p>
      <p>In some areas of the world the song's lyrics have kept it
    from reaching the Top 40 or to even be released at all. Though
    the 
    <i>Toronto Star</i>describes it as "a lesbian-friendly tune",
    whether homophobia fuels negative reactions to the song or the
    song itself appears to divide critics. 
    <i>Slant</i>and other critics suggest that Perry may be
    homophobic, especially given her single "Ur So Gay", which
    makes "I Kissed a Girl" seem like "a classic example of the
    'Guys kissing is gross, girls kissing is hot' line of thought".
    
    <i>The Star Ledger</i>quotes a listener who proposes that
    negative reactions to the song are due to homophobia, saying
    that it would not draw disapproval if sung by a male artist,
    and who compares the level of explicitness in the lyrics with
    other songs on the radio such as rap lyrics. 
    <i>MomLogic.com</i>writer Vuv-A-Licious agrees, asking "What's
    the big deal? ...When this tune is playing and my son and
    daughter are dancing, I will be trying to dance along, or
    trying to acknowledge that they may one day dance to the beat
    of a different drummer than me".</p>
      <p>In an August 2008, interview with the 
    <i>Daily Mail</i>, Perry's mother, Mary Hudson, an evangelical
    Christian preacher, was reported as saying that she disliked
    the song, stating "It clearly promotes homosexuality and its
    message is shameful and disgusting...". However, Perry took to
    her official blog stating that her mother's supposed comments
    were completely fabricated, while also saying her parents love
    and support her and attend many of her shows.</p>
      <p>Regarding the question of her own sexuality that the song
    has raised, Perry told Santa Barbara magazine "I like to kiss
    boys, but there is no doubt in my mind if Angelina Jolie or
    Gisele Bündchen came a callin', who wouldn't pucker up?". In an
    interview on the blog 
    <i>The New Gay</i>, Perry admitted she has never actually
    kissed a girl and is heterosexual. She is quoted as saying
    "Yeah, it’s fantasy, it’s a song about curiosity." However, in
    a separate interview, Perry stated that she has kissed a
    girl.</p>
      <p>In February 2009, Márcio Barros, a substitute English
    language teacher in a Distrito Federal, Brazil public school
    was fired after he used the song in a class activity among
    students ages 12 to 14. He was accused of promoting
    "homosexualism" and alcoholic beverages usage through the
    lyrics of the song. The Secretary of Education supported the
    decision of the head of the school.</p>
      <p>"I Kissed a Girl" debuted at number 76 at Billboard Hot 100.
    After a couple of weeks, the single hit the top 5, due to the
    rising digital downloads and increasing radio airplay. It
    continued to rise the next week, reaching #2 just behind her
    labelmate, Coldplay. The following week, the song reached the
    summit of the US chart, becoming the 1000th #1 song of the rock
    era (the 961st #1 on the Billboard Hot 100). In addition the
    song also gave the Capitol label two consecutive Hot 100 #1's,
    as the week's prior #1 was fellow Capitol artist Coldplay's
    "Viva La Vida", making it the first time since 1976 Capitol has
    had two back to back chart toppers on the Hot 100. The single
    also crossed over to Billboard's sister publication R&amp;R's
    Rhythmic chart in its July 5 issue, where not only did she have
    the highest debut ever for a non-rhythmic track, entering at
    number 26 with 1,065 spins, she also had the highest debut from
    a new artist in over five years. The bow is the best for a
    debut track at Rhythmic since Beyoncé entered at No. 21 with
    "Crazy In Love" in 2003. It also became the first song since
    Gnarls Barkley's "Crazy" to simultaneously appear on the
    Mainstream Top 40, Rhythmic, Adult Top 40 and Alternative
    charts. On July 26, 2008, the track also made history by
    reaching the number one spot on Billboard's Hot Dance Airplay
    chart by three weeks, a first for a solo act with a debut
    single. The song topped the Hot 100 for seven weeks in a row
    before finally being dethroned by Rihanna's "Disturbia". It is
    the second longest running number one on the Hot 100 of 2008
    (tied with "Whatever You Like"), with only Flo Rida's "Low"
    topping the chart for longer. According to Official UK Singles
    Chart, the single has sold over 535,000 copies in the United
    Kingdom as of January 25, 2009, is the first Virgin label
    single to sell more than half a million copies since the Spice
    Girls’ "Goodbye" in 1998.</p>
      <p>In Canada, the single debuted at #55 at Canadian Hot 100,
    reaching #1 on June 12 in a 26-position jump.</p>
      <p>In New Zealand, the song debuted at number 38, the single's
    first appearance in other countries chart outside North
    America, moving to number three the following week. The song
    was certified Gold after seven weeks with sales of over 7,500.
    On August 11, 2008, eight weeks after debuting on the chart, "I
    Kissed A Girl" finally made it to number one. "I Kissed A Girl"
    was certified Platinum in New Zealand after 20 weeks selling
    15,000+ copies.</p>
      <p>In Australia, the song debuted at #13 on the 30th of June on
    downloads alone, then the next week jumped to second position
    behind Jordin Sparks, still on downloads alone. The next week
    it jumped to number one still solely off downloads, becoming
    only the second single to do so. Ironically, by the time the
    song went number 1, this was the time when World Youth Day 2008
    had started and the event held anti-gay views. On July 21,
    2008, after the singles physical release, the track retained
    its number one position and was certified Gold. The single has
    held the number one position for several weeks and was
    certified 2× Platinum.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom, a cover version released by the
    artist Nicki Bliss was climbing up the UK iTunes Chart. It
    debuted on the UK Singles Chart (published August 3, 2008) at
    position number 50.</p>
      <p>A second cover version, by Barnicle, entered the UK Singles
    Chart (published August 3, 2008) at position #116.</p>
      <p>Because of the success of the cover versions, the official
    release of Katy Perry's version was brought forward from
    September 1 to July 30, 2008. On August 3, 2008, the song,
    which had entered the UK Singles Chart at number 139 the week
    before, climbed 135 places to reach position number 4. The song
    has become one of the most requested on Radio 1's request hour.
    The following week it climbed 3 places to reach number 1. The
    following week it stayed at the top spot for a second
    consecutive week and then went on to spend 5 consecutive weeks
    at #1.</p>
      <p>Even parodies of "I Kissed a Girl" are seeing chart success.
    Dr. Demento ranked Robert Lund's spoof "I Peed in the Pool" his
    #1 song of August, 2008, and one of his Funny 25 for the year.
    The song climbed back into the top 20 (reaching #19) in the UK
    on January 4, 2009, five months after it was first
    released.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
