<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woody_woodpecker#.22The_Woody_Woodpecker_Song.22 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woody_woodpecker#.22The_Woody_Woodpecker_Song.22</songId>
   <title>Woody Wood-Pecker</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kay_Kyser</artistId>
      <artistName>Kay Kyser</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1948-07-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>Woody Woodpecker is an animated cartoon character, an
    anthropomorphic acorn woodpecker who appeared in theatrical
    short films produced by the Walter Lantz animation studio and
    distributed by Universal Pictures. Though not the first of the
    screwball characters that became popular in the 1940s, Woody is
    perhaps the most indicative of the type.</p>
      <p>Woody was created in 1940 by storyboard artist Ben "Bugs"
    Hardaway, who had previously laid the groundwork for two other
    screwball characters, Bugs Bunny and Daffy Duck, at the Warner
    Bros. cartoon studio in the late 1930s. Woody's character and
    design would evolve over the years, from an insane bird with an
    unusually garish design to a more refined looking and acting
    character in the vein of the later Chuck Jones version of Bugs
    Bunny. Woody was originally voiced by prolific voice actor Mel
    Blanc, who was succeeded by Ben Hardaway and later by Grace
    Stafford, wife of Walter Lantz.</p>
      <p>Lantz produced theatrical cartoons longer than most of his
    contemporaries, and Woody Woodpecker remained a staple of
    Universal's release schedule until 1972, when Lantz finally
    closed down his studio. The character has been revived since
    then only for special productions and occasions, save for one
    new Saturday morning cartoon, 
    <i>The New Woody Woodpecker Show</i>, for the Fox Network in
    the late 1990s/early 2000s.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Woody Woodpecker</i>cartoons were first broadcast on
    television in 1957 under the title 
    <i>The Woody Woodpecker Show</i>, which featured Lantz cartoons
    bookended by new footage of Woody and live-action footage of
    Lantz. Woody has a motion picture star on the Hollywood Walk of
    Fame on 7000 Hollywood Boulevard. He also made a cameo
    alongside many other famous cartoon characters in the 1988 film
    
    <i>Who Framed Roger Rabbit</i>.</p>
      <p>According to Walter Lantz's press agent, the idea for Woody
    came during the producer's honeymoon with his wife, Gracie, in
    Sherwood Lake, California. A noisy woodpecker outside their
    cabin kept the couple awake at night, and when a heavy rain
    started, they learned that the bird had bored holes in their
    cabin's roof. As both Walter and Gracie told Dallas attorney
    Rod Phelps during a visit, Walter wanted to shoot the thing,
    but Gracie suggested that her husband make a cartoon about the
    bird, and thus Woody was born. The story is questionable,
    however, since the Lantzes were not married until after Woody
    made his screen debut. Also, their story that the bird's cry
    inspired Woody's trademark "Ha-ha-ha-HAA-ha!" is also
    questionable, as Mel Blanc had already used a similar laugh in
    earlier Warner Bros. cartoons such as 
    <i>Elmer's Candid Camera</i>.</p>
      <p>Woody Woodpecker first appeared in the film 
    <i>Knock Knock</i>on November 25, 1940. The cartoon ostensibly
    stars Andy Panda and his father, Papa Panda, but it is Woody
    who steals the show. The woodpecker constantly pesters the two
    pandas, apparently just for the fun of it. Andy, meanwhile,
    tries to sprinkle salt on Woody's tail in the belief that this
    will somehow capture the bird. To Woody's surprise, Andy's
    attempts prevail, and Woody is taken away to the funny farm —
    but not before his captors prove to be crazier than he is.</p>
      <p>The Woody of 
    <i>Knock Knock</i>, designed by animator Alex Lovy, is a truly
    deranged-looking animal. His buggy eyes look in different
    directions, and his head is all angles and sharp points.
    However, the familiar color scheme of red head and blue body is
    already in place, as is the infamous laugh: "Ha-ha-ha-HAA-ha!".
    Woody is perhaps the best example of the new type of cartoon
    character that was becoming popular in the early 1940s — a
    brash, violent aggressor who pesters innocents not out of self
    defense, but simply for the fun of it. Woody's original voice
    actor, Mel Blanc, would stop performing the character after the
    first four cartoons to work exclusively for Leon Schlesinger
    Productions (Later renamed Warner Bros. Cartoons) , producer of
    Warner Bros.' 
    <i>Looney Tunes</i>and 
    <i>Merrie Melodies</i>. At Schlesinger's, Blanc had already
    established the voices of two other famous "screwball"
    characters who preceded Woody, Daffy Duck and Bugs Bunny.
    Ironically, Blanc's characterization of the Woody Woodpecker
    laugh had originally been applied to a Bugs Bunny prototype, in
    shorts such as the aforementioned 
    <i>Elmer's Candid Camera</i>, and was later transferred to
    Woody. Blanc's regular speaking voice for Woody was much like
    the early Daffy Duck, minus the lisp. Once Warner Bros. signed
    Blanc up to an exclusive contract, Woody's voice-over work was
    taken over by Ben Hardaway, who would voice the woodpecker for
    the rest of the decade. To complete the connection full circle,
    Hardaway, who had also worked under Schlesinger at Warner
    Bros., was the designer of the Bugs Bunny prototype that Blanc
    supplied the aforementioned laugh for. Haradaway's nickname
    around Termite Terrace (the ramshackle building where the
    Looney Tunes were originally produced) was "Bugs," and the
    bunny prototype's first model sheet was labeled "Bugs'
    Bunny"--the apostrophe was later dropped.</p>
      <p>Audiences reacted well to 
    <i>Knock Knock</i>, and Lantz realized he had finally hit upon
    a star to replace the waning Oswald the Lucky Rabbit. Woody
    would go on to star in a number of films. With his innate
    chutzpah and brash demeanor, the character was a natural hit
    during World War II. His image appeared on US aircraft and mess
    halls, and audiences on the homefront watched Woody cope with
    familiar problems such as food shortages. The 1943 Woody
    cartoon 
    <i>The Dizzy Acrobat</i>was nominated for the 1944 Academy
    Award for Best Short Subject (Cartoons), which it lost to the
    MGM 
    <i>Tom and Jerry</i>cartoon 
    <i>The Yankee Doodle Mouse</i>.</p>
      <p>Animator Emery Hawkins and layout artist Art Heinemann
    streamlined Woody's appearance for the 1944 film 
    <i>The Barber of Seville</i>, directed by Shamus Culhane. The
    bird became rounder, cuter, and less demented. He also sported
    a simplified color scheme and a brighter smile, making him much
    more like his counterparts at Warner Bros. and MGM.
    Nevertheless, Culhane continued to use Woody as an aggressive
    lunatic, not a domesticated straight man or defensive homebody,
    as many other studios' characters had become. The follow-up to 
    <i>The Barber of Seville</i>, 
    <i>The Beach Nut</i>, introduced Woody's chief nemesis Wally
    Walrus.</p>
      <p>Woody's wild days were numbered, however. In 1946, Lantz
    hired Disney veteran Dick Lundy to take over the direction
    chores for Woody's cartoons. Lundy rejected Culhane's take on
    the series and made Woody more defensive; no longer did the
    bird go insane without a legitimate reason. Lundy also paid
    more attention to the animation, making Woody's new films more
    Disney-esque in their design style, animation, and timing.
    Lundy's last film for Disney was the Donald Duck short 
    <i>Flying Jalopy</i>. This cartoon is played much like a Woody
    Woodpecker short, right down to the laugh in the end. It also
    features a bad guy named "Ben Buzzard" who bears a strong
    resemblance to Buzz Buzzard, a Lantz character introduced in
    the 1948 short 
    <i>Wet Blanket Policy</i>who would eventually succeed as
    Woody's primary antagonist.</p>
      <p>In 1947, contract renewal negotiations between Lantz and
    Universal (now Universal-International) fell through, and Lantz
    began distributing his cartoons through United Artists. The
    UA-distributed Lantz cartoons featured higher-quality
    animation, the influence of Dick Lundy (the films' budgets
    remained the same). Former Disney animators such as Fred Moore
    and Ed Love began working at Lantz, and assisted Lundy in
    adding touches of the Disney style to Woody's cartoons.</p>
      <p>In 1947, Woody got his own theme song when musicians George
    Tibbles and Ramey Idriss wrote "The Woody Woodpecker Song",
    making ample use of the character's famous laugh. Kay Kyser's
    1948 recording of the song, with Harry Babbitt's laugh
    interrupting vocalist Gloria Wood, became one of the biggest
    hit singles of 1948. Other artists did covers, including
    Woody's original voice actor, Mel Blanc. Lantz first used "The
    Woody Woodpecker Song" in the 1948 short 
    <i>Wet Blanket Policy</i>, and became the first and only song
    from an animated short subject to be nominated for the Academy
    Award for Best Song. Lantz soon adopted the song as Woody's
    theme music, and due to the song's popularity, Woody Woodpecker
    fan clubs sprang up, theaters held "Woody" matinées, and boys
    got the "Woody Woodpecker" haircut.</p>
      <p>"The Woody Woodpecker Song" and the 
    <i>Woody Woodpecker</i>cartoons made extensive use of Woody's
    famous laugh, upsetting the man who created it, Mel Blanc. (The
    laugh, in a different recording, was first used for the seminal
    Bugs Bunny prototype character in the 1940 Warner Bros. cartoon
    "
    <i>Elmer's Candid Camera</i>"). Although Blanc had only
    recorded four shorts as the voice of Woody, his laugh had been
    recorded as a stock sound effect, and used in every subsequent 
    <i>Woody Woodpecker</i>short up until this point. Blanc sued
    Lantz and lost, but Lantz settled out of court when Blanc filed
    an appeal. While Lantz would stop using Blanc's Woody
    Woodpecker laugh as a stock effect in the early 1950s, Blanc's
    voice would be heard saying "Guess who?" at the beginning of
    every cartoon for the duration of the 
    <i>Woody Woodpecker</i>series.</p>
      <p>The lower revenues Lantz received from United Artists, in
    contrast to Universal, caused financial problems within the
    studio, and by the end of 1948 Lantz had to shut his studio
    down. The Lantz studio did not re-open again until 1950, by
    which time the staff was severely downsized.</p>
      <p>Beginning with the 1950 feature film 
    <i>Destination Moon</i>, which featured a brief segment of
    Woody explaining rocket propulsion, Woody's voice was taken
    over for this and following films by Lantz's wife, Grace
    Stafford. According to the Lantzes, Stafford slipped a
    recording of herself into a stack of audition tapes, and her
    husband chose her without knowing her identity. Lantz also
    began having Stafford supply Woody's laugh, possibly due to the
    court case with Mel Blanc. Nevertheless, Stafford was not
    credited for her work at her own request until 1958 with the
    film 
    <i>Misguided Missile</i>, as she felt audiences might reject a
    woman doing Woody's voice. Stafford also did her best to tone
    down the character through her voice work, to appease
    Universal's complaints about Woody's raucousness.</p>
      <p>Lantz signed again with Universal (now
    Universal-International) in 1950, and began production on two 
    <i>Woody Woodpecker</i>cartoons that director Dick Lundy and
    storymen Ben Hardaway and Heck Allen had begun before the 1948
    layoff. These shorts have no director's credit, as Lantz claims
    to have directed them himself. 
    <i>Puny Express</i>, released by Universal-International in
    1951, was the first to be released, followed by 
    <i>Sleep Happy</i>. These shorts marked a departure from the
    dialogue-driven shorts of the past. Though Stafford now voiced
    Woody, her job was limited, as Woody (as well as the rest of
    the characters) rarely spoke in the first dozen or so shorts.
    It was because of these shorts that Woody became very popular
    overseas, thanks to the lack of a language barrier (
    <i>The Pink Panther</i>shorts of the 1960s and 1970s would also
    enjoy worldwide popularity due to this pantomime luxury).</p>
      <p>Nine more Lantz-directed Woody cartoons followed, before Don
    Patterson became Woody's new director in 1953. The bird was
    redesigned once again for these new cartoons, this time by
    animator LaVerne Harding. Harding made Woody smaller, cuter,
    and moved his top-knot forward from its original backwards
    position. (The small Lantz Studios logo seen at the start of
    every cartoon - Woody as an armored knight on horseback
    carrying a 
    <i>lance</i>- continued to display Woody with his old topknot
    for a while.) By 1955, Woody also received one more minor
    makeover, making his domestication complete: the hazel
    pigmentation in his eye was eliminated starting with 1955's 
    <i>The Tree Medic</i>, making Woody's eye a simple black
    dot.</p>
      <p>By 1955, Paul J. Smith had taken over as primary director of
    Woody's shorts, with periodic fill-in shorts directed by Alex
    Lovy and Jack Hannah, among others. With Smith on board, the
    shorts maintained a healthy dose of frenetic energy, while the
    animation itself was simplified, due to budget constraints.</p>
      <p>In addition to Lantz's wife Grace Stafford providing Woody's
    voice, which returned the cartoon to being more dialogue-driven
    again, voice talents during this period were generally split
    between Dal McKennon and Daws Butler. This era would also
    introduce several of Woody's recurring costars, most notably
    Gabby Gator (voiced by Daws Butler in the voice he used to
    voice Huckleberry Hound) who first appeared in 
    <i>Everglade Raid</i>(then known as "Al I. Gator"). Other films
    paired Woody with a girlfriend, Winnie Woodpecker, and a niece
    and nephew, Splinter and Knothead (both voiced by June Foray).
    Other antagonists that Woody has dealt with were Ms. Meaney
    (voiced by Grace Stafford) and Dapper Denver Dooley (voiced by
    Dallas McKennon).</p>
      <p>As Lantz was struggling financially, Woody's longevity was
    secured when he made the jump to television in 
    <i>The Woody Woodpecker Show</i>on ABC. The half-hour program
    consisted of three theatrical Woody shorts followed by a brief
    look at cartoon creation hosted by Lantz. It ran from 1957 to
    1958 then entered syndication until 1966. It was later revived
    by NBC in 1970, and again in 1976. In addition, the woodpecker
    was no longer dishing out abuse to his foils, but was instead
    on the receiving end. The first notable short to feature Woody
    as the straight man was 1961's 
    <i>Franken-Stymied</i>. Woody's popularity had been based on
    his manic craziness, and by 1961, this had all but been
    eliminated in favor of a more serious Woody, one that was
    trying to do good. This was due in part to Woody's large
    presence on television, which meant Lantz had to meet the
    stringent rules against violence for children's television.</p>
      <p>Woody continued to appear in new theatrical shorts until
    1972, when Lantz closed his studio's doors due to rising
    production costs. His cartoons returned to syndication in the
    late 1970s. Lantz sold his library of Woody shorts to
    MCA/Universal in 1985. Universal repackaged the cartoons for
    another syndicated 
    <i>Woody Woodpecker Show</i>in 1987. A year later, Woody made a
    brief cameo in 
    <i>Who Framed Roger Rabbit</i>, voiced by Cherry Davis, near
    the end of the film. In 1995, Woody appeared in a Pepsi
    commercial with NBA star Shaquille O'Neal.</p>
      <p>Woody Woodpecker reappeared in the Fox Kids series 
    <i>The New Woody Woodpecker Show</i>, which ran on Saturday
    mornings from 1999 to 2002. The series featured the first new
    Woody cartoons to be produced in over 20 years, and returned
    the character's design to the Dick Lundy/Emery Hawkins version
    of the late 1940s, as well as redesigning characters with later
    appearances, such as Dapper Denver Dooley (who debuted in
    1955's 
    <i>Square Shootin' Square</i>) and Miss Meany (who debuted in
    1963's 
    <i>Calling Dr. Woodpecker</i>). Winnie Woodpecker was
    resurrected from 1954's 
    <i>Real Gone Woody.</i>While there have been plenty of women in
    Woody's life such as a Native American woman in 
    <i>Scalp Treatment,</i>Ga Ga Gazoon from 
    <i>Belle Boys,</i>a Mexican woman from 
    <i>Hot Noon (or 12 O'Clock For Sure),</i>Princess Salami from 
    <i>Socko in Morocco</i>and Gorgeous Gal from 
    <i>A Fine Feathered Frenzy,</i>Winnie was the most obvious
    choice for his love interest on the show. Woody's voice is now
    provided by voice actor Billy West. As of 2009, 
    <i>The New Woody Woodpecker Show</i>remains the most recent
    show featuring Woody Woodpecker.</p>
      <p>Woody and Winnie both appear as costumed characters at
    Universal Orlando, Universal Studios Japan and Universal
    Studios Hollywood.</p>
      <p>The 
    <i>Woody Woodpecker Show</i>was named the 88th best animated
    series by IGN.</p>
      <p>Walter Lantz and movie pioneer George Pál were good friends.
    Woody Woodpecker makes a cameo in nearly every film that Pál
    either produced or directed—for example, during the 1960
    sequence in 
    <i>The Time Machine</i>, there is a brief shot of a little girl
    dropping her Woody Woodpecker doll as she goes into the air
    raid shelter.</p>
      <p>Woody was number 46 on 
    <i>TV Guide'</i>s list of the 50 Greatest Cartoon Characters of
    All-Time in 2002 and 2003. He came in at number 25 on Animal
    Planet's list of 
    <i>The 50 Greatest Movie Animals</i>in 2004. The character has
    been referenced and spoofed on many later television programs,
    among them 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>, 
    <i>American Dad!</i>, 
    <i>South Park</i>, 
    <i>The Fairly OddParents</i>, 
    <i>Family Guy</i>and 
    <i>Seinfeld</i>.</p>
      <p>The Beach Boys' 1967 album 
    <i>Smiley Smile</i>featured a song entitled "Fall Breaks and
    Back to Winter (Woody Woodpecker Symphony)." Also, the first
    song on the 2007 Dan Deacon album 
    <i>Spiderman of the Rings</i>is entitled "Wooody Wooodpecker"
    and makes extensive use of the character's trademark laugh.</p>
      <p>Woody Woodpecker is the mascot for the Universal Studios
    Theme Parks. In 1998, Woody appeared on the nose of the
    Williams Formula One Team, and in 2000, he became the official
    team mascot of the Honda Motorcycle Racing Team. A balloon
    featuring the character has long been a staple of the Macy's
    Thanksgiving Day Parade.</p>
      <p>A handful of non-comprehensive 
    <i>Woody Woodpecker</i>VHS tapes were issued by Universal in
    the 1980s and 1990s, usually including Andy Panda and Chilly
    Willy cartoons as bonuses. A few were widely released on VHS in
    the mid-1980s by Kid Pics Video, an American company of dubious
    legality, who packaged the Woody cartoons with bootlegged
    Disney cartoons. In the early 2000s, a series of mail-order 
    <i>Woody Woodpecker Show</i>VHS tapes and DVDs were made
    available by mail order through Columbia House. However,
    following complaints about censorship (the cartoons included
    featured varying amounts of censorship, from restored and
    intact prints to severely cut TV edits), the series ended after
    fifteen volumes rather than the planned twenty.</p>
      <p>In 2007, Universal Studios Home Entertainment released 
    <i>The Woody Woodpecker and Friends Classic Cartoon
    Collection</i>, a three-disc DVD box set compilation of Walter
    Lantz "Cartunes". The first forty-five Woody Woodpecker shorts
    — from 
    <i>Knock Knock</i>to 
    <i>The Great Who-Dood-It</i>— were presented on the box set in
    chronological order of release, with various 
    <i>Chilly Willy</i>, 
    <i>Andy Panda</i>, 
    <i>Swing Symphonies</i>, and other Lantz shorts also included. 
    <i>The Woody Woodpecker and Friends Classic Cartoon Collection:
    Volume 2</i>, including the next forty-five 
    <i>Woody</i>cartoons — 
    <i>Termites from Mars</i>through 
    <i>Jittery Jester</i>— was released in 2008. A vanilla
    "best-of" release, entitled 
    <i>Woody Woodpecker Favorites</i>, was released in 2009, which
    contained no new-to-DVD material. Plans for further releases,
    as well as a region 1 DVD release of 
    <i>The New Woody Woodpecker Show</i>, are currently on hold,
    although the 1999 series has received VHS and DVD releases
    outside of North America and is available for viewing on
    Hulu.</p>
      <p>Apart from authorized releases, the Woody Woodpecker cartoon
    most widely available on legal home video is 
    <i>Pantry Panic</i>, as that cartoon has fallen into the public
    domain.</p>
      <p>Blanc originated the voice, in a characterization similar to
    his Daffy Duck, minus the lisp, with the recording slightly
    sped up to give a higher pitched tone to the voice. That
    practice would continue with other voice artists.</p>
      <p>Several video games of Woody Woodpecker were released for
    Mega Drive/Genesis, Dreamcast, PlayStation, PlayStation 2, PC,
    Game Boy Color and Game Boy Advance.</p>
      <p>Mattel purchased the rights for a Woody Woodpecker
    Intellivision game, and Grace Stafford recorded new dialog for
    the game, but it was neither completed nor released.</p>
      <p>Additionally, a series of pachinko games has been released
    in Japan by Maruhon.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
