<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Please_Don%27t_Go 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Please_Don%27t_Go</songId>
   <title>Please Don't Go</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KC_and_the_Sunshine_Band</artistId>
      <artistName>KC and the Sunshine Band</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1980-01-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e8/PleaseDontGo.jpg/200px-PleaseDontGo.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/KC-and-the-Sunshine-Band+Please-Don-t-Go.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Do You Wanna Go Party</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 12, 1979</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" Vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:43</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>TK Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Harry Wayne Casey / Richard Finch</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Harry Wayne Casey / Richard Finch</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Please Don't Go" is a song recorded and released in 1979 on
    the KC and the Sunshine Band album 
    <i>Do You Wanna Go Party</i>. The song was the band's first
    love ballad, in which the subject pleads obviously for a second
    chance. Shortly after the song's one-week run at number one,
    the group broke up and Harry Wayne Casey went solo. The song
    was a number-one hit on the Australian ARIA Charts, and the
    band's fifth and final number-one hit on Billboard Hot 100
    charts.</p>
      <p>The song is incorrectly noted by some sources as being the
    last number one hit of the 1970s and the first of the 1980s on
    the Billboard Hot 100. In fact, it was only the number one song
    for the chart week of January 5, 1980, making it the first #1
    single of the 1980s. It was both preceded and followed at
    number one by "Escape (The Piña Colada Song)" by Rupert Holmes,
    which dropped to number two for the week that "Please Don't Go"
    was number one. The B side which was called "Betcha Didn't Know
    That" was number one on the R&amp;B Chart at the same time it
    was an Italian 92' jam, but then was re-mixed by Ajo Rabaccii
    From Abohar.</p>
      <p>A soundalike cover of Double You's arrangement by the
    British group KWS hit number one on the UK Singles Chart for
    five weeks in May 1992 and reached number six on the U.S. 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100. It was recorded and released after
    record company Network failed to secure UK distribution rights
    for the Double You version. The similarity between both
    versions resulted in Network paying compensation to Roberto
    Zanetti, Double You's producer, following legal action . The
    KWS version was claimed to be released in honour of Nottingham
    Forest (European football) defender Des Walker, who was on the
    verge of signing for Italian team Sampdoria.</p>
      <p>In 2008, it was remade into a eurodance tune this time by
    Dance/Techno musician Basshunter.</p>
      <p>The single was released as a single in Sweden where it
    reached #6.</p>
      <p>The song was originally planned to be released in the UK as
    the second single on June 23, 2008. But due to technical
    difficulties, the release was cancelled and "All I Ever Wanted"
    took its place on 
    <span class="mw-formatted-date" title="07-07">
July 7
</span>. It had much more success than originally thought as the
single reached number 2 in the UK charts.</p>
      <p>However, despite rumours that this would be the third UK
    single, "Angel in the Night" was released instead and was
    premiered on BBC Radio 1 on August 22, 2008, during Scott Mills
    Friday Floor Fillers.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
