<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Life_Would_Suck_Without_You 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Life_Would_Suck_Without_You</songId>
   <title>My Life Would Suck Without You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kelly_Clarkson</artistId>
      <artistName>Kelly Clarkson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2009-02-07</week>
      <week>2009-02-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e7/My_Life_Would_Suck_Without_You.jpg/200px-My_Life_Would_Suck_Without_You.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Kelly-Clarkson+My-Life-Would-Suck-Without-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>All I Ever Wanted</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 13, 2009  (2009-01-13) , (See release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital single</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2008</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:32 (Main/Album Version)</length>
      <length>3:51 (Main with Intro)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Max Martin</writer>
      <writer>Dr. Luke</writer>
      <writer>Claude Kelly</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Max Martin</producer>
      <producer>Dr. Luke</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"My Life Would Suck Without You" is a song performed by
    American pop rock singer-songwriter Kelly Clarkson. It is the
    first single from her fourth studio album, 
    <i>All I Ever Wanted</i>. Dr. Luke and Max Martin, writers of
    her hit "Since U Been Gone", co-produced and co-wrote the song.
    Claude Kelly also contributed to the lyrics. It is her second
    number-one single in the United States after 2002's "A Moment
    Like This", her second number-one in Canada after "A Moment
    Like This", and her first number-one in the United Kingdom.</p>
      <p>"My Life Would Suck Without You" is a moderately fast pop
    rock song composed in the key of A major with 145 beats per
    minute. The tempo is set in common time. Clarkson's vocal range
    spans from A
    <sub>3</sub>to E
    <sub>5</sub>. The instruments used in this song are
    synthesizers, guitars, a drum machine, and bass. The song
    begins with mellow guitar plucking and transcends into a melody
    of synthesizers, guitars, and synthesized drums. The melody
    then cascades into a chorus of crashing cymbals, bass,
    synthesizers, and loud guitars.</p>
      <p>The song received generally positive reviews. 
    <i>Billboard</i>labelled it "a propulsive blast of rock-tinged
    pop" and stated that "the countdown to No. 1 begins."
    About.com's Bill Lamb named it "pop perfection that could
    easily end up one of the biggest hits of the year." 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>called the song "fantastic — the early
    favorite for single of the year." and "straight-up pop [that]
    cascades into an avalanche of synths and a steady beat,"
    mentioning that it "has all the characteristics of a surefire
    radio hit."</p>
      <p>Brian Mansfield from 
    <i>USA Today</i>stated that there were "disco rhythms and lots
    of synth-dance-pop layers over the top, but the guitar
    pattern... keeps it from sounding too artificial"; eventually
    stating that he was "liking it". The 
    <i>Los Angeles Times</i>said the song "zooms forward from its
    guitar-plucky intro toward a cymbal-crashing climax without
    ever slowing down", commenting that the song would be "huge";
    however, it also stated that the song had "empty calories
    delivered within those compressed, subtly Auto-Tuned vocals
    [riding] high-fructose beats."</p>
      <p>Originally scheduled to hit airwaves on January 19, the song
    debuted on New York Top 40 station Z100 on January 13, and the
    single was then transmitted digitally to radio stations at
    6:00pm EST for immediate airplay. It went officially for adds
    on radio station playlists on January 20, 2009. It was given a
    digital release on January 16, 2009 at Amazon.com's MP3 store,
    with a subsequent release on the US and Canadian iTunes Stores
    on January 20, 2009.</p>
      <p>The song was also released as a download on January 16 in
    Australia on iTunes. On January 23, the song was announced as
    the most added song to radio in Australia. The song was sent to
    UK radio stations the week of January 19 and was digitally
    released there on February 21.</p>
      <p>On the fall finale of the first season of the hit new Fox
    television series 
    <i>Glee</i>, "Sectionals", "My Life Would Suck Without You" was
    performed by the main characters as the finale of the episodes,
    and the first half of the first season. Their version of the
    song has been released as a single on iTunes and is the final
    song on the soundtrack compilation 
    <i>Glee: The Music, Volume 2</i>.</p>
      <p>"My Life Would Suck Without You" debuted at #97 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100, setting the record for the furthest
    jump to #1 in history. This makes it the second time Clarkson
    has set this record, after her debut single "A Moment Like
    This" went from #52 to #1 in 2002. "My Life Would Suck Without
    You" is also the first song by an 
    <i>Idol</i>alum to top the chart that is not associated with
    the show. The song also advanced to #3 on 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Mainstream Top 40 chart, giving her her
    first top ten airplay hit since "Because of You". The song was
    dethroned from the top of the Hot 100 chart by Eminem's "Crack
    a Bottle". The song has so far sold over 2,000,000 downloads in
    the United States.</p>
      <p>On the American Top 40, "My Life Would Suck Without You"
    made a high jump on February 19, 2009. It rose 21 spots to #10
    from #31.</p>
      <p>On the Canadian Hot 100, the song debuted at #82. The
    following week, it jumped to the top spot, breaking the record
    previously set by Rihanna with "Take A Bow", which moved from
    #70 to #1.. She took that record for 10 months, until October
    2009, when Britney Spears' "3" jumped from 86 to 1.</p>
      <p>"My Life Would Suck Without You" debuted on the Australian
    ARIA Charts at #16 and peaked at #5, and is also Clarkson's
    first physical number #1 single. The single debuted on the New
    Zealand RIANZ chart at #25 and peaked at #11.</p>
      <p>"My Life Would Suck Without You" became Clarkson's biggest
    hit in Sweden (peaking at #2), Ireland (#4), and Germany
    (#6).</p>
      <p>In the Netherlands, "My Life Would Suck Without You" debuted
    at number 26 and peaked at number 3, becoming her first top 10
    hit in the Netherlands since the release of 
    <i>Breakaway'</i>s last European single "Because of You".</p>
      <p>On March 1, 2009, the song climbed from #103 on the UK
    Singles Chart to #1, becoming Clarkson's first UK number-one
    single, selling 51,114 copies in its first week as a digital
    release. Despite being Clarkson's highest charting single in
    the UK, it's stay on the chart is considerably less than some
    of her other singles. With 17 weeks in the top 100 UK Singles
    it ranks behind her #5 hit "Since U Been Gone" at 37 weeks and
    her #7 hit "Because of You" at 25 weeks.</p>
      <p>"My Life Would Suck Without You" has been certified Platinum
    in Australia and Canada, Gold in New Zealand, and Silver in the
    UK.</p>
      <p>It made it to the 2009 Year-End Billboard Chart at #23,
    becoming the highest peak for a Clarkson single in the Year-End
    chart since "Behind These Hazel Eyes" (#10) and "Since U Been
    Gone" (#4) charted in 2005.</p>
      <p>The music video for the song was directed by Wayne Isham and
    was shot in Los Angeles in December 2008. It is now available
    for digital download on iTunes and is featured on the DVD of
    the Deluxe Edition of 
    <i>All I Ever Wanted</i>. A preview of the video was shown
    during a commercial break for 
    <i>American Idol</i>on its January 28, 2009, episode. The full
    video then premiered via AT&amp;T's website directly after the
    broadcast.</p>
      <p>The video begins with a small boy and girl playing on a
    playground together, teasingly pushing each other around. The
    young girl is intended to be Clarkson as a child, presumably
    with her young male best friend. The boy hands her a beaded
    necklace, which she puts on admiringly. The shot closes in on
    the necklace, then pulls back to reveal it's still worn as a
    bracelet on the wrist of now-adult Clarkson.</p>
      <p>Clarkson's boyfriend (played by Houston Rhines) shows up at
    her apartment door, presumably after an argument. Clarkson
    teases him with a set of keys, which she then throws down the
    toilet.</p>
      <p>The two are then shown sitting on a couch, reading
    magazines, when Clarkson grabs her boyfriend's magazine. The
    two are shown throwing various possessions of one another out
    of the apartment window, though in a playful manner. Such items
    include numerous articles of clothing, magazines, a guitar, and
    a fishbowl (with the fish being taken out and put in a glass
    first, after which they look out the window). After throwing
    these items out the window, the two are seen sitting
    affectionately on the couch. Clarkson and her boyfriend are
    shown still fighting and bickering as they did as children,
    over the 
    <i>TV Guide</i>and remote control.</p>
      <p>The latter portion of the video shows the two driving in a
    car (with the necklace/bracelet hanging from the rear view
    mirror), eventually getting into an argument. Distracted by the
    tiff over directions, the Jeep nearly ends up in a head-on
    collision with an approaching car. After spinning out to avoid
    the crash, Clarkson simply grabs her boyfriend and pulls him
    into a kiss, where the video ends.</p>
      <p>Interspersed with the storyline are performance shots of
    Clarkson on a swing set and band shots of Clarkson singing
    throughout the chorus with bright, football stadium lighting
    behind her. The lights fluctuate along with the song, becoming
    bright during certain key moments of musical crescendo and then
    dimming for others.</p>
      <p>The video was nominated for a 2009 MTV Video Music Award in
    the category for Best Female Video.</p>
      <p>Promotional single</p>
      <p>Digital single</p>
      <p>CD single (B001PS0EWU)</p>
      <p>Maxi CD single (88697463372)</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
