<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Moment_Like_This 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Moment_Like_This</songId>
   <title>A Moment Like This</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kelly_Clarkson</artistId>
      <artistName>Kelly Clarkson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2002-10-05</week>
      <week>2002-10-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f0/Kcamlt.jpg/200px-Kcamlt.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Kelly-Clarkson+A-Moment-Like-This.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Thankful</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 17, 2002  (2002-09-17)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>DVD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2002</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:49</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jörgen Elofsson</writer>
      <writer>John Reid</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Stephen Ferrera</producer>
      <producer>Steve Mac</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"A Moment Like This" is a song originally recorded by
    American singer Kelly Clarkson the first winner of American
    Idol, released as her first ever single which topped the
    Billboard Hot 100 from her multi-platinum debut album, 
    <i>Thankful</i>. It has been recorded by Leona Lewis, the third
    winner of the British television programme 
    <i>The X Factor.</i>
      </p>
      <p>The song was co-written by Jörgen Elofsson and John Reid (of
    dance act Nightcrawlers) and produced by Stephen Ferrera and
    Steve Mac. It was written to be the first single for the winner
    of the first season of 
    <i>American Idol</i>. As a result, the four remaining
    finalists, Kelly Clarkson, Justin Guarini, Nikki McKibbin, and
    Tamyra Gray each recorded a version of the song in case he or
    she won. The song was first revealed to the public when Guarini
    and Clarkson competed in a final showdown while singing this
    song, along with another track, "Before Your Love". After the
    American public had voted, Guarini performed the song (and
    Clarkson performed "Before Your Love") at the final show before
    the results were revealed. When Clarkson was announced as the
    winner, she became emotional, and sang the song as her final
    performance.</p>
      <p>"Before Your Love", was also given to radio and had a video
    shot, which debuted on MTV's 
    <i>TRL</i>before "A Moment Like This" did; however, it failed
    to achieve the level of success of "A Moment Like This". To
    date, "A Moment Like This" has sold approximately 1,047,000
    copies.</p>
      <p>On 10/18/2002, the single was certified gold by RIAA and has
    sold over 500,000 copies in all formats in the U.S.</p>
      <p>The music video for "A Moment Like This" is relatively
    simple, and has Clarkson exploring an abandoned theatre. She
    can be seen taking the stage to sing, and clips of her singing
    on 
    <i>American Idol</i>and getting emotional when she won are also
    shown.</p>
      <p>As the first single ever from 
    <i>American Idol</i>, much pressure was put on "A Moment Like
    This" to perform well. The debut single from Will Young, the
    winner of Britain's 
    <i>Pop Idol</i>(the forerunner to 
    <i>American Idol</i>), sold 1.2 million copies in its first
    week, becoming the fastest-selling British debut single of all
    time; however, critics argued that the American singles market
    was different from the British market. The single became a hit
    in the U.S., reaching number one on the Hot 100 for two weeks.
    Sales of the commercial single also helped the song (as
    evidenced by its number-one peak on the Hot 100 Singles Sales)
    break records. With the release of the single, the song broke
    The Beatles' record for the biggest leap ever to number one,
    from 52, in the history of the Hot 100 Chart, a record that
    would stand for five years. She would break the record again
    when her new song "My Life Would Suck Without You" jumped 96
    spots from 97 to 1 in 2009.</p>
      <p>In December 2006, the song was recorded by Leona Lewis, the
    winner of series 3 of 
    <i>The X Factor</i>. The single was rush-released on Wednesday,
    December 20, 2006. This is unusual as most new singles are
    released on a Monday to gain maximum sales for the UK Singles
    Chart the following Sunday. The late release of "A Moment Like
    This" was due to the fact that Lewis was only chosen as the
    artist on the night of Saturday, December 16, when the live
    final was transmitted. The song was available for download
    after she was announced winner of 
    <i>The X Factor</i>.</p>
      <p>In January 2007, "A Moment Like This" was shortlisted for
    the British Single award at the 2007 BRIT Awards. It made it to
    the second round but was eliminated and did not make it to the
    final selection. In May it was awarded the prestigious Ivor
    Novello Award for Best Selling British Single.</p>
      <p>The music video, like Clarkson's, is very simple, with Lewis
    singing the song on a stage. It also features several clips
    from Lewis's time in 
    <i>The X Factor</i>, from her first audition to the moment she
    was announced the winner. Simon Cowell, Sharon Osbourne, Louis
    Walsh, Kate Thornton and Raymond Quinn all feature within the
    clips. The video was directed by JT.</p>
      <p>It was reported that one million copies of the winner's
    single were pre-ordered by stores. "A Moment like This" was
    downloaded 50,000 times within 30 minutes of being available
    online. It ended as the UK's second best selling single of the
    year. In January 2007, the single was awarded platinum status
    by the British Phonographic Industry.</p>
      <p>The single got the iTunes UK number-one spot on the day of
    release, beating Take That who had been at the top spot for two
    weeks. On December 24, 2006 it debuted at number one on the UK
    Singles Chart, making it the coveted Christmas number one, and
    stayed at number one for four weeks. It also spent six weeks at
    the top of the Irish Singles Chart. It re-entered the UK Top 75
    on October 28, 2007 at number 55, when Lewis's second single
    "Bleeding Love" was released.</p>
      <p>There is a cover version of "A Moment Like This" by Dutch
    singer Glennis Grace, a Swedish version called "Ett kort
    Ögonblick" released by Swedish duo Fame, and a cover version by
    Sandra Oxenryd. All three have performed in the Eurovision Song
    Contest in 2005 , 2003 and 2006 respectively. Another version
    of "A Moment like This" is featured in the 
    <i>Drawn Together</i>episode "A Tale of Two Cows", where Toot
    Braunstein sings a shrill, off-key version while having sex
    with Xandir. Toot also sings it in the series finale in a
    parody of American idol in 2007. Kidz Bop Kids covered "A
    Moment like This" on their album 
    <i>Kidz Bop 3</i>. The song was also covered by 
    <i>Idol Sweden</i>2005 finalist Cindy Lamreus on the 
    <i>Idol</i>compilation, 
    <i>My Own Idol</i>.</p>
      <p>Most recently, on October 1, 2008, the top ten finalists of 
    <i>America's Got Talent</i>season three performed the song
    together live on the season's finale episode.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
