<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Islands_in_the_Stream 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Islands_in_the_Stream</songId>
   <title>Islands in the Stream</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenny_Rogers</artistId>
      <artistName>Kenny Rogers with Dolly Parton</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1983-10-29</week>
      <week>1983-11-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/0e/Krdpislands.jpg/200px-Krdpislands.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Kenny-Rogers-with-Dolly-Parton+Islands-in-the-Stream.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Eyes That See in the Dark</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 1983 ( U.S. )</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Country</genre>
   </genres>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bee Gees</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Barry Gibb</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Islands in the Stream" is a 1983 hit country and pop
    single, written by the Bee Gees and sung by Kenny Rogers and
    Dolly Parton. It was the first single from Rogers' album 
    <i>Eyes That See in the Dark</i>and the second pop number-one
    for both Rogers and Parton (Rogers having been there with
    1980's "Lady" and Parton with 1981's "9 to 5"). They went on to
    record a Christmas album together, and had an additional hit
    with their 1985 duet "Real Love". The Gibbs originally wrote
    the song for Diana Ross in an R&amp;B style, only later to
    change it for the Kenny Rogers album.</p>
      <p>It also spent two weeks as the number one country song and
    in the year's final countdown was the number one song of the
    year of 1983. In Australia, the song was number one for one
    week in December 1983 and becoming one of the highest selling
    singles of 1984. In 2005, the song topped CMT's poll of the
    best country duets of all time; Parton and Rogers reunited to
    perform the song on the CMT special.</p>
      <p>In April 2008, South Bend, Indiana radio station WZOW played
    the song continuously for several days on end. This was a stunt
    used to draw attention to the station's format change from
    alternative rock to adult contemporary.</p>
      <p>In many ways it was a rather typical Bee Gees song with a
    straightforward rhythm in the verses being dissolved by a
    unique chorus with heavily syncopated lyrics strongly
    contradicting the still basic rhythmic patterns of the melody.
    The unusual traits of the chorus has been described as "the
    words coming almost half a beat too late".</p>
      <p>In March 2009, actors Ruth Jones and Rob Brydon, in
    character as Vanessa Jenkins and Bryn West from the hit BBC
    show 
    <i>Gavin &amp; Stacey</i>, released a version of the song as a
    single for Comic Relief. Robin Gibb and Sir Tom Jones appear on
    the single as backing singers. Titled "(Barry) Islands in the
    Stream" in reference to the Barry Island setting of 
    <i>Gavin &amp; Stacey</i>, it entered the UK Singles Chart at
    number 1 on 15 March 2009.</p>
      <p>The chorus with reworked lyrics was featured on Pras
    Michel's 1998 hit song "Ghetto Supastar (That Is What You
    Are)". This version of the song featured ODB (Old Dirty
    Bastard) and Mýa, and appeared on the Bulworth soundtrack.,</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
