<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tik_Tok_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tik_Tok_(song)</songId>
   <title>Tik Tok</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kesha</artistId>
      <artistName>Kesha</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2010-01-02</week>
      <week>2010-01-09</week>
      <week>2010-01-16</week>
      <week>2010-01-23</week>
      <week>2010-01-30</week>
      <week>2010-02-06</week>
      <week>2010-02-13</week>
      <week>2010-02-20</week>
      <week>2010-02-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/7e/TiK_ToK_-_Kesha_%28official_single_cover%29.JPG/200px-TiK_ToK_-_Kesha_%28official_single_cover%29.JPG</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Kesha+Tik-Tok.JPG</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Animal</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 7, 2009  (2009-08-07) , (See release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Conway Recording Studios, Los Angeles , California</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>Electropop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:20</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Kesha Sebert</writer>
      <writer>Lukasz Gottwald</writer>
      <writer>Benjamin Levin</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Dr. Luke</producer>
      <producer>Benny Blanco</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Tik Tok" (styled as "TiK ToK") is the lead single by
    American recording artist Kesha from her debut studio album, 
    <i>Animal</i>. Co-written by Kesha, Benny Blanco, and Dr. Luke,
    the song was released digitally on August 7, 2009 and was sent
    to U.S. radio on October 5. Lyrically, the song speaks of
    attending a party one night, coming home half-drunk, and waking
    up the next morning surrounded by 'beautiful women'. The song
    has received mixed reviews from music critics with some
    praising its lyrics and celebration of party lifestyle. Others
    have criticized the song for sounding 'irritating', while it
    has been compared to other particular tracks performed by the
    likes of Lady Gaga, Kylie Minogue and Uffie.</p>
      <p>"Tik Tok" was co-written by Kesha, Dr. Luke and Benny Blanco
    and was co-produced by Dr. Luke and Benny Blanco. The song took
    three takes to get right as Kesha jokingly "white-girl rapped"
    over the beat. At one point, she had wanted to rewrite the
    verses of the song because she did not think they were funny or
    clever.</p>
      <p>In an interview with 
    <i>Esquire</i>, Kesha described her songwriting process, saying
    that after a night out returning home half-drunk stumbling, she
    would usually write down a few words of a song. The next
    morning, she would wake up with the story wanting to be told.
    She related her songwriting process to "Tik Tok",</p>
      <p>"One morning I just woke up, and I live in this house with
    I-don't-even-know-how-many roommates — it's this Laurel Canyon
    house with seven rooms and roommates fluctuating monthly". She
    later added, "I woke up one day after we went to a party, and I
    was surrounded by ten of the most beautiful women you've ever
    seen. And I was like, I'm like P. Diddy — there's no man like
    this in the entire world. So that became the first line of the
    new single, and we just went from there. It's a daily process
    in my life."</p>
      <p>Kesha elaborated on the theme of the song to 
    <i>PopEater</i>,</p>
      <p>"I just really wanted to embody the lifestyle that I live,"
    [...] "We're all young and broke and it doesn't matter. We can
    find clothes on the side of the street and go out and look
    fantastic, and kill it. If we don't have a car that doesn't
    stop us, because we'll take the bus. If we can't afford drinks,
    we'll bring a bottle in our purse. It's just about not letting
    anything bring you down."</p>
      <p>The song utilizes a minimalist "video-game beat"
    interspersed with handclaps and synths. It is sung in the
    chorus and rapped in the verses, enhanced by Auto-Tune in some
    places and features a line by Diddy.</p>
      <p>"Tik Tok" was used to promote season six of 
    <i>Project Runway</i>and was featured in the 2009 reboot of 
    <i>Melrose Place</i>and on an episode of 
    <i>The Hills</i>. The first televised performance of the song
    was a part of 
    <i>MTV Push</i>, a program broadcast on MTV Networks worldwide.
    Kesha also performed the song at the 2009 Z100 Jingle Ball held
    on December 11 in Madison Square Garden. To promote the album 
    <i>Animal</i>, she made appearances on the 
    <i>It's On with Alexa Chung</i>, 
    <i>The Wendy Williams Show</i>, 
    <i>Lopez Tonight</i>, 
    <i>Late Night with Jimmy Fallon</i>, 
    <i>The Tonight Show with Conan O'Brien</i>and 
    <i>The Ellen DeGeneres Show</i>to perform the song. The song
    was featured in the movie 
    <i>Percy Jackson &amp; the Olympians: The Lightning
    Thief</i>.</p>
      <p>The song received mixed reviews, with the most positive
    coming from Kelsey Paine of 
    <i>Billboard</i>who said the song was "a love letter to DJs
    everywhere, with hand claps that build to a crescendo of pure,
    infectious dance-pop." Jim Farber of the New York 
    <i>Daily News</i>called the song "a vintage lick of dance candy
    too tooth-rottingly sweet to resist." Fraser McAlpine of the
    BBC gave the song four out of five stars, noting its
    similarities to "Just Dance" and their partying subject matter,
    but concedes that "[s]he does make it sound kinda fun though."
    He goes on to say that "Tik Tok" "ha[d] 'hit' written all over
    it" and that "you just can't see it cos it's too damn dirty."
    Billy Johnson, Jr. of Yahoo compared "Tik Tok" to the 80's
    L'Trimm hit, "Cars that Go Boom" and notes that Kesha has
    "take[n] on L'Trimm's vocal styling for her own hit." He
    elaborates, saying "[t]he L'Trimm influence on the song is
    obvious as Kesha borrows Lady Tigra and Bunny D's slurred
    cadence and airy persona."</p>
      <p>Jonah Weiner of 
    <i>Slate Magazine</i>gave the song a negative review quoting
    "The song sets up ship on the fault line between charmingly
    daft and deeply irritating." He then continued, making
    comparisons regarding other artists stating "The rapped verses
    are sub-Fergie-grade, proudly stuffed with groaners and
    to-hell-with-the-expiration-date slang." Weiner also made
    comment that the plotline plays a sequel to "Just Dance" by
    Lady Gaga: "girl wakes up drunk, stays drunk, finds a dance
    floor and (spoiler alert) gets even drunker." He noted that
    "Some listeners probably noticed a more-than-passing similarity
    between the song and "Pop the Glock", a minor 2006 club hit by
    the French-American sorta-rapper Uffie, who records for the
    small Parisian dance label Ed Banger." He then said the song
    "rides a minimalist, 8-bit-video-game beat; "Pop the Glock" is
    built around a snare drum machine pattern. Kesha's
    faux-bad-girl rhymes are tweaked by AutoTune; Uffie's
    faux-bad-girl rhymes are run through a vocoder effect, which
    supplies the song with its only hint of melody."</p>
      <p>Jon Caramanica of the 
    <i>The New York Times</i>described the song as "a zippy and
    salacious celebration of late nights and mornings-after." He
    noted that "[s]ome have compared Kesha, unfavorably, to Uffie,
    who is signed to the influential French electronic music label
    Ed Banger and whose sass-rap predated Kesha’s by a couple of
    years." He also postulated, "If anyone should feel fleeced by
    "Tik Tok", though, it’s Lady Gaga, who probably hears
    significant chunks of her hit "Just Dance" in its melody and
    subject matter." Comparing Uffie and Kesha, Complex said that
    "[i]t’s no doubt that Kesha’s strong, catchy vocals" were
    reminiscent of Uffie, but said that "her beats (created by Dr.
    Luke) veer more towards the over-produced sounds of Lady Gaga
    and Sean Kingston than the creative blips we hear from Uffie’s
    Ed Banger beatmakers."</p>
      <p>Rohin Guha of 
    <i>BlackBook Magazine</i>noted similarities of the song with
    "Love At First Sight" by Australian pop singer Kylie Minogue,
    saying "We drew the conclusion that Kesha copped that song’s
    signature synth riff. More problematic, Team Kesha did a pretty
    lousy job covering up the theft. We weren’t alone in unearthing
    this stark similarity, however." He continued stating "Minogue
    didn’t employ the sound of Super Mario jumping over a koopa
    shell as a dance beat. And whereas "Tik Tok" is a song about
    promiscuity, "Love At First Sight" is about monogamous happily
    ever afters. But differences end there. Because once you
    identify "Tik Tok"'s riff as an almost beat-for-beat carbon
    copy of “Love“‘s driving force, it kind of takes the punch out
    of Kesha and a song so charmingly ridiculous in its ability to
    summit the American charts."</p>
      <p>James Reed of 
    <i>The Boston Globe</i>said "Say what you will about last
    year’s big bubblegum anthems - from Miley Cyrus’s "Party in the
    U.S.A." to Lady Gaga’s string of pop confections - but compared
    to "Tik Tok", those songs are practically masterpieces written
    by Bob Dylan and produced by Phil Spector."</p>
      <p>A parody of Tik Tok has been released by British band The
    Midnight Beast in January 2010. The parody charted in Australia
    and Ireland.</p>
      <p>"Tik Tok" made its chart debut on the official New Zealand
    Singles Chart at number seven on the issue dated October 5,
    2009. The following week, it moved up to number one. It held
    the top spot for a total of five consecutive weeks. The song
    also charted in Australia where it debuted on the ARIA Charts
    at number twenty-eight, and reached number one on its third
    week on the chart. In Europe, the song debuted at number
    thirty-eight in Sweden on the issue dated October 23, 2009 and
    managed to peak at number three. The song debuted at
    thirty-nine in Denmark and peaked at number six. In Norway, the
    song debuted at number eleven and peaked at number three. The
    song also charted in both the Flanders and Wallonia regions of
    Belgium, peaking at number four and one respectively. In
    Finland, the song debuted at number sixteen and peaked at
    number seven. It debuted on the official UK Singles Chart at
    number six on November 8, 2009 and over a period of just under
    three months climbed to a peak of number four on January 3,
    2010 based on downloads alone. It has sold a total of 442,287
    copies in the UK.</p>
      <p>On the week ending October 24, 2009, "Tik Tok" made its
    debut on the Hot 100 at number seventy nine. It topped the
    chart on the issue dated January 2, 2010 as the first number
    one of the new decade, and so far topped the chart for nine
    consecutive weeks. This became the first number one solo single
    by the artist, and second overall after appearing on "Right
    Round" with Flo Rida earlier in 2009, although she was not
    officially credited. On the week ending December 27, 2009, the
    song broke records in the United States after selling 610,000
    digital downloads, the highest ever by a female artist since
    tracking began in 2003 and second highest overall, behind
    "Right Round". It was reported on January 24, 2010 that "Tik
    Tok" has sold a total of 3 million downloads in the country
    alone.</p>
      <p>"Tik Tok" made its first ever chart appearance in Canada,
    where the song debuted at sixty-seven on the Canadian Hot 100.
    It ascended to number one seven weeks after its debut, where it
    stayed for nine non-consecutive weeks.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by Syndrome and begins with
    Kesha awaking from a bathtub in a home as she stumbles out and
    begins to look for a toothbrush in the restroom. She makes her
    way down a staircase looking at the picture lining the wall. It
    becomes apparent that she isn't in her own house because she is
    not present in the family portrait hanging from the wall. Kesha
    makes her way to the kitchen, walking in on the family having
    breakfast startling them. She shrugs and then leaves the home
    as the family gets up and follows her. When she arrives at the
    sidewalk, she picks up a gold bicycle lying against a fallen
    fence and rides off. Kesha meets a group of children where she
    trades the bicycle for their boombox. The video cuts to another
    scene where she rejects a guy that is walking down the street
    and looking at her, and is picked up by a man portrayed by
    Simon Rex who drives her in a gold 1978 Trans Am. They are
    pulled over by the police who handcuff Kesha. The scene then
    pans to her singing while standing up in the convertible with
    the handcuffs hanging from one of her arms as she dangles it in
    front of the camera. The next scene showcases Kesha in an empty
    room filled with glitter. She then attends a party with Barry
    for the final scene. The video comes to an end with Kesha lying
    in a different bathtub from the one she woke up in. The gold
    car used in the video belonged to Kesha and the video was shot
    in Kesha's old neighborhood. The final party scene was shot at
    one of her friend's house they called 'The Drunk Tank'.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
