<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nature_Boy 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nature_Boy</songId>
   <title>Nature Boy</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nat_King_Cole</artistId>
      <artistName>King Cole</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1948-05-15</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Nature Boy" is a song by eden ahbez, published in 1947. The
    song tells a fantasy of a "strange enchanted boy... who
    wandered very far" only to learn that "the greatest thing...
    was just to love and be loved in return". Nat Cole's 1948
    recording of the song was a major hit, and "Nature Boy" has
    since become a pop and jazz standard, with dozens of major
    artists interpreting the song.</p>
      <p>The first two measures of the song's melody parallel the
    melody of the second movement in Antonín Dvořák's Piano Quintet
    No. 2 in A, Op. 81 (1887). It is unknown if Ahbez was familiar
    with Dvořák's piece, or if he arrived at the same melodic idea
    independently.</p>
      <p>The content of the song is based on a 1940s Los
    Angeles-based group called "Nature Boys," of which ahbez
    himself was a member.</p>
      <p>An alternative origin story appears in the autobiography of
    Yiddish theater star/producer Herman Yablokoff (excerpted in
    "Memoirs of the Yiddish Stage"), which states that the melody
    had been affixed to a lyric called "Shvayg, Mayn Harts" ("Hush,
    My Heart") which Yablokoff performed in his play "Papirosn" in
    1935.</p>
      <p>Written as a pop ballad, "Nature Boy" follows an "A,B"
    format, with both section being melodically and harmonically
    similar until the final 4-bar phrase of each. The primary
    melodic theme is a pickup note on the 5 of the minor i chord,
    then three notes descending on a minor triad above the pickup
    note. An ascending line over the diminished ii chord returns to
    the initial minor triad.</p>
      <p>The harmonic structure makes frequent use of the standard
    ii-V-i progression in the key of D minor. The second 4-bar
    section featured a chromatic descending line based on the
    lowering of the tonic (Dm, Dm, Dm, Dm). The same descending
    line then continues through Gm, Dm, then finally ending with a
    whole-step down to the G in the chord Em.</p>
      <p>"Nature Boy" was a primary theme of the score for the 1948
    motion picture 
    <i>The Boy with Green Hair</i>. The original version of the
    song was used for it.</p>
      <p>The tune and lyrics feature prominently in the 1993 film 
    <i>Untamed Heart</i>. Versions by Roger Williams and Nat King
    Cole are used. The 2001 movie Moulin Rouge! also opens with a
    slow, deliberate vocal rendition of "Nature Boy." Its
    soundtrack includes a rendition by David Bowie with Massive
    Attack.</p>
      <p>The writing of "Nature Boy" is the theme of a 2000 Canadian
    TV film of the same title, directed by Kari Skogland. In the
    film, nomadic poet and songwriter eden ahbez, interpreted by
    Callum Keith Rennie, writes a tune for Nat King Cole in 1947,
    after falling in love with a woman named Anna Jacobs. Nat
    records the song and the rest is history.</p>
      <p>A recording by Kate Ceberano featured in the film "The
    Crossing" (1990).</p>
      <p>The song is performed in a jazz improvisation in a club in
    the film 
    <i>Angel Eyes</i>, also released in 2001. The rendition is
    featured on the soundtrack performed by Jon Hassell(Trumpet)
    with Ronu Majumdar (flute).</p>
      <p>Prominent versions (vocal and instrumental):</p>
      <p>The most successful version was recorded by Nat King Cole,
    which was released by Capitol Records as catalog number 15054.
    The record first reached the Billboard charts on 16 April 1948
    and stayed for 15 weeks, peaking at #1.</p>
      <p>The Dick Haymes recording was released by Decca Records as
    catalog number 24439. The record first appeared on the
    Billboard charts on 4 June 1948 and lasted 4 weeks, peaking at
    #16.</p>
      <p>The Frank Sinatra recording was released by Columbia Records
    as catalog number 38210. It first reached the Billboard charts
    on 28 May 1948 and lasted 4 weeks, peaking at #18.</p>
      <p>Bobby Darin recorded a version, which entered the US Cash
    Box chart on 10th June 1961, peaking at No.31 on 15th July
    1961. The song also entered the UK singles chart on 6th July
    1961, peaking at No.24 during a 7-week chart run.</p>
      <p>Cher recorded a version as a tribute to her late former
    husband, Sonny Bono.</p>
      <p>Grover Washington, Jr. recorded a version on his 1994 album 
    <i>All My Tomorrows</i>.</p>
      <p>Celine Dion performed the song as part of her 
    <i>A New Day...</i>concert at Caesars Palace. The song appeared
    on her 2002 album 
    <i>A New Day Has Come</i>and on her 2004 live album 
    <i>A New Day... Live in Las Vegas</i>.</p>
      <p>Abbey Lincoln recorded a version on her jazz album 
    <i>A Turtle's Dream</i>.</p>
      <p>Soul trio Central Line (band) covered the song in 1983.</p>
      <p>Vinicius de Moraes recorded a version in 1975, in the album
    "the poet &amp; the guitar" with the guitar player
    Toquinho.</p>
      <p>The Great Society (band) recorded a cover of the song in
    1966, which is featured in their 1968 album 'How it Was'.</p>
      <p>Mina recorded a version on her jazz album "Mina 25" in
    1983.</p>
      <p>A parody named "Serutan Yob" was recorded by Red Ingle and
    his Natural Seven. It was released by Capitol Records as
    catalog number 15210. The record first reached the Billboard
    magazine charts on 1 October 1948 and lasted 4 weeks on the
    chart, peaking at #24.</p>
      <p>There was also a version named "Serutan Yob" by Yma Sumac in
    the 1950s.</p>
      <p>Psychedelic rock band Gandalf recorded a version on their
    self-titled album for Capitol in 1969.</p>
      <p>Jamie Cullum also played the song live for some of his
    concerts during his 
    <i>Catching Tales</i>tour.</p>
      <p>David Bowie's version was a major theme in the musical film 
    <i>Moulin Rouge!</i>(2001). The version contained within the
    film was, however, sung by cast member and actor John Leguizamo
    as the character of Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec during the
    introductory scenes to the film. Some of the premise for the
    film was based on the lyrics, in particular the lines "There
    was a boy... A very strange, enchanted boy." The lyric "The
    greatest thing you'll ever learn is (just) to love and be loved
    in return" is used throughout the film. Massive Attack produced
    a version for the film's closing credits using the Bowie vocal.
    Both versions appear on the film's soundtrack.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
