<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celebration_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celebration_(song)</songId>
   <title>Celebration</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kool_%26_the_Gang</artistId>
      <artistName>Kool &amp; the Gang</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1981-02-07</week>
      <week>1981-02-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/2c/Celebration_single.jpg/200px-Celebration_single.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Kool-the-Gang+Celebration.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Celebrate!"The Ultimate Collection"</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 1980</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" vinyl single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:42 (7" version)</length>
      <length>5:00 (Album version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Mercury Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Donna Johnson</writer>
      <writer>Claydes Charles Smith</writer>
      <writer>Earl Eugene Toon Jr.</writer>
      <writer>James "J.T." Taylor</writer>
      <writer>Ronald Nathan Bell</writer>
      <writer>George Melvin Brown</writer>
      <writer>Dennis Ronald Thomas</writer>
      <writer>Eumir Deodato</writer>
      <writer>Robert Spike Mickens &amp; Robert Earl Bell</writer>
      <writer>Kool &amp; the Gang</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Celebration" is a song released in 1980 by Kool &amp; the
    Gang from their album 
    <i>Celebrate!</i>. It reached number one on the Billboard Hot
    100 chart on February 7, 1981 and held that position until
    February 20, 1981. Late in 1980, the song had also reached
    number one on both the Billboard Dance and R&amp;B charts. The
    song dominated the radio for nearly the entire year, and is
    still heard today at weddings and parties. It was also an
    international hit, reaching number 7 in the UK, and a version
    was recorded with a Spanish language vocal for relevant
    markets.</p>
      <p>It is also a popular anthem for sporting events; for
    example, it is played over the PA system after Oakland
    Athletics, Detroit Tigers, Hagerstown Suns, and Milwaukee Bucks
    victories. The indoor soccer team, the Baltimore Blast plays
    this song when they score a goal and win the game.</p>
      <p>The song is also notable for having played when the
    remaining American hostages returned home following the
    1979-1981 Iran Hostage Crisis. It was also rewritten in 1984 as
    the jingle for Diet Orange Crush.</p>
      <p>The song has been remade by Dragon, Kylie Minogue and Jump 5
    for the soundtrack.</p>
      <p>The song was one of the big musical numbers in the film 
    <i>Muppets from Space</i>, where it was sung by Gonzo's
    family.</p>
      <p>The song was featured in the episode "Everybody Hates
    Tattaglia" from the series 
    <i>Everybody Hates Chris</i>, which aired on October 3,
    2008.</p>
      <p>The song is featured on the video game 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution</i>.</p>
      <p>The song is featured in the computer game Leisure Suit
    Larry: Love for Sail! at the end of the game.</p>
      <p>"Celebration" was also covered as a 1992 single by
    Australian singer Kylie Minogue. It was recorded by Minogue in
    1991 for her fourth studio album, 
    <i>Let's Get To It</i>, but it was not included, later
    appearing on the 1992 
    <i>Greatest Hits</i>album. It was released as a single, peaking
    at number 20 in the UK and number 21 in Australia with the
    music video filmed in Rio de Janeiro. It remains a live
    favourite, being performed on her On a Night Like This tour in
    2001 as well as at the opening ceremony of the Paralympics in
    2000. Minogue's rendition of the song was used in commercials
    for Ford Motor Company truck commercials in the United States
    in 2005 and 2006.</p>
      <p>One of Minogue's least commercially popular singles, it has
    been cited many times as one of her favourite songs, and unlike
    "Finer Feelings" and "What Kind of Fool (Heard All That
    Before)", "Celebration" was included on her greatest-hits
    compilation 
    <i>Ultimate Kylie</i>. The techno-rave mix of the track
    features on the 
    <i>Kylie's Non-stop History 50+1</i>album. This song was the
    last single with PWL and Stock Aitken Waterman.</p>
      <p>CD Single</p>
      <p>7" Single</p>
      <p>12" Single</p>
      <p>Australian CD Single</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
