<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sukiyaki_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sukiyaki_(song)</songId>
   <title>Sukiyaki</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kyu_Sakamoto</artistId>
      <artistName>Kyu Sakamoto</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1963-06-15</week>
      <week>1963-06-22</week>
      <week>1963-06-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/dc/SukiyakiCover.jpg/200px-SukiyakiCover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Kyu-Sakamoto+Sukiyaki.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Sukiyaki and Other Japanese Hits (US)</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1961 (Japan) , 1963 (US, UK)</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>J Pop</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:05</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Toshiba-EMI (Japan) , Capitol (US) , HMV (UK)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Rokusuke Ei and Hachidai Nakamura</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Ue o muite arukō" (上を向いて歩こう "[I] shall walk looking up") is
    a Japanese song that was performed by Japanese crooner Kyu
    Sakamoto, and written by Rokusuke Ei and Hachidai Nakamura. It
    is best known under its alternative title "Sukiyaki" in
    English-speaking parts of the world. The song reached the top
    of the Hot 100 charts in the United States in 1963, and was the
    only Japanese language song to do so. In total it sold over 13
    million copies internationally. The original Kyu Sakamoto
    recording also went to number eighteen on the R&amp;B chart.
    The recording was originally released in Japan by Toshiba in
    1961. It topped the Popular Music Selling Record chart in the
    Japanese magazine 
    <i>Music Life</i>for three months. Well-known English-language
    cover versions include a 1981 cover by A Taste of Honey and a
    1995 cover by 4 P.M.</p>
      <p>The lyrics tell the story of a man who looks up and whistles
    while he is walking so that his tears won't fall. The verses of
    the song describe him doing this through each season of the
    year. The English lyrics of the version recorded by A Taste of
    Honey are not a translation of the original Japanese lyrics but
    a completely different set of lyrics set to the same basic
    melody. Probably the nearest translation, at least in feel, was
    recorded by US soul singer Jewel Akens, on ERA records, as "My
    First Lonely Night" which, although not a literal translation,
    tells a similar story. A lonely man walks through the night,
    after losing his love.</p>
      <p>In 1963, the British record label Pye Records released a
    cover version of the song by Kenny Ball and his Jazzmen. They
    were concerned that English-speaking audiences might find the
    original title too difficult to remember/pronounce, so they
    gave it the new title of "Sukiyaki'". This title was retained
    when Capitol Records in the United States, and His Master's
    Voice (HMV) in the UK, released Kyu Sakamoto's original version
    a few months later.</p>
      <p>The title, sukiyaki (which is a Japanese steamboat dish),
    has nothing to do with the lyrics or the meaning of the song;
    the word served the purpose only because it was short, catchy,
    recognizably Japanese, and more familiar to most English
    speakers. A 
    <i>Newsweek</i>columnist noted that the re-titling was like
    issuing "Moon River" in Japan under the title "Beef Stew."</p>
      <p>Sakamoto's follow-up to "Sukiyaki," "China Nights (Shina no
    Yoru)," charted in 1963 at number fifty-eight. That was the
    last song by an artist from Japan to reach the U.S. pop charts
    for sixteen years, until the female duo Pink Lady had a top
    forty hit in 1979 with their English-language song "Kiss In The
    Dark".</p>
      <p>Several artists have recorded cover versions of the song,
    while others have written and/or performed songs based on the
    melody. A 1981 cover by A Taste of Honey reached number three
    on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 chart (reaching number one on the
    adult contemporary and R&amp;B charts),. while a 1995 version
    by 4 P.M. reached number eight.</p>
      <p>Both the 4 P.M. and A Taste of Honey versions used the same
    English-language lyrics, written by Taste of Honey's Janice
    Marie Johnson. Johnson is quoted in 
    <i>The Billboard Book of Number One R&amp;B Hits</i>by Fred
    Bronson as saying that when she translated the original
    Japanese lyrics into English, she found out that the lyrics
    could be interpreted in three ways: as a man on his way to his
    execution, as someone trying to be optimistic despite life's
    trials, or as the story of an ended love affair. "Me being the
    hopeless romantic that I am," she explained, "I decided to
    write about a love gone bad." Thus, the English version
    featured lyrics like: "In reality/You and I will never
    be/'Cause you took your love away from me." A Taste of Honey,
    who were quite popular in Japan (Johnson and her bandmate,
    Hazel Payne, often wore kimonos in concert), also considered
    their version of the song a tribute to one of the countries
    where they were most popular, and added a whispered "Sayonara"
    at the end of the song.</p>
      <p>In 2000, solo violinist Diana Yukawa recorded "Sukiyaki"
    song on her bestselling debut album (known as 
    <i>Elegy</i>in the UK and 
    <i>La Campanella</i>in Japan). Yukawa also performed Sukiyaki
    various times on the mountainside where her father, Akihisa
    Yukawa, died in the Japan Airlines Flight 123 crash with
    Sakamoto.</p>
      <p>"Sukiyaki" (English: 
    <span lang="en">
            <i>I Shall Walk Looking Up</i>
         </span>) is a single released by Selena in 1989. It was
    released as the fourth single from the 1989 self-titled album 
    <i>Selena</i>. The song received much airplay at the time of
    release. It was a Spanish version of the song (featuring the
    lyrics written by Janice Marie Johnson translated into
    Spanish).</p>
      <p>It was released as a single in the United States and Japan.
    It was included in several of Selena's greatest hits packages
    before and after her death.</p>
      <p>Rapper Slick Rick sang a verse of the Taste of Honey version
    of the song on his and Doug E. Fresh's hit 1985 song, "La Di Da
    Di"; he sang it from the perspective of an older woman who was
    infatuated with Rick. The rap duo Salt-n-Pepa then sang a
    similar verse on their own 1985 debut single, "The Show
    Stopper", which was a response to both "La Di Da Di" and the
    single to which it served as a B-side, 
    <i>The Show</i>. Snoop Dogg included the verse in his 1993
    cover of "La Di Da Di", titled "Lodi Dodi." Slick Rick also
    sang the verse in a guest appearance on Will Smith's 1999 song
    "So Fresh." Possibly in homage to Slick Rick, the verse has
    also been included, in whole or in parts, on other hip-hop and
    R&amp;B songs, including Bone Thugs-N-Harmony's "Bless Da 40
    Oz." and Raphael Saadiq's 1995 hit "Ask Of You." Mary J.
    Blige's 1997 song "Everything" Wii Music also includes this
    song in the handbell harmony section. Bob Dylan has also used
    the song as an instrumental prelude to his concerts circa
    mid-1980s.</p>
      <p>On March 16, 1999, Japan Post issued a stamp commemorating
    this song. The stamp is listed in the Scott Standard Postage
    Stamp Catalogue as Japan number 2666 with a face value of 50
    yen.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
