<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Just_Dance 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Just_Dance</songId>
   <title>Just Dance</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lady_Gaga</artistId>
      <artistName>Lady Gaga featuring Colby O'Donis</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2009-01-17</week>
      <week>2009-01-24</week>
      <week>2009-01-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/bd/LadyGagaJustDance.jpg/200px-LadyGagaJustDance.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Lady-Gaga-featuring-Colby-O-Donis+Just-Dance.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Fame</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 8, 2008  (2008-04-08)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>January 2008; Record Plant Studios , ( Hollywood, Los Angeles )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Electropop</genre>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:01</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Streamline, Kon Live , Interscope , Cherrytree</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lady Gaga</writer>
      <writer>RedOne</writer>
      <writer>Aliaune Thiam</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>RedOne</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Just Dance" is the debut single by American recording
    artist Lady Gaga. Written by Gaga, RedOne and Akon (who also
    provides additional vocals) and produced by RedOne, the song
    features labelmate Colby O'Donis. It was released in 2008 as
    the lead single from Gaga's debut album, 
    <i>The Fame</i>. The song was written by Gaga in ten minutes as
    "a happy record". An uptempo dance song, "Just Dance" also has
    influences of R&amp;B and lyrically speaks about being
    intoxicated at a club.</p>
      <p>The song has been critically appreciated with reviewers
    complimenting its club anthem-like nature and the synth pop
    associated with it. The song has also achieved commercial
    success by topping charts in the United States, Australia,
    Canada, the Republic of Ireland, the Netherlands and the United
    Kingdom, as well as reaching the top ten in many other
    countries. In the United States, "Just Dance" was a sleeper
    hit, spending almost five months on the Hot 100 before finally
    reaching the summit of the chart in January of 2009. It scored
    the third-biggest single-week sum of all time selling 419,000
    downloads in just one week and went to become the second
    best-selling digital song of all time.</p>
      <p>The music video of the song portrayed Lady Gaga appearing in
    a party where she plays the song, prompting party-goers to
    start dancing in enjoyment. Gaga compared her experience of
    shooting the video with being on a Martin Scorsese set. "Just
    Dance" was performed by Gaga in a number of live appearances
    including her first headlining The Fame Ball Tour and the
    second worldwide tour Monster Ball. In 2009, the song received
    a Grammy nomination in the Best Dance Recording category but
    lost to electronic duo Daft Punk for their song "Harder,
    Better, Faster, Stronger".</p>
      <p>"Just Dance" is written by Gaga and Akon with co-writing by
    RedOne who also produced the track. In an interview with 
    <i>Heat magazine</i>Gaga explained her inspiration for writing
    the song. She said,</p>
      <p>"I was very hungover. I wrote the song in about 10 minutes
    with [producer] RedOne. And it was my first time being in a
    Hollywood studio. Very pristine, big huge room with giant
    speakers."</p>
      <p>Gaga wrote "Just Dance" during January 2008 and according to
    her it was "hard work and a lot of people didn't believe in it
    at first". In an interview with Contactmusic.com Gaga explained
    that "Just Dance" is a happy record and is supposed to be
    appreciated by people going through rough times like losing
    jobs and homes etc. Gaga further explained with
    Artistdirect.com that she wanted to write a beautiful record
    with "Just Dance". Being asked the reason for which "Just
    Dance" has become popular, Gaga said that she thought,</p>
      <p>"Everyone is looking for a song that really speaks to the
    joy in our souls and in our hearts and having a good time. It's
    just one of those records. It feels really good, and when you
    listen to it, it makes you feel good inside. It's as simple as
    that. I don't think it's rocket science when it comes to the
    heart. I think it's a heart theme song."</p>
      <p>In March 2010 the song was released as downloadable content
    for the music-based videogame series Rock Band, along side
    "Poker Face", "Monster" and "Bad Romance" as part of "Lady Gaga
    Pack 01".</p>
      <p>"Just Dance" is an uptempo dance song. The song combines
    synths of clipped marching beats, sawing electronics and
    contains mild R&amp;B infused beats. The song is set in
    compound time with a moderate beat rate of 124 beats per
    minute. It is written in the key of C minor. Gaga's vocal spans
    the two octaves of G
    <sub>3</sub>to C
    <sub>5</sub>. The song begins with a fast tempo following by
    the synth arrangement and Gaga uttering "RedOne". The song goes
    into the same tempo during the chorus with Gaga's vocals
    spanning from B
    <sub>3</sub>to C
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♯
</span>. The chords are arranged in the progression of
F—Am—C—G—D—F—Am—C—G—D—F. Colby O'Donis sings the interlude in the
same range as Gaga. An R&amp;B influenced interlude is sung by
Gaga, after which the chorus is repeated with Colby providing
backup vocals and the marching beats. The song ends with an echoing
of the word "dance".</p>
      <p>Lyrically, "Just Dance" throws a partial tongue-in-cheek
    perspective with lyrics like "What's going on on the floor? / I
    love this record, baby but I can't see straight anymore". The
    lyrics deal with being completely intoxicated at a party. The
    opening lyric "A RedOne" has often been misinterpreted as "red
    wine" but in actuality is a reference to producer RedOne.</p>
      <p>The song has received generally positive reviews. Matthew
    Chisling of Allmusic described the song as galactic and
    compared it to "Money Honey", another track from her album.
    Alex Petridis of 
    <i>The Guardian</i>called it a "beguilingly compulsive tale of
    pulling a drug-induced whitey, with a combination of clipped
    marching beats, sawing electronics and mild R&amp;B flavour
    that bears a vague resemblance to Nelly Furtado's "Maneater".
    Ben Norman of About.com said that the song "opens the album
    like a valkyrie leading the charge [...] riding triumphant
    ahead of her army. If you don't know this song, use your
    browser. I won't waste time explaining what it sounds like."
    However he also noted that the song is not groundbreaking and
    compared it to the works of Rihanna, Chris Brown and Pussycat
    Dolls. Bill Lamb from About.com called the song tame but catchy
    enough for Gaga to be noticed by mainstream. He also added that
    "'Just Dance' has strong energy and features Lady GaGa's
    striking voice, but it ultimately adds up to rather bland
    dance-pop." Colby O' Donis' smooth vocals were also
    complimented. Evan Sawdey of PopMatters.com said that "Just
    Dance" is an intensely catchy single and is an excellent
    indicator of what the album was all about. Ben Hogwood of 
    <i>MusicOMH.com</i>praised the song saying, "You won't get many
    more catchy party odes than the chart topping Just Dance this
    year, a polished gem set to lodge in your head for the next few
    weeks." Freedom lu Lac of 
    <i>The Washington Post</i>described the song to be "filled with
    mindlessly frothy synth-pop that matches low-grade dance
    grooves with GaGa's icy, almost disembodied vocals about
    dancing bliss". Lynn Saxberg from 
    <i>The Ottawa Citizen</i>while reviewing Gaga's The Fame Ball
    Tour, called the song a perfect sing-along club anthem. Sal
    Cinquemani from Slant Magazine wrote that the song resembles
    the "desperate train wreck you're likely to encounter getting
    wasted at any dive on the L.E.S. at four in the morning" as is
    emphasized by the lyrics. Talia Kranes from BBC called the song
    irresistible and said that "the catchiness of her songs is sure
    to cement her place in the list of pop idols". However she
    mistakenly wrote the name of the song as "Let's Dance".</p>
      <p>"Just Dance" was a club-hit in United States peaking at
    number two on both the Hot Dance Airplay and Hot Dance Club
    Play charts during the summer of 2008. The song entered the Hot
    100 chart at seventy-six on August 16, 2008. It rose to number
    two on the Hot 100, after selling 419,000 in downloads as per
    the issue dated January 10, 2009. In the same issue, the song
    rose to number one on the Pop 100. The next week, the song
    finally rose to number one on the Hot 100. The single took
    twenty-two weeks to hit the top spot, which is the
    second-longest climb to number one since Creed's "With Arms
    Wide Open" took twenty-seven weeks before finally reaching
    number one in November 2000. The song also appeared on the Hot
    R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs chart where it peaked at seventy-two. On
    March 12, 2009, the single was certified three times platinum
    by the Recording Industry Association of America (RIAA) for net
    sales of three million. The song has sold over five million
    downloads in the United States to date, becoming the second
    song to reach the five million mark in paid downloads.</p>
      <p>The track debuted at number thirty-four on the ARIA Singles
    Chart on July 21, 2008, and moved up to seventeen the next week
    becoming the chart's "greatest gainer". On the issue dated
    September 15, 2008, the track topped the chart for one week
    before being replaced by Pink's single "So What". It has since
    been certified three times platinum by the Australian Recording
    Industry Association (ARIA) with sales of over 210,000 copies.
    In Canada, the song debuted at number ninety-seven on the
    Canadian Hot 100 for the issue dated June 7, 2008.. It reached
    the peak for the issue dated August 23, 2008 and was on the top
    for five consecutive weeks. The song was certified six times
    platinum by the Canadian Recording Industry Association (CRIA)
    in June 2009 for sales of 240,000 in paid digital
    downloads.</p>
      <p>In Ireland, the song debuted at number eleven on the issue
    dated January 2, 2009. On the issue dated January 15, 2009 it
    peaked the chart. The single debuted on the New Zealand charts
    at number nineteen in the same week it appeared in the
    Australian chart. It reached a peak of number three on the New
    Zealand's singles chart. It has been certified platinum by the
    Recording Industry Association of New Zealand (RIANZ). The song
    also peaked the charts in Netherlands on the issue dated
    February 28, 2009.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom, "Just Dance" debuted at number three
    on the issue dated January 4, 2009. It rose to number one on
    January 11, 2009, and remained at the top for three weeks. In
    January 12, 2009 interview, Gaga explained her feelings on
    topping the charts in the United Kingdom. She said, "It's been
    a long running dream to have a big hit in the UK - my fans
    there are so sexy and the people are so innovative and free in
    how they think about pop culture and music. I was in my
    apartment in Los Angeles getting ready to go to dance rehearsal
    when they called and told me, and I just cried." The track has
    achieved similar success throughout Europe reaching the top ten
    in countries like Austria, Denmark, Finland, Norway, Sweden,
    Switzerland and the top twenty of Belgium (Flanders and
    Wallonia) and France. Worldwide the song has sold 7.7 million
    digital copies.</p>
      <p>The video was directed by music video director Melina
    Matsoukas, and is based on the thematic content of the song of
    being in a party. The video begins with Gaga arriving with her
    dancers, Dina and Pepper, at a house party which seems to have
    ended. One of the dancers puts a Discolite Boombox on, blaring
    the music through the house. The crowd at the party appear to
    be sleeping in different areas, and are awoken by the music.
    They all start to dance, and scenes of the party are inter cut
    with scenes of a scantily dressed Lady Gaga dancing in a
    poncho, with a disco ball or in a small rubber pool playing
    with an inflated killer whale. She wears a blue, lightning-bolt
    shaped sticker beneath her right eye like that on the single
    cover, which was a tribute to her music idol David Bowie. Colby
    O'Donis also appears in the video being flanked by several
    girls during the "When I come through on the dance floor"
    interlude. Cameo appearances are made by Akon, Space Cowboy and
    fellow label hip-hop band Flipsyde. MTV called the video as an
    ode to the "Me Decade". During an interview with Australian
    radio in September 2008, Gaga said that "The whole video is
    performance art about being drunk at a party." In an interview
    with About.com when asked regarding the shooting experience of
    the music video, Gaga explained further about the video and her
    experience behind shooting it. She said,</p>
      <p>"Oh it was so fun, it was amazing. For me it was like being
    on a Martin Scorsese set. I've been so low budget for so long,
    and to have this incredibly amazing video was really very
    humbling. It was really fun, but you'll see if you ever come to
    a video shoot of mine one day – I'm very private about those
    things, I don't really talk to everybody. I'm not like the
    party girl running around. I might even seem to be a bit of a
    diva. I'm sort of with myself, in my work head space worrying
    about costumes, and if extras look right, and placement. I
    don't just show up for things, you know. That video was a
    vision of mine. It was Melina the director who wanted to do
    something, to have a performance art aspect that was so pop but
    it was still commercial, but that felt like lifestyle. It was
    all those things, I love it."</p>
      <p>Lady Gaga performed the song on many television shows in the
    United States. She appeared on 
    <i>Jimmy Kimmel Live</i>, 
    <i>The Tonight Show with Jay Leno</i>, 
    <i>So You Think You Can Dance</i>and 
    <i>The Ellen DeGeneres Show</i>. In July, she performed the
    song during the swimsuit competition of the Miss Universe 2008
    beauty pageant in Vietnam. In Australia she performed on
    Sunrise. Her performance caused controversy because of
    allegations that she was lip-synching. Gaga denied it and
    released a statement, saying:</p>
      <p>"I was sick the day of the show but I absolutely, 100 per
    cent, was singing live. [...] have never lip-synched and never
    will. Even on my worst day, I never will."</p>
      <p>She also performed it during her AOL sessions. "Just Dance"
    was added to the setlist of her first headlining The Fame Ball
    Tour where it was performed before the Encore. As the
    performance for the acoustic version of "Poker Face" ended,
    Gaga exited from the stage and a video interlude called "The
    Face" starts telling about Gaga's alternate persona Candy
    Warhol and teaching her to speak. As the video nears the end
    Gaga appears on the stage wearing a tutu shaped dress with
    pointed shoulderpads and peplum. Her dancers were clad in Louis
    Vuitton Steven Sprouse printed trousers which matched Gaga's
    shoes. The backdrop changes to show blinking disco lights and
    Gaga stands while wearing her video sunglasses which display
    the line "Pop Music Will Never Be Low Brow". A remix of the
    intro for "Just Dance" starts and Gaga starts singing it while
    moving around in choreographed dance moves as she is joined by
    her dancers on stage. During the "Half psychotic,
    synch-hypnotic" interlude, Gaga brings out her trademark disco
    stick again. The performance ends with Gaga and her dancers
    taking a bow in front of the stage and exiting with her DJ
    Space Cowboy. It was also added to the setlist of The Monster
    Ball Tour, performed as the second song of the list. After the
    opening song "Dance in the Dark", she strapped on a portable
    silver jewelled keyboard and started performing "Just Dance"
    while inside a white cube from which she emerged from the top,
    and the video screen came up. She was raised on a platform with
    a keytar over her shoulder as eight dancers in white bodysuits
    locked into steps below her.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
