<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rock_Around_the_Clock 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rock_Around_the_Clock</songId>
   <title>Rock Around the Clock " Bill Haley &amp; His Comets</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Learning_the_Blues</artistId>
      <artistName>"Learning the Blues" Frank Sinatra</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1955-07-09</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a3/Rock_Around_the_Clock.jpg/200px-Rock_Around_the_Clock.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Learning-the-Blues-Frank-Sinatra+Rock-Around-the-Clock-Bill-Haley-His-Comets.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Rock Around the Clock (original version)</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 20, 1954  (1954-05-20)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>45 rpm</format>
      <format>78 rpm single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>April 12, 1954  (1954-04-12)</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock And Roll</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:08 (see length variations )</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Decca Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Max C. Freedman</writer>
      <writer>James E. Myers (as Jimmy DeKnight)</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Milt Gabler</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Rock Around the Clock" is a 12-bar-blues-based song written
    by Max C. Freedman and James E. Myers (the latter under the
    pseudonym "Jimmy De Knight") in 1952. The best-known and most
    successful rendition was recorded by Bill Haley and His Comets
    in 1954.</p>
      <p>It was not the first rock and roll record, nor was it the
    first successful record of the genre (Bill Haley had American
    chart success with "Crazy Man, Crazy" in 1953, and in 1954,
    "Shake, Rattle and Roll" reached #1 on the Billboard R&amp;B
    chart), Haley's recording became an anthem for rebellious
    Fifties youth and is widely considered to be the song that,
    more than any other, brought rock and roll into mainstream
    culture in the United States and around the world. The song is
    ranked #158 on the 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's list of The 500 Greatest Songs
    of All Time.</p>
      <p>Although first recorded by Italian-American band Sonny Dae
    and His Knights,[2] the more famous version by Bill Haley &amp;
    His Comets is not, strictly speaking, a cover version. Myers
    claimed the song had been written specifically for Haley but,
    for various reasons, Haley was unable to record it himself
    until April 1954.</p>
      <p>The original full title of the song was "We're Gonna Rock
    Around the Clock Tonight!". This was later shortened to "(We're
    Gonna) Rock Around the Clock", though this form is generally
    only used on releases of the 1954 Bill Haley Decca Records
    recording; most other recordings of this song by Haley and
    others (including Sonny Dae) shorten this title further to
    "Rock Around the Clock".</p>
      <p>There are sources that indicate that "Rock Around the Clock"
    was written in 1953, but documents uncovered by historian Jim
    Dawson indicate it was in fact written in late 1952. The
    original arrangement of the song bore little resemblance to the
    version recorded by Haley, and was in fact closer to a popular
    instrumental of the day called "The Syncopated Clock" (written
    by Leroy Anderson).</p>
      <p>The song was credited to Myers (as "Jimmy DeKnight") and Max
    C. Freedman, although its exact authorship is disputed, with
    many feeling that Freedman wrote the song on his own. There
    were several earlier songs of the title "Rock Around the Clock"
    (by Hal Singer and Wally Mercer), but they are unrelated to the
    Freedman/Myers song. In addition, it is sometimes erroneously
    stated that "Rock Around the Clock" is copied from a late-1940s
    Big Joe Turner recording, "Around the Clock Blues". Aside from
    title similarity, however, the two songs bear little
    resemblance. There are many blues songs with the theme of
    partying or making love "round the clock", with various actions
    specified at various hours.</p>
      <p>However, the verse melody of "Rock Around The Clock" does
    bear a very close similarity to that of Hank Williams' first
    hit, "Move It On Over", from 1947. Williams' song was very
    similar to Charley Patton's "Going To Move To Alabama",
    recorded in 1930 - which itself was at least partly derived
    from Jim Jackson's "Kansas City Blues" from 1927. The song also
    uses phrases from Count Basie's "Red Wagon", first recorded in
    1939.</p>
      <p>According to the Haley biographies 
    <i>Bill Haley</i>by John Swenson and 
    <i>Rock Around the Clock</i>by Dawson, the song was offered to
    Haley in the wake of his first national success "Crazy Man,
    Crazy" in 1953, after being copyrighted with the U.S. Library
    of Congress on March 31. Haley and his Comets began performing
    the song on stage (Comets bass player Marshall Lytle and
    drummer Dick Richards say the first performances were in
    Wildwood, New Jersey), but Dave Miller, his producer, refused
    to allow Haley to record it for his Essex Records label
    (Swenson suggests a feud existed between Myers and Miller).</p>
      <p>Haley himself claimed to have taken the sheet music into the
    recording studio at least twice, with Miller ripping up the
    music each time. Nonetheless, rumors of a 1953 demo recording
    by Haley persist to this day, although surviving members of the
    Comets deny this, as did Haley himself (quoted in the Swenson
    biography) ; a late-1960s bootleg single of the Decca
    Records version of "Rock Around the Clock", with "Crazy Man,
    Crazy" on the B-side and carrying the Essex label, occasionally
    turns up for sale with the claim that it is the demo
    version.</p>
      <p>Myers next offered the song to Sonny Dae &amp; His Knights,
    a novelty all-white musical group led by Italian-American
    Paschal Vennitti. The group's subsequent recording, on the
    Arcade Records label (owned by Haley's manager, Jack Howard),
    was a regional success, although it sounded very different from
    what Haley would later record.</p>
      <p>After leaving Essex Records in the spring of 1954, Bill
    Haley signed with the then-important Decca Records label, and
    the band's first recording session was set for April 12, 1954
    at the Pythian Temple studios in New York City. The recording
    session almost failed to take place because the band were
    traveling on a ferry that got stuck on a sandbar en route to
    New York from Philadelphia. Once at the studio, producer Milt
    Gabler (Uncle of actor Billy Crystal, who had produced Louis
    Jordan as well as Billie Holiday), insisted the band work on a
    song entitled "Thirteen Women (and Only One Man in Town)"
    (previously written and recorded by Dickie Thompson), which
    Gabler wanted to promote as the A-side of the group's first
    single for Decca.</p>
      <p>Near the end of the session, the band finally recorded a
    take of "Rock Around the Clock," but Haley's vocals were
    drowned out by the band. A second take was quickly made with
    minimal accompaniment while Sammy Davis, Jr. waited outside the
    studio for his turn behind the microphone. Decca engineers
    later combined the two versions together into one version.
    (Comets piano player Johnny Grande tells a slightly different
    version, claiming that the only reason a second take was
    recorded was that the drummer made an error.)</p>
      <p>Many musicians have claimed that they performed on the
    recording session for "Rock Around the Clock." The song's
    co-writer, James E. Myers, once claimed he had played drums on
    the piece, although he also claimed to have been advising the
    sound mixer in the recording booth. According to the official
    record sheet from the session, however, the musicians on the
    famous recording are :</p>
      <p>Despite not being members of Bill Haley and His Comets,
    Gussak and Cedrone were trusted session players that Haley had
    used before. Cedrone's guitar solo was one that he used before
    on Bill Haley And The Saddlemen's version of "Rock the Joint"
    in 1952, is considered one of the classic rock and roll guitar
    solos of all time. (Cedrone died in a fall down a stairway on
    June 17, 1954 and never lived to see his contribution become
    famous and legendary.) The second instrumental break recreates
    a popular rhythm and blues "out chorus" with tenor sax and
    guitar emulating the rhythm section.</p>
      <p>In a 2005 retrospective on his uncle Milt Gabler's work (
    <i>The Milt Gabler Story</i>), Billy Crystal identifies Haley's
    1954 recording of "Rock Around the Clock" as the single most
    important song Gabler ever produced. Gabler had previously been
    responsible for the highly successful string of R&amp;B and
    jump blues recordings by Louis Jordan in the late 1940s, which
    were characterised by their strong beat, clearly enunciated
    lyrics and high production values, all features which Gabler
    sought to repeat in Haley's recordings. Also significantly,
    "Rock Around The Clock" was recorded in the very same month
    that Atlantic Records issued Big Joe Turner's "Shake, Rattle
    and Roll". In relation to "Rock Around The Clock", Gabler said:
    "I was aware that rock was starting. I knew what was happening
    in the Philadelphia area, and "Crazy Man, Crazy" had been a hit
    about a year before that. It already was starting and I wanted
    to take it from there."</p>
      <p>As Gabler intended, "Rock Around the Clock" was first issued
    in the spring of 1954 as a B-side to "Thirteen Women (and Only
    One Man in Town)." While the song did make the American 
    <i>Billboard</i>music charts (contrary to popular opinion that
    it was a flop), it was considered a commercial disappointment.
    It was not until 1955, when "Rock Around the Clock" was used
    under the opening credits of the film 
    <i>Blackboard Jungle</i>, that the song truly took off.</p>
      <p>Many versions of the story behind how "Rock Around the
    Clock" was chosen for 
    <i>Blackboard Jungle</i>circulated over the years. Recent
    research, however, reveals that the song was chosen from the
    collection of young Peter Ford, the son of 
    <i>Blackboard Jungle</i>star Glenn Ford and dancer Eleanor
    Powell. The producers were looking for a song to represent the
    type of music the youth of 1955 was listening to, and the elder
    Ford borrowed several records from his son's collection, one of
    which was Haley's "Rock Around the Clock" and this was the song
    chosen.</p>
      <p>On 9 July 1955, "Rock Around the Clock" became the first
    rock and roll recording to hit the top of Billboard's Pop
    charts, a feat it repeated on charts around the world. The song
    stayed at this place for eight weeks. The record was also no.1
    for seven weeks on the Cashbox pop singles chart in 1955. The
    Bill Haley version also hit number three on the R&amp;B
    charts.</p>
      <p>In the UK, Haley's "Rock Around the Clock" reached number 17
    on the pop charts in January 1955, four months before it first
    entered the US pop charts. (Coincidentally, it reached the same
    position as was reached by the Beatles' first single, "Love Me
    Do", in 1962). The song re-entered the UK charts to reach
    number one in November 1955, and after a three-week break
    returned there for a further three weeks in January 1956. It
    re-entered the charts again in September 1956, reaching number
    5. The song was re-issued in 1968, when it made number 20, and
    again in 1974, when it reached number 12.</p>
      <p>"Rock Around the Clock" became wildly popular with teenagers
    around the world. The single, released by independent label
    Festival Records in Australia, was the biggest-selling
    recording in the country at the time. Columbia Pictures cashed
    in on the new craze by hiring Haley and his band to star in two
    quickie movies, 
    <i>Rock Around the Clock</i>(1956) and 
    <i>Don't Knock the Rock</i>(1957). In 1957, Haley toured
    Europe, bringing rock 'n' roll to that continent for the first
    time.</p>
      <p>In 1964, Bill Haley and His Comets recorded a sequel song
    entitled "Dance Around the Clock". Haley actually recorded this
    song on five occasions (a Spanish language version for Orfeon
    Records of Mexico City and an English version for the US label
    Newtown Records (both in 1964), two live versions for Buddah
    Records recorded in New York in 1969 (neither of which were
    released for 25 years), and once more in Nashville, Tennessee
    for the Swedish Sonet Records label in 1970). Despite these
    efforts, the song was not a commercial success.</p>
      <p>Haley would re-record "Rock Around the Clock" many times
    over the years (even scoring a substantial hit with a version
    recorded for Sonet Records in 1968), but never recaptured the
    magic. In 1974, the original version of the song returned to
    the American charts when it was used as the theme for the movie
    
    <i>American Graffiti</i>and a re-recorded version by Haley was
    used as the opening theme for the TV series 
    <i>Happy Days</i>. The original version was also featured in
    the 1978 film 
    <i>Superman</i> ; it is heard playing on a car radio just
    prior to Glenn Ford's final scene in the film ; Ford, as
    noted earlier, had starred in 
    <i>Blackboard Jungle</i>. (However, when ABC broadcast the film
    on TV for the first time, they were unable to obtain the rights
    to "Rock Around the Clock" and it was replaced by another piece
    of music; the song remains in all subsequent VHS, DVD and
    television versions of the film.)</p>
      <p>During the 1970s Haley shortened his performances of "Rock
    Around the Clock", dropping one verse and the second
    instrumental break from most performances. However, his last
    known recorded performance of the song, at a November 1979
    command performance for Queen Elizabeth II, was a complete
    version.</p>
      <p>Following Haley's death in February 1981, a number of major
    tributes involving "Rock Around the Clock" occurred. That fall,
    a TV special marking the 30th anniversary of 
    <i>American Bandstand</i>saw an all-star "supergroup" perform
    the song (accompanied by 1950s-era footage of Haley and the
    Comets). In 1982, Haley's original recording was given the
    Grammy Hall of Fame Award. An excerpt from the recording was
    included in "Haley's Golden Medley", a hastily-compiled single
    in the "Stars on 45" mould which made the UK record charts in
    1982, reaching number 50. In 1989, Haley's original Decca
    recording was incorporated into the "dance mix" single "Swing
    The Mood", credited to Jive Bunny and the Mastermixers, but
    legal considerations forced the album version to substitute a
    patchwork of re-recordings from the 1950s and 1960s (in Haley's
    case, a 1968 version of "Rock Around the Clock" recorded for
    Sonet Records). Since "Swing the Mood" was still on the sales
    charts going into 1990, this means that Haley's "Rock Around
    the Clock", in one way or another, appeared on UK or US sales
    charts in five consecutive decades.</p>
      <p>"Rock Around the Clock" is often cited as the
    biggest-selling vinyl rock and roll single of all time. The
    exact number of copies sold has never been audited; however, a
    figure of at least 25 million was cited by the 
    <i>Guinness Book of World Records</i>in its category
    "Phonograph records: Biggest Sellers" from the early 1970s
    until the 1990s, when the advent of compact discs led to
    Guinness discontinuing the category. Guinness consistently
    listed "Rock Around the Clock" as having the highest claim of
    any pop music recording, coming second in sales only to Bing
    Crosby's 1942 recording of "White Christmas", which was also
    listed as having sold 25 million copies with a further
    estimated 100 million copies sold in other versions. Sales
    figures as high as 35 to 40 million have been cited in various
    reference books and by media, as have lower numbers in the
    15-22 million range, whilst a "more than 30 million copies"
    figure was quoted by Star, as early as 1983, on back cover page
    of Swenson's book. A frequently used piece of promotion
    regarding the song is that it is said to be playing somewhere
    in the world every minute of the day.</p>
      <p>Although originally released to vinyl at a running time of 2
    minutes and 8 seconds, most digital/CD releases of the original
    1954 recording, starting with the "From The Original Master
    Tapes" compilation of Bill's work with Decca Records, mastered
    by Steve Hoffman and released in 1985, clock in at 2:10. This
    is due to the inclusion of a "count-in" by one of the Comets
    (saying, "One...two") at the very start of the song. This was
    never included in the original single or album releases of the
    song. (All of Haley's subsequent studio rerecordings of the
    song run longer than 2:10 with the exception of the abbreviated
    version recorded for 
    <i>Happy Days</i>.) Versions of Haley's song that run longer
    than 2:10 will lack the electric guitar sound of Danny Cedrone
    and the double bass lines of Marshall Lytle. Any version
    recorded after the 1950s will also feature an electric bass
    player. It is these versions that are most commonly
    commercially available, especially on compilations.</p>
      <p>In tribute to the influence of the song and the movie that
    launched its popularity, the March 29, 2005 50 anniversary of
    the opening of 
    <i>Blackboard Jungle</i>was marked by several large
    celebrations in the United States organized by promoter Martin
    Lewis under the blanket title "Rock Is Fifty". Rock Is Fifty
    also hosted additional celebrations in Los Angeles in July,
    2005, as part of a "Rock Around the Clock-a-Thon" to celebrate
    the 50th anniversary of the date the song reached the No. 1
    spot on the American charts, as well as to observe what would
    have been Haley's 80th birthday. These events included numerous
    appearances and performances by surviving members of the
    original Comets, including the band's induction into the Rock
    Walk hall of fame, a performance at the Viper Room club on the
    Sunset Strip, and a special performance for employees of NASA's
    Jet Propulsion Laboratory in Pasadena to celebrate the success
    of the Deep Impact space probe. A special video of "Rock Around
    the Clock" was created to mark the occasion and was featured on
    NASA's website during July and August 2005. The anniversary was
    also marked by the publication of a book on the history of the
    song, 
    <i>Rock Around the Clock: The Record That Started the Rock
    Revolution</i>, by Jim Dawson. [3]</p>
      <p>The United States House of Representatives also recognized
    the 40th anniversary of the composing of "Rock Around the
    Clock" with a special statement by Rep. Robert A. Borski of
    Pennsylvania, which was read into the Congressional Record on
    March 31, 1993.</p>
      <p>As Bill Haley's best-known recording, there have been dozens
    of compilation album releases over the years entitled 
    <i>Rock Around the Clock</i>. The most notable of these
    compilations was the 1955 Decca Records album 
    <i>Rock Around the Clock</i>(Decca DL 8225) which contained
    most of the tracks Haley recorded as singles for the label in
    1954 and 1955.</p>
      <p>Another notable album release entitled 
    <i>Rock Around the Clock</i>was the 1970 Hallmark Records UK
    release 
    <i>Rock Around the Clock</i>(SHM 668) which was the first
    British release of a 1968 album entitled 
    <i>Bill Haley's Biggest Hits</i>which had been released in
    Sweden by Sonet Records. The album consisted of newly recorded
    renderings of Haley classics from the 1950s, along with some
    previously unrecorded songs.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
