<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/When_I_Need_You 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/When_I_Need_You</songId>
   <title>When I Need You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leo_Sayer</artistId>
      <artistName>Leo Sayer</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1977-05-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Endless Flight</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1977</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:09</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Warner</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Albert Hammond</writer>
      <writer>Carole Bayer Sager</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Richard Perry</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"When I Need You" is a popular song written by Albert
    Hammond and Carole Bayer Sager. It was first recorded by
    Hammond on his 1976 album 
    <i>When I Need You</i>. Produced by Richard Perry, Leo Sayer's
    version made number 1 on the UK Singles Chart for two weeks in
    February 1977 after three of his earlier singles had stalled at
    number 2. A massive hit worldwide, it reached number 1 on the
    Billboard Hot 100 for a single week in May 1977; the song also
    went to number 1 on the Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks. He
    performed it on the second show of the third season of 
    <i>The Muppet Show</i>.</p>
      <p>The melody of the "hook" line, or chorus of "When I Need
    You" is identical to the part of the Leonard Cohen song "Famous
    Blue Raincoat," where the lyrics are as follows: "Jane came by
    with a lock of your hair, she said that you gave it to her that
    night that you planned to go clear." The melody of these lyrics
    matches the lyrics of "When I Need You" as follows: "(When I)
    need you, I just close my eyes and I'm with you, and all that I
    so want to give you, is only a heart beat away." This
    similarity raises the question of whether or not the composers
    of "When I Need You" were aware of the Leonard Cohen song
    "Famous Blue Raincoat" and whether or not they used the melody
    from the Leonard Cohen song deliberately.</p>
      <p>The song was covered by Céline Dion, Luther Vandross, Perry
    Como, Rod Stewart (on his compilation album 
    <i>If We Fall in Love Tonight</i>), Alpha Blondy, Brotherhood
    of Man, Julio Iglesias, Cliff Richard and Clay Aiken. A Spanish
    version of the song, "Si Me Amaras (If You Loved Me)," was
    covered by Lani Hall on her 1985 album, 
    <i>Es Fácil Amar</i>. The Cantonese duet version, known as "For
    You, I'll Never Give Up," was covered by Gallen Lo and Flora
    Chan, as the theme song of Hong Kong drama 
    <i>Feminine Masculinity</i>in 1999.</p>
      <p>"When I Need You" is a promotional single from Céline Dion's
    
    <i>Let's Talk About Love</i>album, released on September 7,
    1998 in Brazil only.</p>
      <p>After Céline Dion finished her Falling into You Tour in June
    1997, she began to record her next English album. Dion and her
    manager and husband René Angélil wanted to include few cover
    versions on it. David Foster came up with the idea of recording
    Leo Sayer's hit "When I Need You." The song, recorded at
    Paramount Studios and Chartmaker Studios, was produced by
    Foster and included on Dion's 
    <i>Let's Talk About Love</i>album, released on November 15,
    1997. Céline Dion performed this song during the 
    <i>Let's Talk About Love avec Julie Snyder</i>Canadian TV show
    in late 1997.</p>
      <p>After a string of successful singles like "My Heart Will Go
    On" and "Immortality," Sony Music Entertainment decided to
    release "When I Need You" as a promotional single in Brazil
    (September 1998). Two previous singles were very successful in
    Brazil. However, with no music video and no promotion "When I
    Need You" failed to repeat the success of Céline Dion earlier
    songs.</p>
      <p>Authors of "When I Need You" worked with Dion also on
    several other songs. Albert Hammond wrote "Just Walk Away,"
    included on 
    <i>The Colour of My Love</i>album (1993) and Carole Bayer Sager
    wrote "The Prayer," which became a part of 
    <i>These Are Special Times</i>(1998).</p>
      <p>Brazilian promotional CD single</p>
      <p>On October 29, 2007, Cliff Richard released 
    <i>When I Need You</i>and reached number 38 on the UK Singles
    Chart. It is also one of the five new recordings featured in
    his latest album 
    <i>Love... The Album</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
