<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bleeding_Love 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bleeding_Love</songId>
   <title>Bleeding Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leona_Lewis</artistId>
      <artistName>Leona Lewis</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2008-04-05</week>
      <week>2008-04-26</week>
      <week>2008-05-10</week>
      <week>2008-05-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/9c/LeonaSingle-250.jpg/200px-LeonaSingle-250.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Leona-Lewis+Bleeding-Love.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Spirit</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>19 October 2007  (2007-10-19) , (see release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2007</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:24 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>4:00 (Radio Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Syco , J</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jesse McCartney</writer>
      <writer>Ryan Tedder</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Ryan Tedder</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Departure</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Bleeding Love" is a pop/R&amp;B ballad written by Jesse
    McCartney and Ryan Tedder produced for British singer Leona
    Lewis's debut album, 
    <i>Spirit</i>. The song is the album's lead single (Lewis's
    official second single following "A Moment Like This"),
    released in the United Kingdom and the Republic of Ireland in
    October 2007. "Bleeding Love" became the best-selling single of
    2007 in the United Kingdom, and, since the single's release, it
    has become a major international hit as the best-selling single
    of 2008. The single has reached number one in 34 countries,
    including the UK, Japan, and the United States. This is the
    second song to achieve this feat after "Candle in the Wind".
    The video aired on 17 October 2007, and was uploaded to popular
    video-sharing website YouTube on the same day, where it has
    garnered over 120 million views.</p>
      <p>The track has sold over 3,370,000 digital downloads in the
    United States alone, and was the best selling single there in
    2008. It was named the 17th most successful song in the US from
    2000 to 2009, on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade. The song achieved
    a similar feat in the United Kingdom where it was the
    best-selling single of 2007. 
    <i>Bleeding Love</i>has sold more than 9 million copies
    worldwide as a single putting it in the top 5 selling songs of
    the decade., "Bleeding Love" has charted within the UK top 100
    singles chart in three different years, in 2007 it peaked at
    #1, 2008 at #2 and 2009 at #97. "Bleeding Love" was nominated
    for Record of the Year and Best Female Pop Vocal Performance at
    the 51st Grammy Awards.</p>
      <p>In December 2006, Lewis won the third series of British
    reality singing contest, 
    <i>The X Factor</i>, her prize being a £1 million recording
    contract with Sony BMG, of which Simon Cowell is an A&amp;R
    executive. Cowell also mentored Lewis on the show. Cowell
    wanted Lewis's debut album to be an "incredible record" of
    original material, using some of the world's best record
    producers and songwriters.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, in February 2007, OneRepublic frontman Ryan
    Tedder and pop singer-songwriter Jesse McCartney had written
    the song "Bleeding Love" for McCartney's third studio album, 
    <i>Departure</i>. However, his record label, Hollywood Records,
    did not like the song. Tedder believed it was a "massive" song
    and the record company were "out of [their] mind". McCartney
    wanted to keep it for himself as he had a personal attachment
    to the song, but Tedder realised it would not work for him.
    Despite his own reality TV background, Tedder had previously
    made the decision not to work with contestants from the singing
    competition 
    <i>American Idol</i>, but he had not heard of 
    <i>The X Factor</i>, and on being shown a website about Lewis,
    he thought that "her voice just sounded unreal," saying that
    "from a writer's perspective, this girl — with or without a TV
    show — has one of the best voices I've ever heard." On hearing
    that Cowell was looking for songs for Lewis's debut album,
    Tedder rearranged "Bleeding Love", changed the key and tailored
    it to suit her voice. He pitched the song to Cowell, who said
    it was "the one".</p>
      <p>"Bleeding Love" is a pop song with R&amp;B undertones set in
    the key of F major. It moves at 104 bpm and is set in 4/4 time.
    The album version runs for four minutes and twenty-two seconds
    and the radio edit runs for four minutes and one second. Lewis
    performs (Bb
    <i>5</i>) during the bridge and the final chorus, and (C4)
    during each pre-chorus. The range of the song for her version
    is 1.75 octaves, from C4-Bb5. "Bleeding Love" is constructed in
    the common verse-chorus-bridge song pattern. It employs a
    church organ which is audible throughout the song until the
    bridge. Synthesized strings are also prominent throughout the
    song, which intermittently integrates wood block percussion
    throughout the track. A heavy, distorted marching band-like
    drum loop backs the song. The song employs an interesting yet
    subtle harmonic shift beginning at the bridge. A harmonic shift
    or harmonic variety generally identifies most song bridges.
    What is special in "Bleeding Love" is that the turn around from
    the common I, VI, IV, V (F, Dm, Bb, C) progression used
    exclusively up to the bridge for both verses and choruses
    shifts to focus on the relative minor: VI, IV, I/V, V (Dm, Bb,
    F/C, C). The darker quality of superimposing the second half of
    the verse, as well as the final chorus over this VI chord
    progression, in addition to resolving the song on this relative
    minor, enhances the intensity of the pain and pathos of the
    song.</p>
      <p>McCartney wrote the song about his long-term girlfriend, and
    said: "I kept thinking about being in love so much that it
    hurts. I was away from my girlfriend for four months at the
    time and I really wanted to [quit] and fly home. I was so in
    love that it was painful. It was like bleeding, it cut me
    open." The song refers to someone in a relationship who is
    extremely blinded by love. Regardless of the numerous warnings
    from her friends and the fact that she is emotionally hurt by
    her lover, she continues to love him and accepts the pain.
    Metaphorically, this is represented in him "cutting her open".
    However, all she can do is "bleed love" for him.</p>
      <p>The song's first radio play was on the BBC Radio 1 Chart
    Show on 16 September 2007, and was quickly followed by an
    online exclusive streaming by celebrity blogger Perez Hilton.
    It was reported that over 1.5 million people listened to the
    song online. The song was also Scott Mills's record of the week
    from Monday 24 September to Friday 28 September.</p>
      <p>Lewis went on a two-day regional UK radio tour to promote
    the single and album on 11 and 12 October 2007. This was
    followed by an appearance on 
    <i>This Morning</i>on 15 October. Lewis performed the song live
    on the fourth series of 
    <i>The X Factor</i>on 20 October 2007, and also made
    appearances on several other TV and radio shows such as T4,
    GMTV and 
    <i>Loose Women</i>.</p>
      <p>Lewis also performed the song at the Festival della canzone
    italiana on 29 February 2008, and on German entertainment show 
    <i>Wetten, dass..?</i>on 1 March 2008.</p>
      <p>Lewis made her US television debut on 
    <i>The Oprah Winfrey Show</i>, on 17 March 2008, where she sang
    "Bleeding Love". She has also performed on 
    <i>Good Morning America</i>on 4 April 2008, 
    <i>Live With Regis and Kelly</i>on 8 April 2008, 
    <i>Jimmy Kimmel Live</i>, 
    <i>The Ellen DeGeneres Show</i>on 11 April 2008, and 
    <i>The Tyra Banks Show</i>on 17 April 2008. Lewis performed the
    song live on the seventh series of 
    <i>American Idol</i>on Wednesday 23 April 2008.</p>
      <p>Critical reaction to the song was mostly positive, with
    entertainment website Showbiz Spy describing it as "emotionally
    fuelled", saying, "this track perfectly showcases Leona's
    impressive vocal prowess and from the moment she opens her
    mouth we are instantly reminded about her amazing voice,
    capable of heart stopping intensity and a playful light touch."
    Digital Spy's review of the song gave it four stars out of
    five, saying it is "easily the best single to be released by an
    
    <i>X Factor</i>star," and describing it as "a brilliantly smart
    pop record, managing to offer the lovelorn balladry that Lewis'
    
    <i>X Factor</i>fans are no doubt craving, while also suggesting
    a hint of street cred in the form of some beefy, vaguely modish
    beats." It came second in Digital Spy's Top 20 Singles of 2007
    announced on 31 December.</p>
      <p>However, BBC America's reviewer expressed that "the
    inventive percussion can't stop "Bleeding Love" from sounding
    dated, like filler on some long-lost, late '90s Mariah Carey
    album. It's one of those mid-tempo numbers — too slow for the
    club, too fast for the foxtrot. Actually, with its marching
    band drum beat, it sounds as much like Gwen Stefani's
    "Hollaback Girl" as a ballad can." The critic continues to say,
    "On to the positive: Lewis wisely restrains her vocals, never
    devolving into those vocal acrobatics that have historically
    plagued Christina Aguilera."</p>
      <p>
         <i>Billboard</i>'s review by Singles Review Editor Chuck Taylor
    for "Bleeding Love", the first ahead of the song's release in
    the United States, stated it was "a colossal and timeless
    debut", going on to say "not only a one-listen harmonic
    show-stopper, it is also hip, soulful, beat-rippling and an
    undeniable vocal tour de force." 
    <i>The Village Voice</i>described the song as a "perfectly
    devised emo-pop machine ... the old Mariah is jealous right
    now."</p>
      <p>"Bleeding Love" has earned Lewis numerous awards and
    nominations. In December 2007, "Bleeding Love" won The Record
    of the Year and the award for Best Track in the Virgin Media
    Music Awards 2007. In January 2008, the song was nominated for
    the British Single award at the 2008 BRIT Awards. Although the
    award was won by Take That's "Shine", it was announced that
    "Bleeding Love" had received the second highest number of
    public votes. The massive success of "Bleeding Love" earned
    Lewis the music award at Britain's Best 2008, which was aired
    on ITV1 on Friday 23 May 2008. On 3 December 2008, the song was
    nominated for Record of the Year and Best Female Pop Vocal
    Performance at the 51st Annual Grammy Awards. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine ranked the song 25th in the list
    of The 100 Best Singles of 2008. In April 2009, Tedder and
    McCartney were awarded with the Song of the Year Award at the
    26th Annual ASCAP Pop Music Awards for writing "Bleeding
    Love".</p>
      <p>"Bleeding Love" debuted on the UK Singles Chart at number
    one on 28 October 2007. With "Bleeding Love" reaching number
    one, Lewis became the first contestant from 
    <i>The X Factor</i>to achieve two UK number-one singles. Its
    seven week run at number one was also the longest by a single
    from a UK female solo artist in chart history.</p>
      <p>In Australia, "Bleeding Love" debuted at number nine on the
    Australian ARIA Singles Chart on 24 December 2007, and on 21
    January 2008, topped the chart making Lewis the first artist to
    come from a British reality music talent show to top the
    Australian charts, and the first British act to reach number
    one on the ARIA Singles Chart since Sandi Thom's "I Wish I Was
    a Punk Rocker (With Flowers in My Hair)" in early 2007. On 10
    February 2008, the single received a platinum certification,
    with sales of over 70,000. In New Zealand, Lewis became the
    first British female solo artist to have a number one single
    since the Sugababes topped the chart in January 2006; it stayed
    at number one for five weeks. It also reached number one in
    Switzerland, Norway, Belgium and the Netherlands.</p>
      <p>In the United States, the single's digital release on 18
    December 2007 led to nearly 6,000 legal downloads of the song.
    As the song was added to song rotations throughout the country,
    increased digital sales of the single led to the song's debut
    on the Bubbling Under Hot 100 Singles chart at number 11. The
    song officially debuted on the Hot 100 on 1 March 2008 at
    number 85. The song became Lewis' first U.S. top ten hit, and
    reached #1 on 
    <i>Billboard</i>s Hot 100 chart three separate times, each for
    a one-week run. It also hit #1 on subsidiary charts, including
    Hot Digital Songs , and Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks, where it
    spent 52 weeks.</p>
      <p>Lewis is the third female artist from the UK to have a
    number one hit with a debut U.S. single, following Petula Clark
    with "Downtown" (1965) and Sheena Easton with "Morning Train
    (Nine to Five)" (1981).</p>
      <p>The song has sold over 3 million in U.S. digital
    downloads.</p>
      <p>"Bleeding Love"'s U.S. chart run was atypical. After
    reaching number one for a week, it slipped to number four, rose
    to number two the next week, reclaimed the top spot on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 for another week, was succeeded by Lil
    Wayne's "Lollipop", and then returned to the number one slot,
    this time for two weeks. In doing so, it became just the second
    single to have three separate turns atop the Hot 100; Chic's
    "Le Freak" had done this January 1979, and the pattern has
    since happened twice more. During this time, the parent album 
    <i>Spirit</i>debuted at number one on the Billboard 200, making
    Lewis the first solo British artist in 18 years to
    simultaneously top both the 
    <i>Billboard</i>albums and singles charts. "Bleeding Love"
    spent twenty consecutive weeks in the Top Ten of the Billboard
    Hot 100, including ten weeks in the top two slots. On the
    Billboard End of Decade Chart, Bleeding Love reached #17,
    beating out songs from artists such as Rihanna, Katy Perry and
    Lady GaGa.</p>
      <p>The song also reached number one on the Canadian Hot 100
    dated 5 April 2008. In Spain, the single reached number two on
    the Spanish Singles Chart by PROMUSICAE. It was certificated
    Platinum with sales over 40,000 units. "Bleeding Love" was a
    hit on radio stations around the world, reaching number one in
    the airplay charts of the United Kingdom, Switzerland, Germany,
    France, Australia, New Zealand, Luxembourg, Slovakia, Latin
    America, Estonia and Japan. In the Greek Airplay Chart, it
    reached number two. In Italy the song peaked at number 2 on the
    FIMI singles chart based only on digital downloads; instead it
    peaked at number 1 on the Italian Musica&amp;Dischi singles
    chart, which is based on digital downloads and CD single sales,
    for 13 non-consecutive weeks.</p>
      <p>"Bleeding Love" was released in the United Kingdom in
    physical format on 22 October 2007, when it sold over 66,000
    copies, and topped the UK iTunes Store chart. It was reported
    to be outselling Take That's "Rule the World" by three-to-one
    in chain store Woolworths, and Britney Spears' "Gimme More" by
    ten-to-one. "Bleeding Love" had sold over 126,000 copies by the
    end of Thursday 25 October, and over 150,000 copies by the end
    of Friday 26 October. It went on to sell 218,805 copies in its
    first week, gaining the biggest one-week sales in 2007, a feat
    it maintained until "When You Believe" by Leon Jackson was
    released in December 2007, and outselling the rest of the top
    five singles combined. It had sold around 107,000 downloads and
    112,000 CD singles.</p>
      <p>In its second and third weeks on sale the single sold
    158,370 copies, and 111,978 copies respectively, bringing the
    total sales to 489,153 and making "Bleeding Love" the biggest
    selling single of 2007 after just three weeks of release. It
    stayed at the top of the UK Singles Chart for a total of seven
    weeks, and in the top three for a further four weeks. By the
    end of 2007 the single had sold a total of 788,000 copies and
    was the biggest selling single of the year. It was the first
    time a single by a UK female solo artist had topped the end of
    year singles sales chart in the 55 year history of the official
    charts. "Bleeding Love" was certified gold by the British
    Phonographic Industry on 9 November 2007, and platinum on 18
    January 2008. Currently, it has stayed in the Top 75 for twenty
    weeks, nineteen of those in the Top 40.</p>
      <p>The song has sold 940,000 copies in the UK as stated by the
    Official UK Charts Company. It also has sold over 4 million
    copies in the U.S. alone. As of 19 September 2008, the single
    has been certified Gold and Platinum and 3x platinum in the US,
    and Double Platinum in Australia.</p>
      <p>There are two music videos for "Bleeding Love". The first
    was directed by Melina Matsoukas and was filmed in Los Angeles.
    It is set in a mock apartment block and features four
    storylines about couples in different stages of relationships:
    "The video is extremely emotional and shows everything from
    first love and unbridled passion to heartbreak, loss and
    anger." Lewis stated that it is "real colourful, very funky,
    has lots of extras and I get to really perform." Melina
    explained her meaning of the video in an interview on MTV's 
    <i>Making the Video</i>, saying that the water in the video is
    a metaphor for the tenants' love problems, as if the apartments
    are bleeding love. For the video, Lewis wore a £100,000 Dolce
    &amp; Gabbana crystal-encrusted dress, which weighed
    40 pounds (18 kg). The international version of the
    video was first posted to popular video sharing website YouTube
    on 17 October 2007.</p>
      <p>Lewis filmed a second video in New York City for the US
    release of "Bleeding Love". The treatment for the video was
    written by Ryan Tedder, and centres on a storyline involving
    Lewis arguing with her boyfriend, played by model Nicholas
    Lemons. It was directed by Jessy Terrero. The video premiered
    in the United States on 29 January 2008 on Yahoo! Music, and
    was uploaded to YouTube on 30 January 2008. Its television
    debut was on 4 February 2008 on VH1 as part of their "You
    Oughta Know" campaign.</p>
      <p>The international version of the music video was nominated
    for Best UK Video at the 2008 MTV Video Music Awards. The US
    version was number one on the VH1 Year End Top 40.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
