<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue_Tango 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue_Tango</songId>
   <title>Blue Tango</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leroy_Anderson</artistId>
      <artistName>Leroy Anderson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1952-05-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Blue Tango" is a popular song with music by Leroy Anderson
    and lyrics by Mitchell Parish. It was published in 1952.</p>
      <p>An instrumental version of "Blue Tango" recorded by Anderson
    (Decca Records catalog number 27875, with the flip side "Belle
    of the Ball") reached #1 on the Billboard charts in 1952. It
    first reached the Best Seller chart on December 21, 1951 and
    lasted 38 weeks on the chart. (According to other sources, the
    Anderson recording first reached the charts on December 29,
    1951.) The same recording was released 1952 by Brunswick
    Records (United Kingdom) as catalog number 04870, with the same
    flip side.</p>
      <p>Other versions of the song which charted at that time
    included:</p>
      <p>A vocal version was recorded by Alma Cogan in the United
    Kingdom the same year. It was also featured on the first UK
    singles chart in another instrumental recording by orchestra
    leader Ray Martin. In the radio series 
    <i>Peeling Back The Years</i>, John Peel revealed that this was
    the first record he ever bought.</p>
      <p>The song was subsequently revived by Bill Black's Combo.
    This recording was released by Hi Records as catalog number
    2027, with the flip side "Willie". It first reached the
    Billboard magazine charts on December 12, 1960 and lasted 7
    weeks on the chart. On the composite chart of the top 100
    songs, it reached #16. This version (with the same flip side)
    was also released in Australia by London Records (Australia),
    as catalog number HL-1735.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
