<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It%27s_My_Party_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It%27s_My_Party_(song)</songId>
   <title>It's My Party</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lesley_Gore</artistId>
      <artistName>Lesley Gore</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1963-06-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/86/Lesley_Gore_-_It%27s_My_Party.jpg/200px-Lesley_Gore_-_It%27s_My_Party.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Lesley-Gore+It-s-My-Party.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>I'll Cry If I Want To</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 1963</released>
   <recorded>March 30, 1963</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:19</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Mercury Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Walter Gold</writer>
      <writer>John Gluck Jr.</writer>
      <writer>Herb Weiner</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Quincy Jones</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"It's My Party" is a song most famously sung by American
    singer Lesley Gore in 1963. This song hit #1 on the pop and
    rhythm and blues charts in the United States. . "It's My
    Party", peaked at #9 in the United Kingdom, becoming Gore's
    only major hit there. It was the first hit single for producer
    Quincy Jones.</p>
      <p>The song lyrically portrays the discomfiture of a teenage
    girl at her birthday party when her boyfriend disappears only
    to surface in the company of another girl who's "wearing his
    ring" to indicate she's replaced the birthday girl as his love
    interest.</p>
      <p>The song's chorus, "It's my party, and I'll cry if I want
    to... You would cry too if it happened to you," became a part
    of American pop cultural language as a phrase used to describe
    being utterly humiliated and miserable during an event that is
    supposed to be a happy occasion.</p>
      <p>"It's My Party" was written in 1962 by John Gluck, Wally
    Gold and Herb Weiner who were staff writers employed at the
    Aaron Schroeder Music firm. The demo for the song was cut by
    Barbara Jean English a girl group veteran (the Clickettes, the
    Fashions) who was then working as both a receptionist at the
    firm and, with Jimmy Radcliffe, serving as its in-house demo
    singer; Radcliffe produced the demo and according to English
    "tried to persuade Musicor [the label owned by Aaron Schroeder]
    to release it as a record, or to take me into a master studio
    and redo it, but they weren't interested."[1]</p>
      <p>The first recording of the song was by Helen Shapiro for her
    
    <i>Helen in Nashville</i>album recorded in February of 1963
    with Shapiro's regular producer Norrie Paramor and also Al
    Kasha. Shapiro would recall: "Right from the first time we
    heard the song on the rough demo back in London, we thought we
    were going to sock them between the eyes with that one";[2]
    however Shapiro's version was not one of the cuts chosen as an
    advance single from the album and by the time of the album's
    release that October the "It's My Party" track was perceived as
    a cover of Lesley Gore's hit.</p>
      <p>Lesley Gore recalls that "It's My Party" was among some two
    hundred demos producer Quincy Jones brought to review with her
    in the den of her family home in February of 1963. On hearing
    "It's My Party" Gore told Jones: "That's not half bad. I like
    it. Good melody. Let's put it on the maybe pile." The song
    proved to be the only demo Gore and Jones found agreeable. With
    Jones producing and Claus Ogerman handling arranging and
    conducting duties, Gore recorded "It's My Party" at Bell Sound
    Studios in Manhattan on 30 March 1963.[3]</p>
      <p>In March of 1963 that Phil Spector heard the demo of "It's
    My Party" while visiting Aaron Schroeder's office. Wally Gold
    would recall: "He [Spector] said, 'Great, I love it. I’m gonna
    do it with the Crystals.' We [the song's writers] were really
    excited, because that would ensure that the record was
    #l!"[4]</p>
      <p>Schroeder apparently only learned of the Lesley Gore
    recording of "It's My Party" when Quincy Jones invited him to
    hear the completed track, which Schroeder found formulaic;
    believing that Spector would be able to cut a much stronger
    version of the song with the Crystals and not wanting to lose
    Spector's goodwill, Schroeder attempted to convince Jones to
    suppress the track. Schroeder didn't mention Spector's version
    to Jones but Jones and Spector both happened to attend a
    concert at Carnegie Hall on the evening of 30 March 1963 and
    when they met outside it came up in conversation that Spector
    had recorded a version of "It's My Party" with the Crystals.
    Jones skipped the concert instead spending that night - a
    Saturday - at Bell Sound Studios making a test pressing of the
    track comprising one hundred copies which over the next two
    days Jones mailed out to radio programmers in key markets
    across the US. Gore heard her record played on the radio for
    the first time that Friday; the official release of "It's My
    Party" came later in the month with the disc ascending to #1
    nationally in four weeks.[5] [6] Jones was abroad at the time
    of "It's My Party"'s release; on his return he expressed dismay
    when Aaron Schroeder advised him that the rush release of "It's
    My Party" had precluded coining a more pleasant name for the
    singer than "Lesley Gore" to which Schroeder replied: "Didn't
    anybody tell you?...Quince, the record's number one. Do you
    really give a damn what her last name is?"</p>
      <p>"It's My Party" has also been recorded by the Chiffons, the
    Paris Sisters, Brenda Lee, Sue Thompson and Carol Welsman.</p>
      <p>In 1988 Chaka Khan reached #5 on 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Black Music charts with a track entitled
    "It's My Party" which is not a remake of the Lesley Gore hit
    but rather a composition by Cecil and Linda Womack which
    describes a similar scenario to that in the Gore hit, but with
    the party's host reacting more aggressively.</p>
      <p>Because of the pop cultural obsession with the song and the
    tragic nature of the song, Lesley Gore recorded a sequel titled
    "Judy's Turn to Cry". In the song, the teenage girl narrator
    gets her revenge on Judy after all the pain and humiliation she
    caused her. In the lyrics the narrator explicitly finds
    "foolish" how much she cried when she saw Johnny and Judy
    together, and seems determined to start anew. She kisses
    another guy in front of Johnny and Judy during another party,
    which causes a jealous Johnny to jump at and punch the other
    boy, then get back together with her.</p>
      <p>"Judy's Turn To Cry" was not quite as popular as "It's My
    Party", but still was a sizeable hit, reaching #5 on the
    Billboard charts in the summer of 1963.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
