<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mr._Sandman 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mr._Sandman</songId>
   <title>Mr. Sandman " The Chordettes</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Let_Me_Go,_Lover!</artistId>
      <artistName>"Let Me Go, Lover" Joan Weber</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1955-01-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1954</released>
   <formats>
      <format>45rpm 7-inch vinyl single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1954</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock &amp; Roll</genre>
      <genre>Swing</genre>
      <genre>Traditional Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:22</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Cadence Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Pat Ballard ("Mr. Sandman"); Stock-West ("I Don't Wanna See You Cryin'")</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Archie Bleyer</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Mr. Sandman" (sometimes rendered as "Mister Sandman") is a
    popular song written by Pat Ballard which was published in 1954
    and first recorded in that year by The Chordettes. The song's
    lyrics convey a request to "Mr. Sandman" to "bring me a dream,"
    the word "dream" ambiguously referring to a real significant
    other as well as to a sleeping dream - the traditional
    association with the folkloric figure, the sandman. The pronoun
    used to refer to the desired dream is often changed depending
    on the sex of the singer or group performing the song. Some
    time later, Ballard also rewrote the lyrics for Christmas use
    as "Mr. Santa". The song has an interesting music theoretical
    aspect, as the chord progression in the chorus follows the
    circle of fifths for six chords in a row.</p>
      <p>The Chordettes recording of the song was released on the
    Cadence Records label whose founder, Archie Bleyer, is credited
    on the disc's label as "knees played by" and orchestra
    conductor. The piano is played by Moe Wechsler. The single
    reached #1 on the Billboard United States charts and #11 on the
    United Kingdom charts in 1954. In November 1954, The Four Aces
    released a version that charted even higher in the UK, reaching
    #9 and in the same year a version by Max Bygraves reached #16
    on the UK charts. On the Cash Box magazine charts in the US,
    where all versions were combined, the song also reached #1.</p>
      <p>There are numerous recorded versions of the song including
    versions by Chet Atkins, Mocedades, Blue Diamonds, Marvin Gaye,
    The Supremes, The Puppini Sisters and Blind Guardian, and it
    has featured in a number of TV and film soundtracks including 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>, 
    <i>Back to the Future</i>, 
    <i>Philadelphia</i>and several of the 
    <i>Halloween</i>films.</p>
      <p>The "Mr. Santa" version has been recorded by Lenny Dee, Amy
    Grant, and Suzy Bogguss, among others.</p>
      <p>In 2009, Californian Youtube based duo Pomplamoose released
    a free download version for their 70,000-odd subscribers.
    Collaborating with Ryan Lerman on acoustic guitar, the track
    features Jack Conte on drums &amp; brushes, piano, keyboards, a
    toy piano, xylophone &amp; accordion, with Nataly Dawn coloring
    the song with multi tiered vocal harmonies.</p>
      <p>In 1978, Emmylou Harris, Dolly Parton, and Linda Ronstadt
    recorded a version for a planned trio album that was never
    completed. The song was released by Harris as a single in 1981
    for which she re-recorded all three vocal parts herself as
    neither Parton's nor Ronstadt's record companies would allow
    their artists' vocals on the single. Harris also included her
    version on her album 
    <i>Evangeline</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1996, German power metal band Blind Guardian released a
    single with a cover version of "Mr. Sandman". While the song
    starts in a similar mood to the original, it becomes
    increasingly aggressive, introducing heavy metal guitars in the
    second verse and a double bass drum in the third.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
