<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You%27re_No_Good 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You%27re_No_Good</songId>
   <title>You're No Good</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linda_Ronstadt</artistId>
      <artistName>Linda Ronstadt</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1975-02-15</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1963</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:18</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Vee-Jay</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Clint Ballard</writer>
      <writer>Jr.</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"You're No Good" is a song written by Clint Ballard, Jr.
    which first charted for Betty Everett in 1963 and in 1975 was a
    #1 hit for Linda Ronstadt.</p>
      <p>The original version of "You're No Good" would appear to be
    that cut by Dee Dee Warwick for Jubilee Records in 1963 with
    production by Jerry Leiber and Mike Stoller. However the song
    would first become a hit in November 1963 as recorded by Betty
    Everett for Vee-Jay Records of Chicago. The single peaked at
    number fifty-one on the Hot 100, and at number five on
    "Cashbox's R&amp;B Locations" chart. . Vee-Jay's head a&amp;r
    man Calvin Carter found the song while visiting New York City
    in search of material for his label's roster and he originally
    intended to cut "You're No Good" with Dee Clark. Carter
    recalled: "Then when I went to rehearsal with the tune, it was
    so negative, I said, 'Hey, guys don't talk negative about
    girls, because girls are the record buyers. No, I better pass
    on that.' So I gave the song to Betty Everett." During the
    playback of Everett's track her labelmates the Dells "were
    sitting on the wooden platform where the string players would
    sit....just stomping their feet on this wooden platform to the
    beat of the song as it was playing back....I told the engineer
    'Let's do it again, and let's mike those foot sounds, 'cause it
    really gave it a hell of a beat.' So we did that, and boom, a
    hit." - Carter [1]</p>
      <p>In the UK the Swinging Blue Jeans had the hit version of
    "You're No Good" reaching #3 in the summer of 1964: this
    version also charted in France at #26 and was successful enough
    regionally in the US to reach #97 on the Billboard Hot 100.</p>
      <p>Both Maria Muldaur and Genya Ravan have indicated they were
    interested in remaking "You're No Good" in the mid-70s but it
    was Linda Ronstadt who had her first #1 single with her 1974
    remake: the lead single from her Double Platinum career
    defining 
    <i>Heart Like A Wheel</i>album, Ronstadt's version benefited
    inestimably from the contribution of Andrew Gold who provided
    virtually all the track's instrumentation.</p>
      <p>"You're No Good" was also a hit for Linda Ronstadt in
    Australia (#15), the Netherlands (#17) and New Zealand
    (#24).</p>
      <p>The success of "You're No Good" set a precedent for
    Ronstadt's single releases which over the next five years would
    virtually all be remakes of classic rock and roll songs. (The
    B-side of "You're No Good": "I Can't Help It (If I'm Still in
    Love With You)" - originally by Hank Williams - was
    simultaneously a major C&amp;W hit for Ronstadt at #2.)</p>
      <p>Other artists who have covered "You're No Good" include
    Ellie Campbell, Elvis Costello, Jose Feliciano, Keith
    Hampshire, Lulu, Reba McEntire, Rosie &amp; The Originals,
    Floortje Smit, Ike and Tina Turner, Van Halen and Wild Orchid.
    The 2004 album release 
    <i>California</i>by Wilson Phillips contains a version of
    "You're No Good" which like the Ronstadt version was produced
    by Peter Asher but radically reinvents the song.</p>
      <p>Season seven of American Idol featured a performance of
    "You're No Good" by Kristy Lee Cook. Didi Benami performed the
    song on American Idol season nine.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
