<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Funkytown 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Funkytown</songId>
   <title>Funkytown</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lipps_Inc</artistId>
      <artistName>Lipps Inc</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1980-05-31</week>
      <week>1980-06-07</week>
      <week>1980-06-14</week>
      <week>1980-06-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/4/44/LippsIncFunkytown7InchSingleCover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Lipps-Inc+Funkytown.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Mouth to Mouth</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 1980</released>
   <recorded>1979</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:58/7:49</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Casablanca Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Steven Greenberg</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Steven Greenberg</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Funkytown" is a song performed by the disco band Lipps Inc.
    Released in 1980, the song expresses the pinings for a
    metaphorical place that keeps "me movin', keeps me groovin'
    with some energy". It reached No. 1 on the U.S. Billboard Hot
    100 and Dance charts in 1980, also reaching number 1 in
    Germany, Austria, Switzerland, Norway and The Netherlands. It
    reached No. 2 in the UK, Sweden and on the U.S. R&amp;B chart.
    "Funkytown" is often considered to be one of disco's last
    stands. It was Lipps Inc's only U.S. Top 40 hit.</p>
      <p>In 1980, is covered by th Spanish group Parchís, it's
    possibly the first cover of the song. It was covered, as a
    result of it's popularity like main song of La vuelta ciclista
    a España that year. It is covered completely in Spanish with
    the exception of the main word: 
    <i>Funkytown</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1981, it was covered by SNK in their licensed game
    Fantasy, released by Rock-Ola.</p>
      <p>In 1984, the British post-punk band the 012 covered it at
    about double the original speed on rock instruments, under the
    title "Funkytown People," on their album 
    <i>Let's Get Professional</i>. The performance is sloppy, with
    blurry, atonal guitar playing, and singer/guitarist Kif Kif Le
    Batter (real name: Keith Dobson) throws in lots of asides
    putting the song down. After the 012 split up, Dobson formed
    World Domination Enterprises, and re-recorded the song under
    its proper title for their 1988 album 
    <i>Let's Play Domination</i>. This performance is noticeably
    tighter than the 012's and the lyrics are played straight this
    time (although Dobson interprets "with some energy" as "It's
    Saturday"), but the guitar style remains the same. A "Let's Go
    Mix" of the song is included on World Dom's 1989 split
    remix/live album 
    <i>Love from Lead City</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1986, it was covered by Australian band Pseudo Echo, who
    gave the song a different sound, less of early eighties'
    electronica and more of later eighties' rock, including a
    guitar solo in the middle. Pseudo Echo's version spent seven
    weeks at No. 1 in Australia, (Lipps Inc's was at No. 1 for only
    two weeks in Australia), and was also a No. 6 US hit in July of
    the following year. Curiously, despite Psuedo Echo's rock-like
    arrangement, on the 12" single issue of this version, the
    actual song is labelled as Funkytown (Dance Mix).</p>
      <p>In 1995, it was covered by late Tejano singer Selena during
    her last televised concert before she was brutally murdered by
    her fan club president Yolanda Saldívar. The song was later
    released on the movie soundtrack.</p>
      <p>In 2007, it was covered by Alvin and the Chipmunks as their
    version appeared in the live-action/CGI film adaptation. Their
    version peaked at No. 86. It was also used in the video game
    Rayman Raving Rabbids 2 by Ubisoft for the music rhythm
    games.</p>
      <p>In 2009, the Swedish group Alcazar released a cover of
    "Funkytown", included on their album Disco Defenders.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
