<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stay_(I_Missed_You) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stay_(I_Missed_You)</songId>
   <title>Stay (I Missed You)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lisa_Loeb</artistId>
      <artistName>Lisa Loeb &amp; Nine Stories</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1994-08-06</week>
      <week>1994-08-13</week>
      <week>1994-08-20</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/c/ce/Lisa-loeb-stay-70436.jpg/200px-Lisa-loeb-stay-70436.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Lisa-Loeb-Nine-Stories+Stay-I-Missed-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Reality Bites soundtrack</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1994</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:04</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lisa Loeb</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Stay (I Missed You)" is a song by Lisa Loeb, which became
    her breakthrough song in 1994. It was included on the 
    <i>Reality Bites</i>soundtrack, as well as her debut album, 
    <i>Tails</i>.</p>
      <p>"Stay" ultimately went on to become a number-one hit on the
    Hot 100 chart, earning her the distinction of being the only
    artist to top the U.S. chart before being signed to any record
    label. The song reached number six on the UK Singles Chart and
    even performed the song on 
    <i>Top of the Pops</i>. It also peaked at number 14 on the New
    Zealand RIANZ Top 40.</p>
      <p>"Stay" later placed 93rd on VH1's 100 Greatest Songs of the
    90's.</p>
      <p>Loeb was discovered by actor and friend Ethan Hawke, who
    lived in an apartment across the street from her in New York
    City. She met Hawke through mutual friends in the NYC theatre
    community. Loeb had been performing "Stay (I Missed You)" to
    positive response at her shows, and Hawke gave a tape of Loeb's
    song to director Ben Stiller during the making of the film 
    <i>Reality Bites</i>. Stiller subsequently agreed to use the
    song in the film and on the film's soundtrack.</p>
      <p>This song was just named "Stay" originally. But at the time
    it was getting popular, there were several popular songs with
    "Stay" in their title (such as the U2 song "Stay (Faraway, So
    Close!)"). Because of this, "(I Missed You)" was tacked on to
    the end to differentiate it from the others.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by Ethan Hawke, and features
    Loeb (wearing a black dress and her trademark horn-rimmed
    glasses) singing the lyrics while walking around in the empty
    New York City apartment in which she lived at the time. The
    video can be described as simple as there are no use of any
    visual or audio effects.</p>
      <p>According to VH1 show 
    <i>Pop-Up Video</i>, the video was filmed in just two separate
    takes.</p>
      <p>"Stay" was covered in 2006 by Filipino singer Chris Cayzer
    for his self-titled debut album. In 2007, it was covered by
    pop-punk band New Found Glory for 
    <i>From the Screen to Your Stereo Part II</i>and featured Loeb
    on supporting vocals. Sarah Silverman performed a cover version
    of the song in an episode from the second season of The Sarah
    Silverman Program.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
