<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Loco-Motion 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Loco-Motion</songId>
   <title>The Loco-Motion</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Eva</artistId>
      <artistName>Little Eva</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1962-08-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/55/Tlm_le.jpg/200px-Tlm_le.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Little-Eva+The-Loco-Motion.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Locomotion</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 1962</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>45rpm</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Rhythm And Blues</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:27</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Dimension Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Gerry Goffin</writer>
      <writer>Carole King</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Gerry Goffin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Loco-Motion" is a 1962 popular music song written by
    American songwriters Gerry Goffin and Carole King. The song is
    notable for appearing the American Top 5 three times – each
    time in a different decade: for Little Eva during 1962 (U.S.
    #1); for Grand Funk Railroad in 1974 (U.S. #1); and for Kylie
    Minogue in 1988 (U.S. #3).</p>
      <p>The song is a popular and enduring example of the dance-song
    genre: much of the lyrics are devoted to a description of the
    dance itself, usually done as a type of line dance. However,
    the song came before the dance.</p>
      <p>"The Loco-Motion" is ranked #350 on the 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's list of "the 500 Greatest Songs
    of All Time".</p>
      <p>"The Loco-Motion" is also one of only nine songs to reach US
    #1 by two different artists.</p>
      <p>The original recording of the song was sung by Eva Boyd,
    under the stage name Little Eva. Boyd was actually Carole
    King's babysitter, having been introduced to King and husband
    Gerry Goffin by The Cookies, a local girl group who would also
    record for the songwriters. "The Loco-Motion" was the first
    release by the new Dimension Records company, whose releases
    were mostly penned and produced by Goffin and King, and reached
    #1 in China during 2001.</p>
      <p>A cover version of the song was recorded quickly by British
    girl group The Vernons Girls and scored the chart the same week
    as the Little Eva version. The Vernons Girls' version stalled
    at #47 in the UK, while the Little Eva version reached #2 on
    the UK charts. It re-entered the chart some ten years later and
    almost became a top ten again, peaking at #11.</p>
      <p>In the United States, "The Loco-Motion" was the sixth most
    successful single of 1962 according to Billboard. It was also
    the third most successful single of 1962 in South Africa.</p>
      <p>The Little Eva version of the song was featured by the 2006
    David Lynch film 
    <i>Inland Empire</i>.</p>
      <p>The widely-believed story of how the song "The Loco-Motion"
    came to be is that Carole King was playing music at home and
    Eva Boyd was doing some chores and started dancing to it; the
    dance The Loco-Motion was born. However, this is not true. Eva
    Boyd was introduced to Goffin and King and they realized she
    had a good singing voice, so they had her record "The
    Loco-Motion." Carole King stated this during an interview on
    National Public Radio (NPR) shortly after Little Eva died.</p>
      <p>As the song came before the dance, there was no dance when
    the song was originally written. When the song became a smash
    hit, Eva Boyd ended up having to create a dance to go along
    with the song. Carole King stated this in her "One to One"
    concert video.</p>
      <p>In live performances of the song, Little Eva can be seen
    doing her version of the dance.</p>
      <p>American hard rock group Grand Funk Railroad recorded a
    version of the song during 1974, produced by Todd Rundgren. The
    song appeared on their album 
    <i>Shinin' On</i>album and, released as a single, scored #1 on
    the U.S. charts. The Grand Funk version of the song featured
    guitars, several layers of harmony, and heavy drums.</p>
      <p>A cover version of "The Loco-Motion" was the debut single by
    Australian popular music singer Kylie Minogue.</p>
      <p>After an impromptu performance of the song at an Australian
    rules football charity event with the cast of the Australian
    soap opera 
    <i>Neighbours</i>, Minogue was signed a record deal by Mushroom
    Records to release the song as a single. The single was
    released on July 28, 1987 in Australia, Sweden and Italy under
    the title "Locomotion". The song was a success in Australia,
    reaching number one and remaining there for seven weeks. The
    success of the song in her home country resulted in her signing
    a record deal with PWL Records in London and to working with
    the successful team Stock Aitken &amp; Waterman.</p>
      <p>In 1988, a re-recorded version produced by Stock Aitken
    &amp; Waterman was released worldwide with the title "The
    Loco-Motion". This release again was a major success, reaching
    the top five in the United Kingdom, the United States, and
    Canada. Minogue's version of the track appeared in the 1988
    film Arthur 2: On The Rocks, starring Dudley Moore and Liza
    Minnelli.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Locomotion" was filmed at Essendon
    Airport and the ABC studios in Melbourne, Australia. The video
    for "The Loco-Motion" was created out of footage from the
    Australian music video.</p>
      <p>Near the end of 1988, the song was nominated for 
    <i>Best International Single</i>at the Canadian Music Industry
    Awards.</p>
      <p>The 1987 "Locomotion" release was a huge hit in Minogue's
    native Australia, reaching number one on the AMR singles chart
    and remaining there for seven weeks. The song set the record as
    the biggest Australian single of the decade. Throughout Europe
    and Asia the song also performed well on the music charts,
    reaching number one in Belgium, Finland, Ireland, Israel,
    Japan, and South Africa.</p>
      <p>The 1988 release of the song in the United Kingdom debuted
    at number two on the singles chart — the highest entry on the
    UK singles charts by a female artist — due to strong 7" single
    sales and radio airplay. It remained in the number two position
    for four weeks before falling to number three. With sales of
    440,000 it was the 11th best selling single of the year. The
    song became Minogue's third top five rated single in the UK and
    remains one of her most successful single releases to date.</p>
      <p>During late 1988, Minogue traveled to the United States to
    promote "The Loco-Motion", where she did many interviews and
    performances on American television.</p>
      <p>"The Loco-Motion" debuted at number eighty on the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100 and later climbed to number three for two
    weeks. The song was Minogue's second single to chart in the
    U.S., but her first to reach the top ten. It remains her best
    success in the United States. She would not even reach the top
    ten again until 2002 with the release of "Can't Get You Out Of
    My Head", which reached number seven on the chart.</p>
      <p>In Canada, the song also reached the top spot in the pop
    sales charts.</p>
      <p>Kylie performed the song on the following concert tours:</p>
      <p>The song was also performed on:</p>
      <p>Peru top.100 No.1 for 3 weeks in Nov 1988, ask peru top.100
    for info!!</p>
      <p>In 1962, French singer Sylvie Vartan recorded a version of
    the song in French called "Le Locomotion." It went to #1 in
    France on October 13, 1962 and remained there for one week.</p>
      <p>Carole King herself sings the song on her live album 
    <i>The Living Room Tour</i>released July 12, 2005. The album
    peaked at number 17 on the US album chart on July 30, 2005.</p>
      <p>She also recorded a version for her 1980 album 
    <i>Pearls: Songs of Goffin and King</i>. The album peaked at
    number 44 and spawned King's last top 40 hit to-date, One Fine
    Day, which would reach number 12 on the charts.</p>
      <p>The song has inspired dozens of cover versions over the
    years. Besides those already mentioned:</p>
      <p>Orange Range used the melody line of "The Loco-Motion" on
    their 2004 song "Locolotion" which became the number-one
    success on the Japanese singles chart. The commercially
    successful song brought about controversy because Goffin and
    King were not indicated on its songwriting credit, therefore
    their name were later added as co-writers to avoid lawsuits,
    when the song was featured on the band's 
    <i>musiQ</i>album released during the same year.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
