<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stagger_Lee_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stagger_Lee_(song)</songId>
   <title>Stagger Lee</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lloyd_Price</artistId>
      <artistName>Lloyd Price</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1959-02-09</week>
      <week>1959-02-16</week>
      <week>1959-02-23</week>
      <week>1959-03-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Stagger Lee", also known as "Stagolee", "Stackerlee",
    "Stack O'Lee", "Stack-a-Lee" and several other variants, is a
    popular blues folk song based on the murder of William "Billy"
    Lyons by Stagger Lee Shelton. The version recorded by
    Mississippi John Hurt in 1928 is considered by some
    commentators to be definitive, containing as it does all of the
    elements that appear in other versions.</p>
      <p>A cover with different lyrics was a chart hit for Lloyd
    Price in 1959; Dick Clark felt that the original tale of murder
    was too morbid for his 
    <i>American Bandstand</i>audience, and insisted that they be
    changed to eliminate the murder. In this version, the subject
    was changed from gambling to fighting over a woman, and instead
    of a murder, the two yelled at each other, and made up the next
    day. However, it was the original, unbowdlerized, version of
    Lloyd's performance that reached #1 on Billboard's Hot 100 and
    was ranked #456 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time.</p>
      <p>"Stag O Lee" songs may have predated even the 1895 incident,
    and Lee Shelton may have gotten his nickname from earlier folk
    songs. The first published version of the song was by
    folklorist John Lomax in 1910. The song was well known in
    African American communities along the lower Mississippi River
    by the 1910s.</p>
      <p>Before World War II, it was almost always known as "Stack
    O'Lee". W.C. Handy wrote that this probably was a nickname for
    a tall person, comparing him to the tall smokestack of the
    large steamboat 
    <i>Robert E. Lee</i>. By the time W.C. Handy wrote that
    explanation in the 1920s, "Stack O' Lee" was already familiar
    in United States popular culture, with recordings of the song
    made by such pop singers of the day as Cliff Edwards.</p>
      <p>In Hurt's version, as in all such pieces, there are many
    (sometimes anachronistic) variants on the lyrics. Several older
    versions give Billy's last name as "De Lyons" or "Deslile".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
