<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazed 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazed</songId>
   <title>Amazed</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lonestar</artistId>
      <artistName>Lonestar</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2000-03-04</week>
      <week>2000-03-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/23/Amazed.jpg/200px-Amazed.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Lonestar+Amazed.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Lonely Grill</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 4, 1999</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>7" 45 RPM</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1998</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Country</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:00</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>BNA 65755</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Marv Green</writer>
      <writer>Chris Lindsey</writer>
      <writer>Aimee Mayo</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Dann Huff</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Amazed" is the title of a song written by Marv Green, Aimee
    Mayo and Chris Lindsey. The first version of the song was
    recorded by the American country music group Lonestar, whose
    version was released in 1999 as the second single from their
    1999 album 
    <i>Lonely Grill</i>. Lonestar's version is their
    longest-lasting Number One single and biggest crossover hit,
    spending eight weeks at the top of the 
    <i>Billboard</i>country singles charts. A remix later reached
    the top of the Billboard Hot 100 and #2 on the Hot Adult
    Contemporary Tracks charts as well. Since the release of the
    original, the song has been covered by Bonnie Tyler and Duncan
    James, both of whom released their respective versions as
    singles, as well as Boyz II Men for their 2009 album Love.</p>
      <p>"Amazed" is a power ballad in the key of A-flat major, with
    a vocal range from F4 to A♭5. In it, the narrator states that
    he is "amazed" by his lover:</p>
      <p>Lonestar's rendition is the second single from their 1999
    album 
    <i>Lonely Grill</i>. The song spent eight consecutive weeks at
    #1 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Country Singles &amp; Tracks chart that
    same year. With this accomplishment, it set a record for the
    longest run at Number One on the country charts since the
    Nielsen Broadcast Data Systems was initiated in 1990. This run
    was later tied by Alan Jackson and Jimmy Buffett's 2003 single
    "It's Five O'Clock Somewhere", which spent eight
    non-consecutive weeks at Number One. "Amazed" spent forty-one
    weeks on the country singles charts, giving it the
    second-longest chart run of any country single in the 1990s. In
    addition, the single crossed over into the pop airwaves
    entering the Billboard Hot 100 at #81. It peaked at #24 on
    before falling off the Hot 100.</p>
      <p>"Amazed" was then remixed for pop radio (a tactic commonly
    used to present country-leaning songs to non-country audiences)
    and the new mix's popularity prompted the single to re-enter
    the Hot 100 at #45. On this second chart run, the remixed
    version helped the song hit #1 on March 4. In doing so, it
    became the first country song to top the pop charts since Dolly
    Parton and Kenny Rogers' 1983 duet "Islands in the Stream". It
    also made Lonestar the first country band to place a song in
    the Top Ten of the Hot 100 year-end countdown. All remixes of
    the song made the single spend a combined total of 55 weeks in
    the Hot 100, and 41 weeks on Hot Country Singles &amp;
    Tracks.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom, Lonestar's version of "Amazed"
    reached #21 and spent 22 weeks in the charts. It holds the
    record for the longest number of consecutive weeks spent in the
    UK Singles Chart without reaching the top 20. According a 2009
    survey, this ballad is the most popular song choice for UK
    newly-weds' first dances. The survey was conducted by asking
    2,000 wedding videographers which were the most requested first
    songs at the weddings they attended.</p>
      <p>Trey Fanjoy directed the music video for Lonestar's
    rendition. It was released in July 2000. It alternates between
    shots of the band performing the song in a dark room, and a
    female making seductive poses.</p>
      <p>Amazed [SINGLE]</p>
      <p>Amazed [UK SINGLE]</p>
      <p>Amazed Pt. 2</p>
      <p>The song was covered in 2006 by Duncan James for his album 
    <i>Future Past</i>. It was released as a download only single
    on 12 March 2007 following poor sales of his previous singles
    and his album. The single was released in some European
    countries, such as Germany, which the single was released and
    peaked at #181 on the Germany Singles Chart. In 2007, former X
    Factor contestant Ben Mills recorded a version for his debut
    album 
    <i>Picture of You</i>. Bryan Adams also recorded this song.</p>
      <p>CD 1</p>
      <p>CD 2</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
