<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macarena_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macarena_(song)</songId>
   <title>Macarena" (Bayside Boys Mix)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Los_Del_Rio</artistId>
      <artistName>Los Del Rio</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1996-08-03</week>
      <week>1996-08-10</week>
      <week>1996-08-17</week>
      <week>1996-08-24</week>
      <week>1996-08-31</week>
      <week>1996-09-07</week>
      <week>1996-09-14</week>
      <week>1996-09-21</week>
      <week>1996-09-28</week>
      <week>1996-10-05</week>
      <week>1996-10-12</week>
      <week>1996-10-19</week>
      <week>1996-10-26</week>
      <week>1996-11-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/aa/MacarenaLosDelRio.jpg/200px-MacarenaLosDelRio.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Los-Del-Rio+Macarena-Bayside-Boys-Mix.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>A mí me gustaFiesta Macarena</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 15, 1995 ( U.S. )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1995</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Latin</genre>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>Flamenco</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:53</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Rogerio Rodrigues</writer>
      <writer>Marcia Freitas Rodrigues</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Macarena" is a Spanish song by Los del Río about a woman of
    the same name. It was popular between 1995 and 1996, although
    it continues to have a cult following to this day.</p>
      <p>The "Bayside Boys Mix" became the most well known version of
    the song, as it had English lyrics, sung by uncredited artist, 
    <i>Carla Vanessa</i>. Often mistaken for the original female
    vocals, sung by Alaska.</p>
      <p>The song's dance remains arguably the most popular out of
    any club single ever.</p>
      <p>The song became the second longest running #1 and best
    selling debut single of all time in the U.S. It was ranked the
    "#1 Greatest One-Hit Wonder of all Time" by VH1 in 2002.</p>
      <p>The song uses a type of clave. The song ranks at #5 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top 100.</i>It also ranks at #1 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Latin Songs</i>.</p>
      <p>As a result of their lounge act, Los del Río were invited to
    tour South America in March 1992 and, while visiting Venezuela,
    they were invited to a private party held by the Venezuelan
    empresario (of Cuban descent) Gustavo Cisneros. Many prominent
    Venezuelans were in attendance that night, including former
    president Carlos Andrés Pérez.</p>
      <p>Cisneros had arranged for a local flamenco teacher, Diana
    Patricia Cubillán Herrera, to do a small performance for the
    guests, and Los Del Rio were pleasantly surprised by Cubillán's
    dance skills. Spontaneously, Romero recited the song's
    chorus-to-be on the spot, as an accolade to Cubillán, but
    naming her "
    <i>Ma'dalena</i>" (Magdalena): 
    <i>"Dale a tu cuerpo alegría, Ma'dalena, que tu cuerpo e' pa'
    darle alegría y cosa' güena'"</i>("Give your body some joy,
    Magdalene, 'cause your body is for giving joy and good things
    too"). In Andalusian culture labeling a woman "Magdalena" is to
    give her a faint association with Mary Magdalene's reportedly
    seedy past, and more accurately describes her as being sassy or
    sensuous.</p>
      <p>Romero saw potential in the improvised rhyme and, back at
    their hotel, the duo came up with the basic structure of the
    song. Since "Magdalena" was also the title of another song by
    Spanish singer Emmanuel quite popular at the time, Romero
    suggested that they use "Macarena" instead which, besides being
    part of the name of one of his daughters, is a popular name in
    Andalusia, given its association with the Virgin of the
    Macarena, the incarnation of the Virgin Mary that is a
    patroness of Seville's 
    <i>barrio La Macarena</i>. The Virgin-Magdalene dichotomy
    probably explains the rest of the lyrics: a song about a young
    woman, the girlfriend of a recent recruit to the Spanish Army
    named Victorino (whose name may be inspired from a kind of bull
    with long horns, evoking the 
    <i>cornudo</i>, or male victim of his partner's infidelity, a
    mental image common in Spanish and Latin American culture), who
    celebrates his being drafted by hooking up with two of his male
    friends. Macarena has a weakness for males in uniform, spending
    summers at Marbella, and dreams of shopping at El Corte Inglés
    (
    <i>the</i>major Spanish department store chain), moving to New
    York City and getting a new boyfriend.</p>
      <p>The song was originally recorded in 1992, and released in
    1993 as a rumba. This was the first of six versions of the song
    that can be associated to Los Del Rio. Another version, a new
    flamenco rumba pop fusion theme with fully Spanish lyrics,
    attained significant success in Spain and Mexico. It also
    became popular in Puerto Rico because of its use as an
    unofficial campaign theme song for then-governor Pedro
    Rosselló, who was seeking reelection under the New Progressive
    Party of Puerto Rico's ticket. Being the base for many cruise
    ships, many visitors to the island were constantly exposed to
    the song during their stay in Puerto Rico. This may explain how
    the song spread to — and became a smash hit in — cities with
    sizable Latino communities in the United States, particularly
    Miami and New York City.</p>
      <p>After being remixed by the Bayside Boys and having English
    lyrics added, it became a worldwide hit in mid-1996. The single
    spent 14 weeks at number one on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100
    singles chart, one of the longest runs atop the Hot 100 chart
    in history. During its heyday, the song was played frequently
    at professional athletic games, rallies, conventions, and other
    places. In 1996, many believe a world record for group dancing
    was set, when a crowd of 50,000 people danced the Macarena in
    Yankee Stadium in New York City. The song made such an impact
    that during the Democratic National Convention in 1996, Al Gore
    humorously performed his version of the Macarena by standing
    completely still while the song played.</p>
      <p>"Macarena" remained popular through 1996, but by the end of
    1997, its popularity had diminished greatly. The song also
    broke records at the time by remaining in the Hot 100 chart for
    60 weeks. The Bayside Boys remix includes a sample from Yazoo
    (also known in the United States as Yaz) track 
    <i>Situation</i>- the laughter of Yazoo vocalist Alison Moyet.
    In Addition, the chorus utilized female vocal samples utilized
    by The Farm in their song "Higher and Higher (Remix)" from
    their album, 
    <i>Spartacus</i>. The woman singer was hired by the Bayside
    Boys from their amateur radio station, although uncredited, she
    was the most important part of the promotion of the single
    remix, her name is 
    <i>Carla Vanessa</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1997, the song had sold 11 million copies. While having
    only a 25% take in royalties from the song, Romero and Ruiz
    became immensely wealthy. According to the BBC News Service,
    during the year 2003 alone — a full decade after the song's
    initial release — Romero and Ruiz made USD $250,000 in
    royalties. Julio Iglesias is quoted as congratulating the duo
    personally: "My success singing in English from Miami is
    nothing compared to yours; coming out of Dos Hermanas with
    little international exposure elsewhere and selling these many
    records in Spanish takes two huge sets of 
    <i>cojones</i>."</p>
      <p>In VH1's 2002 documentary 
    <i>100 Greatest One-hit Wonders</i>, "Macarena" was ranked as
    #1. "Macarena" was also ranked #1 on a different VH1
    documentary, 
    <i>40 Awesomely Bad No. 1 Songs</i>
      </p>
      <p>On 
    <i>America's Best Dance Crew</i>, it was danced to on the Whack
    Track Challenge, given to the Ringmasters.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom the song was released in June 1996 and
    peaked at number two on August 17, 1996. It was kept off the
    number one spot by the Spice Girls song "Wannabe".</p>
      <p>There are two different music videos. The most common music
    video, directed by Vincent Calvet, was created in 1996,
    featuring Los del Rio performing on a white backdrop. Ten women
    are also seen dancing with the band. This version samples a
    line from 
    <i>The Graduate</i>("I am not trying to seduce you!") which was
    later removed due to possible copyright issues. The other,
    similar version of the music video was in black and white and
    was more instructional in that the women and men are clearly
    shown performing the specific dance moves.</p>
      <p>Due to the overwhelming success of the song, a Christmas
    version of the song was created for the 1996 Christmas Season.
    It involved the original song with short lines from classic
    Christmas carols (specifically incorporating: "Joy to the
    World," "Jingle Bells," "Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer,"
    "White Christmas" and "Auld Lang Syne") in between the popular
    verses.</p>
      <p>In the music video, the young female dancers wear Christmas
    colored attire but there are nine of them compared to the ten
    dancers in the original. For the sequence featuring a new
    routine (the one being commonly used today), eight of them are
    shown with one of them being switched with a ninth dancer at
    times throughout the chorus.</p>
      <p>The song was also covered by Los del Mar (feat. Pedro
    Castaño), which was first released in 1995 and then again at
    the same time as the original in the United Kingdom and
    Australia in the hope of fooling people into buying their
    version by mistake, which could easily happen because the
    versions were very similar, thus difficult to distinguish. In
    the UK it only reached #43 in the charts (but remained charted
    for almost two months); however, the Los del Rio version peaked
    at number two. In Australia, the Los del Mar version was more
    successful and peaked at number two whilst the Los del Rio
    version was still at number one. In Canada, the Los del Mar
    version was quite popular on MuchMusic and top 40 radio in the
    spring of 1995, eclipsing the later popularity of the
    original.</p>
      <p>Australian CD Single</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
