<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Bamba_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Bamba_(song)</songId>
   <title>La Bamba</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Los_Lobos</artistId>
      <artistName>Los Lobos</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-08-29</week>
      <week>1987-09-05</week>
      <week>1987-09-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>October 1958</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1958</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Latin / Rock / Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:06</length>
   </lengths>
   <writers>
      <writer>Beau Ryan</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bob Keane</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"La Bamba" is a Mexican folk song, originally from the state
    of Veracruz, best known from a 1958 adaptation by Ritchie
    Valens, a top 40 hit in the U.S. charts and one of early rock
    and roll's best-known songs.</p>
      <p>Influenced by Spanish flamenco and Mexican rhythms, the song
    uses the violin, 
    <i>jarana jarocha</i>, guitar, and harp. Lyrics to the song
    greatly vary, as performers often improvise verses while
    performing. However, versions (such as those by musical groups
    Mariachi Vargas de Tecalitlan and Los Pregoneros del Puerto)
    have survived because of the artists' popularity and have
    become the "definitive" versions. The traditional aspect of "La
    Bamba" lies in the tune itself, which remains the same through
    all versions. The name of the dance, which has no direct
    English translation, is presumably connected with the Spanish
    verb 
    <i>bambolear</i>, meaning "to shake" or perhaps "to stomp".</p>
      <p>The traditional "La Bamba" was often played during weddings
    in Veracruz, where the bride and groom performed the
    accompanying dance. Today this wedding tradition is mostly
    lost, but the dance survives through the popularity of 
    <i>ballet folklórico</i>. The dance is performed in much the
    same way, displaying the newly-wed couple’s unity through the
    performance of complicated, delicate steps in unison as well as
    through creation of a bow from a 
    <i>listón</i>, a long red ribbon, using only their feet.</p>
      <p>The "arriba" (literally "up") part of the song suggests the
    nature of the dance, in which the footwork, called "
    <i>zapateado</i>", is done faster and faster as the music tempo
    accelerates. The repeated lyric, 
    <i>"Yo no soy marinero, soy capitán"</i>(lit: "I am not a
    sailor, I am a captain"), refers to Veracruz's marine locale
    and the husband's promise that he will remain faithful to his
    wife.</p>
      <p>At many gatherings, including the youth conventions of
    Esperanto (IJK, Internacia Seminario), one traditionally dances
    to "La Bamba" in a circle. People dance in the circle and
    people dance out of it. The people within the circle can take a
    place in the outer circle by kissing one of the people dancing
    in it, after this ritual one swaps places. Multiple versions
    are used for this, Spanish as well as partly or completely sung
    in Esperanto.</p>
      <p>The traditional song inspired Ritchie Valens' rock and roll
    version "La Bamba" in 1958. Valens' "La Bamba" infused the
    traditional tune with a rock beat, in part provided by drummer
    Earl Palmer, making the song accessible to a much wider
    population and earning it (and Valens) a place in rock history
    (inducted into the Rock &amp; Roll Hall of Fame in 2001). The
    song features a simple verse-chorus form. Valens, who was proud
    of his Mexican heritage, was hesitant at first to merge "La
    Bamba" with rock and roll, but then agreed. Valens obtained the
    lyrics from his aunt Ernestine Reyes and learned the Spanish
    lyrics phonetically, as he had been raised from birth speaking
    English. Valens' version of "La Bamba" is ranked number 345 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone magazine'</i>s list of the 500 Greatest Songs
    of All Time. It is the only song on the list not sung in
    English. The song also ranked #98 in VH1's 
    <i>100 Greatest Songs of Rock and Roll</i>and #59 in VH1's 
    <i>100 Greatest Dance Songs of Rock and Roll</i>, both done in
    2000.</p>
      <p>The tune of "La Bamba" was used to promote 101, a cigarette
    that was Chesterfield (cigarette)'s extra-long brand. To
    emphasize its difference from the other extra long brands which
    were all 100 mm long, commercials in the late 1960s for
    101 cigarettes used the phrase "a silly millimeter longer" sung
    to the tune of "La Bamba".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
