<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hello,_Dolly!_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hello,_Dolly!_(song)</songId>
   <title>Hello, Dolly!</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Louis_Armstrong</artistId>
      <artistName>Louis Armstrong</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1964-05-09</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1964</released>
   <formats>
      <format>45 rpm</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>December 3, 1963</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Rock 'N' Roll</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:27</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Kapp (573)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jerry Herman</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mickey Kapp</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Hello, Dolly!" is the title song of the popular 1964
    musical of the same name. Louis Armstrong's version was
    inducted in the Grammy Hall of Fame in 2001.</p>
      <p>The music and lyrics were written by Jerry Herman, who also
    wrote the scores for many other popular musicals including 
    <i>Mame</i>and 
    <i>La Cage aux Folles</i>.</p>
      <p>"Hello, Dolly!" was first sung by Carol Channing, who
    starred as Dolly Gallagher Levi in the original 1964 Broadway
    cast. In December 1963, at the behest of his manager, Louis
    Armstrong made a demonstration recording of "Hello, Dolly!" for
    the song's publisher to use to promote the show. 
    <i>Hello, Dolly!</i>opened on January 16, 1964 at the St. James
    Theatre in New York City, and it quickly became a major
    success. The same month, Kapp Records released Armstrong's
    publishing demo as a commercial single.</p>
      <p>The best-known recording is by Louis Armstrong, in 1964,
    which reached number-one on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100, ending
    The Beatles' streak of three number-one hits in a row (they
    also held the top three spots) and becoming the biggest hit of
    Armstrong's career, followed by a gold-selling album of the
    same name. For the song Armstrong received a Grammy Award for
    "Best Vocal Performance, Male" in 1964. In 1965, it received a
    Grammy Award for "Best Song" (Jerry Herman (songwriter),
    performed by Louis Armstrong). The song also spent nine weeks
    atop the adult contemporary chart shortly after the opening the
    musical. Louis Armstrong also performed the song (together with
    Barbra Streisand) in the popular 1969 film 
    <i>Hello, Dolly!</i>.</p>
      <p>"Hello, Dolly!" is a pop standard, and has been covered by
    many distunguished artists, including:</p>
      <p>Sinatra's rendition of the song, recorded with the Count
    Basie Orchestra, features new lyrics, improvised by Sinatra,
    which pay tribute to Louis Armstrong.</p>
      <p>The song's refrain is:</p>
      <p>As successful as the stage show and title song itself turned
    out to be, however, the tune "Hello, Dolly!" became caught up
    in a lawsuit which could have endangered timely plans for
    bringing the musical to the silver screen. Mack David
    (1912-1993), an Academy Award-nominated composer also known for
    his compositions for television, sued for infringement of
    copyright, because the first four bars of Herman's show number,
    "Hello, Dolly!", were the same as those in the refrain of
    David's song "Sunflower" from 1948. As he recounts in his
    memoirs, Herman had never heard "Sunflower" before the lawsuit,
    and wanted a chance to defend himself in court, but, for the
    sake of those involved in the show and the potential film, he
    reluctantly agreed to pay a settlement before the case would
    have gone to trial.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
