<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Autumn_Leaves_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Autumn_Leaves_(song)</songId>
   <title>Autumn Leaves " Roger Williams</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>"Love Is a Many-Splendored Thing" Four Aces</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1955-10-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Autumn Leaves" is a much-recorded popular song. Originally
    it was a 1945 French song "Les feuilles mortes" (literally "The
    Dead Leaves") with music by Joseph Kosma and lyrics by poet
    Jacques Prévert. Yves Montand (with Irène Joachim) introduced
    "Les feuilles mortes" in 1946 in the film 
    <i>Les Portes de la Nuit</i>. The American songwriter Johnny
    Mercer wrote English lyrics in 1947 and Jo Stafford was among
    the first to perform this version. Autumn Leaves became a pop
    standard and a jazz standard in both languages, both as an
    instrumental and with a singer.</p>
      <p>On December 24, 1950, French singer Edith Piaf rendered both
    French and English versions of this song on the radio program 
    <i>The Big Show</i>, hosted by Tallulah Bankhead.</p>
      <p>The film 
    <i>Autumn Leaves</i>(1956) starring Joan Crawford featured the
    song, as sung by Nat King Cole over the title sequence. The
    French songwriter Serge Gainsbourg paid tribute to this song in
    his own song "La chanson de Prévert".</p>
      <p>One of the most referred-to instrumental versions of this
    song is the one on the Cannonball Adderley album called
    "Somethin' Else" released in 1958, whose personnel included
    Miles Davis on trumpet, Hank Jones on piano and Art Blakey on
    drums.</p>
      <p>The song also crossed over in the club scene when dance act
    Coldcut recorded a version in 1994, the resulting remix by
    Irresistable Force became widely regarded a classic of the
    chillout genre.</p>
      <p>It is the corps song of the Bluecoats Drum and Bugle
    Corps.</p>
      <p>In 2009 Cecile Bredie made a wonderful version, the song can
    be found in the compilation "Cafè del Mar volume 16".</p>
      <p>In 1955 Roger Williams made the song a number one hit in the
    United States, the only piano instrumental to reach number one
    and remaining in that position for four weeks.</p>
      <p>The song is in AABC form. "Autumn Leaves" offers a popular
    way for beginning jazz musicians to become acquainted with jazz
    harmony as the chord progression consists almost solely of
    II-V-I and II-V sequences which are typical of jazz. For
    example, in the key of G minor it opens with</p>
      <p>The bridge contains the same sequence as well as</p>
      <p>Each chord sustains for 4 beats (X- ) unless otherwise noted
    (X-X-)</p>
      <p>(Verse)</p>
      <p>(Chorus)</p>
      <p>The song also contains all seven scale chords in the key,
    giving the opportunity to utilize all seven scale modes (see
    modal jazz).</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
