<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_Me_Tender_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_Me_Tender_(song)</songId>
   <title>Love Me Tender " Elvis Presley</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>"Love Me Tender" Elvis Presley</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1956-11-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>October 6, 1956</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>August 24, 1956</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:41</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Vera Matson</writer>
      <writer>Elvis Presley (credited); George R. Poulton</writer>
      <writer>Ken Darby (uncredited)</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Ernie Oelhrich</producer>
      <producer>Thorne Norgar</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Love Me Tender" is a song sung by Elvis Presley, adapted
    from the tune of "Aura Lee" (or "Aura Lea"), a sentimental
    Civil War ballad with music by George R. Poulton and words by
    W.W. Fosdick. "Aura Lee" was published in 1861 and this Civil
    War song later became popular with college glee clubs and
    barbershop quartets. It was also sung at the U.S. Military
    Academy at West Point, New York.</p>
      <p>The King performed "Love Me Tender" on the The Ed Sullivan
    Show 9 September 1956, shortly before the single's release and
    about a month before the movie, 
    <i>Love Me Tender</i>, was released, for which the song was
    originally recorded. (This was Presley's only movie that he
    died in.) On the following day, RCA received 1 million advance
    orders for the song, making it a gold record before it was even
    released. The studio, 20th Century Fox, originally wanted to
    call the movie "The Reno Brothers" but instead re-titled it to
    "Love Me Tender" to capitalize on the song's popularity.</p>
      <p>Movie producer Hal Wallis would not allow Presley's regular
    band made up of Scotty Moore, Bill Black, and D.J. Fontana to
    play on the soundtrack. Instead, The Ken Darby Trio provided
    the musical backing with Red Robinson on drums, Charles
    Prescott on bass, Vita Mumolo on guitar, and Jon Dodson on
    background vocals, with Presley providing only lead vocals.</p>
      <p>The song is credited to Presley and Vera Matson because of
    the publishing agreement reached for the assignment of
    royalties, but the principal writer of the lyrics was Ken Darby
    (Matson's husband). The song was published by Elvis Presley
    Music. Darby also adapted the Civil War tune, which was in the
    public domain. When asked why he credited his wife as
    co-songwriter along with Presley, Darby responded, "Because she
    didn't write it either."</p>
      <p>Presley received co-songwriting credit due to his Hill &amp;
    Range publishing deal which demanded songwriters concede 50
    percent of the credit of their song if they wanted Presley to
    record it; Presley never wrote any of his own songs. As with
    nearly all his RCA recordings, Presley took control in the
    studio despite not being credited as producer. He would
    regularly change arrangements and lyrics to the point the
    original song was barely recognizable. This, arguably,
    justified the cowriting credit in this case.</p>
      <p>The song hit #1 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts the week ending November 3, 1956,
    remaining in the position for 5 weeks and reached no. 11 on the
    charts in the UK. "Love Me Tender" also reached number three
    for three weeks on the R&amp;B chart . It was also an
    achievement as "Love Me Tender" succeeded another Presley
    single, "Hound Dog/Don't Be Cruel" at #1. This occurrence
    marked two important events in Billboard history. During this
    time, Elvis accomplished another record at the time; the
    longest consecutive stay at number one by a single artist,
    sixteen weeks, though this was tied by Boyz II Men in 1994 and
    stood for forty-eight weeks until being surpassed by R&amp;B
    singer Usher in 2004 who spent 19 weeks at the top of the
    charts.</p>
      <p>This version was ranked #437 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time.</p>
      <p>In 1968, Presley recorded a 52-second track entitled "Violet
    (Flower of N.Y.U.)" for the soundtrack of the film 
    <i>The Trouble with Girls</i>. Unreleased until after Presley's
    death, the song used the same melody as "Aura Lee", the source
    song for "Love Me Tender".</p>
      <p>Although Presley never re-recorded "Love Me Tender" in a
    studio setting, two live recordings of the song were released
    on the albums: 
    <i>NBC-TV Special</i>(1968) and 
    <i>Elvis: As Recorded at Madison Square Garden</i>(1972), with
    additional performances from concert and television appearances
    being released after Presley's death. The song was also
    performed in the Golden Globe-winning concert film 
    <i>Elvis on Tour</i>(1972).</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
