<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love%27s_Theme 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love%27s_Theme</songId>
   <title>Love's Theme</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barry_White</artistId>
      <artistName>Love Unlimited Orchestra</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-02-09</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Love's Theme" is an instrumental piece recorded by Barry
    White's Love Unlimited Orchestra and released in 1973. It is
    one of the few instrumental and purely orchestral singles to
    reach number one on 
    <i>Billboard's</i>Hot 100 chart in the United States, in early
    1974. The piece was included on the albums 
    <i>Under the Influence of Love Unlimited</i>(by the vocal group
    Love Unlimited) and 
    <i>Rhapsody in White</i>.</p>
      <p>The recording, with a large string orchestra and wah-wah
    guitar, is considered to be an influence to the disco sound,
    which would explode in popularity the following year. The song
    was also popular on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Adult Contemporary chart in the U.S., where the
    song spent two weeks at #1.</p>
      <p>In the mid 1970s all the way to the late 1980s, ABC Sports
    used "Love's Theme" as the opening theme music for its live
    golf coverage. WPIX used it as the closing music for its
    then-Action News franchise from 1975 to 1977. It was used as
    the theme song for the syndicated television series 
    <i>Lifestyles of the Rich and Famous</i>early in its run. It
    was featured on The Weather Channel's 'Local On The 8's'
    segments in 2002 and 2007. It was used as the opening theme to
    the soap opera "Celebridade" (2003) in Brazil. The Vlaamse
    Radio- en Televisieomroep used it throughout the 70s and into
    the 80s as the opening tune to its popular Sunday morning radio
    show, "Relax". The Seven Network in Australia used "Love's
    Theme" as the opener for its music program "Sounds" from the
    mid 1970s until the show was cancelled in 1987. Enoch Light
    recorded a disco instrumental version of the song on his 1977
    album, 
    <i>Disco Disque</i>. The song is also part of Meco's medley
    "Hooked On Instrumentals Part I" (from the album 
    <i>Hooked On Instrumentals</i>). From the late 1980s to the
    early 1990s, Cathay Pacific used the song in its commercials
    and even in its airline boarding/disembarkation audio.</p>
      <p>In addition, "Love's Theme" has been recorded with lyrics
    (penned by White's publisher, Aaron Schroeder), with vocal
    versions by such artists as Love Unlimited (on their 1974 album
    
    <i>In Heat</i>), Julio Iglesias, and Andy Williams. In May
    1993, Orchestral Manoeuvres in the Dark released their single,
    "Dream of Me (Based on Love's Theme)" (from their album 
    <i>Liberator</i>, released the same year) on which they sang
    their own lyrics over a sample of this Barry White's
    composition. This single reached #24 on the UK Singles Chart,
    and writing credits were given to Barry White.</p>
      <p>This song was later covered by an American smooth jazz
    trumpeter Rick Braun.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
