<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stand_Up_(Ludacris_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stand_Up_(Ludacris_song)</songId>
   <title>Stand Up</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ludacris</artistId>
      <artistName>Ludacris featuring Shawnna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2003-12-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/28/Ludacris_Stand_Up.jpg/200px-Ludacris_Stand_Up.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Ludacris-featuring-Shawnna+Stand-Up.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Chicken-n-Beer</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 19, 2003</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2003</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:33</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Disturbing tha Peace / Island Def Jam Music Group</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>C. Bridges</writer>
      <writer>K. West</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Ludacris</producer>
      <producer>Kanye West</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Stand Up" is a song by Ludacris, released as the second
    official single in 2003, and taken from his fourth album 
    <i>Chicken-n-Beer</i>. It was his first number-one single, with
    production by Kanye West and co-production by Ludacris
    himself.</p>
      <p>The chorus consists of three repetitions of Ludacris
    rapping, "When I move you move" and Shawnna responding "Just
    like that". After three repetitions, Ludacris says "Hell yeah,
    hey, DJ, bring that back" Then Shawnna says, "When I move you
    move" and Ludacris says "Just like that" and they trade parts
    of the chorus.</p>
      <p>It topped the Billboard Hot 100 for the week of December 6,
    2003. Ludacris went on to be nominated for a Grammy Award for
    Best Rap Solo Performance. The song remains Ludacris and
    Shawnna's biggest hit single to date. It reached numbber three
    in the UK.</p>
      <p>A music video was made for the song, directed by Dave
    Meyers. Film critic Armond White called the video a
    "masterpiece" that "conveys the urge of life". The video has
    been referred to as a "Ludacris acid trip".</p>
      <p>He enters a night club with a midget painted silver as a
    medallion on his necklace. This video also features disabled
    people in wheel chairs dancing. He appears with a giant shoe
    which stomps hard enough that the impact takes people off their
    feet. Young women munch on giant chicken legs and Ludacris
    chugs out of a huge beer bottle almost his size.A club girl who
    has no other top other than a designer bra who has been
    chastised for her model looks by women who spilled drinks on
    her cleavage is irresistible to Ludacris.She is a seductress
    who is took off guard by Ludacris who kisses her beer drenched
    breast that appeal to his alcoholic ways. The young lady soon
    takes great ecstasy in this. Like other club goers she too has
    had her share of the cartoonishly big servings that are now
    straining her metabolism. Ludacris kissing her on the mouth
    with his beer covered lips is the tipping point causing her
    adolescent like derriere and thighs to grow immensely . She is
    brought down a peg and and her buttocks turning more
    ambiguously mature destroy her innocent like front.Although a
    seductress she refuses to have the appearance of the
    stigmatized "ghetto booty" and frantically shakes her
    gelatinous rear in a attempt to renounce it. A close up reveals
    her skinny jeans have turned into low riders. Fortunately her
    dancing causing her "booty" to deflate. She is seen again
    happily dancing with still wide but not protruding cheeks and
    finally back to normal. Her jeans however, which started off
    skintight now have a bit of slack. She laughs the incident off
    as Ludacris wipes off his lips. The scene ,according to White,
    was a spoof of the girl dancer in a sweater that says Hollywood
    in the Nelly "Hot in Herre" video who complains of her butt
    seeming to get bigger. At the end of the video Ludacris is
    portrayed as a child with a huge afro and nothing on but a
    diaper dancing in the club's child drop off area. A female
    toddler in a diaper turns her head and is shocked by the sight
    of the Ludacris toddler's antics. Her face is just like the one
    of the seductress , further implying the true whorish nature of
    the "booty" girl earlier. He later has his diaper changed and
    pees on the woman doing it.</p>
      <p>An official remix was also recorded, in which Ludacris'
    third verse was removed and replaced with a verse from Kanye
    West. The remix appeared on the 
    <i>Akademiks: JeaniusLevelMusikKanye West Vol. 2</i>&amp; 
    <i>Kon The Louis Vuitton Don</i>mixtapes.</p>
      <p>Richard Cheese and Lounge Against the Machine covered the
    song as a lounge-style version on his 2004 album 
    <i>I'd Like a Virgin</i>.</p>
      <p>Ludacris also made a remix of the song for the Atlanta
    Falcons.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
