<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Money_Maker 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Money_Maker</songId>
   <title>Money Maker</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ludacris</artistId>
      <artistName>Ludacris featuring Pharrell</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2006-10-28</week>
      <week>2006-11-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/9/98/Money_Maker.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Ludacris-featuring-Pharrell+Money-Maker.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Release Therapy</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 17, 2006 (U.S. radio)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2006</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dirty Rap</genre>
      <genre>Pop Rap</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:54</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Def Jam Records / Disturbing tha Peace</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Pharrell Williams</writer>
      <writer>Christopher Bridges</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>The Neptunes</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Money Maker" is the first single from Ludacris's fifth
    album 
    <i>Release Therapy</i>. The song was released to the radio on
    July 17, 2006. The song is produced by The Neptunes and
    features Pharrell. The song was written by Chris Bridges
    (Ludacris), and Pharrell Williams. The video was released on
    August 17, 2006. The video premiered on MTV's 
    <i>Making the Video</i>. The single reached number 1 on various
    charts. It has peaked at number 1 on the Billboard Hot 100, the
    Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs, and number 1 on Hot Rap Tracks in
    the United States. It also became the number 1 single on radio
    in the United States on October 19, 2006. The music video
    managed to enter BET's 106 &amp; Park and peak at number 1,
    where it remained for several days. The single has strong
    airplay on BET and MTV. It also has airplay on Canada's
    Muchmusic. The single has a major promotional status and huge
    airplay on radio around the U.S., North America and other
    countries around the globe. The song was performed on the 2006
    MTV Video Music Awards. This is Ludacris's third #1 hit
    single.</p>
      <p>American R&amp;B singer, Amerie, also recorded an answer
    back (remix) to the single. The song was included on her first
    Mixtape, 
    <i>Because I Love It Volume 1</i>(the mixtape that was released
    to accompany her third studio Because I Love It), but didn't
    appear on the album, that was never released in the United
    States.</p>
      <p>The song won a Grammy Award for Best Rap Song in 2007.</p>
      <p>The "Money Maker" video was released August 17, 2006. It
    premiered on various channels including BET, MTV, and MuchMusic
    in that week.</p>
      <p>The video to "Money Maker" is a simple video. It is
    basically coloured backgrounds of orange, green and black
    throughout the shots. There are shots of Ludacris on the ground
    rapping with girls surrounding him. Pharrell is also singing
    the chorus around girls on stacks of money. Ludacris has a
    counting machine that counts how many times he has got a girl
    to shake her money maker (buttocks) for him - a reference to a
    commercial featuring himself using the same kind of device to
    click off the amount of women who flirt with him in his
    everyday life. Girls are also dancing throughout the video.
    "Money Maker" was shot by director Melina, who directed
    Shareefa's Need a Boss.</p>
      <p>The video is noteworthy in that is was Ludacris' first
    appearance on camera with his newly-cut hair, as Ludacris had
    cut his trademark cornrows in order to signify a new image for
    the rapper.</p>
      <p>The large speakers in the background vibrating throughout
    the video are no more than salad bowls, according to Ludacris
    in MTV's "Making the Video."</p>
      <p>The video also features a Chrysler ME Four-Twelve.</p>
      <p>Cameo appearances are made by Allen Iverson, Shareefa, Bobby
    Valentino, &amp; Lil Fate.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
