<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pop_Muzik 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pop_Muzik</songId>
   <title>Pop Muzik</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/M_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>M</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1979-11-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/ba/Pop_Muzik.jpg/200px-Pop_Muzik.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/M+Pop-Muzik.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>New York • London • Paris • Munich</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1979</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
      <genre>Synthpop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:21</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MCA / EMI / Sire</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Robin Scott</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Robin Scott</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Pop Muzik" is a 1979 hit song performed by the British band
    M, fronted by Robin Scott.</p>
      <p>Robin Scott describes the genesis of "Pop Muzik" this
    way:</p>
      <p>I was looking to make a fusion of various styles which
    somehow would summarize the last 25 years of pop music. It was
    a deliberate point I was trying to make. Whereas rock and roll
    had created a generation gap, disco was bringing people
    together on an enormous scale. That's why I really wanted to
    make a simple, bland statement, which was, 'All we're talking
    about basically (is) pop music.</p>
      <p>The single was released in the UK first, peaking at number 2
    on May 12, 1979, unable to break Art Garfunkel's 6 week stint
    at number 1 with "Bright Eyes". In August of that same year, it
    was released in America, where it eventually climbed all the
    way to number one on November 3.</p>
      <p>Along with Scott, other musicians who played on the track
    were his brother Julian Scott (on bass), then unknown
    keyboardist Wally Badarou, Canadian synthesizer programmer John
    Lewis (who died of AIDS in 1985) and Brigit Novik, the backing
    vocalist.</p>
      <p>The single was bolstered by a promotional video that was
    well received in its day; the clip featured Scott as a DJ
    singing into a microphone from behind an exaggerated turntable
    setup, at times flanked by two female models who sang and
    danced in a robotic manner. One of the sight gags in the video
    depicted Brigit Novik dressed in blue who actually recorded the
    backup vocals which are then mimed by the models, something
    that seems to foreshadow a number of incidents that occurred
    much later in the music industry with groups such as Milli
    Vanilli, C&amp;C Music Factory, and Black Box.</p>
      <p>The single's B-side, "M Factor", was featured in two
    different versions. The original cut appeared on the first UK
    and European releases of the single, while a slightly remixed
    version appeared on the single released in the United States
    and Canada.</p>
      <p>The image of the baby on "Pop Muzik"'s single disc pictures
    Robin Scott's daughter, named Berenice, actually a singer and
    piano/keyboard player and composer herself, and involved with
    his father's friend Phil Gould and Wally Badarou projects.</p>
      <p>The subsequent full-length album 
    <i>New York • London • Paris • Munich</i>was recorded in
    Montreux, Switzerland, at Queen's Mountain Studio, using their
    regular engineer David Richards, as well as Julian Scott, Wally
    Badarou (who would later work with Level 42 and Compass Point
    All Stars, among others) and Brigit Novik. Additional musicians
    on the album included drummer Phil Gould (later of Level 42),
    Gary Barnacle on saxophone and flute and (at the time) local
    Montreux resident David Bowie, who did occasional handclaps.
    The album was also released in the U.S. on Sire Records (with a
    different track listing / order) but it was not a commercial
    success.</p>
      <p>The 12-inch single version was notable for the B-side having
    a double groove such that the two tracks ("Pop Muzik" and "M
    Factor") both started at the outer edge of the record and
    finished in the middle (with a long silence at the end of "M
    Factor" since the track was the shorter of the two). This
    resulted in a random selection of tracks, depending on which
    groove the needle landed in in the lead-in.</p>
      <p>A cover version by male vocal and instrumental band All
    Systems Go entered the UK Singles Chart on 18 June 1988. It
    reached a peak position of number 63, and remained in the chart
    for 2 weeks.</p>
      <p>The Barron Knights recorded a brief parody of Pop Muzik
    ("Chop Suey") as part of their comedy medley "Food for
    Thought".</p>
      <p>Other remixes and remakes recorded by other artists have
    come from all sides since its creation, including Marcus' "Pop
    Muzic 2001", eX-Girl in 2001, and by Junior Vasquez and the Dub
    Pistols in 2003.</p>
      <p>A dance remix of the original M track by Steve Osborne was
    used by U2 during the introduction to each concert on their
    1997-1998 PopMart Tour. The remix was later released as the
    "Pop Mart Mix" on U2's "Last Night on Earth" single, with new
    vocals by Bono and slightly altered lyrics.</p>
      <p>Tricky released a cover version of the song as a B-side to
    his 1999 single "For Real".</p>
      <p>A cover of "Pop Muzik" by 3rd Party appeared on the
    soundtrack album to the 1998 movie A Night at the Roxbury.</p>
      <p>A version of this song is performed in Priscilla Queen of
    the Desert: The Musical by Cynthia for the ping pong scene in
    the pub.</p>
      <p>In 2001, MTV used a new version for one of the special
    programs aired to celebrate the channel's 20th anniversary. The
    lyrics were altered mentioning popular pop artists, mostly at
    the time, but also for the past 20 years, including Britney
    Spears, N'Sync, Backstreet Boys and Spice Girls.</p>
      <p>In 2009, a CD of remixes by various artists was released to
    celebrate the song's 30th anniversary.</p>
      <p>British pop punk band Buck Brothers released a cover of the
    song to promote their first tour of America in March 2008. They
    will release a new revised version of the cover (featuring new
    guitarist Dom Beckford) on April 12th 2010.</p>
      <p>There is in some cases a misconception that the Band Devo
    actually made the song this however is not true, but Devo did
    release a remix of Pop Muzik on the aforementioned remix
    CD.</p>
      <p>The song "That's Boonoonoonoos / Train to Skaville" in the
    1981 album 
    <i>Boonoonoonoos</i>of Boney M. has in common many things with
    "Pop Muzik": it is not a cover, but something similar to.</p>
      <p>Original 7" single released by MCA Records and EMI in
    Europe.</p>
      <p>Single released as a 7" vinyl in the United States by Sire
    Records, and as a 12" vinyl in France by Pathé Marconi EMI,
    both featuring a longer version of the song.</p>
      <p>12" single released in the Netherlands by MCA Records. The
    B-side "M Factor" was featured on the A-side of the vinyl on
    this release, with a remix of the title song on the B-side.</p>
      <p>7" single released in Sweden in 1989 by Freestyle
    Records.</p>
      <p>12" single released in Sweden in 1989 by Freestyle
    Records.</p>
      <p>12" single released in Germany in 1989 by ZYX Records.</p>
      <p>CD single released in Germany in 2001 by ZYX Records.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
