<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Take_a_Bow_(Madonna_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Take_a_Bow_(Madonna_song)</songId>
   <title>Take a Bow</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madonna_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Madonna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1995-02-25</week>
      <week>1995-03-04</week>
      <week>1995-03-11</week>
      <week>1995-03-18</week>
      <week>1995-03-25</week>
      <week>1995-04-01</week>
      <week>1995-04-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a3/MadonnaTakeABow.jpg/200px-MadonnaTakeABow.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Madonna+Take-a-Bow.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Bedtime Stories</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 6, 1994 (worldwide) , January 21, 1995 (UK)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>CD maxi single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1994</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:21</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Maverick , Sire , Warner Bros.</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Babyface</writer>
      <writer>Madonna</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Madonna</producer>
      <producer>Babyface</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Take a Bow" is a song by American singer Madonna from her
    1994 Studio album 
    <i>Bedtime Stories</i>and 1995 Compilation album 
    <i>Something to Remember</i>. It is also Madonna's
    longest-running number-one hit in the United States. The song
    was released as a single in December 1994. Madonna performed
    "Take a Bow" with Babyface at the 1995 American Music
    Awards.</p>
      <p>"Take a Bow", the second single from the 
    <i>Bedtime Stories</i>album, became Madonna's eleventh
    number-one single in America, remaining at the summit of the
    Hot 100 chart for a seven-week run, the longest of her career
    thus far. Co-written by Babyface (who also provides backing
    vocals), the ballad became the singer's first United States
    number one in almost three years and became the highest-selling
    single of 1995. Despite its success on the charts, Madonna has
    never played the song on any tour.</p>
      <p>"Take a Bow" was featured in the final episode of the first
    season of 
    <i>Friends</i>, "The One Where Rachel Finds Out", when Rachel
    goes to the airport to tell Ross that she knows he is in love
    with her. "Take a Bow" was also used for promos for the final
    season of 
    <i>Beverly Hills, 90210</i>.</p>
      <p>"Take a Bow" was a huge success for Madonna on the Hot 100
    chart. It topped the chart for seven weeks and is her
    longest-running number-one single on this chart. "Take a Bow"
    became Madonna's fifth number-one single on the Adult
    Contemporary chart in the U.S., following "Live to Tell", "La
    Isla Bonita", "Cherish", and "I'll Remember". The song is also
    notable as Madonna's last single (to date) to make the top
    forty of the U.S. R&amp;B chart. The single received the remix
    treatment from prominent DJ and record producer Steve Hurley.
    Madonna won Best Female Video honors at the 1995 MTV Video
    Music Awards.</p>
      <p>Although the single was a major hit in the United States,
    garnering gold accreditation, it became one of only a handful
    of her releases not to reach the UK top ten and ended a
    ten-year run of thirty-five consecutive top ten hits. Sales,
    however, were buoyed by the Christmas period and "Take a Bow"
    still sold 102,739 copies which was more than several of
    Madonna's other top ten hits. In Canada the song topped the
    charts, becoming her twelfth number-one single in that
    country.</p>
      <p>The music video (directed by Michael Haussman) was a lavish
    period-style piece filmed from November 3–8, 1994 in the
    bullring of Antequera, Spain. The plot sees Madonna as a
    bullfighter's (played by real-life Spanish bullfighter Emilio
    Muñoz) neglected lover, yearning for his presence. Others,
    however, see it as a statement on classism, as the bullfighter
    arguably feels threatened and angered by the aristocrat's
    station, resulting in his physically abusing and then coldly
    abandoning her. Madonna's 1995 single "You'll See" is
    considered a follow up to "Take a Bow" as the singer and Emilio
    Muñoz reprise their roles in the music video. Madonna requested
    that Haussman give the video a Spanish theme because, at the
    time, she was lobbying for the role of Eva Perón in the film
    version of 
    <i>Evita</i>. She subsequently sent a copy of the video to
    director Alan Parker as a way of "auditioning" for the
    role.</p>
      <p>This video was ranked number twenty-seven on VH1's 50
    Sexiest Video Moments.</p>
      <p>The video generated some controversy with animal rights
    activists who accused the singer of glorifying bullfighting. In
    Australia, music video program 
    <i>Video Hits</i>ran a ticker along the bottom of the screen
    when the video was playing, stating that the producers of the
    program did not endorse the glorification of the sport
    portrayed in the video, while ABC TV video program 
    <i>rage</i>simply refused to play the video at all during their
    G-rated Top 50 program. No such protests seem to have been
    made, however, about the narrative showing a man physically
    abusing a woman, as the bullfighter does to the aristocrat
    portrayed by Madonna. The bulls that were used in the video
    were never harmed in any way and were sent to live out the rest
    of their lives on a farm.</p>
      <p>US Promo CD</p>
      <p>US Single</p>
      <p>US /Australia Maxi-CD</p>
      <p>UK / Australia / Europe CD</p>
      <p>Japan Remixes</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
