<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Justify_My_Love 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Justify_My_Love</songId>
   <title>Justify My Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madonna_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Madonna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1991-01-05</week>
      <week>1991-01-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/dc/MadonnaJustify.jpg/200px-MadonnaJustify.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Madonna+Justify-My-Love.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Immaculate Collection</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 6, 1990 (Worldwide) , December 2, 1990 (U.K.) , December 10, 1990 (Japan)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>CD maxi</format>
      <format>Video</format>
      <format>Cassette</format>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1990</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>New Jack Swing</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:59</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Sire , Warner Bros.</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lenny Kravitz</writer>
      <writer>Ingrid Chavez</writer>
      <writer>additional lyrics by Madonna</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Lenny Kravitz</producer>
      <producer>André Betts</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Justify My Love" is the first single by American
    singer-songwriter Madonna from her 1990 greatest hits
    compilation 
    <i>The Immaculate Collection</i>and was released on November 6,
    1990, by Sire Records. It caused international controversy due
    to the accompanying music video which was sexually explicit and
    even banned by MTV. This outraged Madonna and she appeared on
    ABC's 
    <i>Nightline</i>to defend it. The single was also released as a
    video-single and became the highest selling video single of
    all-time. When released, the single rose to the top of the Hot
    100 (her ninth number one) and many other worldwide charts. The
    single made number two in the UK Christmas charts selling
    228,683 copies.</p>
      <p>"Justify My Love" was written by Lenny Kravitz, Ingrid
    Chavez and Madonna. Kravitz wrote the song for Madonna, based
    on a poem written by friend and Prince protégé Ingrid Chavez.
    Kravitz added the title hook and chorus. Madonna contributed a
    few lines. Chavez was not credited for the song and later sued
    Kravitz in 1992. She received an out-of-court settlement, and
    gained a co-writing credit.</p>
      <p>Producer Kravitz sampled the intro found on Public Enemy's
    instrumental, "Security of the First World", and used it as the
    basis of the song. The song was unique in that Madonna's vocals
    are primarily spoken and whispered. This style served as a
    prelude to her next album 
    <i>Erotica</i>, in which she spoke the lyrics on some of the
    songs rather than singing them. Kravitz provided background
    vocals. Rumors of a love affair between Kravitz and Madonna
    sprang up in the press upon the release of the song. Kravitz
    has denied these rumors.</p>
      <p>In 2003, Madonna fans were asked to vote for their Top 20
    Madonna singles of all-time by 
    <i>Q-Magazine</i>. "Justify My Love" was allocated the #12
    spot.</p>
      <p>Rapper Mase sampled the song on his 1999 album, 
    <i>Double Up</i>, on his song "Stay Out of My Way".</p>
      <p>The song was covered by rapper Vita and pop–R&amp;B singer
    Ashanti for 
    <i>The Fast and the Furious</i>soundtrack in 2001. Vita was
    originally going to make the version her own featuring her
    rapping on the re-make, but Madonna shut her down and only
    cleared the version where Vita does the exact same style as
    Madonna.</p>
      <p>Rapper Jay-Z's song, "Justify My Thug", from his 2003 album,
    
    <i>The Black Album</i>produced by DJ Quik, is a remake of
    "Justify My Love." Enigma sampled "Justify My Love" for their
    "Orthodox Remix" of the 1990 single, "Mea Culpa (Part II)".</p>
      <p>Madonna has only performed this song once on her 1993 Girlie
    Show Tour.</p>
      <p>Directed by Jean-Baptiste Mondino, it features Madonna's
    then-boyfriend, model and actor Tony Ward. Some of the dancers
    featured in the video were also dancers from her Blond Ambition
    Tour. The video is a tribute to Jeanne Moreau of 
    <i>La Baie des Anges</i>.</p>
      <p>The video was banned by MTV. MTV's pass on the video created
    a furor that made headlines. The video itself became a
    bestselling "video single" when it was released on the
    VHS-format that year.</p>
      <p>The video was filmed in grainy black and white in the style
    of a 1960s European art film. There are also several shadowy
    film-noir elements such as characters seen only in silhouette.
    (Much of the imagery echoes an obscure French music video that
    came out in 1988.) The action takes place in an elegant hotel
    that apparently caters to alternate lifestyle couples. Madonna
    (or the character she's playing) enters looking tired and
    distressed as she walks down the hallway toward her room. There
    she has a romantic fling with a mysterious man. Some of the
    doors to the other rooms are ajar and we catch glimpses of
    various couples cavorting in BDSM fetish outfits (leather,
    latex bodysuits, and corsets).</p>
      <p>In a dream-like sequence, Madonna rolls around in bed
    wearing skimpy lace underwear while various figures come and
    go. The only nudity (which led to the video being banned)
    occurs when a topless dominatrix-type woman — suspenders partly
    covering her breasts — appears and roughly grabs a bound man
    (the same man who is with Madonna) by the hair. Her outfit,
    which includes a peaked leather hat and black gloves, copies
    the iconic ensemble worn by Charlotte Rampling in the
    controversial film 
    <i>The Night Porter</i>. (Both the film and the video share
    elements of sadomasochism.) The theme of androgyny is also
    briefly alluded to when a woman who closely resembles Madonna's
    lover is seen in men's clothing with a drawn-on pencil
    mustache. The overall presentation is surreal and deliberately
    ambiguous. The retinue of strange characters may be real or
    simply fantasies from Madonna's imagination. In the end, a
    rejuvenated Madonna rushes out of the hotel room smiling and
    laughing.</p>
      <p>On December 3, 1990, ABC's 
    <i>Nightline</i>played the video in its entirety, then
    interviewed Madonna live about the video's sexual content and
    censorship. When asked whether she stood to make more money
    selling the video than airing it on MTV, she appeared impatient
    and answered, "Yeah, so? Lucky me."</p>
      <p>The video for "Justify My Love" was banned also from regular
    rotation on MuchMusic in Canada, although the controversy (as
    well as the subsequent banning of a video by Mitsou) led
    MuchMusic to launch a new series, 
    <i>Too Much 4 Much</i>, which played controversial music videos
    accompanied by panel discussions on their artistic and cultural
    context.</p>
      <p>In mid-2002, this video was aired in its entirety on MTV2 as
    part of a special countdown showing the most controversial
    videos ever to air on MTV. This countdown was shown only late
    at night because of the graphic imagery of "Justify My Love"
    and several other videos on the countdown.</p>
      <p>As of early May 2007, the video has been receiving strong
    airplay on the late night edition of MuchMusic's request show
    "Punch Much"; however, the video is still banned in many areas
    of Canada, where the show is broadcast from. The video has had
    light to moderate airplay on MuchMoreMusic during its late
    night music video block.</p>
      <p>On the May 11, 1991 episode of the sketch-comedy series 
    <i>Saturday Night Live</i>, Madonna made a guest appearance in
    a pre-filmed segment which spoofed her controversial music
    video as well as her just-released 
    <i>Truth or Dare</i>film.</p>
      <p>During a Wayne's World sketch, Wayne (Mike Myers) and Garth
    (Dana Carvey) encounter a seductive Madonna lying on a bed in a
    hotel room during a fantasy dream sequence (also filmed in
    black and white). After some back-and-forth banter, Wayne and
    Madonna play Truth or Dare. Wayne begins by saying "Truth."
    Madonna then asks "Have you ever made love with two women at
    the same time?" Wayne answers "Uh...yes!" to which Madonna says
    "Okay, I believe you....not!" Wayne then dares Madonna to make
    out with him. As they kiss, the music for "Justify My Love"
    begins to play. Garth is then seen dancing in a parody of the
    video before being abducted by two women in fetish-wear
    outfits.</p>
      <p>"The Beast Within" is a remix of the song, "Justify My
    Love", by Madonna and Lenny Kravitz, which was included on the
    12" release of the single. The remix uses only the chorus and
    certain lines of the original song, with the verses being
    replaced by passages from the Book of Revelation from the
    Bible. As such, and since subsequent live concert performances
    have simply billed the song as "The Beast Within", a song in
    its own right, most fans refer to this track as simply "The
    Beast Within" and do not refer to it as a remix. The song first
    garnered media attention early in 1991 when the Simon
    Wiesenthal Center accused the song of containing anti-semitic
    lyrics; specifically the lyric "those who say that they are
    Jews, but they are not. They are a Synagogue of Satan". Madonna
    denied the accusations, explaining that the song was about
    love, not hatred. Also, one of the verses from which Madonna
    reads is Revelation 21:8, which gives a list of people
    including "fornicators" whose "lot shall be in the lake that
    burns with fire and brimstone."</p>
      <p>'"The Beast Within" was showcased as a dancers' interlude
    during the 1993 The Girlie Show World Tour and was used again
    as the video introduction to the 2004 Re-Invention World Tour.
    The latter used imagery of Madonna from the exhibition 
    <i>X-STaTIC Pro=CeSS</i>, prior to her appearing on stage. It
    was subsequently included on the 2006 live album, 
    <i>I'm Going to Tell You a Secret</i>. This new version omits
    the controversial lyrics which caused the 1991 accusations.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
