<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Your_Heart_(Madonna_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Your_Heart_(Madonna_song)</songId>
   <title>Open Your Heart</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madonna_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Madonna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-02-07</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f5/Open_Your_Heart_1986.png/200px-Open_Your_Heart_1986.png</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Madonna+Open-Your-Heart.png</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>True Blue</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 12, 1986</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>CD Single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1985</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:13</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Sire , Warner Bros.</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Madonna</writer>
      <writer>Gardner Cole</writer>
      <writer>Peter Rafelson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Madonna</producer>
      <producer>Patrick Leonard</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Open Your Heart" is a song by American singer-songwriter
    Madonna. It was released as the fourth single from her third
    studio album 
    <i>True Blue</i>on November 12, 1986 by Sire Records. It has
    since appeared remixed on the compilation albums 
    <i>The Immaculate Collection</i>(1990) and 
    <i>Celebration</i>(2009). Written originally as a rock 'n roll
    song, Madonna changed it to a dance-pop genre. Lyrically it is
    a love song telling about innocent feelings of boy meets girl
    romance and Madonna expressing her sexual desire.</p>
      <p>The song was well-received by critics and achieved
    commercial success worldwide topping the chart in U.S., thus
    making it Madonna's fifth 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 number-one single. The music video,
    however, visualised a different concept of the song. Madonna
    played an exotic dancer in a peep-show club, who befriends a
    little boy and escapes from there. It was critically acclaimed
    for portraying a completely opposite perspective of
    "voyeuristic male gaze and object", and depicting innocence
    rather than sexual overtones, although the entry of a child in
    a strip club was negatively criticized. The video was an homage
    to actresses Liza Minnelli and Marlene Dietrich.</p>
      <p>The song has been performed by Madonna in two of her world
    tours – 1987's Who's That Girl World Tour, and 1990's Blond
    Ambition World Tour, where Madonna wore her infamous conical
    bra during the song. "Open Your Heart" has been covered a
    number of times by different artists, and appeared in the
    Britney Spears film, 
    <i>Crossroads</i>(2002).</p>
      <p>"Open Your Heart" was originally a rock 'n roll song with
    the title "Follow Your Heart" and had been written for singer
    Cyndi Lauper by songwriters Gardner Cole and Peter Rafelson,
    although it was never played to her. The Temptations were also
    considered for the song. Their manager Benny Medina decided
    that they wanted to record the song after all, but upon hearing
    that Madonna had already recorded it, changed their mind. The
    original title according to Cole, was from a local health food
    restaurant called 
    <i>Follow Your Heart</i>in Canoga Park, California. In Fred
    Bronson's book 
    <i>The The Billboard Book of Number 1 Hits</i>, Cole
    explained,</p>
      <p>"Peter and I usually write very quickly. It's usually a day
    or two a song, but for some reason this didn't really hit us as
    a hit song. We didn't give up on it. We just kept working on it
    over the course of a year. Thank God we did. [...] It was the
    first song that was cut on the 
    <i>True Blue</i>album. It made me nervous as a writer, because
    a lot of times the very first song that gets cut doesn't make
    it in the long run. But the song ended up making the album,
    which really opened up a lot of doors for me."</p>
      <p>Cole's manager Bennett Freed was working with Madonna's
    management and they were looking for new material for her
    album. Three of Cole's songs were chosen for reviewing
    including "Open Your Heart". Despite the fact that it did not
    fit exactly with the choice and genre of songs Madonna was
    singing at that time, she nevertheless accepted it. Madonna
    recorded "Open Your Heart", altered the lyrics thus earning a
    co-writing credit, and along with Patrick Leonard added a
    bassline underneath the song which turned it into a rock-dance
    track rather than the original rock 'n roll genre. The song was
    the first recorded cut for the 
    <i>True Blue</i>album in late 1985 and ultimately made it to
    the final released tracklist.</p>
      <p>The song has a continuous percussion filled structure and a
    chorus sounding like Belinda Carlisle, according to author
    Rikky Rooksby in his book 
    <i>The Complete Guide to the Music of Madonna</i>. Lyrically,
    "Open your Heart" is a simple love song. The song speaks of
    earnest innocent notions of boy meets girl kind of feelings.
    According to professor Mavis Tsai, the phrase "Open Your Heart"
    is a metaphor for the act of being vulnerable that corresponds
    to the behavior involved in developing an intimate or close
    relationship. The following lines in the song, "Open Your
    Heart, I'll make you love me; It's not that hard, if you just
    turn the key" illustrate this metaphor vividly. The concept of
    the song places Madonna as a victim of love. The lyrics puts
    Madonna in a more direct position expressing her sexual desires
    for her man according to author Santiago Fouz-Hernández in the
    line "If you gave me half a chance you'd see; My desire burning
    inside of me."</p>
      <p>Author Nicholas B. Dirks, one of the authors of 
    <i>Culture/power/history</i>, reviewed the song saying that it
    was more upbeat than previous single "Live to Tell" and "the
    play with closure in 'Open Your Heart' creates the image of
    open ended jouissance - an erotic energy that continually
    escapes containment". Author Taraborrelli called it as one of
    her most "earnest" songs and compared it with Aretha Franklin's
    song "Respect" as well as Barbra Streisand's "A House is Not a
    Home". According to him "it was a tune people could understand
    and latch on to, which is what makes a pop song memorable". 
    <i>The New York Times</i>writer Stephen Holden compared the
    song with sweeter post-Motown valentine songs. 
    <i>Houston Chronicle</i>writer Joey Guerra called the song
    "perfect" for dancefloor strut. Stephen Thomas Erlewine of
    Allmusic called it a perfect dance song with deepened dance
    grooves. Slant Magazine named the song as one of Madonna's most
    "robust" songs. Robert Christgau said of the song, "I'm not
    saying her flair is pleasureless - the generosity she demands
    in the inexhaustible "Open Your Heart" is a two-way street and
    then some."</p>
      <p>"Open Your Heart" debuted at fifty-one the week ending
    December 6, 1986, on the Hot 100 chart. It had a gradual rise
    and subsequently peaked the chart on February 7, 1987 becoming
    Madonna's fifth number-one single on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 chart. The single also had its
    success on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Dance Club Play chart reaching number-one
    on February 14, 1987. The single was Madonna's sixth entry on
    the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Adult Contemporary chart where it reached a
    peak of twelve. In Canada, the song debuted at number
    eighty-three on the 
    <i>RPM</i>chart on December 13, 1986, and reached a peak
    position of eight for the chart issue dated February 21,
    1987.</p>
      <p>Internationally, it became a top ten hit in several European
    countries including the United Kingdom, Italy, Ireland,
    Netherlands, and Belgium. In the United Kingdom, the single
    debuted on the UK Singles Chart at number eight and
    subsequently reached a peak of four on December 13, 1986. The
    single was on the chart for nine weeks in total, and was
    certified silver by the British Phonographic Industry (BPI) on
    December 1, 1986. It also peaked at number four in Europe, thus
    becoming the only single from 
    <i>True Blue</i>not to top the Eurochart Hot 100. In Australia,
    it only reached a peak of sixteen, breaking a run of nine
    consecutive top ten singles for Madonna in that country.
    Elsewhere, like in Switzerland, Austria, Germany and France, it
    reached within the top 40 of the singles chart.</p>
      <p>The music video was shot at Echo Park in Los Angeles,
    California. Madonna portrays an exotic dancer who befriends a
    young boy, played by child actor Felix Howard. This video was
    originally set to be directed by Madonna's then-husband Sean
    Penn, but in the end the final honors went to Jean-Baptiste
    Mondino, who went on to work with Madonna on her videos for
    "Justify My Love" (1990), "Human Nature" (1995), "Love Don't
    Live Here Anymore" (1996), "Don't Tell Me" (2000) and
    "Hollywood" (2003). The video was shot in July 1986 and was
    released in December 1986. It was produced by David Naylor. The
    video was nominated for three MTV Video Music Awards in 1987.
    In the best female video category "Open Your Heart" lost to
    another Madonna video, when her "Papa Don't Preach" video won
    the award.</p>
      <p>The "Open Your Heart" music video presents an early version
    of Madonna's musings about her Italian-American heritage and
    focus on her feminocentric street theology, which was also
    explicitly brought out by 1987's Who's That Girl Tour. The
    video is structured as a cinematic peep show and voyeurism that
    portrays Madonna as a stripper. It starts with a little boy
    trying to go inside a peep show where Madonna is the star
    performer but getting rebuffed by an old man at the ticket
    booth outside. Inside Madonna starts singing the song from the
    center of a carousel that revolves to display her to the gaze
    of the customers who are sitting safely in their cubicles.
    Madonna is dressed in a black bustier, spike heels, fishnet and
    a black wig which she subsequently removes to reveal her
    slimmed down body at that time. The lighting is bluish and
    dark. Her look is a mix of actresses Marlene Dietrich in the
    movie 
    <i>The Blue Angel</i>as well as Liza Minnelli as the character
    Sally Bowles in the Bob Fosse-directed film musical "Cabaret".
    The dancing is restrained with a single prop: that of a
    solitary chair. At one point in the first segment of the video,
    she is filmed dancing but the camera is almost still and the
    motions of the dance are confined within the small range of the
    camera. As the screens inside the viewing booths open and
    close, the camera slices the shots of Madonna each with its own
    angle and duration. The same imagery is exhibited by the little
    boy outside who tries to frame Madonna's play ball image into
    different angles. There are four other men in the booths who
    are made of wood with paintings of artist Tamara De Lempicka on
    them. Madonna at one point takes off her gloves like Rita
    Hayworth in 
    <i>Gilda</i>and points towards one of the wooden paintings. It
    collapses and she blows on her finger.</p>
      <p>The video is similar in thematic content to Motley Crue's
    video for the single "Girls, Girls, Girls". But in contrast,
    this video tells the story from Madonna's point of view. She
    looks down into the cubicles to make eye contact with the men
    but they are unable to return it. She also looks assertively
    into the camera, making eye contact with the viewer. With these
    scenes Madonna portrays her holding power over the men and the
    ability to pursue them. Madonna represents an assertive woman
    searching for a lover who can accept her as a human being.
    Author Bruce Forbes notes that the men in the cubicles are
    proved unworthy of her and there is an undertone of mockery
    when Madonna addresses them as 'baby' while shaking her body.
    By the end of the video the isolated and sad men depart with
    the doors closing on them. As the final chorus breaks into
    dance grooves, Madonna comes out of the theater and gives the
    boy a quick kiss on his lips. Both are clad in loose-fitting
    gray suits, which gives Madonna an androgynous look. They
    stroll away playfully in the sunrise, reminiscent of Charlie
    Chaplin and Jack Coogan in 
    <i>The Kid</i>with the old boss pursuing them and shouting
    "Come back, come back, we still need you" in Italian. The
    tension between the visual and the musical dimensions of the
    video is extremely unsettling according to author Nicholas B.
    Dirks. Only when she disappears from the carousel and reappears
    to run away from her patriarchal boss with the young boy, then
    the music and visuals become comparable.</p>
      <p>Feminist writer Susan Bordo gave a negative review of the
    video, saying that the leering and pathetic men in the cubicles
    and Madonna's escape with the boy is "cynically and
    mechanically tacked on [as] a way of claiming trendy status for
    what is just cheesecake - or, perhaps, pornography". MTV also
    had some reservations initially before airing the video, which
    was later resolved after a meeting with Warner Officials.
    However socio-critic Mary Harron in her book 
    <i>McRock: Pop as a commodity</i>said that the underlying
    message in the video is that though Madonna sells sexuality,
    she is free. There is no overt representation of anything
    besides friendship with the boy. Their escape together avoids
    Madonna the sexual overtones that would have been stronger if
    she would have escaped with an adult male. This, according to
    author 
    <i>Richard Dienst</i>, seems to suggest a repudiation of the
    adult labor of the stage in favor of childhood, androgyny,
    authenticity and nomadic play. The video is also acclaimed for
    reviving and re-creating the hard glamor of the studio-era of
    Hollywood stars and also for representing women as the dominant
    sex. Author Donn Welton pointed out that the usual power
    relationship between the "voyeuristic male gaze and object" is
    destabilized by the portrayal of the male patrons of the peep
    show as leering and pathetic. At the same time, the portrayal
    of Madonna as porno queen object is deconstructed by the escape
    at the end of the video.</p>
      <p>"Open Your Heart" has been featured as a full song in the
    set lists of two Madonna tours - 1987 Who's That Girl Tour and
    1990 Blond Ambition Tour. It served as the opening song on 1987
    Who's That Girl Tour. It started off with then young dancer
    Chris Finch, imitating Felix Howard from the video. Howard did
    not receive a working license for the tour hence Finch was
    taken for his part. He went on to become an integral part of
    most of the songs performed on the tour. After Finch, two other
    dancers are introduced, before Madonna herself appears on
    stage. She wore the same black pointy corset and fishnets as in
    the music video. She first sings the song alone, then Finch
    joins her again and they dance together till the song ends.</p>
      <p>On the Blond Ambition Tour, "Open Your Heart" follows the
    opening number "Express Yourself". This time there's not a
    young boy but a hunky dancer watching from a distance as
    Madonna entered the stage with her hair stretched into a
    topknot and fake blond ponytail, which was replaced by short
    peroxide tangles in the European leg of the tour. She wore a
    double breasted suit with the outer jacket cut in slits so that
    the conical bra underneath could point through. Showing off the
    satin pink bodysuit and her monocle chain, Madonna proceeds to
    perform the song on a chair. Playing a dominatrix role, Madonna
    got on top of one of the dancers before carrying off an
    exhibitionist dance routine with the chair as a prop.</p>
      <p>The opening musical introduction of the song served as a
    brief twenty-six seconds musical interlude on the Drowned World
    Tour in 2001. As Madonna finished a performance of "Frozen" in
    the Geisha inspired segment of the show, she sat in a
    cross-legged position in front of the stage. The musical intro
    for "Open Your Heart" starts with a dancer in a Japanese
    costume dancing behind her on a raised podium. As the music
    ends, Madonna starts singing "Nobody's Perfect" from her 2000
    album "Music". In 2008, Madonna sang the first verse and chorus
    for the first time in eighteen years at two dates - Las Vegas
    and East Rutherford - of her Sticky and Sweet Tour. Madonna
    forgot the lyrics at the Vegas show and refused to sing the
    song in Boston; she performed "Express Yourself" instead.</p>
      <p>Despite being originally written in English, a Spanish
    version of the song titled "Abre Tu Corazón" was recorded by
    Venezuelan rock singer Melissa (originally born in Peru,
    Melissa moved to Venezuela at an early age), who released it in
    March 1986 on her "Melissa III" album. Considering Madonna
    first released the song on the "True Blue" album three months
    afterwards, Melissa's "Abre Tu Corazón" can be considered the
    first released version of the song, although it is possible
    that Madonna's version (for which she received a co-writer's
    credit) was recorded first. The Madonna tribute compilation 
    <i>Virgin Voices: A Tribute To Madonna, Vol. 2</i>contained a
    cover by the late Israeli singer Ofra Haza. An eurodance
    version was recorded by the group Mad'House for the album
    "Absolutely Mad". A hi-NRG dance version was recorded by Who's
    That Girl for the album 
    <i>Exposed</i>, released through Almighty Records. In 2004 
    <i>Platinum Blonde NRG, Vol. 2: Nrgised Madonna Classics</i>, a
    hi-NRG cover is performed by In-Deep. The song appears in the
    opening of the 2002 film 
    <i>Crossroads</i>. Britney Spears' character lip syncs to the
    song in her room with a brush in her hand, pretending it's a
    microphone. A Madonna poster is visible during the scene.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
