<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Papa_Don%27t_Preach 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Papa_Don%27t_Preach</songId>
   <title>Papa Don't Preach</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madonna_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Madonna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-08-16</week>
      <week>1986-08-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/72/Madonna-Papa-Dont-Preach-5378.jpg/200px-Madonna-Papa-Dont-Preach-5378.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Madonna+Papa-Don-t-Preach.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>True Blue</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 11, 1986</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>CD Single</format>
      <format>CD Video</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1986</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:29</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Sire , Warner Bros.</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Brian Elliot</writer>
      <writer>additional lyrics by Madonna</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Madonna</producer>
      <producer>Stephen Bray</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Papa Don't Preach" is a dance-pop song by American singer
    and songwriter Madonna. The song was written by Brian Elliot
    with additional lyrics by Madonna, and produced by Stephen Bray
    and Madonna for her third studio album 
    <i>True Blue</i>, released in June 1986. The song also appears
    remixed on the 1990 compilation album 
    <i>The Immaculate Collection</i>and in its original form on the
    2009 compilation album 
    <i>Celebration</i>. The song's musical style combines pop and
    classical rhythms, and its lyrics deal with teenage pregnancy
    and abortion. The music video, directed by James Foley, shows
    Madonna's second image makeover, featuring her with a more
    toned and muscular body, and cropped platinum blonde hair.</p>
      <p>Released as the album's second single in mid-1986, the song
    was a commercial success. It became Madonna's fourth number-one
    single on the Hot 100, and performed well internationally,
    reaching the top position in Australia and the United Kingdom.
    It was generally well-received by music critics and was
    frequently cited as a highlight in the album.</p>
      <p>Shortly after its release, the song caused heated
    discussions about its lyrical content. Women's organizations
    and others in the family planning field criticized Madonna for
    encouraging teenage pregnancy, while groups opposed to abortion
    saw it as a positive pro-life message. The song also caused her
    first conflict with the Vatican, as she dedicated the song to
    Pope John Paul II, who urged Italian fans to boycott her
    concerts during the Who's That Girl World Tour in 1987.</p>
      <p>During the autumn of 1985, Madonna started writing and
    recording songs for her third studio album, 
    <i>True Blue</i>. She brought back Steve Bray and hired a new
    songwriter collaborator, Patrick Leonard, to help her co-write
    eight of the album's nine tracks. The album's first track "Papa
    Don't Preach", was written by Brian Elliot, who described it as
    "a love song, maybe framed a little bit differently". The song
    is based on teen gossip he heard outside his studio, which has
    a large front window that doubles as a mirror where schoolgirls
    from the North Hollywood High School in Los Angeles regularly
    stopped to fix their hair and chat. The song was sent to
    Madonna by Michael Ostin, the same Warner Bros. executive that
    discovered "Like a Virgin". Madonna only contributed with some
    minor lyrical revisions, making "Papa Don't Preach" the only
    song in the album that she did not have a strong hand in
    writing. In 2009, during an interview with 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>Madonna was asked by the interviewer Austin
    Scaggs as to why the theme of the song was meaningful to her.
    She replied saying,</p>
      <p>"[The song] just fit right in with my own personal zeitgeist
    of standing up to male authorities, whether its the pope, or
    the Catholic Church or my father and his conservative,
    patriarchal ways. [...] For 'Papa Don't Preach' there were so
    many opinions – that's why I thought it was so great. Is she
    for 'schma-smortion', as they say in 
    <i>Knocked Up</i>? Is she against abortion etc."</p>
      <p>"Papa Don't Preach" is a dance-pop song with instrumentation
    from acoustic, electric, and rhythm guitars, keyboards, and
    string arrangements. It is set in common time, and moves at a
    moderate tempo of 116 beats per minute. The song is written in
    the key of F minor, an unusual choice for a pop song, but
    commonly used in classical music, like Beethoven's 
    <i>Appassionata</i>sonata. The combination of key and tempo
    produces a disjuncture between pop and classical rhythms,
    underlined by the instrumentation during the introduction.</p>
      <p>The song begins with a distinctly Vivaldian style, as the
    fast tempo and classical-style chord progression anticipates
    the lyrics to follow. The opening chords and the melody
    emphasize the tonic of the leading notes: Fm–E
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>–D
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>–Cm–D
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>–E
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>–Fm–D
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>–E
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>–Fm, resembling a Baroque work. This is followed by the
sound of dance music, produced by a powerful beat from the
instruments. Madonna's vocal range spans from F
    <sub>3</sub>to C
    <sub>5</sub>, and has a different sound from her previous work,
    more mature, centered, and with a lower range.</p>
      <p>The lyrics show Madonna's interest in her Roman Catholic
    upbringing, as the song theme is about a teenage girl who
    admits to her father that she is pregnant and refuses to have
    an abortion or give up the baby for adoption despite what her
    friends are telling her to do.</p>
      <p>It is constructed in a verse-chorus form, with a bridge
    before the third and final chorus. At the beginning, she
    addresses her father directly, asking him to talk to her as an
    adult, "You should know by now that I'm not a baby". The
    transition to the chorus employs a more dramatic voice with a
    higher range, ending nearly in cries as she sings the word
    "Please". Leading to the chorus, Madonna switches to a pleading
    voice, singing the song's main hook in a high tone. During the
    bridge, the song features a Spanish-inspired rhythm, one of the
    earliest examples of the influence that Hispanic music had on
    Madonna's musical style.</p>
      <p>"Papa Don't Preach" was generally well-received by pop music
    critics. Davitt Sigerson from 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine in a review of the album 
    <i>True Blue</i>said that if there is a problem with the album
    "it's the lack of outstanding songs", adding that "only the
    magnificent 'Papa Don't Preach' has the high-profile hook to
    match 'Like a Virgin', 'Dress You Up' and 'Material Girl'." In
    its review of 
    <i>True Blue</i>, Allmusic's Stephen Thomas Erlewine said that
    "she is using the music to hook in critics just as she's
    baiting a mass audience with such masterstrokes as 'Papa Don't
    Preach'." Robert Christgau in a review for 
    <i>The Village Voice</i>felt that "she [Madonna] doesn't speak
    for the ordinary teenaged stiff any more", adding that the
    "antiabortion content of 'Papa Don't Preach' isn't unequivocal,
    and wouldn't make the song bad by definition if it were, the
    ambiguity is a cop-out rather than an open door, which is
    bad."</p>
      <p>Sal Cinquemani from Slant Magazine said that "with songs
    like 'Papa Don't Preach', Madonna made the transition from pop
    tart to consummate artist, joining the ranks of 80s icons like
    Michael Jackson and Prince." David Browne from 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>in a review of her first compilation
    album 
    <i>The Immaculate Collection</i>, commented that "in theory a
    30-ish urban sophisticate singing in the voice of a pregnant
    teen, sounds ridiculous", but added that "with the help of
    collaborators like Stephen Bray and Patrick Leonard, though,
    turns into a perfectly conceived pop record". 
    <i>Blender'</i>s Tony Power said that the "baroque faux strings
    and abortion dilemma of 'Papa Don’t Preach' herald a new, less
    querulous Madonna, girlishly in love with Sean Penn and
    bolstered by writer-producer Pat Leonard." In 2005, the same
    magazine placed the song at number 486 on its list of "The 500
    Greatest Songs Since You Were Born". In 1987, the song was
    nominated for Best Female Pop Vocal Performance at the 29th
    Grammy Awards, but lost to Barbra Streisand's 
    <i>The Broadway Album</i>.</p>
      <p>"Papa Don't Preach" was released in the United States in
    June 1986. It debuted on the Hot 100 at number forty-two, and
    within eight weeks of its release, it had reached the top of
    the chart, making it Madonna's fourth number-one single in the
    U.S. It maintained the top position for two weeks, and spent
    eighteen weeks on the chart. In October 1998, the single was
    certified gold by the Recording Industry Association of America
    (RIAA). In Canada the song debuted at the fifty-three position
    of the 
    <i>RPM</i>singles chart on July 5, 1986, reached the top for
    two weeks in August 1986, and stayed on the chart for twenty
    weeks.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom "Papa Don't Preach" was released on
    June 23, 1986. The next week the song debuted at number
    thirteen on the UK Singles Chart, before climbing to number one
    two weeks later. It then spent three consecutive weeks at the
    top, stayed fifteen weeks on the chart, and was certified gold
    by the British Phonographic Industry (BPI) in August 1986.
    Across Europe, "Papa Don't Preach" was successful, topping the
    Eurochart Hot 100 for eleven weeks. It reached the top position
    of the singles charts in Belgium, Ireland, Italy, and Norway,
    and peaked inside the top five in Austria, France, Germany, the
    Netherlands, and Switzerland.</p>
      <p>For the music video Madonna sported a complete image
    makeover. She changed the heavy jewelry and make-up, and
    adopted the gamine look, which is notably applied to describe
    the style and appearance that Shirley MacLaine and Audrey
    Hepburn used during the 1950s. In the video Madonna played a
    tomboy, dressed in jeans, a black leather jacket, and a slogan
    T-shirt that announced "Italians do it Better". The video
    alternated between tomboy shots and those of a sexier Madonna
    with a more toned and muscular body, cropped platinum blonde
    hair, and figure-revealing clothing, consisting of a
    1960s-style black bustier top and capri pants. It was directed
    by James Foley, produced by David Naylor and Sharon Oreck, and
    Michael Ballhaus was in charge of the photography.</p>
      <p>It starts with shots of the New York skyline, the Staten
    Island Ferry, and character close-ups. Madonna plays a
    teenager, who is seen walking along a lane. Then it shows her
    thinking about her father, played by Danny Aiello, and how much
    he loves her. She then sees her boyfriend, played by actor Alex
    McArthur, coming along. The images are juxtaposed with shots of
    Madonna dancing and singing in a small, darkened studio.
    Madonna then moves away from her friends, who warn her from her
    boyfriend. She and her boyfriend spend a romantic evening
    together on a barge where they reflect upon their lives after
    watching an elderly couple. Then Madonna finds out that she is
    pregnant and after much hesitation tells her father. They have
    a few days of tension between them. Her father eventually
    accepts the pregnancy, and the final scene is a reconciliatory
    embrace between father and daughter.</p>
      <p>At the 1987 MTV Video Music Awards, the "Papa Don't Preach"
    video won the Best Female Video award, and was nominated for
    Best Cinematography and Best Overall Performance.</p>
      <p>Madonna has performed the song on three of her world tours.
    She premiered the song in 1987, during her Who's That Girl
    World Tour, where she danced around the stage wearing a white
    Spanish-style dress designed by Marlene Stewart, and a black
    leather jacket similar to the one she used in the music video.
    The screen in the background showed portraits of Pope John Paul
    II and then-President of the U.S. Ronald Reagan, along with
    scenes of John Perry III's short film, 
    <i>The Nightmare</i>, ending with the words "Safe Sex", as
    Madonna finished the song. She dedicated the song to the Pope,
    marking her first conflict with the Vatican, as Pope John Paul
    II urged Italian fans to boycott her concerts. Two different
    performances of the song on this tour can be found on the
    videos: 
    <i>Who's That Girl - Live in Japan</i>, filmed in Tokyo, Japan,
    on June 22, 1987, and 
    <i>Ciao, Italia! - Live from Italy</i>, filmed in Turin, Italy,
    on September 4, 1987.</p>
      <p>Three years later on her Blond Ambition World Tour, Madonna
    evoked Catholic images during the "Papa Don't Preach"
    performance. She wore a black kaftan and energetically danced
    with an accompaniment of six male dancers, with a platform full
    of votive candles in the background. Two different performances
    were taped and released on video, the 
    <i>Blond Ambition - Japan Tour 90</i>, taped in Yokohama,
    Japan, on April 27, 1990, and the 
    <i>Live! - Blond Ambition World Tour 90</i>, taped in Nice,
    France, on August 5, 1990. In 2004, during the Re-Invention
    World Tour, Madonna performed the song wearing a Scottish kilt,
    and a T-shirt that said "Kabbalists do it Better" on most of
    the shows, and "Brits do it Better" and "Irish do it Better"
    T-shirts during the shows in the United Kingdom and Ireland,
    reminiscent of the one she used in the song's music video.</p>
      <p>"Papa Don't Preach" has been covered by numerous artists. In
    2002, British singer Kelly Osbourne recorded together with
    Incubus' members Mike Einziger (guitar), and Jose Pasillas
    (drums), a hard-rock cover of the song that was produced by her
    brother Jack Osbourne. It was included as a bonus track on her
    debut album 
    <i>Shut Up</i>and on the soundtrack of MTV's reality television
    program 
    <i>The Osbournes</i>. The song was released in the United
    Kingdom on September 2002, peaking at number three. In the rest
    of Europe, the song peaked inside the top ten in Ireland and
    Finland, and the top twenty in Sweden. In Australia the song
    debuted at number three, and received a platinum certification
    by the Australian Recording Industry Association (ARIA). This
    version was panned by music critics, who thought that the cover
    "makes precisely zero sense", and that it "reeks of
    opportunism", also criticizing Incubus' collaboration,
    describing it as "unimaginative", and that "their presence
    makes the whole mess barely distinguishable".</p>
      <p>French group Mad'House made an Eurodance cover of the song,
    that was included on their 2002 album 
    <i>Absolutely Mad</i>. Covers of the song on tribute albums
    include Brook Barros on 
    <i>The Music of Madonna</i>, released in 2005, and a jazz
    version on Bo. Da's 
    <i>Plays Madonna in Jazz</i>, released in 2007. The song has
    been sampled at the beginning of Mario Winans' 2004 single
    "Never Really Was", and a slowed down version by Keshia Chante
    sample the song in the 2006 single "Fallen" The television show
    Glee released a cover version performed by Dianna Agron.</p>
      <p>As the song's popularity increased in the U.S., so did the
    criticism and support it received from groups concerned with
    pregnancy and abortion. In July 1986, shortly after the release
    of the video for "Papa Don't Preach", Madonna commented on the
    controversy surrounding the song, to music critic Stephen
    Holden from 
    <i>The New York Times</i>:</p>
      <p>"Papa Don't Preach" is a message song that everyone is going
    to take the wrong way. Immediately they're going to say I am
    advising every young girl to go out and get pregnant. When I
    first heard the song, I thought it was silly. But then I
    thought, wait a minute, this song is really about a girl who is
    making a decision in her life. She has a very close
    relationship with her father and wants to maintain that
    closeness. To me it's a celebration of life. It says, 'I love
    you, father, and I love this man and this child that is growing
    inside me'. Of course, who knows how it will end? But at least
    it starts off positive.</p>
      <p>People that criticized the song's message include Ellen
    Goodman, a national syndicated columnist, who called the video
    "a commercial for teenage pregnancy". Feminist lawyer Gloria
    Allred, the spokeswoman of the National Organization of Women
    (NOW), angrily called for Madonna to make a public statement or
    another record supporting the opposite point of view. Alfred
    Moran, the executive director of Planned Parenthood of New York
    City, also criticized the song, fearing that it would undermine
    efforts to promote birth control among adolescents and that it
    would encourage teenage pregnancy. Recalling how his agency's
    clinics were filled in 1985 with girls wearing clothes that
    were an imitation of Madonna's style, Moran said that the
    song's message is "that getting pregnant is cool and having the
    baby is the right thing and a good thing and don't listen to
    your parents, the school, anybody who tells you otherwise—don't
    preach to me, Papa. The reality is that what Madonna is
    suggesting to teenagers is a path to permanent poverty."</p>
      <p>In contrast, groups opposed to abortion saw "Papa Don't
    Preach" as a positive, pro-life song. Susan Carpenter-McMillan,
    the president of the California chapter of Feminists for Life
    (FFL) in the U.S., said that "abortion is readily available on
    every street corner for young women. Now what Madonna is
    telling them is, hey, there's an alternative." Tipper Gore, a
    founder of the Parents Music Resource Center (PMRC), who a year
    earlier denounced Madonna for the sexual lyrical content of her
    single "Dress You Up", and had led a campaign against explicit
    content in music, commended Madonna for speaking candidly about
    such a serious subject and important social issue.</p>
      <p>The song's writer, Brian Elliot, commented about the debate:
    "I just wanted to make this girl in the song a sympathetic
    character. As a father myself, I'd want to be accessible to my
    children's problems." Madonna avoided the controversy, and did
    not comment on the song's use as an anti-abortion statement.
    Her publicist, Liz Rosenberg, said that "she [Madonna] is
    singing a song, not taking a stand", adding that "her
    philosophy is people can think what they want to think."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
