<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Who%27s_That_Girl_(Madonna_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Who%27s_That_Girl_(Madonna_song)</songId>
   <title>Who's That Girl</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madonna_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Madonna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-08-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/df/Who%27s_that_Girl_single_cover.jpg/200px-Who%27s_that_Girl_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Madonna+Who-s-That-Girl.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Who's That Girl</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 30, 1987 (U.S.) , July 14, 1987 (UK)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>Cassette</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1986</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Latin Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:57</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Sire , Warner Bros.</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Madonna</writer>
      <writer>Patrick Leonard</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Madonna</producer>
      <producer>Patrick Leonard</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Who's That Girl" is a song by American singer-songwriter
    Madonna from the soundtrack album 
    <i>Who's That Girl</i>of the motion picture of same name. It
    was released on June 30, 1987 by Sire Records as the first
    single from the album. It later appeared on the 1991 UK
    compilation EP 
    <i>The Holiday Collection</i>, which was released to accompany
    the 1990 compilation album 
    <i>The Immaculate Collection</i>, and has since been included
    on the two-disc edition of her 2009 greatest hits album 
    <i>Celebration</i>. While shooting for the film, then called 
    <i>Slammer</i>, Madonna had requested Patrick Leonard to
    develop an uptempo song that captured the nature of her film
    persona. She later added the lyrics and vocals to the demo tape
    developed by Leonard, and decided to call both the song and the
    movie "Who's That Girl".</p>
      <p>Featuring instrumentation from drums, bass, and stringed
    instruments, "Who's That Girl" continued Madonna's fascination
    with Hispanic culture by incorporating Spanish lyrics and using
    the effect of double vocals. Although it received mixed
    reactions from reviewers, the song became Madonna's sixth
    single to top the Hot 100, while peaking atop the charts in
    countries like the United Kingdom, Canada, Netherlands, Ireland
    and Belgium.</p>
      <p>The music video portrayed a different persona of Madonna,
    rather than her film character for which it was released. Like
    the song, it incorporated Hispanic culture and portrayed her
    dressed in Spanish style as a young lady in search of a
    treasure. It was criticised for not depicting her real self.
    Madonna performed the song once on the Who's That Girl World
    Tour in 1987. The song has been covered by many artists and has
    appeared in compilations and tribute albums.</p>
      <p>In 1986, Madonna was shooting for her third motion picture 
    <i>Who's That Girl</i>, known at the time as 
    <i>Slammer</i>. Needing songs for the soundtrack of the movie,
    she contacted Patrick Leonard and Stephen Bray, who had written
    and produced her third studio album 
    <i>True Blue</i>in 1986. Madonna explained to them that she
    needed an uptempo song and a downtempo song. She came to the
    studio one Thursday as Leonard developed the chorus of the
    song. He handed over that cassette to Madonna, who went to the
    backroom and finished the melody and the lyrics of the song,
    while Leonard worked on the other parts of the song. After
    finishing the lyrics, Madonna declared that she wanted the song
    to be named "Who's That Girl" and changed the movie to the
    same, rather than 
    <i>Slammer</i>, considering it to be a better title. In Fred
    Bronson's 
    <i>The Billboard Book of Number 1 Hits</i>book, Leonard
    explained that the song was recorded in one day with Madonna
    adding her vocals only once. Additional instrumental tracks
    with guitars and percussion were included by Leonard and Bray
    later. Regarding the development of the music for the film,
    Madonna further explained</p>
      <p>"I had some very specific ideas in mind, music that would
    stand on its own as well as support and enhance what was
    happening on screen and the only way to make that a reality was
    to have a hand in writing the tunes myself. [...] The songs
    aren't necessarily about Nikki [her character name in the
    movie] or written to be sung by someone like her, but there's a
    spirit to this music that captures both what the film and the
    characters are about, I think."</p>
      <p>The song is composed in Madonna's typical style—mingling the
    drum machine, a bubbling bass synth line, and the sound of
    stringed instruments. The three parts of the song, namely the
    bridge, where Madonna sings "what can help me now", the chorus
    and the verse flow together strongly. The chorus has a haunting
    effect in it. The song epitomizes Madonna's interest with
    Hispanic culture that continued after the release of "La Isla
    Bonita", by adding Spanish phrases in the chorus and over the
    trumpets of the second verse, and also by the added
    instrumental break in the middle. It also uses the sonic effect
    brought about by the combination of multiple vocal lines, which
    had been previously used by groups like The Beach Boys in their
    singles "God Only Knows" (1966) and "I Get Around" (1964) as
    well as R.E.M.'s singles "Fall On Me" (1986) and "Near Wild
    Heaven" (1991). "Who's That Girl" employs this effect on the
    last chorus where three or four different vocal hooks are
    intertwined.</p>
      <p>Critical reaction to the song has been mixed. In his book 
    <i>The Complete Guide to the Music of Madonna</i>, author Rikky
    Rooksby explained that the song was Madonna's best take on her
    original music style. Stephen Thomas Erlewine of Allmusic
    commented that "Who's That Girl" along with "Causing a
    Commotion" were not amongst Madonna's best singles. Although
    Tony Power of 
    <i>Blender</i>magazine criticised the whole soundtrack, he
    considered "Who's That Girl" to be its standout track.
    Biographer J. Randy Taraborrelli, in his book 
    <i>Madonna: An Intimate Biography</i>called the song
    "quintessential Madonna music" and went on to describe it as
    "funky, sassy and melodic, with a Latin accent." Noah Robischon
    from 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>opined that with the both the song
    and the movie, Madonna had pushed "synergy over the
    borderline." Bill Lamb of About.com said that the song, along
    with the second single from the soundtrack "Causing a
    Commotion", was not an example of Madonna's best music.</p>
      <p>"Who's That Girl" was released in the United States in June
    1987. It debuted on the Hot 100 at number forty-three, reached
    the top of the chart in its seventh week, maintained the top
    position for one week, and spent sixteen weeks on the chart. It
    became Madonna's sixth number-one single in the United States,
    making her the first artist to accumulate six number-one
    singles in the 1980s, and the first female performer to get
    that many number-ones as a solo act. The song peaked at number
    two on the Hot Dance Club Play chart. In 2000, the song came
    tenth in a vote conducted to determine the favourite Madonna
    song.</p>
      <p>In Canada, the song debuted at the eighty-third position of
    the 
    <i>RPM</i>singles chart on July 11, 1987, reached the top for
    one week on August 29, 1987, and stayed on the chart for
    twenty-three weeks. In the United Kingdom, "Who's That Girl"
    was released on July 14, 1987, and debuted at number three on
    the UK Singles Chart, soon climbing to number one the next week
    to become Madonna's fifth number-one single in the United
    Kingdom. Across Europe, "Who's That Girl" also topped the
    singles charts in Belgium, Italy, Ireland, and the Netherlands,
    as well as peaking in the top five in Austria, France, Germany,
    Norway, Sweden, and Switzerland.</p>
      <p>The music video was shot over two days, at Grayhall Mansion
    in Beverly Hills, California. Madonna had adopted a garish,
    platinum blond hairstyle for the 
    <i>Who's That Girl</i>movie which she used in the music video;
    it was her way of reviving the comedy heroine of the 1930s
    Hollywood screwball comedies. She continued with her Hispanic
    look from the "La Isla Bonita" music video, this time she
    appeared dressed boyishly in a wide-brimmed Spanish hat and
    bolero jacket—a combination which would later become a fashion
    trend.</p>
      <p>The music video, directed by Peter Rosenthal, begins with
    Madonna entering a park. After meeting two children and a
    teenage boy, they start roaming around the park, with Madonna
    singing the song. These scenes are interchanged with scenes
    from the motion picture, which show Madonna as the movie
    character Nikki Fynn. As the music video progresses, Madonna is
    shown to be in search of an Egyptian treasure casket. After
    being directed to it by a postcard displaying her cartoon
    impersonation, Madonna opens it to find a huge diamond. She
    looks up happily to the children. The video ends with them
    continuing dancing and Madonna carrying away the casket.</p>
      <p>The video portrayed a different image of Madonna rather than
    her real self. According to Vincent Canby of 
    <i>The New York Times</i>, Madonna at that time was shrewdly
    pragmatic about her persona and appearance—resembling Marilyn
    Monroe, but with the "comic tartiness" of Jean Harlow. This
    persona was reflected in the second half of the 
    <i>Who's That Girl</i>film. However, the music video chose not
    to capture her real self and qualities, or to promote the movie
    for which it was specifically created. Instead, it concentrated
    on the humerous off-putting personality of Madonna's film
    character depicted in the first half of the film. As a result,
    the video failed to appeal to people who were not acquainted
    with her prior work, nor with people who already knew and
    admired Madonna's erotic and funny performance in her music
    videos.</p>
      <p>Madonna performed the song live only once, on her 1987 Who's
    That Girl World Tour. The song was performed as the part of the
    encore. The outfit for the performance, designed by Marlene
    Stewart, was created with toy watches, plastic lobsters and an
    ashtray—thereby depicting her awareness of surrealism.
    According to biographer Andrew Morton, it also portrayed her
    tongue-in-cheek sense of style: when she bent over in this
    ensemble, she revealed panties with the word "Kiss" written on
    them. The performance included Madonna dancing around the stage
    in the dress and asking the audience to join her. Two different
    performances of the song on this tour can be found on the
    videos: 
    <i>Who's That Girl - Live in Japan</i>, filmed in Tokyo, Japan,
    on June 22, 1987, and 
    <i>Ciao, Italia! - Live from Italy</i>, filmed in Turin, Italy,
    on September 4, 1987.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered many times, mostly on tribute
    albums. In 1999, The Countdown Singers made a sound-alike cover
    version for the album 
    <i>Hit Parade of 80's, Vol. 2</i>. The Royal Philharmonic
    Orchestra (RPO) made an instrumental version of the song for
    the 1998 album 
    <i>Material Girl: RPO Plays Music of Madonna</i>. German
    actress Eva Mattes covered the song for her 2006 album 
    <i>Language of Love</i>. In 2007, The Bubonic Plague recorded a
    cover of the song that was included on the tribute album 
    <i>Through the Wilderness</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
