<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Music_(Madonna_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Music_(Madonna_song)</songId>
   <title>Music</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madonna_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Madonna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2000-09-16</week>
      <week>2000-09-23</week>
      <week>2000-09-30</week>
      <week>2000-10-07</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/1d/Music_%28single%29.jpg/200px-Music_%28single%29.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Madonna+Music.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Music</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 21, 2000</released>
   <formats>
      <format>DVD single</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>CD maxi single</format>
      <format>Video single</format>
      <format>Cassette single</format>
      <format>7" Single</format>
      <format>12" Maxi-single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1999 - 2000</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>Electropop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:45</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Maverick , Warner Bros.</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Madonna</writer>
      <writer>Mirwais Ahmadzaï</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Madonna</producer>
      <producer>Mirwais Ahmadzaï</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Music" is the first single by American singer-songwriter
    Madonna from her 8th studio album 
    <i>Music</i>and was released on August 21, 2000, by Maverick
    Records. It was also released on DVD single, a debut in this
    format by Madonna. It earned two Grammy Award nominations in
    2001, for Record of the Year and Best Female Pop Vocal
    Performance. In 2006, The song was remixed using "Disco
    Inferno" by the Trammps and was re-named "Music Inferno" for
    the 2006 Confessions Tour. This version appears on the 2007
    live album 
    <i>The Confessions Tour</i>.</p>
      <p>On May 27, 2000, an unauthorized copy of the song leaked
    onto the Internet. In several days it spread all over
    cyberspace through forums and Napster. Madonna's spokeswoman
    Liz Rosenberg reacted with the comment that the material was a
    "work-in-progress which was stolen". To counter the trend of
    music piracy, Madonna actively campaigned against Napster with
    fellow performers from other genres, including hip-hop artist
    Dr. Dre and Lars Ulrich, drummer of heavy metal band Metallica.
    Madonna later performed this song and several others on a
    promotional tour; her concert at Brixton Academy in London was
    a live webcast on her website and was watched by a record 10
    million people around the world.</p>
      <p>The opening line of the song ("Hey Mr. DJ, put a record on,
    I want to dance with my baby") features a male-sounding voice.
    The voice is actually Madonna's voice, heavily transformed.</p>
      <p>"Music" earned two Grammy Award nominations in 2001, for
    Record of the Year and Best Female Pop Vocal Performance.</p>
      <p>The song shot to the top of the charts very quickly. It went
    to number one in the USA, United Kingdom, Canada, Australia,
    Italy, South Africa and Argentina, to name but a few countries.
    It was Madonna's twelfth number one single in the USA. By
    reaching number one, it made Madonna the second artist to
    achieve number one hits in the 1980s, 1990s, and 2000s in the
    USA. The first was Janet Jackson, who had done the same
    achievement with "Doesn't Really Matter", which preceded
    "Music" as the Hot 100's number-one single. "Music" also being
    the longest running number-one spot at 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Dance Club Play, with spent a longevity
    five weeks at number one at the 2000s decade. Eventually
    "Music" went platinum, selling over a million copies, proving
    to be one of her biggest-selling singles. The song was her
    first number-one hit in the USA since "Take a Bow" went to
    number-one in 1995. it was also reported to be the best selling
    single of 2000. Music was the 24th best selling single of 2000
    in the UK.</p>
      <p>In 2003, Madonna fans were asked to vote for their top 20
    Madonna singles of all time by 
    <i>Q</i>magazine. "Music" was allocated the #2 spot.</p>
      <p>In 2004, Canadian tech-metal band Out of Your Mouth released
    a cover version, which reached the Top 40 in Canada.</p>
      <p>The music video was shot in April 2000 at A&amp;M Stage and
    a nightclub in downtown Los Angeles by Swedish director Jonas
    Åkerlund. The video stars Madonna and her longtime backup
    singer Niki Haris and actress Debi Mazar as well as comedian
    Sacha Baron Cohen as his famous character Ali G. The video
    starts with Madonna along with her friends boarding Ali G's
    limousine. The song starts and Ali G is directed to take them
    to a club, and later to a strip-club, where he is denied
    entrance. An animated section follows where, Madonna attacks
    various neon signs with the names of many of her songs,
    including "Rain", "Borderline", "Lucky Star", "Bad Girl",
    "Vogue", "Fever", "La Isla Bonita", "Express Yourself" and
    "Material Girl". In the extended version, at the end of the
    animated section, Ali G. briefly interrupts the song to
    demonstrate his rap skills to persuade Madonna to include him
    on her next single. An annoyed Madonna asks him to stop and to
    turn the song back on. Madonna was heavily pregnant with her
    second child, Rocco, during the shooting and the animated
    section of the video was added as a result. The video ends with
    Madonna and her friends travelling in the limousine with many
    of the strippers and Ali G engaging in a rendezvous with
    them.</p>
      <p>The video won several awards, including 
    <i>Best Pop Clip Of The Year</i>at the Billboard Video Awards
    in 2000 and 
    <i>Best Dance Video</i>at the International Dance Music Awards
    in 2000.</p>
      <p>The music video was parodied on MADtv. The parody was called
    
    <i>Movies</i>, and featured Mo Collins as Madonna. The video
    poked fun at Madonna's filmography, with an animated 'Madonna'
    attacking signs that had the names of her movies.</p>
      <p>The video to the single was released on DVD only and
    contains two versions of the music video: a standard version
    and an extended. It also includes a weblink to an official
    Madonna "Music" website, but the site is no longer active. The
    extended version includes the sequence during which Ali G
    interrupts the song to demonstrate his rap skills.</p>
      <p>The first live performance of "Music" was at the 2001 Grammy
    Awards. Since then, 
    <i>"Music"</i>has appeared in all four of Madonna's tours since
    it was released: Drowned World, Re-Invention, Confessions and
    Sticky &amp; Sweet.</p>
      <p>For the Drowned World Tour, it was used as the final encore;
    Madonna wore tight black jeans and a customised Dolce &amp;
    Gabbana halter top that proclaims "Mother" in the front and
    "F*cker" in the back. She sang the song surrounded by her
    dancers, while imagery of her all-time music videos were
    displayed on backdrop screens.</p>
      <p>"Music" was later added to the Re-Invention Tour as the
    fourth song of the Scottish segment; this mix of the song was
    slower, Hip-Hop-based. The same version was used at the 2005
    Live 8 benefit concert</p>
      <p>In the 2006 Confessions Tour, the song was mixed with The
    Trammps' 
    <i>"Disco Inferno"</i>, thus creating the hedonistic 
    <i>Music Inferno</i>. It was preceded by the short video
    introduction "The Duke Mixes The Hits", and it sampled the
    chorus from "Where's The Party", a song from her 1986 album
    "True Blue". Madonna and her two female back-up dancers
    appeared onstage wearing 
    <i>Saturday Night Fever</i>-inspired John Travolta outfits and
    started to sing "Music" together.</p>
      <p>
         <i>"Music"</i>was part of the Hard Candy Promo Tour, in support
    of the 
    <i>Hard Candy</i>album; this version sampled Fedde le Grand's 
    <i>"Put Your Hands Up for Detroit"</i>, getting a Dance-version
    of the song. It was the last song performed during the 2nd act
    of her Sticky &amp; Sweet Tour, the 
    <i>Old School</i>tribute, where Madonna used the version of the
    promotional tour, with a sample of Indeep's 
    <i>"Last Night A DJ Saved My Life"</i>at the beginning of the
    song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
