<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/This_Used_to_Be_My_Playground 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/This_Used_to_Be_My_Playground</songId>
   <title>This Used to Be My Playground</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madonna_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Madonna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1992-08-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/32/ThisUsedToBeMyPlayground.jpg/200px-ThisUsedToBeMyPlayground.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Madonna+This-Used-to-Be-My-Playground.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>A League of Their Own</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 16, 1992 (Worldwide) , July 19, 1992 (U.K.) , July 25, 1992 (Japan)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Cassette</format>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>CD maxi</format>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1992</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:10</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Sire , Warner Bros.</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Madonna</writer>
      <writer>Shep Pettibone</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Madonna</producer>
      <producer>Shep Pettibone</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"This Used to Be My Playground" is a song performed by
    Madonna. It is the theme for the film 
    <i>A League of Their Own</i>, which starred Madonna as well as
    Tom Hanks, Geena Davis and Rosie O'Donnell.</p>
      <p>The song was written and produced by Madonna and Shep
    Pettibone, and recorded as one of the last songs during the
    sessions for her 1992 studio album 
    <i>Erotica</i>. Released in the summer, the single was a
    worldwide hit, spending one week at number one on the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100 in August 1992, and became Madonna's tenth
    chart topper, breaking her tie with Whitney Houston to become
    the female artist with the most number one singles at that
    time. The song entered the charts in the UK top five, peaking
    at number three for two weeks and was another top five hit for
    Madonna in numerous other markets.</p>
      <p>Though featured in the film, it was not available on the
    soundtrack album. It was originally available on the
    Olympics-inspired 
    <i>Barcelona Gold</i>compilation album released that summer,
    but in a shorter edit than any of the versions on the
    commercial singles. It would later be featured on Madonna's
    1995 ballads compilation, 
    <i>Something to Remember</i>.</p>
      <p>In spite of its commercial success, Madonna has never
    performed it in any of her concerts or media appearances. It
    also does not appear on succeeding greatest hits albums 
    <i>GHV2</i>(2001) and 
    <i>Celebration</i>(2009). A reference to this song was made in
    2006 by singer Robbie Williams in his song "She's Madonna".</p>
      <p>The music video, directed by Alek Keshishian, was filmed in
    June 1992 at Raleigh Studios in Hollywood, California and
    Malibu Beach and world premiered on MTV on June 29, 1992. The
    video was commercially released in 2004 as a bonus feature on
    the 2-disc special edition DVD of 
    <i>A League of Their Own</i>. The video shows a photo album
    being viewed by somebody and Madonna singing in different
    settings from the different pictures inside the album.</p>
      <p>The 2000 compilation 
    <i>Virgin Voices: A Tribute To Madonna, Vol. 2</i>features a
    cover by British New Wave/synthpop band A Flock of
    Seagulls.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
