<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Like_a_Prayer_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Like_a_Prayer_(song)</songId>
   <title>Like a Prayer</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madonna_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Madonna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1989-04-22</week>
      <week>1989-04-29</week>
      <week>1989-05-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/3c/Like_a_Prayer_Single_Cover.jpg/200px-Like_a_Prayer_Single_Cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Madonna+Like-a-Prayer.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Like a Prayer</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 27, 1989 (US, Europe) , March 6, 1989 (UK) , March 16, 1989 (Japan)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Cassette</format>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1988</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>Power Pop</genre>
      <genre>Gospel</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:40 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>5:50 ( Immaculate Collection Remix)</length>
      <length>5:19 (7" Version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Sire , Warner Bros.</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Madonna</writer>
      <writer>Patrick Leonard</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Madonna</producer>
      <producer>Patrick Leonard</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Like a Prayer" is the first single by American
    singer-songwriter Madonna from her 4th studio album, 
    <i>Like a Prayer</i>. It was released on February 27, 1989 by
    Sire Records. A power pop song by Madonna, it notably features
    a gospel choir. In Japan and Australia, a mini-album titled 
    <i>Remixed Prayers</i>was also released, which included remixes
    of the title track and also "Express Yourself". It later
    appeared remixed on the 1990 compilation album 
    <i>The Immaculate Collection</i>. It also appears on the 2009
    greatest hits album, 
    <i>Celebration</i>.</p>
      <p>"Like a Prayer" became one of Madonna's highest-selling
    singles in her career, selling over five million copies
    worldwide at the time of its release.</p>
      <p>The single version of "Like a Prayer" (7" remix) is slightly
    different from the album version in some extra background
    production, including a shorter and heavier guitar intro,
    louder bass, string arrangements in the verses and electric
    guitar at the song's climax. In addition, the album version
    features bass guitar played by Randy Jackson, the 7" version
    has a much more complex part created and played by Guy Pratt,
    doubled by an analogue Minimoog bass synthesizer. Several of
    the versions of "Like a Prayer", excluding that on the album,
    were included on 
    <i>Remixed Prayers.</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Like a Prayer" was also remixed as a dance song by Shep
    Pettibone for Madonna's 1990 compilation album 
    <i>The Immaculate Collection</i>. The remix became almost as
    popular as the original version, though is often not as highly
    regarded by critics and fans alike.</p>
      <p>In 2003, Madonna fans were asked to vote for their Top 20
    Madonna singles of all-time by 
    <i>Q-Magazine</i>. "Like a Prayer" was allocated the Number 1
    spot. The song was ranked #300 on Rolling Stone's 500 Greatest
    Songs of All Time list.</p>
      <p>The cover artwork for the 7" single featured Madonna in a
    praying pose. The 12" artwork featured a painting by Madonna's
    brother Christopher of a classic (Catholic) naked Madonna
    wearing a halo and draped in a vine of thorns with a single
    blossoming flower. Of special note on this painted version of
    the cover - it features the letters MLVC (Madonna Louise
    Veronica Ciccone) with a prominently "fallen" letter P near the
    heart of the Madonna, indicating Madonna's recent divorce and
    distancing from husband Sean Penn. The UK and Germany also
    released a 2nd 12" in a mustard yellow colour version of the
    original 12" sleeve featuring three remixes including the
    Churchapella Mix. The 7" single features a unique version of
    the famous black &amp; white photo (also found on the back
    cover of the album of the same same.) This 7" cover version has
    a "hand tinted" colour wash applied which gives the artwork a
    dream-like quality. The same photograph in monochrome was used
    in shops in poster format to promote both the album and the
    single. Of special note, it is extremely rare for a 12" copy of
    a single to bear significantly if not altogether different
    artwork from its 7" counterpart. The original 3" CD single of
    the song was released with the original 7" artwork and is now
    quite rare and collectable. The two 5" reissue CDs of the song
    from the mid 90s feature the original 12" artwork plus an
    additional version with different mixes which has the
    background of the artwork altered to a mustard yellow color.
    The 12" Limited Edition Picture Disc of the release features a
    photograph of Madonna wearing jeans with a purple sheer blouse;
    she has straight dark hair and is posed in the throes of
    uninhibited dance. The reverse features a faded purple tinged
    photo of the original 7" with an overwritten tracklist. A maxi
    "Cassingle" was also issued featuring original "praying pose"
    artwork.</p>
      <p>"Like a Prayer" was a massive hit worldwide. In the U.S. the
    song went straight to the top of the Billboard Hot 100 in
    spring 1989 and also topped the Hot Dance Music/Club Play and
    Hot Dance Music/Maxi-Singles Sales charts. It peaked at number
    3 on the Billboard Adult Contemporary chart. It was released in
    the UK on 6 March 1989 and entered the UK Singles Chart
    straight at #2 before climbing to #1 and remaining there for
    three weeks until Easter Sunday (26 March). It also reached
    number one in countries such as Australia, Canada, Italy,
    Belgium, Ireland and many others. "Like a Prayer" was Madonna's
    fifth number one single on the Eurochart Hot 100 Singles chart,
    reaching the top on March 25, 1989, and staying at number one
    for 12 weeks.</p>
      <p>The highly controversial music video for the song was
    directed by Mary Lambert, who also directed "Borderline", "Like
    a Virgin", "Material Girl" and "La Isla Bonita". It was shot at
    Raleigh Studios in Hollywood, California and Madonna's scenes
    with burning crosses were filmed on San Pedro Hills in San
    Pedro, California. The video features actor Leon Robinson and
    premiered on MTV on March 3, 1989, and later went on to win the
    Viewer's Choice Award at the 1989 MTV Video Music Awards.</p>
      <p>It attracted criticism for its subplot of Madonna making
    love to Saint Martin de Porres - which some perceived as being
    a black version of Christ -, its use of Catholic iconography,
    including a scene where Madonna developed stigmata, and cross
    burning. The video topped MTV's countdown of "100 Videos That
    Broke The Rules" in 2005, and for the 25th anniversary of MTV
    (August 1, 2006), viewers voted the video as the "Most
    Groundbreaking Music Video of All Time". In addition, the video
    was ranked #20 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's "The 100 Top Music Videos" and
    #2 on VH1's 100 Greatest Videos. On November 27, 2007 Fuse
    named "Like a Prayer" as one of its ten "Videos That Rocked The
    World".</p>
      <p>Madonna was paid $5 million by Pepsi-Cola to appear in a
    commercial that would predominantly feature the world premiere
    of "Like a Prayer". The commercial, titled "Make a Wish", was
    filmed at Culver Studios in Culver City, California in late
    January 1989 and was directed by Joe Pytka. Depicting Madonna
    drinking Pepsi and watching a home video of her eighth
    birthday, the tone that the commercial sought to convey sharply
    contrasted with the official music video for the song. When
    Pepsi executives saw the completed video, they quickly yanked
    the advertisement after only two airings in an attempt to
    dissociate themselves from the controversy Madonna had created.
    (The two-minute commercial was shown just once on March 2, 1989
    during 
    <i>The Cosby Show</i>, and, in the UK, after much publicity, on
    March 2 during a commercial break on ITV 12 minutes into 
    <i>The Bill</i>.)</p>
      <p>Though her contract with Pepsi called for three future
    commercials, Madonna got to keep her five-million-dollar
    endorsement fee, without fulfilling her contractual
    obligations. When Madonna won the Viewer's Choice Award for
    "Like a Prayer" video at the MTV Video Music Awards in
    September 1989, in her acceptance speech she thanked Pepsi-Cola
    "for causing so much controversy!".</p>
      <p>During an MTV interview with Kurt Loder entitled "Breakfast
    with Madonna" in 1990, Loder asked Madonna about the "brouhaha"
    surrounding her own video for the song and Pepsi's reaction to
    it. Madonna said, "[Pepsi's spokespeople] said they just didn't
    like it."</p>
      <p>In 1990, Madonna performed a dance mix of "Like a Prayer"
    during her Blond Ambition Tour, the live performance for "Like
    a Prayer" was made with the musical arrangements of the song's
    12" Dance Version and the 12" Club Version. After not having
    performed it for years, she seemed to have re-discovered the
    power of the track , including it in the set of short promo
    performances for 2003 album American Life. It was also included
    in the 2004 Re-Invention Tour, with a back drop film made by PJ
    Lopez. Madonna sung the same version of the song during her
    three song set on Live 8 in 2005. A heavy dance version of the
    song, mixed with fragments of the dance track "Feels Like Home"
    by Meck, features in her 2008-2009 Sticky &amp; Sweet Tour. On
    January 22, 2010, Madonna performed an acoustic version of the
    song live during the Hope for Haiti telethon, broadcast
    worldwide. Jon Caramanica of 
    <i>The New York Times</i>commented: "For 20 years, that song
    has been the symbol of one of the most tumultuous and
    controversial periods in Madonna’s life. But for five minutes
    tonight, it was pure, put in service of something bigger than
    the singer."</p>
      <p>The song was redone as a hi-NRG/eurodance song in 2002 by a
    group called Mad'House and included on their album 
    <i>Absolutely Mad</i>. The Mad'House version reached #1 in
    Germany in 2002, which the original narrowly failed to
    manage.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
