<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vogue_(Madonna_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vogue_(Madonna_song)</songId>
   <title>Vogue</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madonna_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Madonna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1990-05-19</week>
      <week>1990-05-26</week>
      <week>1990-06-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/4f/Vogue_single_cover.jpg/200px-Vogue_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Madonna+Vogue.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>I'm Breathless</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 20, 1990</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Cassette</format>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>CD maxi</format>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>December 1989—January 1990</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>House</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:49 (album)</length>
      <length>4:19 (single)</length>
      <length>5:16 (greatest hits)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Sire , Warner Bros.</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Madonna</writer>
      <writer>Shep Pettibone</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Madonna</producer>
      <producer>Shep Pettibone</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Vogue" is a song by American singer-songwriter Madonna from
    her soundtrack album 
    <i>I'm Breathless (Music from and Inspired by the film Dick
    Tracy)</i>and was released on March 20, 1990, by Sire Records.
    It also appears in a slightly remixed and extended form on the
    1990 greatest hits compilation 
    <i>The Immaculate Collection</i>and Madonna's third greatest
    hits album, 
    <i>Celebration</i>. "Vogue" has become one of Madonna's biggest
    worldwide hits by topping the charts in over 30 countries,
    including Australia, Canada, United Kingdom and United
    States.</p>
      <p>In late 1989, after the album 
    <i>Like a Prayer</i>had spawned three U.S. hits - the title
    track, "Express Yourself" and "Cherish" - and a top-five
    European single in "Dear Jessie" - its fourth US single, "Oh
    Father", stalled at number twenty in the charts. Perhaps to
    ensure that the last single release of "Keep It Together" would
    fare better on the charts, Madonna and producer Shep Pettibone
    decided to compose a new song to be placed on the flipside of
    "Keep It Together" and quickly produced "Vogue". The song and
    video were inspired by the dance of the same name, performed in
    New York clubs on the underground gay scene, in which dancers
    used a series of complex hand gestures, body poses and
    movements to imitate their favourite Hollywood stars (see the
    list of the names of the Hollywood stars below), as well as the
    cover models from the magazine 
    <i>Vogue</i>.</p>
      <p>After presenting the song to Warner Bros. executives, all
    parties involved decided that the song was too good to be
    wasted on a B-side and that it should be released as a single.
    Although the song itself had nothing to do with Madonna's
    then-upcoming movie 
    <i>Dick Tracy</i>, it was included on the album 
    <i>I'm Breathless</i>, which contained songs from and inspired
    by the film.</p>
      <p>Bill Lamb from About.com commented that the song is
    "[p]ossibly the most perfect dance song Madonna, the most
    successful dance artist of all time, has ever recorded." He
    named "Vogue" the second "Top 10 Pop Songs of 1990" and the
    seventeenth "Top 100 Pop Songs of the 1990s." In 2003, Madonna
    fans were asked to vote for their Top 20 Madonna singles of
    all-time by 
    <i>Q-Magazine</i>. "Vogue" was allocated the #14 spot.</p>
      <p>The song is featured in 
    <i>The Devil Wears Prada</i>during a scene with Anne
    Hathaway.</p>
      <p>Aided by both a single version and an extended remix, as
    well as a black-and-white video directed by David Fincher, the
    song shot to number one in numerous countries. In the UK, the
    song knocked Snap!'s "The Power" off the number one slot and
    stayed there for four weeks, continuing a trend of club/pop
    crossovers going to number one. It was helped in the UK by
    mutli-formatting. As well as the 7, 12, CD and cassette
    singles, the label released four limited editions: 12 with Face
    of the 80s poster, 12 with 'X-rated poster and an extra remix
    on the b-side, 7 picture disc and 12 picture disc. In the US,
    the single reached multi-platinum status. In Australia, it was
    released as a double A-side to "Keep It Together", and it went
    to the top spot.</p>
      <p>In the U.S., massive airplay and sales demand in response to
    the popular music video (discussed below) in April 1990 made
    way for "Vogue"'s number 39 debut in the week of April 14. The
    song made it to number one on the Hot 100 in its sixth week on
    the chart, displacing Sinéad O'Connor's four-week run in the
    top spot with "Nothing Compares 2 U". The song also reached
    number one on the Hot Dance Club Play chart, remaining there
    for two weeks. It also became Madonna's first multi-platinum
    single in the United States.</p>
      <p>Worldwide, "Vogue" was the biggest hit in Madonna's career
    at that time, hitting number one in over 30 countries. It was
    later surpassed by Madonna's 
    <i>Guinness World Records</i>holding single, "Hung Up", which
    topped the charts of over 45 countries worldwide in 2005.</p>
      <p>The success of "Vogue" boosted the sales of the 
    <i>I'm Breathless</i>album, and combined with Madonna's 
    <i>Blond Ambition Tour</i>, generated massive publicity for the
    
    <i>Dick Tracy</i>movie.</p>
      <p>The video was directed by David Fincher and shot at The
    Burbank Studios in Burbank, California on February 9–10, 1990.
    In 1993, 
    <i>Rolling Stone magazine</i>listed the video as the
    twenty-eighth best music video of all-time. It was also ranked
    at number five on "The Top 100 Videos That Broke The Rules",
    issued by MTV on the channel's 25th anniversary in August 2006.
    It was the third time Fincher and Madonna collaborated on a
    video (the first being 1989's "Express Yourself" and the second
    being 1989's "Oh Father").</p>
      <p>Filmed in black-and-white, the video recalls the look of
    1930s Hollywood films with the use of artwork by the Art Deco
    artist Tamara de Lempicka and an Art Deco set design. Many of
    the scenes are recreations of photographs taken by noted
    photographer Horst P. Horst, including his famous "Mainbocher
    Corset". Some of the close-up poses recreate noted portraits of
    such stars as Marilyn Monroe, Veronica Lake and Marlene
    Dietrich. (Additionally, several stars of this era were
    name-checked in the song's lyrics.)</p>
      <p>There was some controversy surrounding the video due to a
    scene in which Madonna's breasts (though not her nipples) could
    be seen through her sheer blouse, as seen in the above picture.
    MTV wanted to remove this scene, but Madonna refused, and the
    video aired with the shot intact. The video was edited in
    Australia for daytime screenings, with the sheer blouse images
    replaced with slow motion shots of other parts of the
    video.</p>
      <p>The video features the dancers and back-up vocalists for
    Madonna's then-upcoming Blond Ambition Tour. The choreography
    was set by "Punk Ballerina" Karole Armitage. The video
    world-premiered on MTV on March 29, 1990.</p>
      <p>There are two versions of the video, the regularly aired
    television music video, and an extended version over three
    minutes longer.</p>
      <p>"Vogue" music video received a total of nine MTV Video Music
    Awards nominations, becoming her most-nominated video at the
    award show. It won Best Direction, Best Editing, and Best
    Cinematography.</p>
      <p>A performance of the song was included on the Blond Ambition
    Tour. Then a live performance of "Vogue" at the 1990 MTV Video
    Music Awards also proved popular and was released as a music
    video on 
    <i>The Immaculate Collection</i>compilation. It featured
    Madonna and her dancers dressed in an 18th-century French
    theme, with Madonna bearing great resemblance to Marie
    Antoinette. During the performance, Madonna and her dancers
    flashed their undergarments during their routine, and at one
    point Madonna pushed the faces of two male dancers into her
    breasts, and one of her dancers also fondled her breasts.</p>
      <p>In 1993, Madonna performed "Vogue" on her tour The Girlie
    Show. During the song, she wore a large beaded headdress
    inspired by The King And Iand the music was re-arranged with
    Middle-Eastern sounds. In 2004, Madonna opened her Re-Invention
    Tour with "Vogue". The version is included on the track
    setlists of 
    <i>I'm Going to Tell You a Secret</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2008-2009, Madonna once again performed "Vogue" on the
    Sticky and Sweet Tour. The song was layered over the backing
    horns of "4 Minutes", merging two of her popular hits. It also
    featured samples from Timbaland's "Give It to Me" and U2's
    "Discothèque".</p>
      <p>The lyrics of the song's rap reference the names of several
    20s, 30s, 40s and 50s stars, in this order (order sung in the
    song):</p>
      <p>Nine of the stars were still alive at the time the single
    was released: Garbo (who died less than a month after the
    single was released), Dietrich, DiMaggio, Brando, Gene Kelly,
    Rogers, Bacall, Hepburn, and Turner. Ten years after it was
    released, the only ones still alive were Bacall, Brando, and
    Hepburn. As of 2010, Bacall is the only one still alive.</p>
      <p>With the release of the song, Madonna brought the
    underground "vogueing" culture into the mainstream, although
    Malcolm Mclaren had a number one on the Billboard Dance Chart
    with Deep in Vogue the previous year. Before Madonna
    popularized the dance, Vogue was only performed in bars and
    disco of New York City on the underground gay scene.</p>
      <p>US CD Single</p>
      <p>US 12" Single</p>
      <p>7" Single (Worldwide)</p>
      <p>UK / EU CD Single</p>
      <p>UK / EU 12" Single</p>
      <p>US Cassette Single</p>
      <p>UK / EU Cassette Single</p>
      <p>JP 3" CD Single</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
