<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crazy_for_You_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crazy_for_You_(song)</songId>
   <title>Crazy for You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madonna_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Madonna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1985-05-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/67/Crazy_For_You_single_cover.jpg/200px-Crazy_For_You_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Madonna+Crazy-for-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Vision Quest</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 2, 1985</released>
   <formats>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>Cassette single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:10</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Geffen , Warner Bros. , CBS , Sire</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>John Bettis</writer>
      <writer>Jon Lind</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>John "Jellybean" Benitez</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Crazy for You" is a song by American recording artist
    Madonna, for the 1985 film 
    <i>Vision Quest</i>. It was released on March 2, 1985 by Geffen
    Records, as the first single from the soundtrack album of the
    film. The song appears remixed on the 1990 greatest hits album 
    <i>The Immaculate Collection</i>and was re-released on February
    24, 1991 by Sire Records to promote the album. It was also
    included on the ballads compilation 
    <i>Something to Remember</i>(1995) and the greatest hits
    compilation 
    <i>Celebration</i>(2009). Producers Jon Peters and Peter Guber,
    and music director Phil Ramone decided to use Madonna, after
    listening to her previous recordings. They employed John Bettis
    and Jon Lind to write the song. After reading the script of the
    film, Bettis and Lind wrote the song about the situation where
    the lead characters meet at a nightclub. Initial recording
    sessions did not impress Bettis and Lind, and they felt that
    "Crazy for You" would be dropped from the soundtrack. However,
    a new version was recorded which impressed them.</p>
      <p>John "Jellybean" Benitez was the producer for the song, and
    it was a challenge for him, as previously he was associated
    with recording dance-pop songs only. Initially Warner Bros.
    Records did not want the song to be released as a single, since
    they believed that "Crazy for You" would take away the
    attention from Madonna's sophomore release 
    <i>Like a Virgin</i>. In the end, Peters and Guber convinced
    Warner officials to green light the release of the single.
    "Crazy for You" ushered a new musical direction for Madonna, as
    previously she did not record any songs in the ballad genre. It
    features instrumentation from snare drums, harp, bass
    synthesizer and electric guitar. Lyrically the song talks about
    sexual desire between two lovers and consists of innuendos. It
    received positive reception from contemporary critics and
    scholars, and earned a Grammy Award nomination in 1986 for Best
    Female Pop Vocal Performance.</p>
      <p>The song became Madonna's second number-one single on the
    U.S. Hot 100 as well as reaching the peak position in the
    charts of Australia and Canada. It also reached number-two in
    the charts of Ireland, New Zealand and the United Kingdom,
    where it was released twice, once in 1985 and again in 1991.
    Madonna has performed "Crazy for You" in two of her concert
    tours – The Virgin Tour in 1995 and the Re-Invention World Tour
    in 2004. The performances were included in the home video
    release of the tours. The song has been covered by a number of
    artists.</p>
      <p>"Crazy for You" was written by John Bettis and Jon Lind. The
    ballad was released as the first single from the soundtrack of
    the 1985 film 
    <i>Vision Quest</i>, a coming of age drama about a wrestler
    played by Matthew Modine. Producers Jon Peters and Peter Guber,
    and music director Phil Ramone was aware of the then unknown
    Madonna, who was just signed to Sire Records. Ramone took her
    for dinner at his house in Carolwood Records, where she played
    some of her music videos. Ramone and the other Warner
    executives present there, were impressed by Madonna's
    self-possession and fishnet-crucifix style. So they decided to
    test her voice in a New York studio. Peters was impressed with
    Madonna and assigned Joel Sill, an executive in charge of music
    at Warner Bros. Pictures, to handle the recording of the two
    songs for the film. Sill sent the script of the film to Bettis
    and Lind. After going through the script, Bettis wanted to
    write a song about the situation, where the main characters – a
    young boy and a girl boarding at a house – dance together at a
    nightclub. He elaborated,</p>
      <p>"We were noodling around and 'Crazy for You' was something
    that Jon was singing over that section of the song. It was
    really descriptive of the scene in the film. [...] After that,
    I was out on vacation out in the desert and [Sill] called and
    said Phil Ramone was in love with the song and wanted to cut it
    on Madonna. [Laughing] 'Borderline' was out at that time and I
    said, 'Excuse me? This is for Madonna? Really? Can she sing a
    song like this?' Jon and I were surprised at the choice of
    artist at the time, if you want to know the truth."</p>
      <p>After Sill let Bettis and Lind know that Madonna was singing
    the song, some time elapsed before either of them heard
    anything from Warner Bros. Records. In between, they went to
    one of the recording sessions and were not impressed with the
    process of recording the song. Bettis commented, "We went to
    one of the sessions, and to be honest, that particular session
    did not go all that well. [...] Jon and I were depressed about
    the way the song had come out. We heard nothing else about it
    and we were a little nervous that the song was going to be
    dropped from the picture." Bettis went to England to work on
    the 1985 fantasy film 
    <i>Legend</i>with music producer Jerry Goldsmith. It was there
    he received a call from Lind, who informed Bettis that a new
    version of "Crazy for You" was recorded and was made ready for
    a single release. An astounded Bettis went over to Lind's
    house, where he warmly received the new recorded version of the
    song, incorporating a different arrangement from the demo
    version. The arrangement was done by composer Rob Mounsey who
    rearranged the original track and added the background vocals.
    Bettis showed his gratitude to Mounsey saying "We owe a big
    debt of gratitude to [Mounsey]. He really made a hit record out
    of [the song]." Mounsey was introduced in the project by record
    producer John "Jellybean" Benitez who was producing "Crazy for
    You". Benitez was previously associated with producing
    dance-pop themed songs and it was the first time that he
    produced a ballad. In Fred Bronson's 
    <i>The Billboard Book of Number 1 Hits</i>, Benitez
    commented,</p>
      <p>"The song was recorded live. It was the first time that I
    produced a live session, as opposed to having synthesizers and
    drum machines do everything. [...] I was tense because I had
    never done a record like this. [...] Everything I did was
    totally on instinct. I tried to make the song stand on its own,
    but at the same time work in the two scenes in which it was
    used in the movie."</p>
      <p>Benitez also noted that "Crazy for You" was an important
    recording for Madonna, as the song being a ballad, was openly
    accepted at adult contemporary radios. She had already charted
    with her singles "Like a Virgin" and "Material Girl", hence
    Madonna wanted to prove that she can sing in a different genre
    of music. However, Warner initially did not want the song to be
    released as a single, since the release of 
    <i>Vision Quest</i>coincided with the release of Madonna's
    second studio album 
    <i>Like a Virgin</i>and releasing "Crazy for You" would have
    distracted attention from the album. Warner Bros. Records chief
    Mo Ostin went to Robert A. Daly, chairman of Warner, and
    requested him to pull out the Madonna tracks from the 
    <i>Vision Quest</i>soundtrack. Daly summoned Peters and Guber
    to his office and informed them that they had to let-go of the
    Madonna tracks. Peters protested and shouted at Daly, resulting
    him escaping in fright and Warner allowing "Crazy for You" to
    be released as a single.</p>
      <p>"Crazy for You" ushered in a new musical direction for
    Madonna, as she had never recorded ballad songs previous to
    this. The song is sophisticated compared to her previous
    singles. The introduction features a melody by a woodwind
    instrument and an electric guitar chord, sliding from one motif
    to the other. It features beats by a snare drum on the last
    beat of the bar, leading to the spacey quality of most of the
    verses. Other instrumentation comes from a harp, a bass
    synthesizer and a chattering single note guitar lick. The
    fuller rhythm of the song does not start, until the chorus is
    reached. The turn of the melody allows Madonna's voice to
    stretch further on the higher notes. "Crazy for You" is set in
    the time signature of common time, with a medium tempo of 104
    beats per minute. It is set in the key of E major with
    Madonna's voice spanning between the high note of G to the low
    note of C. The song has a basic sequence of A–G
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♯
</span>–C
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♯
</span>m7–G/A – A/B as its chord progression. Unlike her previous
singles, the chord sequence does not repeat itself and the chorus
slowly unravels to the climax of the song. Lyrically, the song
talks about extreme love for one another. It contains innuendos
similar to The Crystals' 1963 song "Then He Kissed Me". According
to scholar Dave Marsh, the lyrics talk about a state of frank
sexual desire among two teenagers. He also said that the line "I'm
crazy for you; Touch me once and you'll know it's true" was not
ambiguous and it helped Madonna capitalize on such
disambiguation.</p>
      <p>Rikky Rooksby, author of 
    <i>The Complete Guide to the Music of Madonna</i>, complimented
    the song calling it sophisticated. Alex Henderson of Allmusic
    felt that the other song on the 
    <i>Vision Quest</i>soundtrack, titled "Gambler", should have
    been the more successful single. Stephen Thomas Erlewine from
    Allmusic called the song as one of her biggest hits. Biographer
    J. Randy Taraborrelli called the song "sassy" and commented
    that the song provided proof that Madonna was vocally capable
    of delivering a serious ballad. Author Andrew Morton believed
    that the song cemented Madonna as a talented and serious singer
    which "had been missing from her past recordings." Allen Metz
    and Carol Benson, authors of 
    <i>The Madonna Companion: Two Decades of Commentary</i>, said
    that the song sounded like a "remake of sweet-sixteen Connie
    Francis tune, dripping with old-fashioned, hand-held romance"
    especially in the line "It's so brand new; I'm really crazy for
    you." Dave Marsh, author of 
    <i>The heart of rock &amp; soul: the 1001 greatest singles ever
    made</i>, felt that with the coda of the song, Madonna
    transformed her record into an adult love song. William McKeen,
    author of Rock and roll is here to stay: an anthology, felt
    that the song "offered an aggressive sexuality for women".
    Maria Raha, author of 
    <i>Cinderella's big score: women of the punk and indie
    underground</i>, said that with the song, "Madonna brought a
    trunk full of trite lyrics on the long-standing tradition of
    pop music, love." "Crazy for You" was nominated for Best Female
    Pop Vocal Performance at 1986 Grammy Awards, but lost to
    Whitney Houston's "Saving All My Love for You". The song was
    ranked number 38 on VH1's "100 Greatest Love Songs", and during
    the special it was revealed that "Crazy for You" was recorded
    in one take. In 2003, Madonna fans were asked to vote for their
    Top 20 Madonna singles of all-time by magazine. "Crazy for You"
    was allocated the eleventh spot.</p>
      <p>In the United States, "Crazy for You" became Madonna's
    second number-one single on the Hot 100. The song debuted on
    the chart at number fifty-four on the issue dated March 30,
    1985. After six weeks, the song reached the top of the chart,
    replacing "We Are the World" by USA for Africa, and stayed at
    the position for one week. "Crazy for You" was the second
    number-one song for Bettis as a songwriter, after "Top of the
    World by The Carpenters (1973). With "Crazy for You", Bettis
    was in doubt whether the song would reach the top, after it was
    stuck at number two for three weeks, behind "We Are the World".
    Both he and Lind commented, "If you gotta lose to something, it
    as well be ['We Are the World']. Luckily enough, the final week
    of the upsurge of the record, we topped 'We Are the World',
    which lets you know how hot the song and how hot the artist
    was." "Crazy for You" was certified gold by the Recording
    Industry Association of America (RIAA) on July 16, 1985, for
    shipment of one million copies of the single across United
    States – the requirement for a gold single prior to 1989. The
    song reached number two on the Adult Contemporary Singles and
    eighty on the Hot Black Singles chart. In Canada, the song
    debuted at number seventy on the 
    <i>RPM</i>issue dated March 16, 1985. On its eleventh week on
    the chart, the song reached the top position. It was present on
    the chart for twenty-five weeks and ranked seventh on the 
    <i>RPM</i>Year-end chart for 1985.</p>
      <p>The song reached number one in Australia and displaced
    another Madonna release, "Angel"/"Into the Groove", from the
    top spot on the Australian Kent Music Report chart, making
    Madonna one of only a handful of acts who have ever replaced
    themselves at the No.1 spot on the Australian singles chart.
    After the song was released in the United Kingdom on June 8,
    1985, it debuted and peaked at two. In February 1991, the song
    was re-released and again reached a peak of two. "Crazy for
    You" was certified gold by the British Phonographic Industry
    (BPI) for shipment of 400,000 copies across United Kingdom.
    Such was Madonna's popularity that when 
    <i>Vision Quest</i>was released in home video, it was re-named
    as 
    <i>Crazy for You</i>, to cash in on her success. "Crazy for
    You" was also a number-two hit in Ireland and New Zealand. The
    song reached the top-twenty in Belgium, Europe, Italy, Japan,
    Netherlands, Sweden and Switzerland and top forty of Austria,
    France and Germany.</p>
      <p>Madonna first performed "Crazy For You" on her 1985 The
    Virgin Tour. She wore a black top and long black skirt with her
    hair in knots and a crucifix attached in the back. After an
    energetic performance of "Over and Over", Madonna sat down on
    the steps and sang "Crazy for You". Paul Grein, music editor of
    
    <i>Billboard</i>, commented that "She was at her best on 'Crazy
    for You', making good use of a deeper, huskier vocal quality
    that mirror's the song's deeper lyrical approach. The
    performance was included in the VHS release 
    <i>Live – The Virgin Tour</i>recorded in Detroit, Michigan. In
    the Re-Invention World Tour of 2004, Madonna performed the song
    in the last segment of the show. She wore a Scottish kilt and a
    t-shirt which had different captions in different venues;
    usually it had the caption "Kabbalists Do It Better", however
    she also had "Brits Do It Better" and "Irish Do It Better" on
    the British and Irish stops of the tour, respectively. As
    Madonna finished singing "Papa Don't Preach", she went to the
    second stage and announced: "This next song I dedicate to all
    my fans who has been with me for all the twenty years," and
    started to sing the song. At the end of the performance, she
    threw her t-shirt to the audience. The performance was excluded
    from the album of the documentary on the tour titled 
    <i>I'm Going to Tell You a Secret</i>, which was released in
    2005.</p>
      <p>Several Filipino acts have recorded remakes of "Crazy for
    You" including, Sponge Cola in 2004, Michael Cruz in 2005 and
    MYMP on their album 
    <i>New Horizon</i>(2006). In 2007, Groove Armada recorded a
    cover with Alan Donohoe of art rock band The Rakes on vocals
    for the compilation 
    <i>Radio 1 Established in 1967</i>. New Found Glory recorded a
    punk pop cover of the song with Max Bemis for their 2007 album 
    <i>From the Screen to Your Stereo Part II</i>. A cover of the
    song by Lion of Panjshir was included on the 2007 Madonna
    tribute compilation 
    <i>Through the Wilderness</i>. Melissa Totten did a Hi-NRG
    cover for her 2008 dance album, 
    <i>Forever Madonna</i>. An instrumental version was played in
    the 
    <i>Full House</i>episode 
    <i>13 Candles</i>when Kimmy dares DJ to kiss Kevin at her
    party. It was also featured in the 2004 film 
    <i>13 Going on 30</i>, starring Jennifer Garner. Chris Griffin
    performed the song during the "Long John Peter" episode of 
    <i>Family Guy</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
