<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Like_a_Virgin_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Like_a_Virgin_(song)</songId>
   <title>Like a Virgin</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madonna_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Madonna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1985-01-05</week>
      <week>1985-01-12</week>
      <week>1985-01-19</week>
      <week>1985-01-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/d0/Likeavirgin.jpg/200px-Likeavirgin.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Madonna+Like-a-Virgin.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Like a Virgin</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 6, 1984</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>April 1984</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Dance</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:38</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Sire , Warner Bros.</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Billy Steinberg</writer>
      <writer>Tom Kelly</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Nile Rodgers</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Like a Virgin" is a song by American recording artist
    Madonna from her second album of the same name. It was released
    on November 6, 1984 by Sire Records, as the first single from
    the album. The song appears on the greatest hits compilation
    albums 
    <i>The Immaculate Collection</i>(1990) and 
    <i>Celebration</i>(2009). It was written by Billy Steinberg and
    Tom Kelly and produced by Nile Rodgers; Steinberg said that the
    song was inspired by his personal experiences of romance. It
    was chosen for Madonna by Michael Ostin of Warner Bros. Records
    after listening to a demo sung by Kelly. However, Rodgers
    initially felt that the song did not have a good enough hook
    and was not suitable for Madonna, but subsequently changed his
    opinion after the hook was stuck in his mind.</p>
      <p>Musically "Like a Virgin" is a dance-oriented song, composed
    of two hooks. Madonna's voice is heard in a high register while
    a continuous arrangement of drums are heard along the bassline.
    The lyrics of the song is ambiguous and consists of hidden
    innuendo. In sexual terms, the lyrics can be interpreted in
    different ways for different people. "Like a Virgin" received
    positive reviews from contemporary as well as old critics, who
    frequently called it as one of the defining songs for Madonna.
    It became her first number-one single on the Hot 100, while
    reaching the top of the charts in Australia, Canada and Japan
    and the top-ten of the other countries.</p>
      <p>The music video portrayed Madonna sailing down the riverways
    of Venice in a gondola, as well as roaming around a palace
    wearing a white wedding dress. With the video, scholars noted
    Madonna's portrayal of a sexually independent woman, the
    symbolism of the appearance of a man with lion's mask to that
    of Saint Mark, and compared the eroticism of the video to the
    vitality of the city of Venice. Madonna has performed the song
    in five of her concert tours, most recent being the Confessions
    Tour in 2006. Majority of the time, her performances of "Like a
    Virgin" has been associated with strong reaction and uproar
    from the media.</p>
      <p>"Like a Virgin" has been covered by a number of artists and
    has appeared in feature films such as 
    <i>Reservoir Dogs</i>, 
    <i>Moulin Rouge! and Bridget Jones: The Edge of Reason</i>.
    Family groups sought to ban it as they believed that the song
    promoted sex without marriage. On the other hand, Madonna's
    public persona of an indomitable, sexually unashamed, supremely
    confident woman was widely accepted by the younger generation
    who emulated her style and fashion. Scholars have credited
    "Like a Virgin" as the song, which cemented her place in the
    pop music scene.</p>
      <p>"Like a Virgin" was written by Billy Steinberg and Tom
    Kelly. In an interview with the 
    <i>Los Angeles Times</i>, Steinberg explained that the song was
    not only not written for Madonna, it was not even written for a
    female singer but was inspired by his personal experiences.</p>
      <p>"I wasn't just trying to get that racy word 
    <i>virgin</i>in a lyric. I was saying ... that I may not really
    be a virgin — I've been battered romantically and emotionally
    like many people — but I'm starting a new relationship and it
    just feels so good, it's healing all the wounds and making me
    feel like I've never done this before, because it's so much
    deeper and more profound than anything I've ever felt."</p>
      <p>Kelly recorded the demo, and invited Michael Ostin of Warner
    Bros. Records' A&amp;R department to his house to listen to it.
    Steinberg and Kelly played four or five tunes for Ostin, and
    further discussed "Like a Virgin" – they were not sure for
    which artist the song would be suitable. Due to meet with
    Madonna the next day to discuss her sophomore album, Ostin
    intended on playing the demo to her, believing the lyrics and
    the groove of the song were perfect for Madonna. "When I played
    it for Madonna she went crazy, and knew instantly it was a song
    for her and that she could make a great record out of it,"
    Ostin recalled. In 2009, 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>interviewer Austin Scaggs asked Madonna
    what her first impressions were after listening to the demos of
    "Like a Virgin" and "Material Girl". Madonna replied:</p>
      <p>"I liked them both because they were ironic and provocative
    at the same time but also unlike me. I am not a materialistic
    person, and I certainly wasn't a virgin, and, by the way, how
    can you be 
    <i>like a virgin</i>? I liked the play on words, I thought they
    were clever. They're so geeky, they're cool. I never realised
    they would become my signature songs, especially the second
    one."</p>
      <p>In mid-1984, Madonna met up with producer Nile Rodgers at
    the then Power Station studios in New York. Rodgers initially
    did not want Madonna to record "Like a Virgin", as he felt that
    the lyric 'like a virgin' was not a terrific hook, according to
    him it was not an all-time catch phrase. Madonna did not care
    about the song either, after hearing the demo, she thought that
    it sounded "really stupid and retarded". Later, Madonna had
    second thoughts, "It's weird because I couldn't get it out of
    my head after I played it, even though I didn't really like it.
    It sounded really buble-gummy to me, but it grew on me. I
    really started to like it, [...] But, my first reaction to it
    was, 'This is really queer.'"</p>
      <p>Rodgers credits Madonna with recognizing the song's
    potential, he later said: "I handed my apology to Madonna and
    said, 'you know... if it's so catchy that it stayed in my head
    for four days, it must be something. So let's do it.'" Hence
    the song was finally recorded. Steinberg reflected on the
    recording process and commented that:</p>
      <p>"When Madonna recorded it, even as our demo faded out, on
    the fade you could hear Tom saying, 'When your heart beats, and
    you hold me, and you love me...' That was the last thing you
    heard as our demo faded. Madonna must have listened to it very,
    very carefully because her record ends with the exact same
    little ad-libs that our demo did. That rarely happens that
    someone studies your demo so carefully that they use all that
    stuff. We were sort of flattered how carefully she followed our
    demo on that.", "It was the perfect union, I knew it from the
    first day in the studio. The thing between us, man, it was
    passionate, it was creative. [...] Madonna was sometimes
    temperamental during the recording, everyone told me she was a
    terrible ogre, but I thought she was great."</p>
      <p>Jason Corsaro, the record's audio engineer, persuaded
    Rodgers to use digital recording, a new technique at the time
    which Corsaro believed was going to be the future of recording
    because test pressings always sounded consistent. To ensure
    this, Corsaro used a Sony 3324 24-track digital tape recorder
    and a Sony F1 two-track for the 12-bit mix. Madonna recorded
    the lead parts in a small, wooden, high-ceilinged piano room at
    the back of Studio C, also known as Power Station's "R&amp;B
    room".</p>
      <p>Corsaro then placed gobos around her while using the top
    capsule of a stereo AKG C24 tube microphone, with a Schoeps
    microphone preamplifier and a Pultec equalizer. Once the track
    met with everybody's approval, Robert Sabino added the keyboard
    parts, playing mostly a Sequential Circuits Prophet 5, as well
    as some Rhodes piano and acoustic piano, while Rodgers also
    played a Synclavier. Madonna, although not required, was
    present every minute of the recording sessions and the mixing
    process, Corsaro commented: "Nile was there most of the time,
    but she was there all of the time. She never left".</p>
      <p>Composed as a dance-oriented song, the intro of "Like a
    Virgin" consists of two hooks. The song is set in common time,
    with a moderately dance-groove of 118 beats per minute. It is
    composed in the key of F major with Madonna's voice ranging
    from the tonal nodes of high-tone G
    <sub>3</sub>to low-tone C
    <sub>5</sub>. According to Rikky Rooksby, the bassline on the
    intro is a re-working of the three-note bass motif present in
    the Four Tops' 1965 song "I Can't Help Myself (Sugar Pie Honey
    Bunch)", where Chuck Berry provided the chord arrangement. The
    bassline also has some similarity with Michael Jackson's
    "Billie Jean" especially during the second verse. Madonna sings
    the song in her high register while drum arrangement by Tony
    Thompson is heard alongside the bassline, which is also
    supported by a synthesizer arrangement, giving it a circular
    progression through all the seven diatonic chords of
    I–IV–VII–III–VI–II–V–I.</p>
      <p>Regarding the lyrics, Madonna had commented: "I like
    innuendo, I like irony, I like the way things can be taken on
    different levels." This statement highlighted the ambiguity of
    the lyrics of the song, which is hung on the word 'like'.
    Rooksby interpreted the meaning of the song in different ways
    to different people. He said that for women who were really
    virgins, the song encouraged them to hold their compose before
    they engaged in their very first sexual act. For sexually
    experienced girls, the song meant that they would be able to
    re-live the feelings of their first sexual encounter all over
    again. For the boys, the song presented a narcissistic image of
    them making the girl forget her past encounters and enjoy the
    sexual act as if for the first time.</p>
      <p>Stephen Thomas Erlewine from Allmusic said that "Like a
    Virgin" was a definitive statement. He added that the song, and
    "Material Girl" from the same album, made Madonna an icon. He
    added that both overshadowed the rest of the record, "because
    they are a perfect match of theme and sound." Debbie Miller
    from 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>commented that Madonna's voice "doesn't
    have the power or range of, say, Cyndi Lauper, but she knows
    what works on the dance floor." Dave Karger from 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>, while reviewing the album in 1995,
    felt that the song came off a bit repetitious and immature when
    compared to the present context. Jim Farber from 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>felt that the song raised the
    "madonna-whore" ante. Sal Cinquemani from Slant Magazine called
    the song a classic. Tony Power from 
    <i>Blender</i>listed the song as a standout track from the
    album. Alfred Soto from Stylus Magazine felt that the song was
    chic in its style. Katie Henderson from 
    <i>The Guardian</i>commented that the song was saucy in nature.
    Michael Paoletta from 
    <i>Billboard</i>commented that the song sustained a "fevered
    dance-rock momentum."</p>
      <p>In 2000, "Like a Virgin", was honored by 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>and MTV, as the fourth song on their list
    of the "100 Greatest Pop Songs". It was voted ten on VH1's 100
    Best Songs of the Past 25 Years. The song was listed at
    ninety-five on 
    <i>Billboard Hot 100 All-Time Top Songs</i>. In 2003, Madonna
    fans were asked to vote for their 'Top 20 Madonna singles of
    all-time', by 
    <i>Q</i>magazine. "Like a Virgin" was allocated the fifth spot
    on the list.</p>
      <p>"Like a Virgin" became Madonna's first of 12 number-one hits
    on the Hot 100, where it debuted at number forty-eight on the
    issue dated November 17, 1984. After five weeks, it reached the
    top of the chart and remained there for six weeks. The song was
    certified gold by the Recording Industry Association of America
    (RIAA) on January 10, 1985, for shipping a million copies
    across United States – the requirement for a gold single prior
    to 1989. The song also reached number-one on the Hot Dance
    Music/Club Play chart, and was her first top-ten entry on the
    Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs chart at position nine. In Canada,
    the song debuted on the Singles Chart at seventy-one on the 
    <i>RPM</i>issue dated November 24, 1984, and reached the top of
    the chart on January 19, 1985. It was present on the chart for
    a total of twenty-three weeks and ranked thirty-five on the 
    <i>RPM</i>Year-end chart for 1985.</p>
      <p>The song debuted on the UK Singles Chart on November 17,
    1984 at number 51 and peaked at number three on January 12,
    1985; it spent a total of 18 weeks in the chart, and was
    certified gold by the British Phonographic Industry (BPI) for
    shipment of 400,000 copies across United Kingdom. Across
    Europe, the song peaked within the top-ten of the charts of
    Austria, Belgium, France, Germany, Ireland, Italy, Netherlands,
    Norway and Switzerland. "Like a Virgin" became Madonna's first
    number-one song on the Australian Kent Music Report chart and
    on the Japanese International Singles Chart. It peaked at
    number-two on the New Zealand Singles Chart, fifteen on the
    Swedish charts and peaked the Eurochart Hot 100 Singles.</p>
      <p>The music video, directed by Mary Lambert, was shot in
    Venice, Italy and partly in New York City in July 1984. Madonna
    was portrayed as a knowing virgin, a figment of the
    pornographic mind, as she walked through marble rooms, wearing
    a wedding gown. It alternated with scenes of a slutty-looking
    Madonna on-aboard a gondola. The video started with Madonna
    boarding on a boat from the Brooklyn Bridge and travels to
    Venice. As she steps down into the city, she moved like a
    stripper and undulated sinuously. She wore a black dress and
    blue pants with a number of Christian symbol embedded jewellery
    around her neck. She sang the song at full volume as she
    watches a lion walking between the columns of the Piazza San
    Marco of Venice and along the statute of Saint Mark. A number
    of game-playing involving carnival masks, men, lions, werelions
    were portrayed with allusions to eighteenth-century practices
    and Saint Mark. Sheila Whiteley, author of 
    <i>Women and popular music: sexuality, identity, and
    subjectivity</i>, felt that Madonna's image signified a denial
    of sexual knowledge, but also portrayed her in simulated
    writhing on a gondola, thus underpinning the simulation of
    deceit. The intrusion of a male lion, confirmed the underlying
    bestial discourse of both mythological fairytale and
    pornographic sex. Whiteley observed that in the video,
    Madonna's lover wears the lion's mask and while cavorting with
    him, Madonna sheds the veneer of innocence and showed her
    propensity for wild animal passions. Having instilled desire,
    metaphorically she turned her lover into a Beast.</p>
      <p>With the video, scholars noted the expression of Venetian
    vitality in it. Margaret Plant (2002) commented: "With the lion
    of Saint Mark and the virginal city to the forefront, old
    sacrosanct Venice was propelled into a pop world of high-energy
    gyration, and endless circulation." She also noted that Saint
    Mark was a symbol of a time when sexual crime was punished
    severely in Venice and acts of rape, homosexuality and
    fornication incurred the loss of a nose, a hand or sometimes
    life itself. Madonna appeared to challenge such brutality and
    stretch the boundaries of tolerance in the video. As the
    lion-man carried Madonna to the Venetian palace, it symbolized
    an instance of the Saint taking the simulated Virgin, where
    Madonna became a symbol for La Serenissima, the Republic
    itself. Plant also noted that Madonna, in the video, restored
    the energy and eroticism of Venice, which had its name taken
    from Venus in familiar elision. As she exchanged her blue top
    for a black one during the video, Madonna demonstrated her
    mastery and bravery of the city, which had a reputation of
    turning out its visitors as victims. Carol Clerk (2002)
    commented that with the video, "Madonna's days as a cheap and
    cheerful video star were over. She was moving into serious
    spectacle."</p>
      <p>In 1985, a live music video of "Like a Virgin" from The
    Virgin Tour filmed in Detroit, was used to promote 
    <i>Live - The Virgin Tour</i>video release. This version was
    nominated for Best Choreography at the 1985 MTV Video Music
    Awards. The live performance of "Like a Virgin" from the Blond
    Ambition World Tour in Paris, France was released as a music
    video on May 9, 1991 to promote the documentary film 
    <i>Truth or Dare</i>. This version was nominated for two awards
    at the 1991 MTV Video Music Awards in the categories of Best
    Female Video and Best Choreography. This video was ranked at
    position sixty-one on VH1's 100 Greatest Videos.</p>
      <p>Madonna performed "Like a Virgin" at the first MTV Video
    Music Awards in 1984, where Madonna appeared on stage atop a
    giant wedding cake dressed in a wedding dress, adorned with the
    infamous "Boy Toy" belt buckle, and veil. The climax of her
    risqué performance found her humping and rolling around on the
    stage. Still today, the performance is noted as one of the
    iconic and biggest performance in MTV's history. The song has
    also been included in five of Madonna's eight concert tours.
    For 1985's The Virgin Tour, Madonna again donned wedding attire
    and performed a straight version of the song featuring a
    quotation from Michael Jackson's similar-sounding Motown-style
    single, "Billie Jean". Balloons floated out towards the
    audience as she rolled around the stage, carrying a wedding
    bouquet in her hand. The performance was included in the VHS
    release 
    <i>Live – The Virgin Tour</i>recorded in Detroit, Michigan. In
    the 1987's Who's That Girl World Tour, the song was given a
    lighthearted comedic theme and included quotations from The
    Four Tops' "I Can't Help Myself (Sugar Pie Honey Bunch)".
    Madonna took off her outfit piece by piece, until she was
    standing in a black corset, and ended the performance while
    flirting with an young male dancer who played her bridegroom.
    Two different performances of the song on this tour can be
    found on the videos: 
    <i>Who's That Girl – Live in Japan</i>, filmed in Tokyo, Japan,
    on June 22, 1987, and 
    <i>Ciao, Italia! – Live from Italy</i>, filmed in Turin, Italy,
    on September 4, 1987.</p>
      <p>For the 1990 Blond Ambition World Tour, the song was
    re-invented with a middle-eastern arrangement and risqué
    choreography which found Madonna wearing a gold corset, while
    simulating masturbation on a red silk bed, accompanied by two
    male dancers who wore the infamous cone bras designed by
    Jean-Paul Gaultier. The performance garnered a lot of
    attention, particularly when police in Toronto, Canada,
    threatened to arrest Madonna and charge her with indecency
    unless she altered the performance. Madonna refused and she was
    never arrested, as the show went on unaltered. Two different
    performances were taped and released on video, the 
    <i>Blond Ambition – Japan Tour 90</i>, taped in Yokohama,
    Japan, on April 27, 1990, and the 
    <i>Live! – Blond Ambition World Tour 90</i>, taped in Nice,
    France, on August 5, 1990. During The Girlie Show World Tour in
    1993, Madonna wore a tuxedo and adopted a Marlene Dietrich-like
    persona, singing the song with a thick German accent. She sang
    the word 'virgin' as '(w)irgin', while including a quotation
    from Dietrich's signature tune, "Falling in Love Again (Can't
    Help It)". The overplayed accent and three-quarter time
    signature gave the performance a sense of parody. Dietrich's
    look in the 1930 film 
    <i>Morocco</i>inspired the whole performance. The performance
    was included on 
    <i>The Girlie Show – Live Down Under</i>home video release,
    recorded on November 19, 1993 at Sydney, Australia.</p>
      <p>In April 2003, while promoting her ninth studio album 
    <i>American Life</i>, an impromptu acoustic performance of the
    song was done by Madonna at New York's Tower Records. Madonna's
    performance of "Hollywood" at the 2003 MTV Video Music Awards
    recreated the 1984 performance of "Like a Virgin". The
    performance started with Britney Spears emerging from a giant
    cake singing the first few lines. She was joined by Christina
    Aguilera and both of them writhed on the stage. Madonna
    appeared on the cake dressed as a groom and sang "Hollywood"
    with them ultimately kissing them both on the mouth. The
    performance was met with strong reaction from media.</p>
      <p>During the Confessions Tour in 2006, the song was given a
    horse riding theme. Madonna wore a tight, black body suit, and
    performed the song atop a studded leather S&amp;M carousel
    horse while X-rays of her broken bones, the result of a
    horse-riding accident on her forty-seventh birthday, flashed on
    the screens behind her. The performance was included on 
    <i>The Confessions Tour</i>live album, released in 2007. In
    2008's Sticky &amp; Sweet Tour, Madonna sang the song in Rome
    and dedicated the song to Pope Benedict XVI, commenting "I'd
    like to dedicate this song to the Pope, I know he loves me" and
    saying that she is a child of God. She asked the audience to
    sing with her.</p>
      <p>In 1985 The Lords of the New Church recorded "Like a Virgin"
    for their compilation album 
    <i>Killer Lords</i>. Gary Hill from Allmusic called the
    composition as "very funny and obnoxious". The same year,
    "Weird Al" Yankovic parodied the song with his single "Like a
    Surgeon" from the album 
    <i>Dare to Be Stupid</i>. Eugene Chadbourne from Allmusic
    commented: "Turning the tacky Madonna hit inside out and upside
    down, Yankovic comes up with a hilarious satire of the medical
    profession." In 1991 Glaswegian band Teenage Fanclub covered
    "Like a Virgin" on their debut album, 
    <i>The King</i>. The song also appears on the soundtrack of the
    2001 film 
    <i>Moulin Rouge!</i>and is sung by the characters Harold
    Zidler, played by Jim Broadbent, and The Duke of Monroth,
    played by Richard Roxburgh.</p>
      <p>In the opening scene of the 1992 film 
    <i>Reservoir Dogs</i>, Quentin Tarantino (as Mr. Brown) was
    shown talking about the song, and has an insight that "Like a
    Virgin" is a "metaphor for big dicks". When Madonna met Quentin
    Tarantino at a party, after the film was released, she gave him
    an autographed copy of her 
    <i>Erotica</i>album, signing "Quentin: it's about love, not
    dick". In the 2004 film 
    <i>Bridget Jones: The Edge of Reason</i>, the title character
    teaches the song to women in a Thai prison, after becoming
    annoyed that they are singing the song badly. She tells them,
    "Madonna is nothing if not a perfectionist!" In one of the
    episodes of the TV show 
    <i>Grey's Anatomy</i>, the character of Christina Yang hums the
    song during surgery to take the focus off herself. However,
    when her assisting surgery, Lexie Grey starts singing along,
    Christina looks venomously at her until she quiets down.</p>
      <p>After the song and its video were released, "Like a Virgin"
    attracted the attention of family organizations who complained
    that the video and the song, promoted sex without marriage and
    undermined family values, offering an unsavoury image of
    Madonna as a whore. Outraged moralists condemned her as a sex
    kitten and sought to ban the song and the video. Conservatives
    were angered that Madonna dared to portray religious symbolism
    and the virginal wedding attire in a sexual context. Clerk
    noted the song attracted an unprecedented level of attention
    from social groups compared to any female singer's song. "The
    main problem was that most of them listened superficially to
    the lyric of the song, imagining that it detailed or called on
    an innocent's sexual initiation." While one section of the
    population were outraged at the scandal, other were taking joy
    at the very notion of a virginal Madonna, who retorted by
    saying,</p>
      <p>"I was surprised by how people reacted to 'Like a Virgin'
    because when I did that song, to me, I was singing about how
    something made me feel a certain way – brand-new and fresh –
    and everyone interpreted it as I don't want to be a virgin
    anymore. Fuck my brains out! That's not what I sang at all.
    'Like a Virgin' was always absolutely ambiguous."</p>
      <p>The song's influence was most profound on the younger
    generation. Madonna's public persona of an indomitable,
    sexually unashamed, supremely confident woman struck a chord
    with them. Biographer Andrew Morton noted that most of
    Madonna's admirers were females, who were born-and-brought-up
    with an image of old-fashioned stereotypes of women as virginal
    brides, or as whores, or with feminist values that rejected the
    use of a woman's looks for her self-advancement. Author William
    McKeen of 
    <i>Rock and roll is here to stay: an anthology</i>commented
    that with the song, Madonna became the last word in attitude
    and fashion for young girls of that time. He compared that
    image of Madonna with that of Barbie. McKeen explained that
    Madonna intermixed middle-class ideas of femininity with
    examples of what femininity meant to her, which was having
    equal opportunity. She offered an aggressive sexuality that
    implied it was acceptable for women not only to initiate
    relationships, but also enjoy them. In addition, according to
    Morton, at a time when eighties fashions were promoting
    flat-chested, stick-thin women as ideals of beauty, the more
    curvaceous Madonna made average girls feel that it was fine to
    be in the shape they were. A new word called 'Madonna wannabe'
    was introduced to describe the thousands of girls who tried to
    emulate Madonna's style. At one point, Macy's allotted an
    entire floor area to the sale of Madonna-look clothing,
    including cut-off gloves, rubber bangles and lacy leggings.
    University professors, gender-studies experts and feminists
    earnestly started discussing her role as a post-modernist style
    and cultural icon. According to author Debbi Voller, "Like a
    Virgin" gave rise to the icon Madonna.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
