<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Tree_in_the_Meadow 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Tree_in_the_Meadow</songId>
   <title>A Tree in the Meadow</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Margaret_Whiting</artistId>
      <artistName>Margaret Whiting</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1948-10-09</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"A Tree in the Meadow" is a popular song. It was written by
    Billy Reid, and the song was published in 1948.</p>
      <p>The songwriter, orchestra leader Billy Reid, recorded the
    first version in the United Kingdom, with Dorothy Squires as
    vocalist. It was recorded on 9 January 1948, and released by
    Parlophone Records as catalog number R-3092. The biggest hit
    version of the song in the United States was recorded by
    Margaret Whiting. Other versions were recorded by Monica Lewis,
    The Ames Brothers, John Laurenz and Joe Loss.</p>
      <p>Margaret Whiting's version was recorded on 25 May 1948, and
    released by Capitol Records as catalog number 15122. The record
    first reached the 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts on 9 July 1948 and lasted 23 weeks on
    the chart, peaking at #1.</p>
      <p>The Monica Lewis and Ames Brothers recording was released by
    Decca Records as catalog number 24411. The record first reached
    the Billboard charts on 13 August 1948 and lasted 1 week on the
    chart, at #22.</p>
      <p>The John Laurenz recording was released by Mercury Records
    as catalog number 5148. The record first reached the Billboard
    charts on 17 September 1948, and lasted 1 week on the chart, at
    #28.</p>
      <p>The Joe Loss recording was released by RCA Victor Records as
    catalog number 20-2965. The record first reached the Billboard
    charts on 10 September 1948, and lasted 1 week on the chart, at
    #30.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
