<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vision_of_Love 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vision_of_Love</songId>
   <title>Vision of Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1990-08-04</week>
      <week>1990-08-11</week>
      <week>1990-08-18</week>
      <week>1990-08-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/98/Vision_of_Love.jpg/200px-Vision_of_Love.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+Vision-of-Love.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Mariah Carey</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 15, 1990  (1990-05-15)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>January 1989</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:31</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>Ben Margulies</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Vision of Love" is a song written by Mariah Carey and Ben
    Margulies, and produced by Rhett Lawrence and Narada Michael
    Walden for Carey's eponymous debut album, 
    <i>Mariah Carey</i>(1990). The ballad was released as the
    album's first single in the second quarter of 1990 in the
    United States and the third quarter of 1990 elsewhere. The song
    topped the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 for four consecutive
    weeks.</p>
      <p>"Vision of Love" was the first song Carey and Margulies
    co-wrote after Columbia Records executive Tommy Mottola signed
    Carey to a recording contract. The album version of the song
    was altered from Carey and Margulies's original demo recording,
    which had a 1950s-style shuffle.</p>
      <p>The song's protagonist describes having a "vision of love"
    and of being eternally grateful not to a lover, but to God; the
    lyrics are also related to the realisation of Carey's dreams as
    a singer. Carey told 
    <i>Ebony</i>magazine that the song "represents everything in my
    life" and "is a song from the heart." According to her, its
    lyrics are based on personal struggles she experienced when was
    younger, including her parents' divorce, moving frequently and
    the attitudes of the people in her neighborhoods to her
    ethnicity. Carey's vocal range in the song is Eb3-C7.</p>
      <p>The song was nominated for three 1991 Grammy Awards: Best
    Female Pop Vocal Performance (which it won), Record of the Year
    and Song of the Year. The song received the Soul Train Music
    Award for Best R&amp;B/Soul Single, Female and a Songwriter
    Award at the BMI Pop Awards.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>wrote in 2005, "from those opening
    sci-fi-esque synths to that signature dog-whistle high note,
    Mariah's very first single is inspired." 
    <i>The Village Voice</i>said that "Vision of Love" is the song
    that set off the melisma trend. In 2006, 
    <i>The New Yorker</i>named the song "the Magna Carta of
    melisma" for it and Carey's influence on R&amp;B singers and 
    <i>American Idol</i>contestants. Also 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>said that "the fluttering strings of notes
    that decorate songs like "Vision of Love", inspired the entire 
    <i>American Idol</i>vocal school, for better or worse, and
    virtually every other female R&amp;B singer since the
    nineties." Slant Magazine critic also said "I think ["Vision of
    Love"] was a vision of the future world of 
    <i>American Idol</i>." About.com said that "'Vision of Love' is
    one of the best songs of Mariah's recording career [...] It is
    simply one of the most stunning debut releases ever by a pop
    recording artist."</p>
      <p>VH1 named "Vision of Love" the fourteenth greatest song of
    the 1990s. About.com ranked it fourth on its top ten pop hits
    of 1990 list and twenty-eighth on its top 100 pop songs of the
    1990s list. 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>included it on their "10 Great (and
    10 Grating) Karaoke Songs" list as a grating karaoke song,
    saying: "You cannot do this song. Seriously. Tackling this
    lung-crusher might seem like a fun challenge, but three
    minutes, five octaves, and one 10-second note later, you will
    realize that you did not conquer 'Vision of Love.' 'Vision of
    Love' conquered you." 
    <i>USA Today</i>critic Elysa Gardner picked "Vision of Love" as
    one of the most intriguing tracks, saying that it is still
    Mariah's best song. T. Field and a research team discovered
    that "Vision of Love" is one of the songs that has
    physiological and biochemical effects on depressed female
    adolescents.</p>
      <p>R&amp;B singer Beyoncé Knowles said that she began doing
    vocal "runs" after listening to "Vision of Love" for the first
    time, and pop singer Mikaila said that the song is what made
    her want to sing. "Vision of Love" is also R&amp;B singer
    Rihanna's favorite Mariah Carey song.</p>
      <p>In the United States, "Vision of Love" entered the Billboard
    Hot 100 at number 73 in the week of June 2, 1990, and it
    reached number 1 nine weeks later. It remained at number 1 for
    four weeks and was ranked sixth on the Hot 100 year-end chart.
    The single also reached number 1 on the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop
    Songs for two weeks and Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks for three
    weeks. The RIAA certified "Vision of Love" as a gold single in
    August 1990.</p>
      <p>"Vision of Love" reached the top ten in Australia, United
    Kingdom, Ireland and the Netherlands. It went to number 1 in
    Canada and New Zealand.</p>
      <p>The single's music video, directed by Bojan Bazelli,
    features Carey on a darkly lit stage against a background of
    moving clouds and a staircase. The video was the second to be
    commissioned for the song, after a previous video was scrapped.
    According to 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>, an "informal source" said that the two
    videos cost a combined US$450,000. Columbia Records executive
    Don Ienner said the figure was "total bullshit," adding, "If
    we're gonna take the time and effort that we did with Mariah,
    on every level, then we're going to image her the right way. If
    it costs a few extra dollars to make a splash in terms of the
    right imaging, you go ahead and do it."</p>
      <p>Two live versions of the track were released as exclusive
    live performance bonus tracks on non-U.S. releases of the
    singles. The first live version was culled from the EP 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>(1992). The live version released on the
    single is not the same as the version found on the 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>album; it was edited and the intro and
    outro were faded. The first version is most often found on the
    UK single of "I'll Be There" (1992). The other live performance
    is taken from Carey's DVD 
    <i>Fantasy: Mariah Carey at Madison Square Garden</i>(1996),
    and is available on most European singles of "Open Arms"
    (1996).</p>
      <p>Worldwide CD single</p>
      <p>UK CD single</p>
      <p>UK CD maxi-single</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
