<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_Takes_Time 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_Takes_Time</songId>
   <title>Love Takes Time</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1990-11-10</week>
      <week>1990-11-17</week>
      <week>1990-11-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/39/Mariah_carey-love_takes_time.jpg/200px-Mariah_carey-love_takes_time.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+Love-Takes-Time.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Mariah Carey</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 11, 1990  (1990-09-11)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Spring 1990</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:49</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>Ben Margulies</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Walter Afanasieff</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Love Takes Time" is a song written by Mariah Carey and Ben
    Margulies, and produced by Walter Afanasieff for Carey's debut
    album, 
    <i>Mariah Carey</i>(1990). It was released as the album's
    second single in the third quarter of 1990. It was the first of
    several adult contemporary-influenced Carey ballads to be
    released as a single, and its protagonist laments the loss of a
    lover and confesses that "love takes time" to heal and that her
    feelings for her ex-lover remain. It became Carey's second
    number 1 single in the United States and Canada, but was only a
    moderate success elsewhere.</p>
      <p>Mariah Carey's debut album for the label was completed and
    being mastered when she wrote the song with Ben Marguiles. "It
    was sort of a gospelish thing I was improvising, then we began
    working on it," Marguiles relates. "It was on a work tape that
    we had...and we recorded a very quick demo. It was just a piano
    vocal demo - I played live piano, and she sang it."</p>
      <p>Carey was on a mini-tour of ten states, playing acoustically
    with a piano player and three back-up singers. While on a
    company plane, she played the demo of "Love Takes Time" for
    Columbia Records president Don Ienner. "All the important guys
    were on the plane," Marguiles recalls. "Tommy Mottola, Ienner,
    and Bobby Colomby." Carey was told the song was a
    "career-maker," and that it had to go on the first album. She
    protested - her album was already being mastered, and she
    intended this ballad for her next release.</p>
      <p>The demo was sent to producer Walter Afanasieff. When Carey
    flew west to work with Narada Michael Walden on some tracks for
    her first album, Tommy Mottola and Don Ienner were impressed
    with Afanasieff's work and gave him an executive staff producer
    job with the label.</p>
      <p>"I guess to see if he made the right choice, (Tommy) called
    me up one day," remembers Afanasieff. "He said, 'We've got this
    Mariah Carey album done, but there's a song that she and Ben
    Marguiles wrote that is phenomenal, and I want to try
    everything we can to put it on the album.' I said, 'What do you
    want me to do?' and he said, 'You only have a couple of days,
    but are you ready to cut it?' I couldn't believe the
    opportunity that it was. I'd never produced anything by myself
    up until that time."</p>
      <p>The demo was very close to what Mottola wanted the finished
    product to be, according to Afanasieff. "We cut the song and
    the music and the basics in about a day - and the only reason
    is this deadline. It was do it or we were gonna miss out on the
    whole thing. We got the tape and recorded everything and we got
    on the plane and went to New York (and) did her vocals. She did
    all the backgrounds, practically sang all night...We came back
    to the studio that afternoon, and we had to fix one line very
    quickly, and then (engineer) Dana (Jon Chapelle) and I got back
    on the plane with the tape, went back to the studio in
    Sausalito, and mixed it. So it was a three-day process: a day
    and a half for music, kind of like a day for vocals, and a day
    for mixing."</p>
      <p>Afanasieff heard from Columbia executives as soon as they
    received the mix. They wanted Carey's vocal a little louder, so
    a remix was quickly completed. The producer asked if the song
    would still make the debut album, and was told, "We're going to
    do our best."</p>
      <p>When the album was released, "Love Takes Time" was not
    listed on the cassette or compact disc. "(On) some of the
    original first copies of the record, they didn't have time to
    print the name of the song," Marguiles laughs. "And so the
    song's on there, but it doesn't say that it's on there. It was
    a song that actually was strong enough to stop the pressing...I
    don't know if they had to throw away a few hundred copies."</p>
      <p>"Love Takes Time" was another success like Carey's debut
    single "Vision of Love" in the United States: it reached number
    1 in its ninth week on the Billboard Hot 100 and spent three
    weeks at the top of the chart, from November 10 to November 24,
    1990. It spent seventeen weeks in the top forty and the RIAA
    certified it gold. It topped every other 
    <i>Billboard</i>chart for which it was eligible (including the
    Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs and Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks).
    Because its success was divided over two calendar years it did
    not rank high on 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s year-end charts, making 76 on the 1990 chart
    and 69 on the 1991 chart.</p>
      <p>However, "Love Takes Time" failed to emulate its U.S.
    success in any other market except Canada, where it topped the
    Canadian Singles Chart for one week. "Love Takes Time" reached
    the top ten in New Zealand. It did not make much of an impact
    elsewhere, becoming a moderate top twenty hit in Australia, and
    top forty hit in the UK and the Netherlands, but failed to
    reach the top forty in Germany.</p>
      <p>The song did not receive as many awards as "Vision of Love",
    but it still managed to win a BMI R&amp;B Award for Song of the
    Year and a Songwriter Award.</p>
      <p>The single's video, directed by Jeb Brien and Walter Maser,
    features Carey walking around a beach after a man walks away
    with luggage in Venice, Los Angeles, California. The video is
    not included on the DVD/home video 
    <i>#1's</i>(1999) because Carey has admitted she is ashamed of
    it. A live performance of the song filmed at Proctor's Theatre
    in New York in 1993 was included instead.</p>
      <p>Kelly Clarkson did a cover of this song while performing at
    a mini tour in 2003.</p>
      <p>Worldwide CD single</p>
      <p>UK CD single</p>
      <p>European CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>UK CD maxi-single</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
