<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Don%27t_Wanna_Cry 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Don%27t_Wanna_Cry</songId>
   <title>I Don't Wanna Cry</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1991-05-25</week>
      <week>1991-06-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/2/2b/IDWC22.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+I-Don-t-Wanna-Cry.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Mariah Carey</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 25, 1991  (1991-04-25)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1990</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Slow Jam</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:49</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>Narada Michael Walden</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Narada Michael Walden</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Don't Wanna Cry" is a song written by Mariah Carey and
    Narada Michael Walden, and produced by Walden for Carey's debut
    album, 
    <i>Mariah Carey</i>(1990). The ballad was released as the
    album's fourth single in the second quarter of 1991. It became
    another U.S. number 1 single for Carey. Like the previous
    singles released from 
    <i>Mariah Carey</i>, the song received a BMI Pop Award.</p>
      <p>"I Don't Wanna Cry" was Carey's first single that she did
    not co-write with Ben Margulies. When she and Walden first
    wrote the song, she was excited because it sounded like
    something that would be played on the radio. Because of bad
    experiences during its production and because she feels it
    "doesn't have a message," Carey stated in a MTV interview that
    she dislikes the song and tries to sing it as rarely as
    possible. Carey had lobbied to co-produce the song, but was
    denied permission by Columbia Records. She often fought with
    Walden in the studio concerning the song's production, and as a
    result Walden became her least favorite among the producers who
    worked on her debut album. Walden's protégé at the time, Walter
    Afanasieff, later said that he co-wrote and produced the song,
    and that in return for giving Afanasieff the work, Walden took
    the credit.</p>
      <p>"I Don't Wanna Cry" became Carey's fourth number 1 hit on
    the U.S. Billboard Hot 100, making her only the second act (and
    first female and first solo artist) after The Jackson 5 to have
    their first four singles reach number 1 on the Hot 100. It also
    made 
    <i>Mariah Carey</i>a record-breaking album: every single
    released from it was a chart-topper in the U.S. "I Don't Wanna
    Cry" reached number 1 in its eighth week and spent two weeks at
    the top, from May 19 to June 1, 1991. It replaced "I Like the
    Way (The Kissing Game)" by Hi-Five, and was replaced by
    Extreme's "More Than Words". The single became Carey's third
    number 1 single on the Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks chart. It
    remained in the top forty on the Hot 100 for thirteen weeks and
    was one of four Carey singles on the chart's 1991 year-end
    chart, ranking 26. The song also hit number 7 in Canada and
    number 49 in Australia but failed to chart elsewhere.</p>
      <p>The single's music video, directed by Larry Jordan, features
    Carey in a dark Midwest home and in maize, brooding over her
    tainted relationship.</p>
      <p>Part of an alternative version of the music video was
    released on the DVD/home video 
    <i>The First Vision</i>(1991), and the original, more familiar
    version was included on the DVD/home video 
    <i>#1's</i>(1999) as a director's cut. The 1991 version had a
    few sepia-toned sequences that were eliminated and replaced for
    the DVD release. It was the only video from Carey's debut album
    to be included on 
    <i>#1's</i>, because she was ashamed of the three previous
    music videos.</p>
      <p>"I Don't Wanna Cry" was released as a single on iTunes from
    Jason Castro on 
    <i>American Idol</i>, for which he performed the song on the
    show's seventh season.</p>
      <p>CD single</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
