<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_All 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_All</songId>
   <title>My All</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1998-05-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/2/21/Myall1.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+My-All.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Butterfly</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 21, 1998</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
      <format>VHS</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Latin</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:50</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>Walter Afanasieff</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mariah Carey</producer>
      <producer>Walter Afanasieff</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"My All" is a song written by American singer Mariah Carey
    and Walter Afanasieff for Carey's seventh album, 
    <i>Butterfly</i>(1997). It is built around a Latin guitar,
    Latin chord, and also makes subtle use of Latin percussion in
    the first chorus, before taking on a more conventional
    contemporary R&amp;B-style beat. Its protagonist declares she
    would give "her all" to have just one more night with her
    estranged lover. It was released as the album's fifth and final
    single in 1998. It was produced by Carey and Afanasieff with
    keyboards by Afanasieff and producer Dan Shea. "My All" was
    mixed by Mick Guzauski. "My All" at the time set a record,
    giving Carey her thirteenth number-one hit on the Billboard Hot
    100 chart, the most by any female recording artist.</p>
      <p>Although "My All" was the fifth single released from 
    <i>Butterfly</i>, it was only the second commercial release in
    the U.S. It was released worldwide beginning in April 1998. In
    the U.S., it was commercially released as a double A-side with
    "Breakdown" (the album's third, radio-only U.S. single). In
    June 1998, a remix maxi-single entitled "My All/Stay Awhile"
    was released. "My All" became Carey's thirteenth number 1
    single on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 chart, making her the
    female artist with the most U.S. number 1 hits (she had
    previously shared this record with Diana Ross &amp; the
    Supremes). It debuted at number 2 (her second to do so
    following "Always Be My Baby" in 1996), and two weeks later it
    ascended to number 1. It spent one week at the top of the
    chart, from May 17 to May 23, 1998, Carey's only one-week stay
    at number 1 at the time.</p>
      <p>"My All" continued the trend in Carey's singles begun with
    "Honey" (1997) of strong sales but moderate radio airplay,
    which worked against its chart performance because the
    formulations made by 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine during this period were becoming much
    more focused on radio airplay than sales. It spent twelve weeks
    in the top ten and a total of twenty weeks on the chart, was
    certified platinum by the RIAA and was ranked 16 on the Hot 100
    1998 year-end chart. The single was only a moderate success
    outside the U.S., achieving top ten peaks in the United
    Kingdom, France and Switzerland, and reaching the top twenty in
    many other countries.</p>
      <p>"My All" ranks among one of Carey's most remixed tracks, and
    two maxi-singles were released in the U.S. The main R&amp;B
    remix of this single is the So So Def remix, which features
    re-recorded vocals by Carey. It is built around a sample of the
    Loose Ends song "Stay a Little While". Carey's vocal
    interpolation blends the first verse and chorus of "My All"
    with the verse and chorus of "Stay a Little While". It was
    produced by Jermaine Dupri and features raps from Lord Tariq
    and Peter Gunz. The single also features a version without JD
    or Tariq and P. Gunz rap.</p>
      <p>The song's main dance remix is by David Morales. Known as
    the Classic Club mix, it is Carey's first collaboration with
    Morales for which she did not record entirely new vocals.
    Consequently, the song is fairly close to the original chord
    progressions of the album version, though some new vocals were
    added. The remix was a major U.S. dance hit, consolidating
    Morales and Carey's positions as club hitmakers. This remix was
    used as a dance break on Carey's Charmbracelet World Tour: An
    Intimate Evening with Mariah Carey (2003) and The Adventures of
    Mimi Tour (2006).</p>
      <p>Carey recorded a Spanish version of "My All", "Mi Todo"
    (translated by Manny Benito), and it was released outside the
    U.S. on the "My All" single and the Latin American versions of 
    <i>Butterfly</i>. Unlike "Hero" (1993) and "Open Arms" (1996),
    Carey recorded the Spanish version of the song in a different
    key from the original English version. The first line of the
    song had been mistranslated and was grammatically incorrect,
    and Carey later mentioned on her website that she would no
    longer record Spanish versions of her songs until she could
    verify the correct lyrics and pronunciation ("My All" remains
    her last song to be recorded in Spanish as well as English).
    Columbia Records commissioned Ippocratis "Grego" Bournellis
    (a.k.a. DJ Grego) to remix "Mi Todo", but these four mixes were
    only released promotionally in Mexico.</p>
      <p>The song has also been released and resung in 2005 as a
    Bachata version in both English and Spanish lyrics by the group
    Dominicanado.</p>
      <p>The single's video, shot entirely in black and white and on
    location in Puerto Rico, was directed by fashion photographer
    Herb Ritts. The video (released in March 1998) starts with
    Carey lying on an overturned rowboat in the ocean and
    progresses to her exploring the beach past flowers and a beam
    from the beach's lighthouse. The images of Carey lying in the
    shell and in front of the flowers were inspired by Sandro
    Botticelli's painting 
    <i>The Birth of Venus</i>. The video climaxes to a scene where
    Carey and her lover make love, but then ends with Carey alone.
    The video was later re-edited to portray intimate kissing and
    caressing before its release as the official video for the
    Classic Club Radio Mix.</p>
      <p>A music video was filmed for the So So Def remix. Directed
    by Diane Martel, it features Carey, Dupri, Lord Tariq, and
    Peter Guns partying at a friend's house. The video was shot in
    a grainy fashion to simulate a home video.</p>
      <p>European CD single</p>
      <p>Japanese/U.S. CD single</p>
      <p>Australian CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>Mexican CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>U.S. CD maxi-single #1</p>
      <p>U.S. CD maxi-single #2</p>
      <p>European CD maxi-single #1</p>
      <p>European CD maxi-single #2</p>
      <p>European CD maxi-single #3</p>
      <p>European CD maxi-single #4</p>
      <p>European CD maxi-single #5</p>
      <p>"My All"/"Breakdown"</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
