<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/One_Sweet_Day 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/One_Sweet_Day</songId>
   <title>One Sweet Day</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey and Boyz II Men</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1995-12-02</week>
      <week>1995-12-09</week>
      <week>1995-12-16</week>
      <week>1995-12-23</week>
      <week>1995-12-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/7/7b/Mariahcareysingle_osd.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey-and-Boyz-II-Men+One-Sweet-Day.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Daydream</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 14, 1995</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1995</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:41</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>Walter Afanasieff</writer>
      <writer>Wanya Morris</writer>
      <writer>Nathan Morris</writer>
      <writer>Shawn Stockman</writer>
      <writer>Michael McCary</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Walter Afanasieff</producer>
      <producer>Mariah Carey</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"One Sweet Day" is a song recorded by American singer Mariah
    Carey and quartet Boyz II Men and written by Carey, Walter
    Afanasieff and Boyz II Men members Wanya Morris, Shawn
    Stockman, Nathan Morris, and Michael McCary, and was produced
    by Carey and Afanasieff for Carey's sixth album 
    <i>Daydream</i>, and was released as the album's second single
    in 1995.</p>
      <p>It holds the record for the longest run at number 1 on the
    U.S. Billboard Hot 100 (16 weeks total), and is one of the
    biggest American hits of both Carey's and Boyz II Men's
    careers.</p>
      <p>The song ranked at number 29 on 
    <i>Billboard's Hot 100 All-Time Top Songs</i>.</p>
      <p>"One Sweet Day" was inspired by the death of producer and
    C+C Music Factory member David Cole, as well as Carey's "guitar
    legend," Def Leppard guitarist Steve Clark, in 1991. While
    brainstorming with Boyz II Men on a possible collaboration,
    Carey discovered that the group had written a tribute to their
    road manager Kahlil Roundtree, who was murdered while they were
    on tour. Her song plus theirs became "One Sweet Day." David
    Cole worked with Mariah Carey on her two previous albums,
    including her 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>EP. During this period, she had arranged to
    record a song with Boyz II Men. This is also one of the songs
    that Carey uses to showcase the power of her voice on her 
    <i>Daydream</i>album.</p>
      <p>In terms of 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine charts, the song is the most
    successful single for both Mariah Carey and Boyz II Men. The
    protagonists lament the deaths of friends, but say that they
    will be together again "one sweet day."</p>
      <p>The single became Carey's tenth number 1 single on the
    Billboard Hot 100 and Boyz II Men's fourth, remaining at the
    peak for a record-breaking, consecutive sixteen weeks from
    November 26, 1995 to March 16, 1996. Boyz II Men had previously
    held this record twice, with "End of the Road" (1992) spending
    thirteen weeks at the top and "I'll Make Love to You" (1994)
    spending fourteen. (The former song shares this record with
    Brandy and Monica's "The Boy Is Mine", and the latter song
    shared its record with Whitney Houston's "I Will Always Love
    You". Mariah Carey's 2005's "We Belong Together" and Black Eyed
    Peas's 2009's "I Gotta Feeling" managed to stay at number 1 for
    fourteen weeks as well. "One Sweet Day" replaced "Exhale (Shoop
    Shoop)" by Whitney Houston at number 1, and was replaced by
    Celine Dion's "Because You Loved Me".</p>
      <p>The single also debuted at number 1, making Carey the first
    artist to have more than one number 1 debut, and also the only
    artist ever to have two consecutive singles debut at number 1.
    The single spent twenty-six weeks in the top forty, was
    certified double platinum by the RIAA, and ranked number 2 on
    the Hot 100 1996 year-end charts.</p>
      <p>Despite its success in the United States, it was a hit
    elsewhere, as previous Carey singles such as "Fantasy", the
    first release from 
    <i>Daydream</i>. It reached the top 10 in over 13 countries and
    topped New Zealand's. While it had success across Europe, but
    failed to match the success of "Fantasy". It was Boyz II Men's
    biggest success outside the U.S. since "End of the Road", and
    was later included on their greatest hits release 
    <i>Legacy: The Greatest Hits Collection</i>(2001).</p>
      <p>The song became MTV Asia Hitlist's longest number 1 single,
    topping the charts for a record-breaking eleven weeks.</p>
      <p>"One Sweet Day" was nominated for the 1996 Grammy Awards for
    Record of the Year and Best Pop Collaboration with Vocals,
    losing both categories. As two of the top nominees at the 1996
    Grammy Awards, Carey and Boyz II Men were invited to perform,
    and sang "One Sweet Day". Carey began the evening happily as
    she had been nominated for six Grammys that night. "One Sweet
    Day" was the current number 1 record on the Hot 100 at that
    time, and the following morning it was announced that it had
    just broken the record set by Whitney Houston, giving Carey a
    "consolation prize".</p>
      <p>There are no major remixes of the song, but there is a Chuck
    Thompson-produced remix, "One Sweet Day" (Chucky's remix),
    which gives the song a slightly more R&amp;B feel. An a
    cappella version of the song, known as the Sweet a cappella,
    features slightly different vocal arrangements and a new intro
    which also serves as a counter melody throughout the song.</p>
      <p>During the Mariah Carey themed week of UK TV show 
    <i>X Factor</i>, boyband JLS performed the song, receiving high
    praise from all 4 judges and Carey herself (during the
    masterclass).</p>
      <p>The single's music video, directed by Larry Jordan, is made
    up of footage showing Carey and Boyz II Men writing and
    recording the song in the studio, as it was difficult for both
    Boyz II Men and Carey to schedule a time to film a video.</p>
      <p>This song is referenced in an episode of the MTV show 
    <i>Daria</i>, "The Misery Chick" (number 113). Principal Angela
    Li says, "can someone get him out of here so we can sing "One
    Sweet Day"?"</p>
      <p>This song was performed by the top 7 contestants of 
    <i>American Idol</i>season 7. It was the group performance on
    the elimination night.</p>
      <p>Worldwide CD single</p>
      <p>Japanese CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>UK CD maxi-single #1</p>
      <p>UK CD maxi-single #2</p>
      <p>U.S. CD maxi-single</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
