<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotions_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotions_(song)</songId>
   <title>Emotions</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1991-10-12</week>
      <week>1991-10-19</week>
      <week>1991-10-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/b4/Emotionscover.jpg/200px-Emotionscover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+Emotions.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Emotions</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 13, 1991  (1991-08-13)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1991</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:09</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>David Cole</writer>
      <writer>Robert Clivillés</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>David Cole</producer>
      <producer>Robert Clivillés</producer>
      <producer>Mariah Carey</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Emotions" is a song written and produced by Mariah Carey,
    and David Cole and Robert Clivillés of the C+C Music Factory,
    and recorded for Carey's second album 
    <i>Emotions</i>(1991). It was released as the album's first
    single in the third quarter of 1991 in the United States and in
    the fourth quarter elsewhere. This disco-influenced song has
    its protagonist going through a variety of emotions, from high
    to low, up to the point where she declares "you got me feeling
    emotions" and sings high notes.</p>
      <p>Carey was sent to work with the C+C Music Factory and they
    composed the song "You're So Cold", which became the first
    choice for the album's first single. However, a second session
    with the production team had them feeling in a lighter mood
    when "Emotions" was created and finally decided upon as the
    lead single.</p>
      <p>"Emotions" is disco-influenced pop song and it is written in
    the key of C major. Carey usually prefers to transpose the key
    to B♭ major when performing live (one example of this is on 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>). Carey's vocal range spans more than four
    octaves on the track, from C
    <sub>3</sub>to E
    <sub>7</sub>. The song tested and challenged Carey's vocal
    range and is her first song to require the execution of
    multiple high notes. It starts on a falsetto note followed by a
    belted note. This is one of the reasons why many singers who
    try to emulate her vocal technique may use an incorrect vocal
    technique. The sheet music of the song has a 8va marking on the
    last part of the song.</p>
      <p>The single's music video, directed by Jeff Preiss, features
    Carey and friends with exotic animals experiencing emotions
    while partying and having fun around town in New York. The
    video was desaturated but still maintains various different
    color tints, which change from brown to red to blue and so
    forth.</p>
      <p>David Cole and Robert Clivillés created the main remix of
    "Emotions" known as "Emotions" (12" club mix). Although Carey
    did not re-record her vocals for it, she added a new
    gospel-style intro before the song's dance portion. This new
    intro was used when she performed "Emotions" on 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>in 1992, as well as at some later concerts.
    A music video was created using the 12" club mix, but only
    slight changes in editing differentiate it from the video for
    the original version.</p>
      <p>"Emotions" was nominated for the 1992 Grammy Award for Best
    Female Pop Vocal Performance, losing to "Something to Talk
    About" by Bonnie Raitt. It won a BMI R&amp;B Award, continuing
    Carey's unbroken streak of wins for this award.</p>
      <p>"Emotions" became Carey's fifth consecutive number 1 hit on
    the U.S. Billboard Hot 100, giving her the distinction of being
    the first and to date only act to have their first five singles
    make number 1 on the Hot 100. (She had previously shared a
    record of four with The Jackson 5.) It reached number 1 in its
    seventh week and spent three weeks at the top, from October 6
    to October 26, 1991. It replaced "Good Vibrations" by Marky
    Mark and the Funky Bunch featuring Loleatta Holloway, and was
    replaced by Karyn White's "Romantic". It remained in the top
    forty for twenty weeks and was one of four singles from Carey
    on the Hot 100's 1991 year-end charts, ranking 22. The song
    topped the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs chart and became her
    second number 1 single on the Hot Dance Club Play chart. The
    RIAA certified it gold.</p>
      <p>Outside the U.S., it was Carey's most successful single
    since "Vision of Love" (1990), the lead single from her debut
    album. It reached the top five in Canada and New Zealand, and
    became her first single to reach the United Kingdom top twenty
    since her debut. It was a modest hit in Australia, where it
    just missed the top ten, but its success in Europe was
    limited.</p>
      <p>It was used for a 2009 
    <i>Australian Idol</i>advertisement.</p>
      <p>On New Year's Eve, 2009, Carey sang Emotions on the first
    night of her 'Angels Advocate Tour'. It is the first time she
    has sang Emotions live in 10 years, since the Rainbow World
    Tour.</p>
      <p>Worldwide CD single</p>
      <p>U.S. CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>European maxi-single #1</p>
      <p>European maxi-single #2</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
