<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Honey_(Mariah_Carey_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Honey_(Mariah_Carey_song)</songId>
   <title>Honey</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1997-09-13</week>
      <week>1997-09-20</week>
      <week>1997-09-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/c/c0/Mariahcareysingle_honey.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+Honey.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Butterfly</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 26, 1997</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
      <format>VHS</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>February 1997</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:58</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>Puff Daddy</writer>
      <writer>Stevie J</writer>
      <writer>Q-Tip (The Ummah)</writer>
      <writer>Bobby Robinson</writer>
      <writer>Stephen Hague</writer>
      <writer>Ronald Larkins</writer>
      <writer>Malcolm McLaren</writer>
      <writer>Larry Price</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mariah Carey</producer>
      <producer>Puff Daddy</producer>
      <producer>Stevie J</producer>
      <producer>Q-Tip (The Ummah)</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Honey" is a song co-written and co-produced by American
    singer Mariah Carey, Puff Daddy, Stevie J, and Q-Tip (listed in
    credits as "The Ummah"), and recorded for Carey's seventh album
    
    <i>Butterfly</i>(1997). It uses two samples: "Hey DJ",
    originally performed by the World's Famous Supreme Team, and
    "The Body Rock" by the Treacherous Three. It was released as
    the first single from 
    <i>Butterfly</i>in 1997 and became one of Carey's bigger hits,
    reaching number one in the United States. It became her twelfth
    chart-topper there, surpassing Madonna as the female artist
    with most number-one singles.</p>
      <p>The song is best known for its music video, which presented
    a more sexual and less conservative image of Carey than had
    been previously seen. It also marked a musical transition in
    her career, moving her away from pop music and further towards
    hip hop. "Honey" was nominated for the 1998 Grammy Awards for
    Best Female R&amp;B Vocal Performance and Best R&amp;B
    Song.</p>
      <p>"Honey" was Carey's twelfth number 1 single on the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100 and became her third single to debut at
    number 1, consolidating her position as the artist with the
    most number-one debuts (the others being "Fantasy" and "One
    Sweet Day", both 1995). After its debut it spent three weeks at
    the top of the chart, from September 7 to September 27, 1997.
    It replaced "Mo Money Mo Problems" by The Notorious B.I.G.
    featuring Puff Daddy and Mase, and it was replaced by Boyz II
    Men's "4 Seasons of Loneliness". After its sales had begun to
    decline, and despite the single being a #1 hit on the Rhythmic
    Top 40, radio airplay in general was not strong enough to keep
    "Honey" popular, and it began a new trend for Carey's singles
    that did not end until the release of "We Belong Together"
    (2005): the CD single would sell well, but the song would only
    achieve average success on the radio. Her records became
    increasingly less successful on charts that were weighing
    airplay far more heavily than sales. "Honey" remained in the
    U.S. top forty for eighteen weeks and was ranked 32 on the Hot
    100 1997 year-end charts.</p>
      <p>"Honey" was a substantial hit outside the U.S., going top
    three in the United Kingdom and Canada. Its success across most
    of Europe, however, did not rival that of singles such as
    "Hero" (1993), "Without You" (1994) and "Fantasy". It peaked
    inside the top ten in Sweden and Australia.</p>
      <p>The best-known aspect of "Honey" was its music video, which
    forever changed Carey's public image. Carey had previously been
    dressed conservatively, as the "girl next door". Starting with
    "Honey" (directed by Paul Hunter), she was seen in revealing
    clothing. The video compliments the sexual innuendo from the
    song's lyrics.</p>
      <p>The video premiered on MTV and BET on July 30, 1997 and was
    inspired by James Bond films and shot in Puerto Rico in July
    1997. It starts out with Carey, clad in a conservative-looking
    dress and 4-inch metal stiletto heels, being held prisoner in a
    mansion. After escaping her captors (Eddie Griffin, Frank
    Sivero) via a swimming pool, (as people have thought that this
    may be an intentional metaphor of Carey's divorce from Tommy
    Mottola but she has denied the claims) she then takes off her
    dress in the water to reveal a bikini, inspired by Bond girl
    Honey Rider's famous white bikini in 
    <i>Dr. No</i>(1962). Carey dresses into a wetsuit and uses a
    watercraft to evade her captors, who are also on watercraft.
    The video is intercut with sequences of Carey singing in a
    two-piece outfit on an island, and sequences involving her
    dancing with sailors. Carey's captors interrogate the sailors,
    but she is nowhere to be seen. The video ends with Carey
    frolicking around on a beach with Cuban American male model
    David Fumero and her dog, Jack. The video was nominated at the
    1998 MTV Video Music Awards for Best Female Video.</p>
      <p>Several remixes were commissioned for "Honey", most notably
    the Bad Boy remix and the Classic mix, the latter of which
    appears on Carey's remix compilation 
    <i>The Remixes</i>(2003). The former is similar to the original
    version, but there is a new spoken intro from Carey in which
    she states, "I thought I told you, we won't stop." The string
    chords present in the original "Honey" are entirely excised
    from the Bad Boy remix, and it features rapping by The Lox and
    Mase. The rap from Mase entirely replaces the second chorus of
    the song, while the Lox's parts replaces a section of the
    song's bridge.</p>
      <p>The song's main remix, "Honey" (Bad Boy remix), also has a
    music video, with additional sequences directed by Paul Hunter.
    Much of the footage of the video for this remix is from the
    original video, with the new sequences featuring Carey with
    Puff Daddy, Mase, the Lox (later known as D Block), and Puff
    Daddy in a long beige tunnel flowing with water ("The Honey
    Tunnel"). During Mase's rap, Carey is rescued by Mase (rather
    than joining the sailors on the boat) when he lowers a rope
    into the ocean from his helicopter.</p>
      <p>Another major hip-hop mix of the song was released: "Honey"
    (So So Def mix), produced by Jermaine Dupri and featuring raps
    from him and Da Brat. Carey re-recorded some of her vocals, but
    most lyrical and melodic structures are kept similar to the
    album version. The song uses a new sample from "It's Great to
    Be Here" (originally performed by The Jackson 5), but it does
    not use "The Body Rock" from the album version and Bad Boy
    remix. The So So Def remix does use the sample of "Hey DJ", but
    in a different manner: the album version and Bad Boy remix use
    the piano riff from "Hey DJ", while the So So Def remix uses
    the line "Hey JD, won't you play that song, keep them dancing,
    dancing all night."</p>
      <p>David Morales created several dance remixes of the song, the
    most notable being "Honey" (Classic mix), and variations of
    this include "Honey" (Def Club mix), "Honey" (Rascal dub), and
    "Honey" (Boss Anthem mix). These give songwriting credit to the
    writers of "The Body Rock", although this is not sampled.
    Morales is also credited as a songwriter for the remixes,
    although they are close to the original melodic and lyrical
    structure of the original song.</p>
      <p>Worldwide CD single</p>
      <p>Australian/European/U.S. CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>UK CD maxi-single #1</p>
      <p>UK CD maxi-single #2</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
