<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dreamlover_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dreamlover_(song)</songId>
   <title>Dreamlover</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1993-09-11</week>
      <week>1993-09-18</week>
      <week>1993-09-25</week>
      <week>1993-10-02</week>
      <week>1993-10-09</week>
      <week>1993-10-16</week>
      <week>1993-10-23</week>
      <week>1993-10-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/e/e5/Mariahcareysingle_dreamlover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+Dreamlover.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Music Box</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 27, 1993  (1993-07-27)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1992</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:53</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>Dave Hall</writer>
      <writer>Walter Afanasieff</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mariah Carey</producer>
      <producer>Dave Hall</producer>
      <producer>Walter Afanasieff</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Dreamlover" is a song written and produced by American
    singer Mariah Carey, Dave Hall and Walter Afanasieff, and
    recorded for Carey's fourth album 
    <i>Music Box</i>(1993). Columbia Records executives brought in
    Afanasieff to tone the song down, because they felt the
    original production was too rough and mellow. It is built
    around a sample of The Emotions' "Blind Alley," written by
    David Porter, but uses a Hammond organ. Its protagonist
    pictures an ideal man, her "dream lover".</p>
      <p>It was released as the first single from 
    <i>Music Box</i>in the third quarter of 1993, and marked the
    start of a trend of Carey's to use samples as backbones for the
    lead singles from her studio albums; later examples include
    "Fantasy" (1995), "Honey" (1997) and "Heartbreaker" (1999). It
    was nominated for the 1994 Grammy Award for Best Female Pop
    Vocal Performance, losing to "I Will Always Love You" by
    Whitney Houston. It won a BMI Pop Award, as had Carey's every
    U.S. single other than "I'll Be There".</p>
      <p>"Dreamlover" has been one of Carey's most popular songs in
    concert, through 2006 holding a regular slot in all of her
    tours' setlists, often near the beginning of the show.</p>
      <p>Rock singer Bruce Springsteen sampled "Dreamlover" for his
    song "Let's Be Friends," from the album 
    <i>The Rising</i>(2002).</p>
      <p>"Dreamlover" became Carey's seventh number 1 single on the
    Billboard Hot 100 and was easily her biggest hit in the U.S. at
    the time. It reached number 1 in its sixth week (her quickest
    climb prior to her first of three number 1 debuts) and spent
    eight weeks at the top (her longest stay at the time), from
    September 5 to October 30, 1993. Mariah Carey later bested that
    with "One Sweet Day" and "We Belong Together," the first of
    which was with Boyz II Men. It replaced "Can't Help Falling in
    Love" by UB40 at the number 1 spot, and was replaced by Meat
    Loaf's "I'd Do Anything for Love (But I Won't Do That)." It
    spent twenty-six weeks in the top forty and was ranked number 8
    on the Hot 100 1993 year-end charts. The song topped eight
    other 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts, and was Carey's first single to be
    certified platinum by the RIAA.</p>
      <p>The single was a success outside the U.S., becoming Carey's
    fourth number 1 single in Canada, staying three weeks atop the
    chart, and it peaked at number 2 in New Zealand and it was
    certified gold there by the RIANZ. It reached the top ten in
    several countries including the United Kingdom, Australia, and
    the Netherlands. It was certified gold in Australia by the
    ARIA. "Dreamlover" was moderately successful across Europe,
    making the top twenty in most markets, but failed to reach the
    top forty in France.</p>
      <p>The single's music video, directed by Diane Martel, was one
    of the first over which Carey was given more creative control.
    It shows her frolicking around fields in upstate New York on a
    summer day with her dog Jack (who would appear in some of her
    later videos), before boarding a hot air balloon as a legion of
    shirtless male hip hop dancers dance on.</p>
      <p>"Dreamlover" marked the first time Carey was given control
    over remixes of her songs. She enlisted David Morales to create
    the Def club mix, and was the first of Carey's remixes to use
    re-recorded vocals. The success of the remix contributed to
    Morales' career as a remixer, aided in bridging the gap between
    pop and house music, and also started a trend of having
    renowned remixers create new versions of pop singles. The Def
    club mix of "Dreamlover" is considered a breakthrough record in
    the house music industry.</p>
      <p>Besides the dubs, edits, and other variations of the Def
    club mix, other remixes using the original vocals from the
    song's original album version also exist, as created by Brian
    Alexander Morgan of Bam Jam Productions: Theo's club joint mix
    and Bam jam soul. An officially-released live version of
    "Dreamlover," derived from the television special 
    <i>Here Is Mariah Carey</i>(1994), is also available.</p>
      <p>"Dreamlover" B-side track ("Do You Think of Me") was written
    and produced by Carey, Walter Afanasieff, Cory Rooney and Mark
    Morales.</p>
      <p>Worldwide CD single</p>
      <p>European CD maxi-single #1</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
