<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hero_(Mariah_Carey_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hero_(Mariah_Carey_song)</songId>
   <title>Hero</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1993-12-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/2/2f/Mariahcareysingle_hero.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+Hero.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Music Box</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 19, 1993  (1993-10-19)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1992</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:19</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mariah Carey</producer>
      <producer>Walter Afanasieff</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Hero" is a song written and produced by American singer
    Mariah Carey and Walter Afanasieff, and recorded for Carey's
    fourth album, 
    <i>Music Box</i>(1993). Its protagonist declares that even
    though we may feel discouraged or down at times, in reality we
    are "heroes" if we look inside ourselves and see our own inner
    strength; in time, this will help us "find the way." It was
    released as the album's second single in the fourth quarter of
    1993 and became a worldwide commercial success. "Hero" is
    considered one of Carey's signature songs, and she regularly
    performs it when invited to charity events and closes most
    concerts with it. It is also known for being one of the most
    frequently performed songs at her concerts next to "Vision of
    Love". The song was nominated for the 1995 Grammy Award for
    Best Female Pop Vocal Performance, losing to Sheryl Crow's "All
    I Wanna Do". "Hero" won two ASCAP Rhythm &amp; Soul Music
    Awards, one ASCAP Pop Music Award and one BMI Pop Award for the
    Songwriter Award.</p>
      <p>Dustin Hoffman and Geena Davis starred in a movie for
    Columbia Pictures called 
    <i>Hero</i>. Producer Walter Afanasieff recalls, "The people
    over at Epic Records were going to do the soundtrack for the
    film. They wanted to have Mariah sing the theme to it, but they
    didn't really think they could because at that time you
    couldn't get near Mariah to do anything film-wise. So they
    wanted to try the next best thing, which was to have us write
    something."</p>
      <p>The film was screened for Afanasieff in Los Angeles and he
    was told that Gloria Estefan would probably be asked to sing a
    title theme. At the time, the producer was working with Carey
    on her 
    <i>Music Box</i>album. "I went to New York and we were in the
    studio and came to a break. I was sitting at the piano and told
    Mariah about this movie. Within two hours, we had this
    incredible seed for this song, 'Hero'. It was never meant for
    Mariah to sing. In her mind, we were writing a song for Gloria
    Estefan for this movie. And we went into an area that Mariah
    didn't really go into - in her words, it was a little bit too
    schmaltzy or too pop ballady or too old-fashioned as far as
    melody and lyrics."</p>
      <p>The pair were almost finished writing the song when Tommy
    Mottola, president and CEO of Sony Music Entertainment and
    Carey's fiance (later her husband), walked into the studio.
    Hearing the song they were working on, he asked them what it
    was, and Carey replied, "This is a song for the film 
    <i>Hero</i>." Afanasieff recalls Mottola responding, "Are you
    kidding me? You can't give this song to this movie. This is too
    good. Mariah, you have to take this song. You have to do
    it."</p>
      <p>Initially, Carey was guided by the subject of the film, but
    Afanasieff acknowledges that the artist made it a very personal
    song. After she decided not to give the song away, she
    completed the lyric and made it her own. The producer went back
    to the soundtrack people and told them, "You know what? I
    didn't come up with anything." Estefan never heard the tune was
    originally meant for her, and the song that ended up in the
    soundtrack was "Heart of a Hero", written, produced and
    recorded by Luther Vandross.</p>
      <p>Afanasieff and Carey came up with a couple of different
    versions of "Hero" in the studio. "There was a simpler
    performance on tape and a more difficult one, with Mariah
    singing out more, with more licks. But we chose a happy medium.
    The song really calls for not anything really fancy. But she's
    always fighting the forces inside of her because she's her own
    devil's advocate. She wants to do something that's so over the
    top and use her talents and the voice she has. But she also
    knows she has to restrain herself and do what the music really
    calls for."</p>
      <p>"Hero" was the subject of a copyright plagiarism case.
    Christopher Selletti, a former limo driver for Sly Stone, said
    that the lyrics were based on a poem that he showed Stone in
    1991 (and that he believed Stone had shown to Carey). Carey
    defended herself with entries from her personal lyrics
    notebook, although the lyrics from the notebook were dated six
    weeks after the release of the film 
    <i>Hero</i>(for which the song had originally been intended).
    Nevertheless, the $20 million lawsuit was eventually dismissed,
    and Selletti was forced to pay a fine to Carey. Years later
    Selletti launched a second lawsuit, which was also dismissed,
    but he has stated that he will try a third time.</p>
      <p>"Hero" became Carey's eighth number 1 single on the U.S
    Billboard Hot 100. It reached number 1 in its tenth week and
    spent four weeks at the top, from December 19, 1993 to January
    15, 1994. It replaced "Again" by Janet Jackson, and was
    replaced by Bryan Adams, Rod Stewart and Sting's "All for
    Love". It remained in the top forty for twenty-five weeks, with
    fourteen of those spent in the top ten. It received heavy radio
    airplay and was certified platinum by the RIAA. It was one of
    the year's biggest hits, being ranked fifth on the Hot 100 1994
    year-end chart.</p>
      <p>"Hero" also became a hit outside the U.S., reaching the top
    ten in the UK (where it peaked higher than "Dreamlover", the
    previous single from 
    <i>Music Box</i>) France, and Australia. It was more successful
    across Europe than "Dreamlover" by reaching the top ten in most
    markets, but it performed moderately in Canada compared to
    Carey's previous singles. "Hero" was certified platinum in
    Australia by ARIA, gold in New Zealand by RIANZ and silver in
    France by SNEP.</p>
      <p>The single's music video, directed by Larry Jordan, is
    derived from Carey's 1993 concert at Proctor Theatre, which
    became a television special and was later released on the home
    video 
    <i>Here Is Mariah Carey</i>(1993). The live performance of the
    song at Proctor Theatre was officially released. The video is
    included on Mariah's DVD #1's (1998).</p>
      <p>Carey also re-recorded "Hero" in Spanish from a translation
    by Jorge Luis Piloto, which was Carey's first Spanish song.
    Critics thought that her pronunciation wasn't right and the
    adaptation is unworthy to the original version; the Spanish
    speaking public criticized it for being mediocre both in
    pronunciation and lyrical content. The Spanish language version
    of "Hero" ("Héroe") was included as a B-side on various Carey
    singles released outside the U.S. between 1994 and 1997, and it
    was included on the Mexican, Argentinian and Spanish edition of
    
    <i>Music Box</i>as a bonus track. "Héroe" was released in
    1995.</p>
      <p>Carey sang "Hero" with Luciano Pavarotti at the 1999
    "Pavarotti and Friends" concert. Parts of "Hero" were
    incorporated into Carey's charity single "Never Too Far/Hero
    Medley" (2001). One of Carey's most widely seen performances of
    "Hero" was at the 2005 London Live 8 concert, during which she
    sang the song with the African Children's Choir. Later that
    year a cover in spanish of the song by operatic pop vocal group
    Il Divo was released on their album 
    <i>Ancora</i>.</p>
      <p>"Hero" is included on 
    <i>Voices from the FIFA World Cup</i>, an album comprising
    songs featured in the 2006 FIFA World Cup. On CBC's 
    <i>Hockey Night in Canada</i>coverage of the Stanley Cup
    playoffs, the song was played in the collaborate footage,
    following the New York Rangers 1994 Stanley Cup championship
    season.</p>
      <p>The B-side of "Hero," "Everything Fades Away," was written
    and produced by Carey and Walter Afanasieff.</p>
      <p>In the fifth series, of the popular British television show,
    The X Factor, the top 12 finalists, sang their own version of
    "Hero", which was a charity single, it topped the UK Singles
    Chart, for 4 weeks.</p>
      <p>In early 2009, Mariah recorded an alternate version of 
    <i>Hero</i>to promote her compilation album 
    <i>The Ballads</i>.</p>
      <p>Japanese/U.S. CD single</p>
      <p>European CD single</p>
      <p>Non-European CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>European CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>In Japan, EPs are charting on the albums chart.</p>
      <p>The twelve finalists from the fifth series of TV talent show
    
    <i>The X Factor</i>in the United Kingdom released a cover of
    the song on October 27, 2008 for the Help for Heroes and The
    Royal British Legion charities. The release was backed by, and
    originally suggested by, 
    <i>The Sun</i>newspaper.</p>
      <p>The finalists performed the single for the first time on the
    third live show, on October 25, 2008. The single was released
    on download on October 26, 2008, followed by the physical
    release the day after.</p>
      <p>It was announced on October 30 that the British Chancellor
    of the Exchequer, Alistair Darling, would waive all tax on
    copies sold on the single. He said "I support the efforts being
    made by the 
    <i>X Factor</i>contestants and in recognition of that I'm
    proposing effectively to waive the VAT on the sale of these
    singles. We will do that by making a donation equivalent to the
    value of the VAT."</p>
      <p>The music video was released on November 8, 2008 before the
    fifth live show, when the finalists (excluding Diana Vickers
    because of illness) sang it again, this time accompanied by
    guest star Mariah Carey. All the finalists appeared in the
    video, which also showed still images of soldiers in Iraq.</p>
      <p>Upon its release the single was expected to reach number 1
    in the UK, and on November 2, 2008 it did so. It is also the
    fastest selling single of 2008. Online retailer Amazon.com said
    it had sold out of the track in just a few hours. The song sold
    100,000 copies in the first day of release and 313,244 copies
    by the end of the week. It has sold over 770,000 copies and
    raised over one million pounds for Help For Heroes.</p>
      <p>The track could become one of the biggest-selling releases
    of the decade. HMV spokesman Gennaro Castaldo said: "This is
    proving to be one of the biggest single releases for years if
    not the decade. Only Leona Lewis's debut hit "A Moment Like
    This", which sold over 500,000 copies in its first week, can
    compare. It's selling more than most Christmas No 1s would, and
    HMV has placed an urgent order for more copies."</p>
      <p>The song went straight to number 1 on the Irish Singles
    Chart, where it stayed for three weeks.</p>
      <p>On December 28, 2008, the UK Singles Chart listed this as
    number 2 biggest selling single for the year end countdown.</p>
      <p>
         <i>The X Factor</i>finalists version was shortlisted for the
    Best British Single award at the 2009 BRIT Awards, however was
    eliminated third, finishing in 8th place. The song came #19 on
    the Biggest Selling Singles of the Decade from 2000-2009.</p>
      <p>Template:Diana Vickers</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
