<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heartbreaker_(Mariah_Carey_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heartbreaker_(Mariah_Carey_song)</songId>
   <title>Heartbreaker</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey featuring Jay-Z</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1999-10-09</week>
      <week>1999-10-16</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/a/a9/Mariahcareysingle_heartbreaker.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey-featuring-Jay-Z+Heartbreaker.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Rainbow</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 21, 1999  (1999-09-21)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>May—July 1999</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:46</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>Jay-Z</writer>
      <writer>Jeff Cohen</writer>
      <writer>Narada Michael Walden</writer>
      <writer>Shirley Elliston</writer>
      <writer>Lincoln Chase</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mariah Carey</producer>
      <producer>DJ Clue</producer>
      <producer>Mr Fingaz</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Heartbreaker" is a song recorded by American singer Mariah
    Carey for her ninth studio album, 
    <i>Rainbow</i>(1999). Written by Carey, the track features a
    guest appearance from American rapper Jay-Z. The singer wrote
    the song, initially planning for it to be featured in a movie
    project. However, the project was postponed, making Carey
    include it on her then-upcoming album.</p>
      <p>The track was released in 1999, as the album's lead single
    to mixed reviews from music critics. Nevertheless, it was
    another commercial success for Carey, reaching the top ten in
    most major markets, while achieving the top of the charts in
    the United States, Canada and New Zealand. In the United
    States, the song became Carey's 14th number 1 single and
    brought other new feats to her career. Its music video portrays
    a cinematic plot where the singer is shown as two different
    women. It is one of the most expensive ever made, with a cost
    of US$2,500,000 and remains as one of her fan favorites to
    date.</p>
      <p>After the release of Carey's first compilation album, 
    <i>#1's</i>(1998), the singer began to work on her seventh
    studio album, 
    <i>Rainbow</i>(1999). According to her, the album took three
    months to be recorded and she spent most of that time working
    on its first single, "Heartbreaker". The song was originally
    intended for the soundtrack of 
    <i>All that Glitters</i>—a movie project which had been in
    development for two years, in which she starred as the main
    character. Due to the fact the movie had been postponed, the
    singer decided to include it on her latest studio album because
    she "didn't want to wait on putting it out."</p>
      <p>Produced by New York mixtape DJ Clue, it has a guest
    participation from rapper Jay-Z, who makes a featured rap over
    the song, with lines written by himself. In an interview with
    MTV News, Carey revealed her thoughts about the track:</p>
      <p>"It's pretty much [in] the classic style of my up-tempo
    classics like 'Fantasy' or 'Dreamlover,' [...] But it's kind of
    fun and has a new edge to it, I think, and definitely having
    Jay-Z takes it to a whole 'nother level. And [DJ] Clue makes it
    really fun and stuff."</p>
      <p>"Heartbreaker" is a moderately slow pop track, with hip-hop
    and R&amp;B influences. Written in the key of D♭ major, the
    beat is set in common time and moves at a moderate 92 bpm. The
    song has a "midtempo" and a "percolating beat" over which Carey
    sings with a nasal, silken and declarative voice.</p>
      <p>"Hearbreaker" samples R&amp;B—dance singer Stacy Lattisaw's
    "Attack of the Name Game." An article in Entertainment Weekly
    claims there is a sample of the Tom Tom Club's Genius of Love,
    however this cannot be verified from the album credits. This
    drew criticism at the time due to the fact that Carey had
    already used this sample in a previous single, "Fantasy". 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly'</i>s Tom Sinclair pointed out her lack
    of originality when claiming she was "recycling" early
    material.</p>
      <p>The lyrics are constructed in the verse-pre-chorus-chorus
    form. Carey starts with the hook "Gimme your love, gimme your
    love," repeated eight times in a row. It follows the
    verse-pre-chorus-chorus-hook-verse-pre-chorus-chorus and then
    giving way to the Jay-Z's rap—with mostly of its lines
    initiated by "She wanna". Carey repeats the chorus four times,
    ending the song with a final "Gimme your love, gimme your
    love."</p>
      <p>Released as 
    <i>Rainbow'</i>s lead single, "Heartbreaker" was premiered on
    the official site of Microsoft's Windows Media on August 16,
    1999. The site had a 12-hour exclusive on the tune before its
    release to radio. Its commercial release, however, only
    happened in the United States on September 21, 1999. It was
    released in the United Kingdom on November 2, 1999, two months
    later than the American release.</p>
      <p>"Heartbreaker" received mixed reviews from music critics,
    although most of them agreed it was a good song. Some, however,
    pointed negatively at strong resemblances to Carey's previous
    releases. Arion Berger of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>declared that the singer was at her most
    insinuating: "nasal, silken, declarative, riding the
    percolating beat," and MTV Asia said that she exuded as much
    sentiment as hollowed-out driftwood, describing the track as an
    "airy ditty." A negative review came from Tom Sinclair of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>, who said the song is a "rehash" of
    her 1995 hit "Fantasy". At the end, 
    <i>Billboard</i>concluded: "Yes, it's a hit, and her voice is
    in fine form [...] radio will be eager to introduce audiences
    to the latest from one of the staple artists of the '90s, even
    if this single doesn't represent a creative step forward."</p>
      <p>Jay-Z's guest appearance on the track, however, was received
    with favorable reviews. Jose Promis of Allmusic stated that his
    rap embellished it further, and added that it was "comical".
    Elysa Gardner of 
    <i>Los Angeles Times</i>described it as a "sly rap". Arion
    Berger of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>claimed he ran a "funny litany" of Carey's
    bad behavior on the song. 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly'</i>s Danyel Smith observed that she
    smartly used Jay-Z's rap as "tart counterpoint to her creamy
    tones", while 
    <i>Billboard</i>recognized that it had added to the song's
    radio appeal.</p>
      <p>The song's main remix is the Desert Storm Remix that
    features female rappers Da Brat &amp; Missy Elliott and it's
    the first Mariah Carey remix that was produced by Desert Storm
    Records producer &amp; rapper DJ Clue, who made a intro on the
    remix. This remix is the 7th track of the album. The remix and
    Da Brat's first verse was sampled from "Ain't No Fun (If the
    Homies Can't Have None)" by Snoop Dogg. There is a music video
    of the remix that the video was filmed in black &amp; white,
    Snoop Dogg makes a cameo appearance in the video.</p>
      <p>"Heartbreaker" entered the Hot 100 on September 4, 1999 at
    number 60. However, when the song was commercially available,
    it sold 273,000 copies—the second biggest first-week sales of
    her career—and then achieved the summit of the chart. It was
    Carey's 14th number 1 single, and also her 59th week at the top
    of the chart with a single. When the track stayed another week
    at number-one, Carey surpassed rock and pop band The Beatles
    for the act with most total weeks spent at number-one, and with
    the song reaching number-one in 1999, the singer was also the
    only artist to have had a number-one single for every year of
    the 1990s. When commenting about all these new feats to her
    career, Carey had stated:</p>
      <p>"When you're doing the work, you hope that people will
    respond, [...] but you never think that things will reach such
    incredible heights. Personally, I don't know how creative I
    could be if I spent time thinking about sales figures and stuff
    like that."</p>
      <p>Internationally, it received similar responses, topping the
    charts in Canada and New Zealand. In the United Kingdom,
    "Heartbreaker" was Carey's ninth top five when it debuted at
    the fifth position, failing to reach a new peak in the
    following weeks. The single peaked inside the top ten in most
    others major markets, including Australia, France and the
    Netherlands.</p>
      <p>Directed by Brett Ratner, the song's music video was
    reported to be the 7th most expensive ever made, with a cost of
    U$2,500,000. Furthermore, it remains a fan favorite.</p>
      <p>The music video puts the singer in two roles: an innocent
    and sweet blond Carey and an "evil" brunette Carey, named
    Bianca. Located in a movie theater, the blond Carey is
    convinced by her friends to catch her boyfriend (played by
    Jerry O'Connell) cheating on her, then discovering that he is
    in a date with the brunette Carey. When the blond one tries to
    confront the brunette about stealing her boyfriend, the two end
    up with a catfight in the theater's bathroom inspired by 1973
    American martial arts film 
    <i>Enter the Dragon</i>. The story ends with the blond Carey
    pouring a drink in the lap of her former boyfriend.</p>
      <p>During the part of the song where Jay-Z raps, an animated
    sequence featuring cartoon versions of Carey and her friends
    was shown instead—an idea decided by the singer herself and
    Brett Ratner. The part where Carey and her friends have fun on
    the bed was inspired by the 1978 musical film "Grease". It
    happened because the rapper was contractually obligated to
    restrict video appearances during two weeks. The version of
    "Heartbreaker" video, which included Jay-Z himself, premiered
    on the MTV show 
    <i>Making the Video</i>on August 30, 1999.</p>
      <p>There is another version of the video with alternate scenes
    and Jay-Z in the video as he is in a hot tub smoking, with
    Mariah dancing in the background.</p>
      <p>(Released: September 21, 1999)</p>
      <p>(Released: September 21, 1999)</p>
      <p>
         <i>Side A</i>
      </p>
      <p>
         <i>Side B</i>
      </p>
      <p>(Released: September 21, 1999)</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
