<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/We_Belong_Together_(Mariah_Carey_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/We_Belong_Together_(Mariah_Carey_song)</songId>
   <title>We Belong Together</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2005-06-04</week>
      <week>2005-06-11</week>
      <week>2005-06-18</week>
      <week>2005-06-25</week>
      <week>2005-07-09</week>
      <week>2005-07-16</week>
      <week>2005-07-23</week>
      <week>2005-07-30</week>
      <week>2005-08-06</week>
      <week>2005-08-13</week>
      <week>2005-08-20</week>
      <week>2005-08-27</week>
      <week>2005-09-03</week>
      <week>2005-09-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/6/6f/Webelongtogether.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+We-Belong-Together.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Emancipation of Mimi</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 29, 2005  (2005-03-29) , (see release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Right Track Studios , ( New York City , New York ) , Southside Studios , ( Atlanta , Georgia )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:22</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Island</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>Jermaine Dupri</writer>
      <writer>Manuel Seal</writer>
      <writer>Johntá Austin</writer>
      <writer>Kenneth "Babyface" Edmonds</writer>
      <writer>Darnell Bristol</writer>
      <writer>Sid Johnson</writer>
      <writer>Bobby Womack</writer>
      <writer>Patrick Moten</writer>
      <writer>Sandra Sully</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mariah Carey</producer>
      <producer>Jermaine Dupri</producer>
      <producer>Manuel Seal</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"We Belong Together" is a song recorded by Mariah Carey for
    her tenth studio album 
    <i>The Emancipation of Mimi</i>(2005) and released as the
    album's second single in 2005. Written and produced by Carey,
    Jermaine Dupri, Manuel Seal, and Johntá Austin, the song was
    inspired by 1980s R&amp;B and soul. Its arrangement is built on
    simple piano chords and an understated backbeat, and its lyrics
    chronicle a woman's desperation for her former lover to return
    after their separation. Billboard magazine named it the most
    popular song of the 2000's and most successful song by a female
    artist in Billboard history.</p>
      <p>Following a career-decline between 2001 and 2005, Carey
    achieved major worldwide success with "We Belong Together" as
    the song topped the charts in Australia and the United States
    (for 14 non-consecutive weeks). In the U.S., the song also
    repeatedly broke many BDS Airplay records and was warmly
    received by critics. It won Carey a number of industry awards,
    including two Grammy Awards in 2006. 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine listed "We Belong Together" ninth on
    The Billboard: All-Time Hot 100 Top Songs and the most
    successful song of the 2000s decade.</p>
      <p>"We Belong Together" was not composed until late into the
    production of 
    <i>The Emancipation of Mimi</i>. Following an unsuccessful
    career period between 2001 and 2003, Carey began production on
    the album in 2004. By November of that year she had considered
    the album complete, but some of what became its more popular
    tracks had yet to be written. L. A. Reid, the chairman of
    Island Def Jam Music Group, encouraged Carey to attempt
    additional studio sessions with producer Jermaine Dupri. "L.A.
    was like, 'You and Jermaine Dupri make magic together, why
    aren't you in the studio with him?'" she recalled. "'I said, 'I
    love Jermaine, is he free? I know he's doing a million things.'
    [...] But Jermaine said, 'Come on down.'"</p>
      <p>Carey flew to Dupri's Atlanta studio and after two days,
    they composed two tracks for 
    <i>The Emancipation of Mimi</i>("Shake It Off" and "Get Your
    Number") and she returned to New York City; however, at this
    point "We Belong Together" was still not written. Reid was
    impressed with the album's new material and decided that Carey
    should return to Atlanta to compose more tracks.</p>
      <p>In another two-day studio stint Carey, Dupri, Seal and
    Austin produced the album's first single "It's like That" as
    well as "We Belong Together". The composers discussed the
    song's melody at length, and subsequently simplified the
    arrangement in order to accentuate Carey's vocals.</p>
      <p>"We Belong Together" is a pop ballad that exhibits strong
    influences from hip hop and R&amp;B. The song is propelled by a
    programmed Roland TR-808-styled kick and hi-hat, which is
    prominently utilized in hip hop music.</p>
      <p>Carey adopts a reserved, rap-flavored singing style, which
    garnered approval from the critics who admonish her ornate,
    melismatic singing style. Reviewer Jennifer Vineyard comments
    that Carey's spare and understated singing approach gives the
    song more power, which would not have been achieved if Carey
    had belted. Besides hip hop, the song incorporates 1980s
    retro-soul music by "cleverly" referencing Bobby Womack's "If
    You Think You're Lonely Now" (1981) and The Deele's "Two
    Occasions" (1987, with Babyface). In the second verse of "We
    Belong Together," Carey sings: "Bobby Womack's on the radio/
    Singing to me, 'If you think you're lonely now'." She then
    flips across a radio dial: "So I turn the dial, tryin’ to catch
    a break/ And then I hear Babyface/ 'I only think of you...'."
    Due to the inclusion of the lyrics from both songs, the
    songwriters were given co-writing credits on "We Belong
    Together."</p>
      <p>"We Belong Together" comprises a very simple and understated
    musical arrangement: it is set in C major and is composed in
    4/4 time. Similarly, within the song, Carey's vocal range spans
    from G
    <sub>3</sub>to A
    <sub>5</sub>. Carey's vocal range is demonstrated with a
    greater emphasis in the ending chorus, where the chorus is
    raised an octave higher, lying from G
    <sub>4</sub>to A
    <sub>5</sub>. As such, Carey ends with an anticipated coda,
    completing both the chorus and the entire song with a potent
    and unequivocal belted note of C
    <sub>5</sub>for approximately four semibreves. It follows the
    common verse-chorus form and is structured into three sections
    that portray the protagonist in a range of emotions; from
    doleful and resigned in the first section, to desperate and
    agitated in the second. In the last section the song climaxes
    with an octave raise, which not only emphasizes the
    protagonist's heightened desperation, but her determination to
    be with her lover.</p>
      <p>Carey has often recorded remixes for some of her more
    popular songs, some of which have become more successful than
    their original counterparts. For "We Belong Together," she
    recorded the DJ Clue remix, which was produced by DJ Clue and
    features rappers Jadakiss and Styles P, and the Peter Rauhofer
    Reconstruction Mix/Atlantic Soul Vocal Mix. The remixes are
    fundamentally different from the album version and contain more
    distinct elements of hip hop music. The Atlantic Soul Vocal
    Mix, for example, features a synthetic bass line, a piano and
    guitar line, and distinctive hi-hats that produce a more
    up-tempo, hard-hitting beat.</p>
      <p>Both remixes were offered as downloads in May 2005, and
    achieved success: the Atlantic Soul Mix reached number 1 on the
    U.S. Hot Dance Club Songs chart, while the DJ Clue version
    peaked at number 5 on the Hot Digital Songs chart.</p>
      <p>The song's music video was directed by Brett Ratner and
    filmed in Los Angeles. It serves as the sequel to the video for
    "It's like That," the first single released from 
    <i>The Emancipation of Mimi</i>. Beginning with the "It's like
    That" video, the protagonist is at her bachelorette party,
    where one of the guests reveals himself as a former lover
    (played by Wentworth Miller). The video for "We Belong
    Together" begins the following morning, when the protagonist
    remembers her former boyfriend, as she is preparing for her
    wedding. As she marches down the aisle, the protagonist debates
    whether she belongs with her former boyfriend or her fiance
    (played by Eric Roberts). Once she reaches the altar, she
    catches sight of her former lover who is watching the wedding
    from a distance. She runs from the ceremony and into his arms,
    shocking everyone at the wedding. The video is noted for the
    fact that Carey wore the same Vera Wang wedding dress that she
    wore at her wedding to Tommy Mottola in 1993.</p>
      <p>The video reached number 1 on several video-chart
    countdowns, including BET's 
    <i>106 &amp; Park</i>, MTV's 
    <i>TRL</i>(where it retired after it remained on the countdown
    for fifty days), MuchMusic's 
    <i>Countdown</i>, and VH1's 
    <i>Top 20 Video Countdown</i>. VH1 named the song number 1 on
    its "Top 40 Videos Of 2005" in December of that year. By July
    25, 2005 it was Launchcast's most-watched video of the year,
    with 7.5 million streamed performances. The video was nominated
    for "Best R&amp;B Video" and "Best Female Video" at the 2005
    MTV Video Music Awards.</p>
      <p>"We Belong Together" became a "career re-defining" song for
    Mariah Carey at a point when many fans and critics had
    considered her career over.</p>
      <p>Unlike most of Carey's more recent singles, "We Belong
    Together" received generally positive reviews from critics,
    most of whom hail the song as a "return to form," following
    reviews of 
    <i>Charmbracelet</i>(2002) that suggested Carey had lost her
    signature vocal range and power. A review for Slant Magazine
    writes, "the...diva [keeps] cool with breathy, rapid-fire
    verses until the final full strong-voiced climax that... proves
    that 'The Voice' has indeed returned." They also said that "The
    song is as 'innovative' as Mariah has been in years" Other
    critics commended Carey on her novel singing style which,
    according to Kelefa Sanneh of 
    <i>New York Times</i>, gives the song its propulsion.
    Similarly, 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine and Johnny Loftus of 
    <i>Metrotimes</i>characterized the song as "perfect," "classy,"
    and "sublime," while Pitchfork Media gave it four stars and a
    half.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Billboard</i>listed "We Belong Together" ninth on The
    Billboard Hot 100 All-Time Top Songs and second on Top
    Billboard Hot 100 R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs. 
    <i>Blender</i>ranked it fifteenth on its 100 Greatest Songs of
    2005 list. Slant Magazine ranked it 2nd on their best songs of
    2005 list. In Australia, the song finished 14th on ARIA Top 100
    Singles of 2005 Chart.</p>
      <p>Between 2001 and 2003, Carey's popularity had substantially
    declined and many had considered her career over. However,
    after being released to North American radio on March 26, 2005,
    "We Belong Together" became the biggest success of Carey's
    career and for her label. The song spent fourteen
    non-consecutive weeks at number 1 on both the U.S. Billboard
    Hot 100 — after making its debut at number 81 — and on the Hot
    R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs chart. It had major cross-over success,
    becoming the first song to simultaneously occupy the number 1
    position on nine 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts on the week ending August 6, 2005: the
    Hot 100, Billboard Hot 100 Airplay, Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs,
    Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Airplay, Pop 100 Airplay, Top 40
    Mainstream, Rhythmic Airplay Chart, Hot Dance Club Songs, and
    the Hot Ringtones charts. One week earlier, it had become the
    first song to top eight charts concurrently. According to
    Mediabase and Nielsen BDS, "We Belong Together" broke several
    airplay records in the United States: it gathered both the
    largest one-day and one-week audience total in BDS history,
    reaching 32.8 million and 223 million impressions respectively.
    To date, "We Belong Together" has been listened to more than 8
    billion times in the U.S alone. It was certified 2x Platinum by
    the RIAA. On Billboard Hot 100 Year-end Chart of 2005, the song
    was declared the number 1 song, a career first for Carey. It's
    also ended at 2 on 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs Year-end chart of
    2005. The song was also declared the most popular song of the
    2000's by Billboard magazine.</p>
      <p>"We Belong Together" achieved success in several major
    non-U.S. markets. It debuted at the top of the Australian
    chart, where it remained for two weeks. It reached a peak
    position of number 2 for three weeks in New Zealand. Promotion
    for the song was strongest in the UK, where it debuted at
    number 2 behind Tupac Shakur's "Ghetto Gospel", selling 39,436
    copies, only missing the top spot by 392 physical and digital
    sales. Across Europe the song was a moderate success. It
    reached the top five in Spain, Ireland, Netherlands, Denmark
    and Switzerland, top ten in Norway, and top twenty in France,
    Belgium, Sweden, Italy and Germany. On the Australia's ARIA Top
    100 singles end of the year chart of 2005, "We Belong Together"
    was ranked 17 and 10 on the Urban singles end of the year
    chart. It was certified 2x platinum in Australia by ARIA and
    platinum in New Zealand by RIANZ.</p>
      <p>European CD single</p>
      <p>Japanese CD single</p>
      <p>Australian CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>European CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>UK CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>
         <span id="interwiki-hu-fa"/>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
