<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27ll_Be_There_(Jackson_5_song)#Mariah_Carey_version 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27ll_Be_There_(Jackson_5_song)#Mariah_Carey_version</songId>
   <title>I'll Be There</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1992-06-20</week>
      <week>1992-06-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/b/b5/J5-ill-be-there-45.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+I-ll-Be-There.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Third Album</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 28, 1970  (1970-08-28)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" 45 RPM</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Hitsville West, Los Angeles in 1970</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:57</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Motown , M 1171</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Berry Gordy</writer>
      <writer>Bob West</writer>
      <writer>Hal Davis</writer>
      <writer>Willie Hutch</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Berry Gordy</producer>
      <producer>Bob West</producer>
      <producer>Hal Davis</producer>
      <producer>Willie Hutch</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I'll Be There" is a soul song written by Berry Gordy, Bob
    West, Hal Davis, and Willie Hutch, which resulted in two U.S.
    number 1 hit singles: the original 1970 recording by American
    vocal quintet The Jackson 5 and a 1992 live version by American
    R&amp;B singer Mariah Carey and American R&amp;B singer Trey
    Lorenz.</p>
      <p>The Jackson 5 original was recorded for Motown Records, and
    released as the first single from their 
    <i>Third Album</i>in 1970. Produced by the songwriters, "I'll
    Be There" was The Jackson 5's fourth number 1 hit in a row,
    following "I Want You Back," "ABC," and "The Love You Save."
    "I'll Be There" is also notable as the most successful single
    released by Motown during its "Detroit era" (1959-1972). It is
    also the fourth in the group's string of four consecutive
    number one pop hits, making them the first black male group to
    achieve this.</p>
      <p>The Mariah Carey/Trey Lorenz cover was recorded during
    Carey's appearance on 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>in 1992, and released as the first single
    from her EP 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>in the second quarter of 1992. Co-produced
    by Carey and Walter Afanasieff, "I'll Be There" became Carey's
    sixth number 1 single in the U.S., and her biggest hit
    elsewhere at the time.</p>
      <p>After three upbeat "bubblegum soul" number 1 singles from
    the Jackson 5 ("I Want You Back," "ABC," and "The Love You
    Save"), Motown head Berry Gordy decided to take a risk and
    craft a ballad for the group. For this song, he brought in
    writer/producers Hal Davis, Willie Hutch, and Bob West, as
    opposed to working with the rest of The Corporation, who had
    crafted the first three hits.</p>
      <p>The resulting song was a gentle ballad, in which the
    narrator asks his ex-lover to give their love another chance.
    He promises that, this time, he'll always be there "to comfort
    you," and that even if she "should ever find someone new,"
    he'll still be there for her if her new love treats her wrong.
    Jackson 5 lead singers Michael Jackson and his older brother
    Jermaine share the lead vocals on this song. Michael's
    ad-libbed "just look over your shoulders, honey" is an allusion
    to "Reach Out I'll Be There," a 1966 number 1 hit single
    recorded by Four Tops. He was instructed by Gordy to say "just
    look over your shoulder" (exactly as Levi Stubbs had said it in
    "Reach Out I'll Be There"), but the slightly flubbed line was
    allowed to remain in the final mix.</p>
      <p>In his 
    <i>Moon Walk</i>autobiography, Michael Jackson noted that "I'll
    Be There" was the song that solidified The Jackson 5's careers
    and showed audiences that the group had potential beyond
    bubblegum pop. Allmusic.com commented that "rarely, if ever,
    had one so young sung with so much authority and grace,
    investing this achingly tender ballad with wisdom and
    understanding far beyond his years".</p>
      <p>The most successful single ever released by the Jackson 5,
    "I'll Be There" sold 4.2 million copies in the United States,
    and 6.1 million copies worldwide. It replaced Marvin Gaye's "I
    Heard It Through the Grapevine" as the most successful single
    released on Motown in the U.S., a record it held until the
    release of Lionel Richie's duet with Diana Ross, "Endless Love"
    (1981). Outside the U.S., "I Heard It Through the Grapevine"
    remained Motown's biggest selling record with worldwide sales
    of over 7 million copies.</p>
      <p>The song held the number 1 position on the Pop Singles Chart
    for five weeks from October 17 to November 14, replacing
    "Cracklin' Rosie" by Neil Diamond, and replaced by "I Think I
    Love You" by The Partridge Family. "I'll Be There" was also a
    number 1 hit on the Black Singles Chart for six weeks, and a
    number 4 hit in the United Kingdom. The single's B-side was
    "One More Chance."</p>
      <p>"I'll Be There" was the Jackson 5's final number 1 Hot 100
    hit as a group. For the rest of their career as a major-label
    act, Jackson 5 singles would get no higher than number-two.
    Michael Jackson scored several number 1 hits as a solo artist,
    beginning with "Ben" in 1972. He performed "I'll Be There" on
    all his world tours. In the live versions from his 1981 Triumph
    Tour to his 1987 solo Bad World Tour, Jackson would seemingly
    break down in tears, struggling with the words until feeling a
    jolt as he harmonized and shouted "can you feel it!" to the
    delight of the audience before dancing to the beat of "Rock
    With You," in his later tours from Dangerous World Tour
    onwards, by the time he would almost cry and struggle with the
    words, instead, he reminisced on his childhood past, shouting
    out his brothers' names and ending the song with a jump and a
    spin to end the song.</p>
      <p>"I'll Be There" remains one of the most popular of the
    Jackson 5's hits, and has been covered by a number of artists,
    including Josie and the Pussycats and Mariah Carey, whose cover
    brought the song back into the public's consciousness two
    decades after its original release. The song was also covered
    by the punk band Me First and the Gimme Gimmes on their album 
    <i>Take a Break</i>.</p>
      <p>"I'll Be There" was one of the songs used in the showcase
    for 
    <i>Grease: You're the One that I Want!</i>.</p>
      <p>In this song was also by the 2008 music simulation game, 
    <i>Wii Music</i>.</p>
      <p>Punk rock band Green Day has frequently performed a live
    medley beginning with their original song "King For A Day",
    morphing into The Isley Brothers' "Shout" and breaks into a
    smaller medley including, but not limited to, The Penguins'
    "Earth Angel," "I'll Be There," and Ben E. King's "Stand By
    Me", then back into "shout."</p>
      <p>The song was performed by Michael Jackson in the 2009 film 
    <i>Michael Jackson's This Is It</i>. However, the song was
    performed by Jackson and backup singers as if they were the
    Jackson 5. During the song, clips of the Jackson 5 is shown. At
    the end of the song, Michael dedicates the song to all of his
    brothers and his parents.</p>
      <p>Mariah Carey had included "I'll Be There" as a last-minute
    addition to her 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>setlist, after she had been informed that
    most acts on the show commonly perform at least one cover.
    "I'll Be There" was the sixth track on Carey's 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>special, taped on March 16, 1992. It was
    performed as a romantic duet, with Carey singing Michael
    Jackson's lines and R&amp;B singer Trey Lorenz singing Jermaine
    Jackson's lines. The program and resulting 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>album were produced by Carey and Walter
    Afanasieff, who played the piano for the performance.</p>
      <p>The 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>special aired on May 20, 1992, and was a
    notable success. Carey's label, Columbia Records, received many
    requests to release "I'll Be There" as a single, which had not
    been planned. A radio edit of the song was created which
    removed dialogue portions of the performance, and "I'll Be
    There" was released as a single. In the U.S., the song was
    issued with "So Blessed" as a B-side; in the United Kingdom,
    the "I'll Be There" single included the live version of "Vision
    of Love", and the album versions of "If It's Over" and "All in
    Your Mind".</p>
      <p>"I'll Be There" was nominated for the 1993 Grammy Award for
    Best R&amp;B Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocals, losing
    to Boyz II Men's "End of the Road". The "I'll Be There" music
    video, directed by Larry Jordan, was compiled from footage of
    Carey's 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>appearance.</p>
      <p>During Michael Jackson's memorial service on July 7, 2009,
    Carey and Lorenz sang their rendition of the song in tribute to
    Jackson.</p>
      <p>Worldwide CD single</p>
      <p>European CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>UK CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>After the underperformance of "Make It Happen" compared to
    her previous singles, "I'll Be There" was a return to form for
    Carey: it became her sixth number 1 on the U.S. Billboard Hot
    100 and allayed any concerns her record label had about her
    career in decline. "I'll Be There" was the number 1 song on the
    Hot 100 for two weeks, from June 13, 1992 to June 27; it was
    the second time that the song hit number 1. It replaced "Jump"
    by Kris Kross, and was itself replaced by "Baby Got Back" by
    Sir Mix-a-Lot. It became a number 1 success on the U.S. Hot
    Adult Contemporary Tracks. In fact, it is the only single
    released from the 
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>series that went number one.</p>
      <p>"I'll Be There" was Carey's breakthrough hit outside North
    America, becoming her most successful single in numerous
    markets. It topped the Canadian Singles Chart for two weeks,
    and became her biggest hit so far in the United Kingdom (where
    it hit number 2) and Australia (where it reached number 9). It
    peaked inside the top twenty in most markets across Europe,
    where Carey's success had previously been limited.</p>
      <p>The Temptations did a cover version of this song for their
    album 
    <i>Reflections</i>. The band Westlife did a cover version of
    "I'll Be There" for the self-titled album. 
    <i>American Idol</i>fifth place finalist RJ Helton belted out
    this song on Wild Card night and advanced to the finals in
    season 1. 
    <i>American Idol</i>finalist Jasmine Murray got eliminated in a
    double elimination with Jorge Núñez on top 13 week after
    singing "I'll Be There" in season 8. Jamie Foxx and Ne-Yo
    concluded the 2009 BET Awards show with this song.</p>
      <p>New Kids on the Block covered the song live on the day of
    Jackson's death.</p>
      <p>American Punk Trio Green Day covered this song while playing
    "King for a day/Shout on their 21st Century Breakdown World
    Tour, which kicked off just after Michael Jackson's death.
    Jason Freese, one of the band's touring members who plays sax
    on the song, dressed up as Michael Jackson during the
    performance.</p>
      <p>The finalists of the third season of X-Factor Denmark, did a
    cover version i order to raise money for Haiti.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
