<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Always_Be_My_Baby 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Always_Be_My_Baby</songId>
   <title>Always Be My Baby</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1996-05-04</week>
      <week>1996-05-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/8/84/ABMB2.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+Always-Be-My-Baby.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Daydream</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 19, 1996  (1996-03-19)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>December 1994</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:18</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>Jermaine Dupri</writer>
      <writer>Manuel Seal</writer>
      <writer>Jr.</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mariah Carey</producer>
      <producer>Jermaine Dupri</producer>
      <producer>Manuel Seal</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Always Be My Baby" is a pop/R&amp;B song written and
    produced by American singer Mariah Carey, producer/rapper
    Jermaine Dupri, and songwriter Manuel Seal. Released in 1996 as
    the third single in the U.S. (fourth in other markets) from
    Carey's fourth studio album 
    <i>Daydream</i>(1995), the song reached number 1 on the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100 chart, number 2 in Canada, and peaked within
    the top twenty of the majority charts on which it appeared. The
    lyrics chronicle a relationship that has ended, the protagonist
    asserts that her former lover will "always be her baby," and
    will come back to her once he realizes that he misses her. The
    song received a 1996 Grammy Award nomination for Best Female
    R&amp;B Vocal Performance.</p>
      <p>"Always Be My Baby" debuted On Urban Radio On Feb 27,1996,
    stayed at that position for four weeks, and reached #1 for two
    weeks before returning to the #2 position for an additional
    five weeks, bringing the total to nine weeks at #2. The song
    became Carey's eleventh #1 single in the United States, tying
    her with pop singers Whitney Houston and Madonna as the female
    solo artist with the most #1 singles. Due to the song spending
    nine weeks at the #2 position, "Always Be My Baby" is to date
    Carey's longest stay at #2 and the fourth longest stay at that
    position.</p>
      <p>Whereas "Fantasy" and "One Sweet Day" were sales-record
    singles, "Always Be My Baby" was a major airplay hit. The song
    also managed to reach #1 on the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs; it
    was also the most-played single on American radio in 1996 and
    was the number-one airplay single of 1996 according to the Hot
    100 Airplay year-end charts, but despite this achievement, it
    never reached #1 on that chart throughout the year. Due to its
    extensive airplay, the single became Carey's first number 1 on
    the Hot Adult Top 40 Tracks; it also reached the top five on
    the Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks and the Top 40 Mainstream
    charts.</p>
      <p>Outside the United States, the song became another success,
    but it was unable to match the chart success of "Fantasy" in
    most markets. Although generally performing less well than "One
    Sweet Day," it reached the top five in Canada and the United
    Kingdom, where it fared better than all of Carey's releases
    from 
    <i>Daydream</i>. In Australia, it reached the top twenty.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Always Be My Baby" was the second to be
    directed by Carey. She is the seemingly happy narrator of a
    tale of young love, as a young boy and a girl elope in the
    middle of the night. The video was filmed on location at
    Carey's sponsored charity, the Fresh Air Fund upstate New York
    camp.,</p>
      <p>The main remix of this song, also known as "Always Be My
    Baby" (Mr. Dupri Mix), features re-sung vocals with most of the
    melodic structure retained while using a sample of the song
    "Tell Me If You Still Care" by The SOS Band, including vocals
    from Da Brat and Xscape. (Da Brat would later go on to rap on
    remixes of "Honey" (1997), "I Still Believe" (1998),
    "Heartbreaker" (1999), "Loverboy" (2001), and "4real4real", an
    international bonus track for Carey's album, 
    <i>E=MC²</i>.) A video was created for the Mr. Dupri Mix, which
    shows Carey, Da Brat, and Xscape hanging out around Carey's
    former mansion. It is in black and white and has the shot of
    Carey in a beret that would become the cover for this
    single.</p>
      <p>Dance remixes with re-recorded vocals were created by David
    Morales and Satoshi Tomiie of Def Mix Productions. There was
    also a reggae remix featuring Li'l Vicious. The North American
    Single includes a song called "Slipping Away" which was
    recorded for the "Daydream" album, but failed to make it onto
    the final track listing. The song is written by Mariah Carey
    and co-produced by Dave Hall.</p>
      <p>On season 7 of 
    <i>American Idol</i>, David Cook performed a rock arrangement
    of the song during the April 15, 2008 episode, in which Carey
    mentored the contestants on her songs. His version received
    high praise from all three judges, and even Carey herself.
    Cook's version charted and peaked on the Billboard Hot 100 at
    number 67.</p>
      <p>European CD single #1</p>
      <p>European CD single #2</p>
      <p>North American CD single</p>
      <p>Australian/European/U.S. CD maxi-single #1</p>
      <p>Australian/European CD maxi-single #2</p>
      <p>Japanese CD single</p>
      <p>UK maxi-single #1</p>
      <p>UK CD maxi-single #2</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
