<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Someday_(Mariah_Carey_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Someday_(Mariah_Carey_song)</songId>
   <title>Someday</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1991-03-09</week>
      <week>1991-03-16</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/b/bd/Someday11.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+Someday.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Mariah Carey</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 13, 1990  (1990-12-13)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>December 1988—October 1990</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>New Jack Swing</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:07</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>Ben Margulies</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Ric Wake</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Someday" is a song written by Mariah Carey and Ben
    Margulies, and produced by Ric Wake for Carey's debut album, 
    <i>Mariah Carey</i>(1990). It was released as the album's third
    single in 1990 and is a jackswing-influenced track. Though it
    topped the U.S. charts, it was not a huge success elsewhere. As
    did previous singles from 
    <i>Mariah Carey</i>, "Someday" received a BMI Pop Award.</p>
      <p>"Someday" was one of the five songs on the demo tape, handed
    by Brenda K. Starr to record executive Tommy Mottola, that led
    to Carey being given a recording contract. Sony made
    alterations to the version on the demo tape because they
    thought it was too rough—the horn melodies were taken out and
    replaced with electric guitar melodies, and the ending was
    shortened by about eight seconds. Carey and Margulies were
    forced to accept the changes that were made because neither had
    been allowed to co-produce. Reportedly, Carey was unhappy with
    the final version of "Someday" produced, because both she and
    Margulies thought it had been too "polished."</p>
      <p>"Someday" continued Carey's streak of number 1 hits in the
    U.S., becoming her third consecutive number 1 single on the
    Billboard Hot 100. It reached number 1 in its eighth week on
    the Hot 100 and spent two weeks at the top of the chart, from
    March 3 to March 16, 1991. It replaced "All the Man That I
    Need" by Whitney Houston, and was replaced by Timmy T's "One
    More Try". "Someday" spent fifteen weeks in the top forty and
    was ranked 13 on the Hot 100 year-end chart of 1991, making it
    one of the year's biggest hits. The RIAA certified it gold.</p>
      <p>A large number of remixes were produced by Shep Pettibone,
    in particular the main remix of the song known as "Someday"
    (new 7" jackswing) and an extended version of it known as
    "Someday" (new 12" jackswing). There is also a house mix known
    as "Someday" (new 12" house), a slightly extended album version
    known as "Someday" (new 7" straight), and an a cappella,
    "Someday" (pianoapercapella).</p>
      <p>The single's video, directed by Larry Jordan, was filmed on
    location at Bayonne High School in Bayonne, New Jersey and
    depicts a boy who treated a girl badly now wanting her back in
    his life. A group of hip-hop dancers appear, and at one point
    in the video, Carey joins them. It also featured Larry Wright
    drumming on plastic buckets. The main version of the video was
    based on "Someday" (new 7" jackswing), but there is an extended
    video with the music from "Someday" (new 12" jackswing). The
    new 12" jackswing version of the video was replaced by the 1992
    
    <i>MTV Unplugged</i>live performance of the song on the
    DVD/home video 
    <i>#1's</i>(1999).</p>
      <p>Worldwide CD single</p>
      <p>Worldwide CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>UK CD maxi-single #1</p>
      <p>UK CD maxi-single #2</p>
      <p>Spain 7" Promo Single</p>
      <p>In Japan, EPs are only eligible to chart on the albums
    chart.</p>
      <p>In 2003 "Someday" was covered by the dance group Rezonance
    Q, featuring Nazene on vocals, with Mike Di Scala producing the
    music. The song, which was released on 17 February 2003,
    reached #29 in the UK Singles Chart. The video for this song
    was filmed in the 051 club in Liverpool.</p>
      <p>From the AATW online store:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
