<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fantasy_(Mariah_Carey_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fantasy_(Mariah_Carey_song)</songId>
   <title>Fantasy</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1995-09-30</week>
      <week>1995-10-07</week>
      <week>1995-10-14</week>
      <week>1995-10-21</week>
      <week>1995-10-28</week>
      <week>1995-11-04</week>
      <week>1995-11-11</week>
      <week>1995-11-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/e/e2/Mariahcareysingle_fantasy.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+Fantasy.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Daydream</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 12, 1995</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>early 1995</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:04</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>Dave Hall</writer>
      <writer>Tina Weymouth</writer>
      <writer>Chris Frantz</writer>
      <writer>Steven Stanley</writer>
      <writer>Adrian Belew</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mariah Carey</producer>
      <producer>Dave Hall</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Fantasy" is a song co-written and co-produced by American
    singer Mariah Carey and Dave Hall, and recorded for Carey's
    fifth album 
    <i>Daydream</i>(1995). It is built around a sample of the Tom
    Tom Club's single "Genius of Love" (1981), which was written by
    Tina Weymouth, Chris Frantz, Steven Stanley and Adrian Belew.
    It was released as the album's first single in 1995. The urban
    remix of "Fantasy" features Ol' Dirty Bastard. For the sixth
    year in a row, Mariah Carey received a Grammy Award nomination
    for Best Female Pop Vocal Performance. The cover of the single
    was shot by top fashion photographer Steven Meisel. The cover
    for her album 
    <i>Daydream</i>is a cropped version of the single cover. The
    song was number 1 for eight consecutive weeks and is one of
    Carey's signature songs.</p>
      <p>"Fantasy" became Carey's ninth number 1 single on the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100 chart. It was the first single by a female
    artist to debut at number 1 in the U.S., and only the second
    single to do so after "You Are Not Alone" by Michael Jackson.
    It spent eight weeks at the top of the chart, from September 24
    to November 18, 1995, Carey's longest stay at the time
    alongside "Dreamlover" (1993). It replaced " Gangsta's
    Paradise" by Coolio, and was replaced by Whitney Houston's
    "Exhale (Shoop Shoop)". "Fantasy" spent twenty-three weeks in
    the top forty and was successful on other 
    <i>Billboard</i>formats, including the R&amp;B and dance
    charts. Its strong sales led it to be certified double platinum
    by the RIAA, Carey's first single to do so. It was ranked
    number 7 on the Hot 100 year-end charts for 1995 and 49 on the
    1996 year-end charts. The song was as well featured in the 1998
    Rush Hour movie.</p>
      <p>The single topped the charts in Canada, Australia and New
    Zealand and reached the top five in the United Kingdom. It
    remained at the top of the Canadian Singles Chart for twelve
    weeks, a record it shared with six other singles until the
    release of "I'll Be Missing You" (1997) by Puff Daddy featuring
    Faith Evans. "Fantasy" also reached the top ten in most
    countries across Europe, and the top twenty on the Oricon chart
    in Japan.</p>
      <p>The single's music video was the first that Carey directed
    entirely on her own. She can be seen exploring an amusement
    park (Playland, located in Rye, New York), on roller blades and
    riding on a roller coaster, before joining a group of hip hop
    dancers after nightfall. The video also contains a scene
    involving an lovable young girl who tries to emulate Carey and
    whose character reappears in the video for Carey's single
    "Shake It Off" (2005). The video shoot took place in mid-August
    1995.</p>
      <p>Carey worked with producer Puff Daddy to create the official
    remix, the Bad Boy remix of "Fantasy". The Bad Boy remix used
    guest raps from Ol' Dirty Bastard and background vocals by Puff
    Daddy. Some of the song's R&amp;B elements were removed for the
    remix, while the bassline and "Genius of Love" sample were
    emphasized. There is a version omitting Ol' Dirty Bastard's
    verses.</p>
      <p>Carey re-recorded vocals for club remixes of the song by
    David Morales. One of these remixes won the Winter Music
    Conference National Dance Award for Dance Record of the
    Year.</p>
      <p>Worldwide CD single</p>
      <p>UK #1/U.S. CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>UK CD maxi-single #2</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
