<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Forget_About_Us 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Forget_About_Us</songId>
   <title>Don't Forget About Us</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mariah_Carey</artistId>
      <artistName>Mariah Carey</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2005-12-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/dc/Dontforgetaboutus.jpg/200px-Dontforgetaboutus.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mariah-Carey+Don-t-Forget-About-Us.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Emancipation of Mimi</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 12, 2005  (2005-12-12) , (see Release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Japan and New York City</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:53</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Island</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mariah Carey</writer>
      <writer>Jermaine Dupri</writer>
      <writer>Johntá Austin</writer>
      <writer>Bryan-Michael Cox</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mariah Carey</producer>
      <producer>Jermaine Dupri</producer>
      <producer>Johnta Austin</producer>
      <producer>G Daoud</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Don't Forget About Us" is a song co-written by Mariah
    Carey, Jermaine Dupri, Johntá Austin and Bryan-Michael Cox, and
    recorded by Carey for the re-release of her tenth studio album 
    <i>The Emancipation of Mimi</i>(2005). It was co-produced by
    Carey, Dupri and Austin and released as the album's fifth
    single (fourth in North America) in late 2005. The song reached
    number one in Finland and the U.S., and the top forty
    elsewhere. It was nominated for two awards at the 49th Grammy
    Awards. Carey's vocals span from B2 to G6 in the song.</p>
      <p>The song is a midtempo jam that harkens back to 1990s-styled
    R&amp;B, and its protagonist regrets a failed relationship that
    never had a proper conclusion. Unlike "We Belong Together",
    another song from 
    <i>The Emancipation of Mimi</i>, she is not very despondent,
    and has accepted that her ex-lover is now seeing someone else.
    However, she does not want him to forget what they had when
    they were together: "Nothing can compare to your first true
    love, so I hope this will remind you, when it's for real it's
    forever, so don't forget about us". She also reminds her
    ex-lover that no matter who his new girl is, "I bet she can't
    do like me, she'll never be MC." Carey has been accused of
    repeating formulas for her singles if they are successful. For
    instance, in the past, she was called out for making songs such
    as "Heartbreaker" (1999) and "Loverboy" (2001) too similar to
    other up-tempos like "Dreamlover" (1993) and "Fantasy" (1995).
    Several music critics have drawn parallels between "Don't
    Forget About Us" and "We Belong Together", the second and most
    successful single from 
    <i>The Emancipation of Mimi</i>. Chuck Taylor of 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine called the song "little more than a
    continuation of the previous hit ... On its own, "Forget" is a
    soulful, satisfying track, but it suggests that Carey has hit a
    creative wall." Bill Lamb of About.com, in a more positive
    summary of the song, wrote "It doesn't mess with the brilliant
    formula of "We Belong Together" ... [but] those wanting variety
    from Mariah Carey need to look elsewhere."</p>
      <p>"Don't Forget About Us" was nominated at the 2006 BET Awards
    in the BET.com "Viewers' Choice" category. It was nominated for
    the 49th Grammy Awards for Best Female R&amp;B Vocal
    Performance and Best R&amp;B Song.</p>
      <p>"Don't Forget About Us" officially impacted U.S. radio on
    October 11, 2005, but had already been added to many radio
    station playlists before that. It premiered on the radio and
    the internet in late September. It reached number 1 on the
    Billboard Hot 100 in its eleventh week and spent two weeks at
    the top, from December 25 to January 8. It replaced "Run It!"
    by Chris Brown, and was replaced by D4L's "Laffy Taffy". "Don't
    Forget About Us" stayed in the top forty for eighteen weeks and
    it also reached number 1 on several other 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts, including the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop
    Songs. It then tied Carey with Elvis Presley for the most
    number 1 singles in the U.S. by a solo artist with seventeen,
    she has since surpassed this record and is now behind only The
    Beatles, who hold the record with twenty.</p>
      <p>The song's successful start to its U.S. chart performance
    was because of its strong radio airplay, but it advanced more
    slowly on the Hot 100 than Carey's previous two singles because
    of the lack of digital downloads. The album cut and several
    remixes were released to digital retailers on December 13, 2005
    when the song was already number 2 on the Hot 100. The RIAA
    later certified "Don't Forget About Us" platinum. In 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s 2006 recap the single ended at number 50 on
    the top 100 singles list.</p>
      <p>Outside the U.S, it topped the chart in Finland and reached
    the top twenty in the United Kingdom and Australia. It
    performed moderately in Europe.</p>
      <p>The single's music video reunited Carey with Paul Hunter,
    director of the video for "Honey" (1997), and it jumps between
    two different time frames. The first of these involves a
    tearful Carey in the present, while the second invokes memories
    of a relationship with a former lover (played by Dolce &amp;
    Gabbana model Christian Monzon). The video pays homage to
    actress Marilyn Monroe, whom Carey dressed up as in the music
    video for "I Still Believe" (1998): the shot in which Carey is
    in the pool with her leg protruding out of the water emulates
    an identical shot from Monroe's unfinished film 
    <i>Something's Got to Give</i>(1962) in which she struck a
    similar pose.</p>
      <p>The video was officially released promotionally on November
    1, 2005, but was premiered by surprise on October 29 on MTV's 
    <i>Spanking New</i>series. It reached number 1 on 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>, where it eventually retired, on
    BET's 
    <i>106 &amp; Park</i>countdown (for twenty-one non-consecutive
    countdowns), and on VH1's 
    <i>Top 20 Video Countdown.</i>
      </p>
      <p>The main remix of "Don't Forget About Us" was produced by
    Jermaine Dupri and is known as the Mr. Dupri mix. It features
    guest appearances from rappers Juelz Santana, Krayzie Bone and
    Layzie Bone, and Carey's parts are greatly reduced. It
    premiered on Chicago's B-96 FM on November 29, 2005. The Mr.
    Dupri mix later was added to iTunes Music Store for download,
    while several dance remixes (by Ralphi Rosario &amp; Craig J.,
    Quentin Harris and Tony Moran &amp; Warren Rigg) were produced
    and made available for sale at other download retailers. The
    Mr. Dupri mix sold well enough to help "Don't Forget About Us"
    top Billboard's Hot Digital Songs chart, whereas the album cut
    reached only number 2 on the Hot Digital Tracks chart.</p>
      <p>In January 2007, a new remix titled the Desert Storm remix,
    produced by DJ Clue (who also remixed "We Belong Together" and
    "Shake It Off") and featuring Fabolous and Styles P, was
    released to radio. It was originally supposed to be recorded
    with Cam'ron and Da Brat, but their recording session was
    cancelled after Cam'ron was injured during a shooting. On this
    version of the song, Carey's verses remain the same but
    although the chorus is altered, it keeps its original message
    and can be heard in its original lyrics once near the end of
    the song. The Desert Storm remix appeared on DJ Clue's album 
    <i>The Professional, Pt. 3</i>. A video was also helmed for the
    Desert Storm mix. It can be found on Clue's official MySpace
    page and has shots of Carey, DJ Clue and Fabulous in the studio
    and out having fun.</p>
      <p>European CD single</p>
      <p>European CD single</p>
      <p>Australian CD single</p>
      <p>European CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>UK CD maxi-single</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
