<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teen_Angel_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teen_Angel_(song)</songId>
   <title>Teen Angel</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Dinning</artistId>
      <artistName>Mark Dinning</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1960-02-08</week>
      <week>1960-02-15</week>
   </weeks>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:42</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MGM Records, Inc.</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jean &amp; Red Surrey</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jim Vinneau</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Teen Angel" is a teenage tragedy song written by Jean
    Dinning and her husband, Red Surrey, and performed by both
    Jean's brother, Mark Dinning, and Alex Murray in 1959. As a
    one-hit wonder for Dinning, it reached number one on the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100 (February 1960) and number thirty-seven in
    the UK Singles Chart (even though it was banned from being
    played by the BBC).</p>
      <p>Because of its rather taboo subject matter at the time, 
    <i>Teen Angel</i>was one of the first songs of the '60s to
    attract controversy, and was banned by many radio stations for
    being morbid.</p>
      <p>The song is about a girl who is out on a ride with her
    boyfriend. Their car is stalled on a railroad track when he
    pulls her to safety. But when she runs back, she gets hit by a
    train. When they find her body, the narrator's high school
    class ring is in her hand, apparently the reason that she ran
    back.</p>
      <p>American rock and roll revival act Sha Na Na performed 
    <i>Teen Angel</i>at the 1969 Woodstock festival.</p>
      <p>Despite the gloomy subject matter, "Teen Angel" and its
    predecessor at the Hot 100's top spot, "Running Bear" by Johnny
    Preston, continued a string of pop tunes in which someone,
    usually a female teenage love interest, dies tragically.</p>
      <p>In 1974, the Canadian band, Wednesday, released its own
    version of "Teen Angel" much like it had released its own
    version of "Last Kiss". But rather than being a remake of the
    original, the storyline of the 1974 version reverses the role.
    After losing his girlfriend some time before, the 16-year-old
    boy loses his life in the same manner as the girl in the 1960
    song (and the song in this case is narrated by a group of the
    boy's friends, rather than an individual).</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
