<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Makes_Me_Wonder 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Makes_Me_Wonder</songId>
   <title>Makes Me Wonder</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maroon_5</artistId>
      <artistName>Maroon 5</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2007-05-12</week>
      <week>2007-05-19</week>
      <week>2007-06-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/87/Maroon5-makes-me-wonder.jpg/200px-Maroon5-makes-me-wonder.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Maroon-5+Makes-Me-Wonder.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>It Won't Be Soon Before Long</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 1, 2007 ( U.S. ) , May 9, 2007 ( Netherlands ) , May 12, 2007 ( Australia ) , May 16, 2007 ( Germany ) , May 19, 2007 ( UK )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2006</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
      <genre>Funk Rock</genre>
      <genre>Alternative Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:31</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>A&amp;M/Octone Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Adam Levine</writer>
      <writer>Jesse Carmichael</writer>
      <writer>Mickey Madden</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mark Endert</producer>
      <producer>Maroon 5</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Makes Me Wonder" is the Grammy Award winning first single
    released from Maroon 5's second album, 
    <i>It Won't Be Soon Before Long</i>(2007). World premiering on
    the Las Vegas station Mix 94.1, the song has been released in
    several countries and was very well-received, becoming the
    band's first number-one on the Billboard Hot 100 chart, as well
    as the first rock song to top the same chart since Nickelback's
    How You Remind Me in 2001. The song broke a record previously
    held by Kelly Clarkson's "A Moment Like This" for the biggest
    jump to number-one in the history of the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 chart, rising from number 64 to the
    top. Maroon 5 performed the song in May 2007 on 
    <i>The Tonight Show with Jay Leno</i>. This song was #49 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s list of the 100 Best Songs of 2007.</p>
      <p>The lyrics of "Makes Me Wonder" have two different meanings.
    One meaning is about Adam Levine's frustration at the state of
    politics and the US role in the war in Iraq. According to him,
    the song shows their confusion about the politics in the US.
    The song was also called a hard hitting pop rock anthem.</p>
      <p>The second meaning is simply about love. The lyrics in the
    chorus reflects one of Levine's relationships that went
    horribly wrong. Levine states about their relationship, "It had
    something to do with our growing dissatisfaction with things
    and the confusion that was in the air."</p>
      <p>The song was upgraded to the A-list of BBC Radio 1 on May 7,
    2007.</p>
      <p>This song was performed at the 2007 Nickelodeon Kid's Choice
    Awards, American Idol, and many talk shows.</p>
      <p>It was featured as downloadable content for Rock Band on
    June 25, 2009.</p>
      <p>The video premiered on MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>on March 29, 2007. From interviews
    given by the band members it was confirmed that the video is
    shot at a futuristic airport with the actual song content about
    heartache and politics. The video was shot in the Los Angeles
    International Airport and at the Los Angeles Department of
    Transportation, and was directed by John Hillcoat. Levine said
    the director had an idea of turning the airport into a bizarre,
    surreal, sexually charged, fashionable world. In the video, the
    gate they are in is "M5", which stands for Maroon 5.</p>
      <p>The song has two censored clean versions, the "super clean"
    and "clean" versions. The tracks are identical except the
    "super clean" version has the word "God" removed from the 2nd
    verse and the word "fuck" is more clearly censored out. The
    "Super clean" version was played at the 2007 Kids Choice
    Awards.</p>
      <p>A kid-friendly version of "Makes Me Wonder" is covered by
    the Kidz Bop Kids on their album 
    <i>Kidz Bop 12</i>.</p>
      <p>The band won their 3rd Grammy award for "Best Pop
    Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal" for "Makes Me Wonder"
    at the 50th Anniversary show of the Grammys on February 10,
    2008. It was their second win in this category after "This
    Love".</p>
      <p>The song has had one of the biggest bullets in Hot Adult
    history, with many AC radio stations putting it into heavy
    rotation mere days after its release. The song reached number
    11 on the U.S. Adult Top 40 after only two weeks on the chart,
    becoming only the third song since 2000 to reach the top 15 of
    the Adult Top 40 in two weeks or less. The song was also
    released on the U.S. iTunes Store and climbed to number one on
    their top 100 sales chart.</p>
      <p>In the 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine issue dated May 12, 2007, Maroon 5
    scored their first number-one on the Billboard Hot 100, due to
    strong radio airplay and 243,500 digital downloads. By doing
    so, they broke a record held by Kelly Clarkson's "A Moment Like
    This" for the biggest jump to number one in Hot 100 history,
    leaping from number 64 to number one (Clarkson's single had
    jumped from number 52 in October 2002). "Makes Me Wonder"
    remained at number one for a second week before falling to
    number two and then returning to number one in the following
    week. It is the first song by a rock band to reach number one
    on the Billboard Hot 100 since Nickelback did the same on
    December 22, 2001 with "How You Remind Me". The song reached
    number one again on June 2.</p>
      <p>In the UK the song debuted at #19 with downloads alone a
    week before its physical release and rose to #2 the second
    week.</p>
      <p>In Mexico went on to sell over 420,000 digital
    downloads.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
