<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/El_Paso_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/El_Paso_(song)</songId>
   <title>El Paso</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marty_Robbins</artistId>
      <artistName>Marty Robbins</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1960-01-04</week>
      <week>1960-01-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/a/a6/El_Paso_by_Marty_Robbins_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Marty-Robbins+El-Paso.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Gunfighter Ballads and Trail Songs</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 1959</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>April 1959</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Country</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:44</length>
   </lengths>
   <writers>
      <writer>Marty Robbins</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"El Paso" is a country and western ballad written and
    originally recorded by Marty Robbins, and first released on 
    <i>Gunfighter Ballads and Trail Songs</i>in September 1959. It
    was released as a single the following month, and became a
    major hit on both the country and pop music charts, reaching
    Number One in both at the start of 1960. It won the Grammy
    Award for Best Country &amp; Western Recording in 1961, and
    remains Robbins' best-known song. It is widely considered a
    genre classic for its gripping narrative, haunting harmonies by
    Tompall and the Glaser Brothers and the eloquent Spanish guitar
    accompaniment by Grady Martin that lends the recording a
    distinctive Tex-Mex feel.</p>
      <p>"El Paso" was, at some four minutes and forty-five seconds
    in duration, far longer than most contemporary singles at the
    time. Robbins' record company was unsure if radio stations
    would play such a long song, and so released two versions of
    the song: the full-length version on one side, and an edited
    version on the other which was nearer to the three-minute mark.
    The full-length version was overwhelmingly preferred.</p>
      <p>The song is a first-person narrative told by a cowboy who is
    in El Paso, Texas, in the days of the Wild West. He falls in
    love with Feleena, at 
    <i>Rosa's Cantina dancing. When another man makes advances on
    "wicked Feleena", the narrator guns down the challenger, then
    flees El Paso for fear of being hanged for murder or killed in
    revenge by his victim's friends. He hides out in the "badlands
    of New Mexico".</i>
      </p>
      <p>The narrator switches from the past tense to the present
    tense for the remainder of the song, describing the yearning
    that drives him to return to El Paso in the face of almost
    certain death: "It's been so long since I've seen the young
    maiden / My love is stronger than my fear of death". Upon
    entering the town, he is attacked and fatally wounded by a
    posse, but the cowboy is found by Feleena, and he dies in her
    arms.</p>
      <p>In the late 1980s "El Paso" became known as the Official
    Fight song of the University of Texas at El Paso Miners.</p>
      <p>"El Paso" was covered by the Grateful Dead. They started
    performing the song in 1969. When performed, it was sung by
    rhythm guitarist Bob Weir with Jerry Garcia contributing
    harmony vocals on the chorus. The last time they performed the
    song as The Grateful Dead was on July 5, 1995, 4 days prior to
    their final show. On the album 
    <i>Ladies and Gentlemen... The Grateful Dead</i>Bob Weir
    introduces the song as the Dead's "most requested number." In
    all, they performed it 386 times.</p>
      <p>El Paso has become extremely popular in the American West
    with many crediting Robbins with capturing the spirit of the
    West.</p>
      <p>Plotting the hints from Marty Robbins’ “El Paso” trilogy of
    songs, one can determine approximately where to find Rosa’s
    Cantina. At a juncture near where Texas, Chihuahua, and New
    Mexico converge, at the bottom of a hill, with a back door from
    which the narrator can run, there is an actual neighborhood bar
    called Rosa’s Cantina. Its address is 3454 Doniphan, El
    Paso,TX, and its ambience lends itself to the lyrics of the
    three songs.</p>
      <p>In 1962, Robbins released the album 
    <i>More Gunfighter Ballads and Trail Songs</i>. This included
    "San Angelo", similar to "El Paso" in both story and
    arrangement, and five-and-a-half minutes long. The narrator is
    an outlaw who crosses the border from "Old Mexico" to San
    Angelo, Texas for a rendezvous with his Mexican sweetheart
    Secora. It turns out to be a trap: Secora runs to warn him, but
    is shot dead. The outlaw shoots her killer, but is shot by
    other ambushers, kissing Secora's dead lips at the last. The
    story of the song was loosely adapted into a 1964 movie called 
    <i>Ballad of a Gunfighter</i>, starring Robbins as the outlaw
    (also named "Marty Robbins") and Joyce Redd as Secora.
    "Robbins" is a Robin Hood figure, who falls out with a comrade
    also in love with Secora. The soundtrack features no music or
    performance by Robbins; it does include a version of "The
    Ballad of Hopalong Cassidy" performed by Johnny Rivers.</p>
      <p>In 1966, Robbins recorded "Feleena (From El Paso)", telling
    the life story of Feleena, the "Mexican girl" from "El Paso",
    in a third-person narrative. This track was over eight minutes
    long. Robbins wrote most of it in Phoenix, Arizona, but went to
    El Paso seeking inspiration for the conclusion.</p>
      <p>Born in a desert shack in New Mexico, Feleena runs away from
    home at 17, living off her charms for a year in Santa Fe,
    before moving to the brighter lights of El Paso to become a
    paid dancer. After another year, the narrator of "El Paso"
    arrives, the first man she did not have contempt for. He spends
    six weeks romancing her, before shooting the other man with
    whom she was flirting through "insane jealousy." Her lover's
    return to El Paso comes only a day after his flight;
    immediately after his dying kiss, Feleena shoots herself with
    his gun. Their ghosts are heard to this day in the wind blowing
    around El Paso: "It's only the young cowboy showing Feleena the
    town".</p>
      <p>In 1976 Robbins released another reworking, "El Paso City",
    in which the narrator is on an airplane over El Paso and
    remembers a song he had heard "long ago", proceeding to
    summarize the original "El Paso" story. "I don't recall who
    sang the song", he sings, but he feels a supernatural
    connection to the story: "could it be that I could be the
    cowboy in this mystery", he asks, suggesting a past life. This
    song was a country number one. The arrangement includes riffs
    and themes from the previous two El Paso songs. Robbins wrote
    it while flying over El Paso, in - he reported - the same
    amount of time it takes to sing, four minutes and fourteen
    seconds. It was only the second time that ever happened to him;
    the first time was when he composed the original El Paso as
    fast as he could write it down.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
