<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Heard_It_Through_the_Grapevine 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Heard_It_Through_the_Grapevine</songId>
   <title>I Heard It Through the Grapevine</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marvin_Gaye</artistId>
      <artistName>Marvin Gaye</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1969-01-04</week>
      <week>1969-01-11</week>
      <week>1969-01-18</week>
      <week>1969-01-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/66/Marvin-Gaye-Grapevine.jpg/200px-Marvin-Gaye-Grapevine.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Marvin-Gaye+I-Heard-It-Through-the-Grapevine.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>In the Groove</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 30, 1968</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>April 10, 1967 , Hitsville USA (Studio A) , ( Detroit, Michigan )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Psychedelic Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:16</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Tamla , T 54176</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Norman Whitfield</writer>
      <writer>Barrett Strong</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Norman Whitfield</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Heard It Through the Grapevine" is a landmark song in the
    history of Motown Records. Written by Norman Whitfield and
    Barrett Strong in 1966, the single was first recorded by Smokey
    Robinson &amp; the Miracles. Released on September 25, 1967 as
    Soul 35039 by Gladys Knight &amp; the Pips, who recorded the
    third version of the song, it has since become a signature
    song, however, for singer Marvin Gaye, who recorded the second
    version of the song prior to the Pips' version but released the
    song after theirs on October 30, 1968 as Tamla 54176. Creedence
    Clearwater Revival released their popular version of the song
    in 1970. It was referenced in Talkin' 'Bout Your
    Generation.</p>
      <p>Gaye's version has since become a landmark in pop music. In
    2004, it ranked #80 on Rolling Stone's list of The 500 Greatest
    Songs of All Time. On the commemorative 50th Anniversary of the
    
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 issue of magazine in June 2008, Gaye's
    version was ranked as the 65th biggest song on the chart. It
    was also inducted to the Grammy Hall of Fame for "historical,
    artistic and significant" value.</p>
      <p>In 1966, Barrett Strong, a former recording artist for
    Motown Records and the singer behind the label's breakthrough
    hit, "Money (That's What I Want)", had begun to work in the
    songwriting staff after failing to produce a follow-up hit.
    Motown CEO Berry Gordy hired Strong to work with Norman
    Whitfield to work on recordings for The Temptations following
    the success of Whitfield's recording of the group's "Ain't Too
    Proud to Beg". Strong originally composed "I Heard It Through
    the Grapevine" due to his own personal relationship. Whitfield
    began collaborating with Strong on the song and eventually
    decided to record it with The Miracles, who recorded the song
    on August 6, 1966. Due to Gordy's strong veto power during
    Motown's annual Friday meetings at Hitsville USA's Quality
    Control Department, the Miracles' version was deemed
    unreleasable. Gordy's thoughts on the song were that he thought
    the song was "horrible" and advised Whitfield and Strong to
    create a stronger single, however the duo refused to budge.
    Years later, a second version by The Miracles, with a similar
    arrangement to their first version, appeared as an album track
    on their 1968 
    <i>Special Occasion</i>LP. Their original recording was issued
    years later on a compilation album entitled 
    <i>Motown Sings Motown Treasures</i>. The Isley Brothers were
    rumored to have recorded the song, but there is no evidence
    that they ever did. Some Motown historians believe that a
    session may have been scheduled but canceled.</p>
      <p>Whitfield recruited his early collaborator Marvin Gaye to
    record the song on April 10, 1967. Later recordings of Marvin's
    version took more than a month due to Whitfield overdubbing
    Marvin's vocals with that of The Andantes' background vocals,
    and including several tracks featuring The Funk Brothers on the
    rhythm track and the Detroit Symphony Orchestra on the
    orchestral background. The session featuring Gaye led to
    arguments between the producer and singer, particularly over
    vocal registry. Whitfield struggled to convince Gaye to perform
    the song in a high rasp, a move that had worked on David Ruffin
    during the recording of The Temptations' hit, "Ain't Too Proud
    to Beg". Whitfield was later described by several Motown
    employees as "cocky" and "arrogant" but "always got what he
    wanted out of the performer". Marvin eventually agreed to
    record it in Whitfield's key and the song later led to a change
    in the singer's vocals, first reflected on the Ivy Jo
    Hunter-produced "You" and the Frank Wilson-produced "Chained".
    The mixture of Marvin's bluesy raspy vocals and The Andantes'
    sweeter harmonies, made Whitfield confident that he had a hit,
    however, Motown CEO Berry Gordy was not impressed. The label
    instead released the sweeter "Your Unchanging Love", a song
    that was included on the singer's 1966 album 
    <i>Moods of Marvin Gaye</i>. This recording was featured on the
    music video game 
    <i>Band Hero</i>.</p>
      <p>Gladys Knight &amp; the Pips was the next Motown act to
    record "Grapevine". Signed to Motown in 1966, the group had
    already scored a few hits prior to signing with the label and
    in early 1967, had a hit with their third Motown single,
    "Everybody Needs Love". After hearing Aretha Franklin's version
    of "Respect", Whitfield again rearranged the song to fit its
    style. According to David Ritz, Whitfield set to record a song
    that would "out-funk" Aretha. After Whitfield presented the
    demo tapes for "Grapevine", members Gladys Knight, Bubba
    Knight, William Guest, and Edward Patten worked for several
    weeks on their vocal arrangement. To make the song suitable for
    Gladys, the first line of the second verse (
    <i>"I know a man ain't supposed to cry/But these tears I can't
    hold inside"</i>) was altered to (
    <i>"Take a good look at these tears in my eyes/Baby, these
    tears I can't hold inside"</i>). After much talk, Gordy
    reluctantly allowed the Pips' version to be a single. Motown
    put little support behind it and the Pips relied on connections
    with DJs across the United States to get the record played. The
    Pips' version of "Grapevine" reached number one on the
    Billboard R&amp;B chart on November 25, 1967, and stayed there
    for six weeks, making it the group's second R&amp;B number one
    after 1961's "Every Beat of My Heart". It reached two on the
    Billboard Pop Singles singles chart the same month, with The
    Monkees' "Daydream Believer" holding top spot. It was Motown's
    best-selling single to that point.</p>
      <p>Despite this success, Whitfield felt Marvin Gaye's version
    was still a hit and he continued asking Gordy to release Gaye's
    "Grapevine" as a single, but Gordy didn't want to release
    Marvin's version after the Pips made a hit out of it. In
    September 1968, Whitfield managed to have Gaye's "Grapevine"
    added to Gaye's 1968 album 
    <i>In the Groove</i>. The single for 
    <i>In the Groove</i>, "You", made it to 34 on the pop charts,
    while "Grapevine" became the most-played and requested track
    from the album. After radio deejays prompted Motown to release
    it, Gordy finally relented, releasing Marvin's version as a
    single on October 30, 1968. Gaye's "I Heard It Through the
    Grapevine" eventually outsold the Pips', and until The Jackson
    5's "I'll Be There" 20 months later, was the biggest hit single
    of all time on the Motown label. It stayed at the top of the
    Billboard Pop Singles chart for seven weeks, from December 14,
    1968 to January 25, 1969. Gaye's "Grapevine" also held number
    one on the R&amp;B chart during the same seven weeks, and
    stayed at number one in the United Kingdom for three weeks
    starting on March 26, 1969. The label was pleased with the
    success, although Gaye, depressed because of issues such as the
    illness of singing partner Tammi Terrell (which would kill her
    less than a year later), was quoted as saying that his success
    "didn't seem real" and that he "didn't deserve it".</p>
      <p>Due to the song's success, 
    <i>In the Groove</i>was re-issued as 
    <i>I Heard It Through the Grapevine</i>and peaked at number two
    on the R&amp;B album chart and number sixty-three on the album
    chart, which was at the time Marvin's highest-charted solo
    studio effort to date. Because of the success of both versions
    , "I Heard It Through the Grapevine" was the first and last
    number one on the Billboard R&amp;B chart in 1968: the Pips
    version was the first week of January, the Gaye version the
    last week of December. Knight was not pleased that Gaye's
    version usurped her own. She stated that Gaye's version was
    recorded over an instrumental track Whitfield had prepared for
    a Pips song, an allegation Gaye denied. Despite initial
    disappointment, Gladys and Marvin would later patch things up
    and in 1983, the two now-former Motown label mates reunited to
    perform their versions of the single.</p>
      <p>"I Heard It Through the Grapevine" has been rendered in
    different ways, although the theme, a relationship beginning to
    break up, remains prominent in each. The narrator has no clue
    that his relationship is in a bad state, and only learns after
    gossip "through the grapevine" that his lover is cheating. Of
    the first four versions produced by Norman Whitfield, only the
    Gaye version makes pain and confusion a clear part of the
    texture: Whitfield surrounds Gaye with horror-film strings,
    voodoo drums and percussion, and an ominous Wurlitzer electric
    piano line doubled by the guitar. The Miracles' version is a
    mid-tempo number, while Gladys Knight &amp; the Pips' version
    is built around bravado and a quick-tempo gospel feel.</p>
      <p>Marvin's recording of the single gave way later on to the
    soul subgenre known as psychedelic soul, pioneered by Whitfield
    and Sly Stone the same year Marvin's version was released.
    Marvin would record in this style until after the release of 
    <i>What's Going On</i>in 1971 before settling into a funk sound
    in the 1970s. Other artists who recorded in the "psychedelic
    soul" genre included The Temptations, (Diana Ross &amp;) The
    Supremes, Stevie Wonder and The Isley Brothers after their
    Motown tenure fizzled.</p>
      <p>Following Marvin Gaye's 1968 release of the single, his
    version has been frequently covered by artists of varied
    genres. In 1969, Whitfield produced a version for The
    Temptations for their hit album, 
    <i>Cloud Nine</i>though their version recalled The Pips'. In
    1971, The Undisputed Truth became the final Motown act to
    record the song in its Marvin-styled version. The song was also
    covered by The Chi-Lites on their 1969 debut album 
    <i>Give It Away</i>.</p>
      <p>Creedence Clearwater Revival recorded an eleven-minute
    version for their album, 
    <i>Cosmo's Factory</i>, released in 1970. Other versions have
    been recorded in other genres such as punk rock where the
    UK-based The Slits recorded a heavily dub version as a b-side
    of their first single recording it in the Marvin Gaye version.
    Other groups such as Tuxedomoon, The Crust Brothers and the
    disco band, P'Zzazz, featuring Mildred Vancy on vocals, also
    recorded the song.</p>
      <p>In 1981, funk musician Roger Troutman, released a cover of
    the song in an extended version off his debut solo project, 
    <i>The Many Facets of Roger</i>. Troutman's version brought the
    song back to number one on the R&amp;B chart in early 1982
    marking the third time the single reached the top spot on that
    chart. It also made the Billboard Hot 100, peaking at number
    seventy-nine. In 2010 Andrew Garcia covered the song during
    American Idol's 9th season Billboard #1 hits week.</p>
      <p>In 1986, several studio singers re-recorded the song and
    featured it in a commercial for the clay-animated singing group
    The California Raisins. Their version became their signature
    tune, mainly due to a pun on the fact that raisins originate
    from "the grapevine."</p>
      <p>Other artists to have recorded the song have included Trini
    Lopez, the Soultans and the Flying Pickets, the Doug Anthony
    All Stars, Giorgia, Marisa Monte, Kaiser Chiefs, Michael
    Chapdelaine, Paul Weller and Amy Winehouse in a duet version
    while performing on Jools Holland, The Robustos, Tina Turner,
    Elton John, Diana DeGarmo, Michael McDonald, Birds of Tokyo,
    and Fairport Convention in a live version with vocals by
    Richard Thompson.</p>
      <p>A humorous cover of the song was recorded by Paul Shanklin
    for the album, 
    <i>Bill Clinton: The Early Years</i>, based on former President
    Bill Clinton. Antonio Forcione recorded an instrumental version
    on his live album. Australian cult comedy trio the Doug Anthony
    All-Stars performed the song at many of their concerts during
    the height of their fame. Queen Latifah used the song in Gaye's
    version as a basis for her 1998 single Paper, produced by Pras
    Michel for her album Order in the Court.</p>
      <p>On the last night of the Melbourne International Comedy
    Festival each year, the song is always performed by the closing
    act at the Moosehead Award Benefit show. 'Grapevine' was the
    favorite song of Brian 'Moosehead' McCarthy, in whose memory
    the award is named. This tradition goes back over 20 years.</p>
      <p>Marvin Gaye's version has been featured in films including 
    <i>The Big Chill</i>(1983) and 
    <i>Remember the Titans</i>(2001) and was featured in the 2008
    play, 
    <i>The Big Payback</i>. In 1986, the song was featured on a UK
    commercial when Levi's used a cover for a retro-themed
    commercial titled "Launderette", directed by Roger Lyons and
    featuring Nick Kamen renewing interest in the Marvin Gaye
    version. Tamla-Motown re-released the single and the song shot
    to number eight on the UK Singles chart marking its second
    chart performance. In 2008, the Freemasons remixed the Marvin
    Gaye version for dance clubs.</p>
      <p>On September 28, 1974, John Lennon commented on WNEW-FM, a
    New York City radio station, introducing Electric Light
    Orchestra's "Showdown":</p>
      <p>soundclip[1]</p>
      <p>Queen Latifah also used the melody of the song in her 1998
    single "Paper".</p>
      <p>The Gossip have used the refrain "Heard it on the grapevine
    that no longer would I be your baby" and transposed it into
    their song "Love Long Distance" with the words "Heard it
    through the bass line Not much longer would you be my baby"
    "The Gossip".</p>
      <p>
         <i>The Soulful Moods of Marvin Gaye</i> (1961)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>That Stubborn Kinda Fellow</i> (1962)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>When I'm Alone I Cry</i> (1964)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Hello Broadway</i> (1964)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>How Sweet It Is to Be Loved by You</i> (1965)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>A Tribute to the Great Nat "King" Cole</i> (1965)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Moods of Marvin Gaye</i> (1966)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>In the Groove/I Heard It Through the
    Grapevine</i> (1968)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>M.P.G.</i> (1969)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>That's the Way Love Is</i> (1970)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>What's Going On</i> (1971)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Let's Get It On</i> (1973)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>I Want You</i> (1976)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Here, My Dear</i> (1978)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>In Our Lifetime</i> (1981)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Midnight Love</i> (1982)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Dream of a Lifetime</i> (1985)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Romantically Yours</i> (1986)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Vulnerable</i> (1997)</p>
      <p>
         <i>Together</i> (1964)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Take Two</i> (1966)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>United</i> (1967)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>You're All I Need</i> (1968)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Easy</i> (1969)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Diana &amp; Marvin</i> (1973)</p>
      <p>
         <i>Marvin Gaye Recorded Live on Stage</i> (1963)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Trouble Man</i> (1972)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Marvin Gaye Live!</i> (1974)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Live at the London Palladium</i> (1977)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Marvin Gaye at the Copa</i> (2005)</p>
      <p>"Pride and Joy"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"How Sweet It Is
    (To Be Loved by You)"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"I'll Be Doggone"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"Ain't That
    Peculiar"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"Your Precious
    Love"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"If I Could Build
    My Whole World Around You"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"Ain't Nothing
    Like the Real Thing"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"You're All I
    Need to Get By"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"
    <strong class="selflink">
I Heard It Through the Grapevine
</strong>"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"Too Busy
    Thinking About My Baby"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"Abraham, Martin
    &amp; John"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"The Onion Song"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"That's the Way
    Love Is"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"What's Going On"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"Mercy Mercy Me
    (The Ecology)"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"Inner City Blues
    (Make Me Wanna Holler)"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">"Trouble Man"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         </span>"Let's Get
    It On"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"Come Get to
    This"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"You Are
    Everything"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"Got to Give It
    Up"
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>"Sexual
    Healing"</p>
      <p>Marvin Gay, Sr.
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Alberta Gay
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Anna Gordy Gaye
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Frankie Gaye
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Janis Hunter Gaye
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Nona Gaye
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Gordon Banks</p>
      <p>Discography
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Songs
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Albums
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Songs by Marvin
    Gaye
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Albums produced
    by Marvin Gaye
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Marvin Gaye
    vocalists
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Songs in memory
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Death
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Harvey Fuqua
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>The Moonglows
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Tammi Terrell
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Leon Ware
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Marvin's Room</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
