<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bent_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bent_(song)</songId>
   <title>Bent</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matchbox_Twenty</artistId>
      <artistName>Matchbox Twenty</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2000-07-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/78/Bent_-_Matchbox_Twenty.jpg/200px-Bent_-_Matchbox_Twenty.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Matchbox-Twenty+Bent.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Mad Season</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 11, 2000</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>audio cassette</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1999</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Alternative Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:16</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Matt Serletic</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Bent" is the first single from 
    <i>Mad Season</i>, the second album by the rock band Matchbox
    Twenty. The song reached number one on the Billboard Hot 100 on
    July 22, 2000, and stayed there for one week before being
    unseated by 'N Sync's "It's Gonna Be Me".</p>
      <p>The song had an interesting reception in the UK market, as
    "bent" is a slang term synonymous with "gay": the chorus of the
    song contains the lyric 
    <i>"Can you help me? I'm bent."</i>The song also contains
    suggestive lyrics in this vein: 
    <i>"Keep breaking me in"</i>, a slang term for being sexually
    penetrated.</p>
      <p>This song has no links to homosexuality; Thomas spoke on 
    <i>Storytellers</i>that this song is about two people who are
    both messed up, but because they're together, it doesn't
    matter. This was Thomas' first attempt at a love song and he
    believes it is co-dependent of the 21st century.</p>
      <p>The video, directed by Pedro Romhanyi, seems to be a bit of
    a play on Rob Thomas' increased profile following the 1999
    mega-hit, "Smooth", since it features other members of the band
    mistreating him. It starts with him being hit by a car driven
    by Adam Gaynor. As he lies on the ground, Kyle Cook shows up
    and empties Thomas of all money in his wallet. After this, Rob
    recovers from the car hit and walks off, singing the chorus.
    After the first chorus, he bumps into Paul Doucette. Rob sings
    a few more lines to a clearly unimpressed Paul, who basically
    shoves Thomas out of his way. At this point Rob walks off
    again, singing the second chorus, and the wind seems to hit him
    stronger than it hits other people. He then heads into an alley
    where day and night intermix. He's assaulted yet again, at
    which point Brian Yale shows up apparently to help him off the
    ground. Rob refuses the hand and walks off, eventually leaving
    the alleyway and emerging back into the daylight, when the
    events seem to re-occur from the beginning of the video.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
