<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stay_(Maurice_Williams_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stay_(Maurice_Williams_song)</songId>
   <title>Stay</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Zodiacs</artistId>
      <artistName>Maurice Williams and the Zodiacs</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1960-11-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/a/a2/StayTheFourSeasonsSingle.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Maurice-Williams-and-the-Zodiacs+Stay.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Ain't That a Shame and 11 Others</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 1964</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>1:52</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Vee Jay</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Maurice Williams</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bob Crewe</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Stay" is a doo-wop song recorded by Maurice Williams and
    The Zodiacs. The song was written by Williams in 1953 when he
    was 15 years old. He had been trying to convince his date not
    to go home at 10 o'clock as she was supposed to. He lost the
    argument, but as he was to relate years later, "Like a flood,
    the words just came to me."</p>
      <p>In 1960, the song was put on a demo by Williams and his
    band, the Zodiacs, but it attracted no interest until a
    ten-year-old heard it and impressed the band members with her
    positive reaction to the tune. The band's producers took it
    along with some other demos to New York City and played them
    for all the major record producers that they could access.
    Finally, Al Silvers of Herald Records became interested, but
    insisted that the song be re-recorded as the demo's recording
    levels were too low. They also said that one line, "Let's have
    another smoke" would have to be removed in order for the song
    to be played on commercial radio. After the group recorded the
    tune again, it was released by Herald Records and was picked up
    by CKLW. It entered the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 on October 9,
    1960 and reached the number one spot on November 21, 1960. It
    was dislodged a week later by Elvis Presley's "Are You Lonesome
    Tonight?".</p>
      <p>The original recording of "Stay" remains the shortest single
    ever to reach the top of the American record charts, being only
    1 minute and 37 seconds long. By 1990, it had sold more than 8
    million copies.</p>
      <p>It received a new lease of popularity after being featured
    on the Dirty Dancing soundtrack.</p>
      <p>The song was covered by the Hollies (who took it to number
    eight in the UK Singles Chart) and by the Four Seasons in 1964,
    whose version peaked at number sixteen in the U.S. Vee Jay
    originally released the latter as the B-side of "Peanuts" in
    January, but when disc jockeys started to "turn the single
    over" to play "Stay" on the air, the record company superseded
    the single with a new one with "Stay" as the A-side and
    "Goodnight My Love" as the new B-side.</p>
      <p>The song was also covered in 1966 by the Virginia Wolves
    (Amy Records AMY966 in the USA, Stateside Records SS563 in the
    UK) augmented by a brass punch that has seen it become a staple
    tune on the UK Northern Soul scene.</p>
      <p>A version of the song with revised lyrics is the last track
    on Jackson Browne's 1977 album 
    <i>Running on Empty</i>. The song, which follows on the heels
    of Browne's "The Load-Out" begs the audience to stay for an
    encore and includes an extensive playout. It includes backing
    contributions from David Lindley (sometimes attributed
    mistakenly to Tiny Tim) and from Rosemary Butler. Browne,
    Butler, and Lindley each contribute a similar verse in turn in
    ascending vocal ranges. It was released as a single and reached
    number twenty in the U.S.</p>
      <p>Recently, a version of the song has been used to promote
    travel to and tourism in Wisconsin. In 2005, a version was used
    to advertise Kellogg's Crunchy Nut Cornflakes.</p>
      <p>A dance version of the song by the Italo Disco duo 
    <i>Marx and Spencer</i>(David Marx and Tracy Spencer) was
    released in 1983.</p>
      <p>"Stay" was the third and final single from Cyndi Lauper's
    2003 cover album 
    <i>At Last</i>.</p>
      <p>It was a promo-only single, released only in the U.S. and
    Australia. The video that accompanied it is rarely seen but is
    commercially available as a special feature on the DVD, 
    <i>Live at Last</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1980 Austrian singer Georg Danzer wrote a German text to
    the Jackson Browne medley The Load Out/Stay. It was performed
    live on the album Direkt as “Roadie Song“.</p>
      <p>The British reggae group Dreamhouse released a dancehall
    version of the song in 1998.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
