<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27d_Do_Anything_for_Love_(but_I_Won%27t_Do_That) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27d_Do_Anything_for_Love_(but_I_Won%27t_Do_That)</songId>
   <title>I'd Do Anything for Love (but I Won't Do That)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meat_Loaf</artistId>
      <artistName>Meat Loaf</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1993-11-06</week>
      <week>1993-11-13</week>
      <week>1993-11-20</week>
      <week>1993-11-27</week>
      <week>1993-12-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f4/Id_do_anything_for_love_%28single%29.jpg/200px-Id_do_anything_for_love_%28single%29.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Meat-Loaf+I-d-Do-Anything-for-Love-but-I-Won-t-Do-That.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Bat Out of Hell II: Back into Hell</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1993</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl</format>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>Cassette</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Ocean Way Recording ( LA )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>12:01 (album version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jim Steinman</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jim Steinman</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I'd Do Anything for Love (But I Won't Do That)" is a song
    composed and written by Jim Steinman, and recorded by Meat
    Loaf. The song was released in 1993 as the first single from
    the album 
    <i>Bat Out of Hell II: Back into Hell</i>.</p>
      <p>The final verse features a female vocalist who was credited
    only as "Mrs. Loud" in the album notes. She was later
    identified as Lorraine Crosby, a club performer from North East
    England. She does not, however, appear in the video, in which
    her vocals are lipsynched by Dana Patrick. Meat Loaf promoted
    the single with American vocalist Patti Russo performing the
    live female vocals. The title of the song confused some
    listeners, who did not realize that each "that" is a reference
    to the particular promise that he made earlier in the same
    verse.</p>
      <p>The song was a commercial success, reaching number one in
    twenty-eight countries. The single was certified platinum in
    the United States and became Meat Loaf's first number-one
    single on the Billboard Hot 100 chart and on the UK singles
    chart. The song earned Meat Loaf a Grammy Award for Best Rock
    Vocal Performance, Solo.</p>
      <p>The song opens with a guitar played to sound like a revving
    motorcycle, which scholar Anne Bader interprets as
    foreshadowing "the male angst to come". This is a reference to
    Todd Rundgren's contribution in the middle of "Bat Out of
    Hell". Roy Bittan's piano begins to play, along with the
    guitars. The vocals begin at the 1:50 point, which is where
    many pop songs are beginning their second chorus. Steinman
    "alternates ... [a bombastic] style with mellow moments where
    the hard-hitting piano licks are fleshed out with ethereal
    synthesizer and choral-styled backing vocals."</p>
      <p>These opening vocals are accompanied by piano and backing
    vocals. The song then becomes much louder as the band,
    predominately piano, plays the main melody for twenty seconds.
    An instrumental section follows the first verse and chorus,
    lasting over 45 seconds, follows, with piano playing the title
    melody, accompanied by guitar and wordless background vocals by
    Todd Rundgren, Rory Dodd and Kasim Sulton. The lead vocals
    recommence with another verse. The popular phrase "sex, 
    <i>drugs</i>and rock 'n' roll" was censored to become "Some
    days I just pray to the god of sex and 
    <i>drums</i>and rock and roll."</p>
      <p>At the 9:28 point, the song transforms into a duet coda,
    which scholar Ann Bader analyzes as presenting "the
    relationship from the woman's point of view. Just like
    Rapunzel, Snow White and the countless other passive victims
    who populate our culture's stories, this woman awaits her
    rescuer. In lyrics that float airily above the level of pop
    songwriting, she asks her suitor to fix everything for her."
    The structure of the verses remain, but the female now asks
    what the male would do. He answers in the affirmative for the
    first four sections.</p>
      <p>The song's tone changes for the final two sections, the girl
    guesses that he would eventually do things to upset her and
    their relationship: firstly that he'd forget all of their
    memories and feelings between them and want 
    <i>"to move on"</i>, and, secondly, would be 
    <i>"screwing around"</i>. Both times, he responds 
    <i>"But I won't do that"</i>.</p>
      <p>Each verse mentions two things that he would do for love,
    followed by one thing that he will not do. The title phrase
    repetition reasserts that he "won't do that" previously stated
    one thing. Each mention of "that" is a reference to the
    particular promise that he made earlier in the same verse. For
    example, one such line is 
    <i>"But I'll never forget the way you feel right now ..."</i>In
    addition, at the song's conclusion, the female vocalist
    predicts two other things that he will do: 
    <i>"You'll see that it's time to move on"</i>and 
    <i>"You'll be screwing around"</i>. To both of these, he
    emphatically responds, 
    <i>"I won't do that!"</i>
      </p>
      <p>Some people misunderstand the lyrics, claiming that the
    singer never identifies what "that" thing is, which he will not
    do. Steinman predicted this confusion during production. An
    early episode of the VH1 program 
    <i>Pop-up Video</i>made this claim at the end of the song's
    video: "Exactly what Meat Loaf won't do for love remains a
    mystery to this day." A reviewer writing for 
    <i>Allmusic</i>commented that "The lyrics build suspense by
    portraying a romance-consumed lover who pledges to do anything
    in the name of love except 'that,' a mysterious thing that he
    will not specify." The reviewer concludes that the mystery is
    revealed during the closing stages of the song, incorrectly
    implying that all references of "that" refer to the female
    vocalist's predictions at the end. Others assume that "that" is
    a reference to a sex act. Scholar Anne Bader interprets this as
    providing "an enlightening example of how listeners project
    their own thoughts, values, and concerns onto the meaning of
    the song with misconstrued lyrics."</p>
      <p>Although Meat Loaf believed that the lyrics were
    unambiguous, the singer recalls that Steinman predicted that
    they would cause confusion. Meat Loaf says that the question,
    "What is 'that'?" is one of the most popular questions he is
    asked. In his 1998 
    <i>VH1 Storytellers</i>special, he even explained it on stage
    using a blackboard and a pointing stick. In a 1993 promotional
    interview, Steinman states that the definition of "that" is
    fully revealed in the song in each of the several verses in
    which it is mentioned.</p>
      <p>It sort of is a little puzzle and I guess it goes by - but
    they're all great things. 'I won't stop doing beautiful things
    and I won't do bad things.' It's very noble. I'm very proud of
    that song because it's very much like out of the world of
    Excalibur. To me, it's like Sir Lancelot or something - very
    noble and chivalrous. That's my favorite song on the record -
    it's very ambitious.</p>
      <p>Steinman's songs are usually much longer than most other
    songs, and "I'd Do Anything for Love (But I Won't Do That)" is
    no exception. The song is a full twelve minutes, and Steinman
    broke down when executives advised him that he had to cut it
    down to get radio play. Manager Allen Kovac warned that any
    song over five minutes would not be played on radio, saying
    that if Steinman and the group did not make the cuts then the
    stations would. Even after they made the cuts, Steinman sent
    his own version to the stations.</p>
      <p>The single version was edited down to almost six minutes,
    where the entire motorcycle introduction is omitted. The video
    version was whittled down to seven minutes and thirty-eight
    seconds, where the motorcycle intro remains, but not in its
    entirety. In the video version and single version, the lengthy
    instrumental break is completely omitted. In the video and
    single versions, the refrain, which reads "I'd do anything for
    love, anything you've been dreaming of, but I just won't do
    that", which is sung before the instrumental bridge, was to be
    repeated three times, but was whittled down to having the one
    line repeated twice. Lorraine Crosby sings six verses in the
    complete song. In the video version, the second and third
    verses are omitted. In the single versions, the second, third,
    and fifth verses are omitted.</p>
      <p>Lorraine Crosby, a club singer from North East England,
    performed the female vocals. Crosby and her partner Stuart
    Emerson had moved to Los Angeles to work with Jim Steinman, who
    became their manager. He secured them a contract with Meat
    Loaf's recording label MCA. While visiting the company's
    recording studios on Sunset Boulevard, Crosby was asked to
    provide guide vocals for Meat Loaf, who was recording "I'd Do
    Anything for Love". Crosby recalls, "in I went and sang it
    twice and I never thought anything more of it until six months
    later when I got a phone call saying, `Would you mind if we
    used your vocals?'" Cher, Melissa Etheridge and Bonnie Tyler
    had been considered for the role. However, as Crosby had
    recorded her part as guide vocals, she did not receive any
    royalties from the song.</p>
      <p>Michael Bay directed the music video. He also directed the
    videos for "Objects in the Rear View Mirror May Appear Closer
    than They Are" and "Rock and Roll Dreams Come Through", also
    from 
    <i>Bat Out of Hell II</i>. Filming took place in Los Angeles
    County, California in July 1993; the opening chase was filmed
    at Chávez Ravine, with the interior mansion scenes filmed at
    Greystone Mansion in Beverly Hills. The cinematographer was
    Daniel Pearl, particularly known for filming 
    <i>The Texas Chain Saw Massacre</i>in 1973. Pearl says that
    this video "is one of my personal all-time favorite projects...
    I think the cinematography is pure, and it tells a story about
    the song." He would later film the remake, which was produced
    by Bay.</p>
      <p>The video is based on 
    <i>Beauty and the Beast</i>and 
    <i>The Phantom of the Opera</i>. Bob Keane did Meat Loaf's
    make-up, which took up to two hours to apply. The make-up was
    designed to be simple and scary, yet "with the ability to make
    him sympathetic." It went over budget, and was filmed in
    90 °F (32 °C) heat, across four days. According to
    one executive, it "probably had the budget of 
    <i>Four Weddings and a Funeral</i>." It is the abridged seven
    minute single version, rather than the twelve minute (11:58)
    album version.</p>
      <p>The actress in the video, Dana Patrick, is miming to
    Crosby's vocals, however, as she would to Patti Russo's in the
    1995 song "I'd Lie for You (And That's the Truth)". According
    to the captions aired on 
    <i>Pop-Up Video</i>, Patrick received several offers for record
    deals after the video aired, by executives who assumed she was
    actually singing in the video.</p>
      <p>The single cover is a cropped version of the painting 
    <i>Leavetaking</i>by fantasy illustrator Michael Whelan, who
    also painted the 
    <i>Bat Out of Hell II</i>cover.</p>
      <p>All songs written and composed by Jim Steinman. </p>
      <p>The song reached number one in the charts in 28 countries.
    It was Meat Loaf's first and only number one solo single. It
    was number one in the US five weeks. In the UK, it topped the
    singles chart, and at seven minutes and 52 seconds, "I'd Do
    Anything For Love" becoming the longest song on top there since
    The Beatles' hit "Hey Jude". This was then broken when Oasis
    released their 1997 hit "All Around The World", clocking in at
    9 minutes and 20 seconds.</p>
      <p>In the UK, this was the biggest hit of 1993, selling 761,200
    copies and staying at number one for seven weeks. As a result
    of its success, "Bat Out of Hell" was reissued in the UK, this
    time reaching the top ten (which it didn't achieve on its first
    release in 1979), meaning Meat Loaf achieved the rare feat of
    having two singles in the UK Top Ten at the same time.</p>
      <p>Critical reaction was mixed. Allmusic said that "Meat Loaf
    sells the borderline-campy lyrics with a full-throated vocal
    whose stirring sense of conviction brings out the heart hidden
    behind the clever phrases." Meat Loaf won a Grammy Award for
    Best Rock Vocal Performance, Solo for the song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
