<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sixteen_Tons 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sixteen_Tons</songId>
   <title>Sixteen Tons " Tennessee Ernie</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Memories_Are_Made_of_This</artistId>
      <artistName>"Memories Are Made of This" Dean Martin</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1956-01-07</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Sixteen Tons" is a song about the life of a coal miner,
    first recorded in 1946 by American country singer Merle Travis
    and released on his box set album 
    <i>Folk Songs of the Hills</i>the following year. A 1955
    version recorded by Tennessee Ernie Ford reached number one in
    the Billboard charts, while another version by Frankie Laine
    was released only in the United Kingdom, where it gave Ford's
    version some stiff competition.</p>
      <p>Travis claimed authorship of the song, but a competing claim
    was made by George S. Davis.</p>
      <p>The chorus of "Sixteen Tons" is:</p>
      <p>You load sixteen tons, what do you get?, Another day older
    and deeper in debt., Saint Peter, don't you call me, 'cause I
    can't go;, I owe my soul to the company store.</p>
      <p>According to Travis, the line from the chorus "another day
    older and deeper in debt" was a phrase often used by his
    father, a coal miner himself. This and the line "I owe my soul
    to the company store" is a reference to the truck system and to
    debt bondage. Under this system workers were not paid cash;
    rather they were paid with unexchangeable credit vouchers for
    goods at the company store, usually referred to as scrip. This
    made it impossible for workers to store up cash savings.
    Workers also usually lived in company-owned dormitories or
    houses, the rent for which was automatically deducted from
    their pay. In the United States the truck system and associated
    debt bondage persisted until the strikes of the newly-formed
    United Mine Workers and affiliated unions forced an end to such
    practices.</p>
      <p>However, "Sixteen Tons" is not simply sociology. While the
    choruses refer to the difficulties of life in coal camps, the
    verses depict a mythos of toughness in the face of
    adversity.</p>
      <p>A dispute exists regarding the authorship of "Sixteen Tons".
    While the song is generally attributed to Merle Travis, to whom
    it is credited on his 1947 recording, George S. Davis, a folk
    singer and songwriter who had been a coal miner in Kentucky,
    claimed when he was recorded for Folkways in 1966 to have
    written the song as "Nine-to-ten tons" in the 1930s. Davis'
    recording of his version of the song appears on the albums 
    <i>George Davis: When Kentucky Had No Union Men</i>and 
    <i>Classic Mountain Songs from Smithsonian</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1955 
    <i>Sixteen Tons</i>was recorded by Tennessee Ernie Ford as the
    b-side of his cover of the Moon Mullican standard, "You Don't
    Have to Be a Baby to Cry". It hit Billboard's Country Music
    charts in November and held the #1 position for ten weeks, then
    crossed over and held the #1 position on the pop music charts
    for eight weeks, besting the competing version by Johnny
    Desmond. In the United Kingdom, Ford's version competed with
    versions by Edmund Hockridge and Frankie Laine. Laine's version
    was not released in the United States, but sold well in the
    U.K.: it was released on October 17 and by October 28 had sold
    400,000 copies. On November 10, a million copies had been sold;
    two million were sold by December 15. Another early cover was
    the one recorded by The Platters in 1957.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by a wide variety of
    musicians:</p>
      <p>Also:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
