<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Down_Under_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Down_Under_(song)</songId>
   <title>Down Under</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Men_at_Work</artistId>
      <artistName>Men at Work</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1983-01-15</week>
      <week>1983-01-22</week>
      <week>1983-01-29</week>
      <week>1983-02-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/03/Down_Under.jpg/200px-Down_Under.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Men-at-Work+Down-Under.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Business as Usual</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1981 (AUS) , November 1982 (USA)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>October 1981</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:42</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>CBS</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Colin Hay</writer>
      <writer>Ron Strykert</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Down Under" (also known as "Land Down Under") is a pop song
    recorded by Men at Work for their debut album 
    <i>Business as Usual</i>(1981). The song went to #1 on
    American, British, and Australian charts. It was reissued in
    1982 and is the only Men at Work song that went to #1 in the
    UK. It has become a popular and patriotic song in
    Australia.</p>
      <p>The lyrics are about an Australian traveller circling the
    globe, proud of his nationality and about his interactions with
    people he meets on his travels who are interested in his home
    country. One of the verses refers to Vegemite sandwiches, among
    other things, and this particular lyric has become a well-known
    phrase.</p>
      <p>Colin Hay told Songfacts: "The chorus is really about the
    selling of Australia in many ways, the over-development of the
    country. It was a song about the loss of spirit in that
    country. It's really about the plundering of the country by
    greedy people. It is ultimately about celebrating the country,
    but not in a nationalistic way and not in a flag-waving sense.
    It's really more than that."</p>
      <p>The flute part in the song was based around the tune of
    "Kookaburra", a well-known Australian children's rhyme.
    Originally, "Down Under" was released as the B-side to
    "Keypunch Operator", a rare custom-pressed single by Men at
    Work - some of the guitar melodies from that version were
    further developed into flute parts on the later release. The
    video also features several litre-size cans of what appear to
    be Foster's Lager (although the brand is removed), a beer drunk
    mainly outside Australia while being marketed as
    Australian.</p>
      <p>The song is a perennial favourite on Australian radio and
    television, and topped the charts in the U.S. and U.K.
    simultaneously in early 1983. It was later used as a theme song
    by the crew of 
    <i>Australia II</i>in their successful bid to win the
    America's Cup in 1983. Men at Work played this song in the
    closing ceremony of the 2000 Sydney Olympics, alongside other
    Australian artists. The song was played extensively during the
    September 2009 One-Day International cricket series between
    England and Australia, which Australia took by six matches to
    one.</p>
      <p>In May 2001, Australasian Performing Rights Association
    (APRA) celebrated its 75th anniversary by naming the Best
    Australian Songs of all time, as decided by a 100 strong
    industry panel, "Down Under" was ranked as the fourth song on
    the list.</p>
      <p>In October 2006, Triple M had the Essential 2006 Countdown
    of the most popular songs of all time, voted by the listeners.
    "Down Under" was the number 3 voted/ranked song.</p>
      <p>The song was voted #96 on VH1's 100 Greatest Songs of the
    80s</p>
      <p>A variation of the song is currently used as part of Qantas'
    new advertisement.</p>
      <p>The song was also used in the video game 
    <i>Saints Row 2</i>.</p>
      <p>Professional Australian darts player Simon Whitlock uses the
    song for his entrance music</p>
      <p>Professional Australian cruiserweight boxer Danny Green used
    this song for his entrance for his fight against Roy Jones, Jr.
    on 2009-12-02.</p>
      <p>The music video was filmed in a number of places, including
    Lake Mackenzie on Fraser Island.</p>
      <p>Another version of the song was released in 1999 by the punk
    rock band Pennywise, as a bonus track on the album 
    <i>Straight Ahead</i>. While Pennywise is an American band,
    they frequently tour Australia, and often play the song at live
    shows as a tribute to their many Australian fans.</p>
      <p>British ska punk band spunge also covered the song on their
    2004 covers album 
    <i>That Should Cover It!</i>and regularly perform the song at
    live shows.</p>
      <p>A version of this song is on the 
    <i>Kangaroo Jack</i>soundtrack. The song was also used in
    advertisements for the Disney/Pixar movie 
    <i>Finding Nemo</i>, though it never appears in the film
    itself.</p>
      <p>The punk rock band Funeral Dress also had a version of the
    song on its album 
    <i>A Way of Life</i>.</p>
      <p>In the 
    <i>Scrubs</i>episode "My Hard Labor", John Dorian daydreams
    that his pregnant girlfriend gives birth to Colin Hay, who
    subsequently sings "Down Under". Also, in the episode "My
    Porcelain God", when Dr. Kelso questions J.D. and Dr. Kevin
    Casey about strange noises the patients have been hearing, J.D.
    suggests they may be hearing the song. He sings a small portion
    of the song and asserts that if that is what the patients were
    hearing, it wasn't him.</p>
      <p>Colin Hay had his version as well as an acoustic version on
    his album 
    <i>Man @ Work</i>.</p>
      <p>During the 1980s Yossi and Avi Piamenta recorded traditional
    Jewish wedding lyrics to the tune of the song. The name of this
    song is 
    <i>Asher Bara Sasson ve'Simcha</i>. It is often played at
    Orthodox Jewish weddings and celebrations. Whilst the
    composition remains unaffected none of the lyrics relate to the
    original song.</p>
      <p>In 1985 Lithuanian rock band Antis made a cover of the song,
    which became one of their most well known hits. It was called
    "Zombiai" (the Lithuanian word for zombies). This Lithuanian
    version had unique lyrics which represented ironic attitude
    towards Soviet regime (Lithuania was occupied by Soviet Union
    at the time), but some parts remains very similar.</p>
      <p>The Northern Vermont folk rock outfit, Flatlander is known
    to cover "Down Under."</p>
      <p>In 2008, Australia's national airline Qantas, rolled out an
    ad campaign as "The World's Most Experienced Airline" with a
    prominent instrumental composition of "Down Under" as the
    background music.</p>
      <p>A Finnish cover version titled "Tervetuloa Länteen, Andrej"
    (
    <i>Welcome to west, Andrej</i>) of the song was released by
    Vilperin Perikunta in 1992. The original story of the song was
    changed to tell a tale of Andrej, a Russian proletarian who
    travels to Finland to search for a job and better life in a
    welfare state. In the chorus Finland is described as "road to
    the top of heaven" and "road to freedom" for a Russian. In this
    cover version the flute parts were played with violin and a
    banjo lick was added to the background.</p>
      <p>In 2001, a performance of the song by the Red Army Choir was
    released on the CD 
    <i>Andrew Denton's Musical Challenge</i>. The song was
    performed in the manner of a Russian folk song and featured
    clapping, and accordion. The song is also featured in the 2008
    game 
    <i>Saints Row 2</i>.</p>
      <p>This song was partly sung by Peter Griffin from the
    television show 
    <i>Family Guy</i>in the episode "Long John Peter".</p>
      <p>On the television show 
    <i>Yes Dear</i>Jimmy and his friend Billy are annoyed when Greg
    sings "vegemite sandwich," believing the line to be "dynamite
    son-bitch."</p>
      <p>In 2009 the song resurfaced on the TV show 
    <i>Australia's Got Talent</i>where Jay Parrino aka 'JP the one
    man band' used a looping pedal to create a unique rendition of
    the song, which even Colin Hay himself heralded as the 'best
    version of the song he'd ever heard'.</p>
      <p>This song is played during the end credits of the Paul Hogan
    movie 
    <i>Crocodile Dundee in Los Angeles</i>. The song is also
    partially played in the documentary television series, 
    <i>The Adventure of English</i>, to help illustrate Australia's
    newfound confidence in its linguistic identity in the late 20th
    Century.</p>
      <p>This song can also be heard in the episode of "The Topaz
    Connection" in the 
    <i>Knight Rider</i>TV series from 1982, while Michel is driving
    to Las Vegas.</p>
      <p>The flute part of the song is allegedly based on the
    children's rhyme "Kookaburra." While the song Kookaburra is
    still under copyright according to Australian copyright law,
    Marion Sinclair died in 1988, and so the publishing rights are
    held by Larrikin Music. In the United States, the rights are
    administered by Music Sales Corporation in New York City.</p>
      <p>In June 2009, Larrikin Music sued Men At Work for copyright
    infringement, alleging that part of the flute riff of "Down
    Under" was copied from "Kookaburra". The counsel for the band's
    record label and publishing company (Sony BMG Music
    Entertainment and EMI Songs Australia) claimed that, based on
    the agreement under which the song was written, the copyright
    was actually held by the Girl Guides Association. On July 30,
    Justice Peter Jacobson of the Federal Court of Australia made a
    preliminary ruling that Larrikin did own copyright on the song,
    but the issue of whether or not Hay and Strykert had
    plagiarised the riff would be determined at a later date.</p>
      <p>On February 4, 2010, Justice Jacobson ruled that Larrikin's
    copyright had been infringed because "Down Under" reproduced "a
    substantial part of 
    <i>Kookaburra</i>". A decision on the percentage of royalties
    that Larrikin is entitled to receive was not made. Larrikin's
    lawyer Adam Simpson said EMI and the band may be forced to hand
    over as much as 60 per cent of their earnings from the
    international hit record. When asked how much Larrikin would be
    looking for, he replied: 
    <i>"Obviously, the more the better but it depends - anything
    from what we've claimed, which is between 40% and 60%, and what
    they've suggested which is considerably less."</i>
      </p>
      <p>Until this high-profile case, 
    <i>Kookaburra'</i>s standing as a traditional song combined
    with the lack of visible policing of the song's rights by its
    composer had led to the general public perception that the song
    was within the public domain.</p>
      <p>The revelation of 
    <i>Kookaburra'</i>s copyright status, and more-so the pursuit
    of royalties from it, has generated a negative response among
    sections of the Australian public. This has added fuel to
    claims that only the songs lyrics are copyrighted, because the
    tune is taken from a much older Welsh folk song. However, the
    reverse is considered more probable by musicologists, with
    lyrics to a much older Welsh song having been adapted to fit
    the tune of the more popular Kookaburra song, some time after
    the folk revival of the 1960s.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
