<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Who_Can_It_Be_Now%3F 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Who_Can_It_Be_Now%3F</songId>
   <title>Who Can It Be Now?</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Men_at_Work</artistId>
      <artistName>Men at Work</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1982-10-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Business as Usual</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 1982 (USA)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:23</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Colin Hay</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Peter McIan</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Who Can It Be Now?" is a song by Australian band Men at
    Work. It was the second single and first track from their 1981
    debut album, 
    <i>Business as Usual</i>. "Who Can It Be Now?" was first
    released as a single in Australia in June 1981, prior to the
    recording of the rest of the album. The track peaked at #2 on
    the Australian singles chart in August that year and went on to
    reach #1 in the USA and #45 in the UK in 1982. As one of Men at
    Work's biggest hits, it was featured on their later compilation
    albums, and a live version can be found on 
    <i>Brazil</i>.</p>
      <p>The lyrics of "Who Can It Be Now?" feature the narrative of
    a reclusive, perhaps paranoid man who hears knocking at his
    house door and wishes to be left in solitude. The presence of a
    "childhood friend" is mentioned, and the bridge lyrics give the
    impression that the narrator fears once again being taken away
    to a mental institution. Musically, the song features prominent
    saxophone lines and a mid tempo beat. Its chorus vocals, which
    make up the song title, feature a melody that is echoed through
    saxophone in a call and response fashion. The second chorus
    pushes the anxious lyrics further and becomes flush with vocal
    harmony.</p>
      <p>"Who Can It Be Now?" remains a popular symbol of New Wave
    music and has been featured on numerous 1980s compilations. The
    song appears on the game 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Party</i>and can be heard in "I Don't
    Wanna Know Why the Caged Bird Sings," an episode of 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>. David Fricke of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>commended it by noting "Ham's blowsy sax
    and the rousing chorus of voices raised in alcoholic harmony
    spark the rugged boogie of 'Who Can It Be Now?'" Allmusic's
    Stephen Thomas Erlewine called the song an "excellent single
    that merged straight-ahead pop/rock hooks with a quirky New
    Wave production and an offbeat sense of humor." Heather Phares
    reviewed the song specifically and summed up by saying "In
    keeping with current trends but just quirky enough to be
    instantly memorable, the song seems custom-built for repeated
    play; it's easy to see why it became one of 1982's biggest
    hits, as well as a definitive New Wave single."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
