<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Are_Not_Alone 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Are_Not_Alone</songId>
   <title>You Are Not Alone</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Michael Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1995-09-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/1e/You_Are_Not_Alone.jpg/200px-You_Are_Not_Alone.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Michael-Jackson+You-Are-Not-Alone.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>HIStory: Past, Present and Future, Book I</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 15, 1995</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>November 1994 , at The Chicago Recording Company, Chicago, Illinois</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:45 (Album version)</length>
      <length>4:34 (Radio edit)</length>
      <length>4:56 (Radio edit w/ intro)</length>
      <length>5:35 (Video edit)</length>
      <length>6:02 (Extended version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>R. Kelly</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Michael Jackson</producer>
      <producer>R. Kelly</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"You Are Not Alone", released in August 1995, is the second
    single from Michael Jackson's album 
    <i>HIStory</i>. The R&amp;B ballad was written by R. Kelly in
    response to difficult times in his personal life. He then
    forwarded a bare demo tape to Jackson, who liked the song and
    decided to produce it with Kelly. Jackson's interest in the
    song was also linked to recent events in his personal life.</p>
      <p>The vast majority of critical reaction to "You Are Not
    Alone" was positive, although it did not attain unanimous
    praise. The song was the recipient of Grammy and American Music
    Award nominations. The corresponding music video, which
    featured Jackson and his wife was also notable for its scenes
    of semi-nudity.</p>
      <p>Commercially, the song was a significant success. It holds a
    
    <i>Guinness World Record</i>as the first song in the 37-year
    history of the Hot 100 to debut at number one; it was later
    certified platinum by the RIAA. The song peaked highly in all
    major markets. "You Are Not Alone" was Michael Jackson's last
    number one hit song in the United States during his
    lifetime.</p>
      <p>"You Are Not Alone" is an R&amp;B ballad about love and
    isolation. The song was written by R. Kelly and produced by
    Kelly and Jackson. Kelly wrote the song after the loss of close
    people in his life. Kelly was delighted to be able to work with
    his idol, explaining "I was psyched ... I feel I could
    have done his whole album. Not being selfish. I was just that
    geeked about it. It was an experience out of this
    world ... It's amazing to know that five years ago I was
    writing songs in a basement in the ghetto and now I'm writing
    for Michael Jackson ... I'd be a fool not to say it's a
    dream come true." Jackson contacted Kelly to see if he had any
    material available. Kelly forwarded a tape recording of the
    song and Jackson then agreed to work with Kelly on the piece.
    On the tape sent to Jackson, Kelly sung "You Are Not Alone"
    mimicking Jackson's vocal style, explaining, "I think I am him.
    I become him. I want him to feel that as well." Jackson found
    the interpretation amusing. They spent the last week of
    November 1994 together in the studio working on the track.</p>
      <p>Jackson explained that he instantly liked the song, but
    listened to it twice before making his final decision. Although
    the song was written by Kelly, Jackson was adamant that the
    production should be a collaborative effort amongst the two
    musicians. The tape sent to him had no harmony or modulations,
    so Jackson added a choir in the final portion and added a sense
    of climax and structure to the final piece.</p>
      <p>James Hunter of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>noted that, "the excellent current single
    'Scream' or the first-rate R&amp;B ballad 'You Are Not Alone' –
    manage to link the incidents of Jackson's infamous recent past
    to universal concepts like injustice or isolation. When he
    bases his music in the bluntness of hip-hop, Jackson sketches
    funky scenarios denouncing greed, blanket unreliability and
    false accusation". Jon Pareles of 
    <i>The New York Times</i>said that it was the only conventional
    love song on the new material on 
    <i>HIStory</i>. He compared it to Mariah Carey's song "Hero"
    and said it "sounds like a surefire hit".</p>
      <p>In more recent years, Stephen Thomas Erlewine of Allmusic
    expressed the opinion that "You Are Not Alone" was amongst some
    the best songs Jackson ever released, calling the song
    seductive. The R&amp;B critic and journalist Nelson George
    described the song as lovely and supple. Writer and journalist
    J. Randy Taraborrelli wrote of the song in 2004, "[it] remains
    among Michael's best songs ... On listening to 'You Are
    Not Alone', one wonders how many times Michael tried to tell
    himself, during his most desperate and anguished times, that he
    
    <i>did</i>have support in his life, from a higher power, or
    even friends and family, whether he actually believed it or
    not".</p>
      <p>Fred Shuster of the 
    <i>Daily News of Los Angeles</i>described it as the best song
    on the album. Conversely, while Steve Holsey of 
    <i>Michigan Chronicle</i>gave the album a positive review, he
    described the song as the worst on the album, calling the Kelly
    penned lyrics "trite" and below the standard set by Jackson's
    own lyrical skills. "You Are Not Alone" received an American
    Music Award nomination and a Grammy nomination both for "Best
    Pop Vocal Performance".</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by Wayne Isham and begins with
    a large number of paparazzi taking photographs of Jackson. The
    plot then centers around two locations: a temple where Jackson
    appears in an affectionate semi-naked scene with his then wife
    Lisa Marie Presley and a theater where Jackson performs the
    song to an empty hall. Jackson also appears alone in other
    locations such as deserts and mountain tops. It is the first
    high profile video where Jackson's hair is cut relatively
    short. The slightly extended version that appeared on 
    <i>HIStory on Film, Volume II</i>was notable for a scene where
    Jackson appeared as a guardian angel over his wife, special
    effects were used to give Jackson white feathery wings.</p>
      <p>In one scene, Jackson originally appeared in complete
    nudity, but just before the video aired a decision was made to
    use special effects to remove or cover these aspects. Despite
    giving the song a positive review, Taraborrelli said of the
    video, "The only problem with 'You Are Not Alone' was the
    bizarre video for it, in which Michael and Lisa Marie frolic
    about semi-nude against an ethereal backdrop...The semi-nudity
    made no sense and was a bit disconcerting; one wished they
    would put their clothes back on". Afterward Presley expressed
    regret about doing the video, saying she was "sucked up in the
    moment. It was kind of cool being in a Michael Jackson video.
    Come on!".</p>
      <p>Commercially, "You Are Not Alone", remains one of Jackson's
    best selling singles. It holds the 
    <i>Guinness World Record</i>for the first song ever to debut at
    number one on the 
    <i>Billboard</i> Hot 100 chart. First week sales were
    120,000 copies, it was certified platinum by the RIAA for
    shipments of at least one million units within the US. It broke
    the record set by his previous single "Scream/Childhood", which
    was the first song in the 37 year history of 
    <i>Billboard</i>to debut at number five—where it peaked. It
    peaked at number one in the UK after a debut at number three in
    the prior week. The song also reached number one in Wallonia,
    France, New Zealand, Spain and Switzerland. With the exception
    of Italy, it became a top ten hit in every major market.</p>
      <p>In 2007, a Belgium court ruled that R. Kelly had plagiarized
    the 1993 song "If We Can Start All Over" when composing "You
    Are Not Alone". The court transferred rights of Jackson's hit
    to the twin composer brothers, Eddy and Danny Van Passel. The
    judgment is only recognized in Belgium and airplay of the hit
    has been banned in that nation.</p>
      <p>Canadian &amp; U.S.</p>
      <p>Japan single</p>
      <p>Austria single</p>
      <p>Visionary single</p>
      <p>The final twelve acts from the sixth series of TV talent
    show 
    <i>The X Factor</i>in the United Kingdom released a cover
    version of the song on November 15, 2009 in aid of Great Ormond
    Street Hospital. The finalists premiered the song live on the
    November 15 edition of the programme; the single was available
    for digital download that day and a physical release followed
    the day after. The release of the song follows a similar
    occurrence a year earlier, when the final twelve acts from the
    fifth series released a cover version of Mariah Carey's "Hero"
    in aid of Help for Heroes and raised over £1 million.</p>
      <p>The video is very similar to the video of the cover version
    of the charity single of the year before. It shows various
    contestants performing their part in front of a plain black
    background, then shows the 12 finalists together performing the
    song in front of a screen of photos. Photos and video footage
    of the finalists at the Great Ormond Street Hospital are shown
    throughout the video.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
