<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Way_You_Make_Me_Feel 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Way_You_Make_Me_Feel</songId>
   <title>The Way You Make Me Feel</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Michael Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1988-01-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/b3/The_Way_You_Make_Me_Feel.jpg/200px-The_Way_You_Make_Me_Feel.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Michael-Jackson+The-Way-You-Make-Me-Feel.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Bad</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 9, 1987</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1987</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:57 (Album version)</length>
      <length>4:26 (Single version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Michael Jackson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Michael Jackson and Quincy Jones</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Way You Make Me Feel" is a song by American songwriter
    and recording artist Michael Jackson. "The Way You Make Me
    Feel" was released by Epic Records in November 1987, as the
    third single from Jackson's seventh studio album 
    <i>Bad</i>. The song was written by Jackson and co-produced by
    Jackson and Quincy Jones. Musically, the song is credited as
    being a pop, funk and R&amp;B song. The song's lyrics pertain
    to being in love with someone. Aside from appearing on
    Jackson's 
    <i>Bad</i>album, the song has also been featured on the first
    disc of Jackson's complication album 
    <i>HIStory: Past, Present and Future, Book I</i>in 1995 and 
    <i>This Is It</i>in 2009. "The Way You Make Me Feel" has been
    covered by multiple recording artists since its release.</p>
      <p>The song received mixed reviews from contemporary critics.
    "The Way You Make Me Feel" became 
    <i>Bad</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s third consecutive
    single to peak at number one on s Hot 100 music chart.
    Internationally, the song primarily charted within the top ten
    and twenty. A music video for "The Way You Make Me Feel" was
    released in 1987. The video shows Jackson perusing a female.
    Since the music video's release it has become influential on
    other artists' material. The song has been performed on all of
    Jackson's world concert tours as a solo artist, and was planned
    to have been performed during the This Is It concerts from 2009
    to 2010. Notable live performances of the song by Jackson
    include a performance at the 1988 Grammy Awards ceremony.</p>
      <p>"The Way You Make Me Feel" was recorded by Michael Jackson
    in 1987 for his seventh studio album 
    <i>Bad</i>which was released the same year it was recorded. The
    song was released by Epic Records as the third single from the
    album in November 1987. "The Way You Make Me Feel" was written
    by Jackson and produced by Jackson and Quincy Jones. Prior to
    the recording of 
    <i>Bad</i>, Jackson had written over sixty songs for the album,
    with plans of releasing a three disc album, but after Jones
    convinced Jackson to make 
    <i>Bad</i>a one disc LP, "The Way You Make Me Feel", as well as
    ten other songs were selected for the album.</p>
      <p>"The Way You Make Me Feel" has been featured on multiple
    greatest hits and compilation albums by Jackson since the songs
    release. The song has been included on the first disc of
    Jackson's two disc complication album 
    <i>HIStory: Past, Present and Future, Book I</i>in 1995, as
    well as the 2001 Special Edition of 
    <i>Bad</i>. The song was also included on Jackson's greatest
    hits album, 
    <i>Number Ones</i>in 2001 and the 
    <i>This Is It</i>complication album in 2009.</p>
      <p>"The Way You Make Me Feel" is credited as a being a pop,
    funk and contemporary R&amp;B song. The song's composition
    consist of blues harmonies. The song's opening lyrics are "Hey,
    pretty baby with the high heels on". "The Way You Make Me
    Feel"'s lyrics pertain to being in love, as well as the feeling
    of loving someone. Throughout the song Jackson's vocal range
    spans from B3 to A5. The song is played in the key of E major.
    "The Way You Make Me Feel" has a mid-tempo of medium rock and
    has a metronome of 120 beats per minute. The song follows in
    the chord progression of B—D/B—B—B/D in the first line, when
    Jackson sings "Hee-hee! Ook Go on!" and continues on the same
    progression in the second line, when Jackson sings "Girl!
    Aaow!".</p>
      <p>"The Way You Make Me Feel" generally received positive
    reviews from contemporary music critics. Stephen Thomas
    Erlewine, a writer for Allmusic, listed "The Way You May Me
    Feel" as well as the albums title track, "I Just Can't Stop
    Loving You" and "Man In The Mirror" as being a 'track picks'
    from 
    <i>Bad</i>. Erlewine commented that out of all of 
    <i>Bad</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s songs, "only three
    can stand alongside album tracks from its predecessor" which
    were "Bad", "The Way You Make Me Feel," and "I Just Can't Stop
    Loving You". Jon Pareles, a writer for 
    <i>The New York Times</i>commented that Jackson's songs, "The
    Way You Make Me Feel" and "I Just Can't Stop Loving You", "say
    nothing more personalized than their titles".</p>
      <p>Richard Cromelin, a writer for 
    <i>The Los Angeles Times</i>, described "The Way You Make Me
    Feel" as being a "loping shuffle". David Sigerson, a writer for
    
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>commented that "The Way You Make Me Feel"
    was "nearly as good" as being the third best song on 
    <i>Bad</i>. Greg Quill, a writer for the 
    <i>Toronto Star</i>, commented that "The Way You Make Me Feel"
    was to a "lesser extent in the love songs" because the song
    dealt "more with surrender than conquest or
    self-gratification." Rickard Harrington, a writer for 
    <i>The Washington Post</i>, commented that on songs like "The
    Way You Make Me Feel," Jackson "sings the way he dances".</p>
      <p>"The Way You Make Me Feel" generally charted within the top
    ten and top twenty positions on worldwide music charts. The
    song charted within the top ten, peaking at number seven, on
    the Hot 100 on the charts issue date of December 26, 1987.
    After charting within the top ten for five weeks, the song
    peaked at number one on the Hot 100 on January 23, 1988. The
    Way You Make Me Feel" became the album's third consecutive
    single to peak at number one on the Hot 100. "The Way You Make
    Me Feel" also charted on 
    <i>Billboard</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s Adult Contemporary
    Charts, peaking at number nine, and on the Hot Dance Music/Maxi
    Single Sales Chart at the peak of number three. The song also
    charted at number one on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot R&amp;B/Hip Hop Singles Charts and Dance
    Music/Hot Club Play Singles Chart. The song entered the United
    kingdom music carts at number sixteen on December 5, 1987. The
    following week the song moved up thirteen spaces to number
    three, which was the song's peak position. The song stayed at
    its peak position for two consecutive weeks, and remained on
    the country's chart for ten weeks, before falling out of the
    top 100 positions, only to re-enter the charts two weeks
    later.</p>
      <p>The song peaked at number two on New Zealand music charts on
    January 17, 1988, and remained on the chart for a total of
    eleven weeks in 1987 and 1988. In the Netherlands, the song
    debuted on the chart at number twenty on November 28, 1987. Two
    weeks later the song charted at its peak position, at number
    six. "The Way You Make Me Feel" debuted at number fourteen on
    Switzerland charts on December 13, 1987; the following week,
    the song charted at its peak position at number eight. The song
    charted within the top thirty positions for ten consecutive
    weeks from 1987 to 1988. The song debuted on French music
    charts on December 26, 1987 at number 47, and eventually peaked
    within the top thirty positions at number 29. The song charted
    within the top 50 positions for ten consecutive weeks on the
    country's chart.</p>
      <p>"The Way You Make Me Feel" re-entered music charts worldwide
    after Jackson's music was re-issued for the 
    <i>Visionary</i>album. The song debuted on the Spanish Singles
    Chart at number one on April 9, 2006. The song remained on the
    country's chart for ten weeks. In Italy, the song debuted
    within the top ten, peaking at number seven, on April 6, 2006;
    after two weeks, the song charted out of the top 100 positions.
    "The Way You Make Me Feel" re-entered Dutch charts on April 1,
    2006 at number 24. The song re-entered French music charts on
    April 1, 2006 at number 59; the song remained within the top
    100 positions for two consecutive weeks. Following Jackson's
    death, his music experienced a surge in popularity. The song
    re-entered Dutch charts for the third time on July 4, 2009, at
    its peak position at number 40; the song remained on the chart
    for four consecutive weeks in 2009. The song charted within the
    top ten, peaking at number six, on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Digital Songs on July 11, due to digital
    download sales. The song debuted on Swedish charts at number
    thirty on July 3, and peaked at number twenty four the
    following week. On July 4, the song re-entered the United
    Kingdom charts at number 47, and peaked at number 34 the
    following week.</p>
      <p>The music video for "The Way You Make Me Feel" was directed
    by Joe Pytka. The video, with a length of almost seven minutes
    long, begins with a female walking down streets alone, with a
    clip being intercut that shows a male (Jackson) talking with
    other people. Shortly after the male walks out of an alley and
    stands in front of the female while she's walking down the
    street, although she ignores him and keeps walking. He gets her
    attention by shouting, and then begins singing "The Way You
    Make Me Feel" to her while also dancing. Uninterested, she
    walks away. He follows her, having been cheered on by his
    friends to pursue her. Another dance routine begins, involving
    the males friends, which leads to the male pursing the female
    throughout the neighborhood. The video ends with the male
    eventually winning the female over, and embraces her while a
    fire hydrant is spraying out water. The music video was
    released in late 1987. The music video received one nomination
    at the 1988 MTV Video Music Awards Ceremony. The video,
    alongside Jackson's '"Bad" video, was nominated for Best
    Choreography, but lost to Jackson's younger sister Janet's
    video "Pleasure Principle".</p>
      <p>"The Way You Make Me Feel" was performed by Jackson on all
    three of his world concert series tours as a solo artist as
    well as during award shows. For a majority of the songs
    performances, Jackson would wear a blue dress shirt with a
    white t shirt and black pants with a white belt. The song was
    first performed in concert by Jackson during the encore of the
    second leg of his Bad World Tour from 1987 to 1989. Notable
    live performance of the song include Jackson's performing "The
    Way You Make Me Feel" at the 1988 Grammy Awards Ceremony.
    During the Grammy performance Jackson performed the song, in
    his signature outfit and his signature black fedora, while
    doing a dance routine with four other dancers, and performed
    the song along with another of his songs, "Man In The Mirror".
    Jackson's performance received a standing ovation from the
    audience.</p>
      <p>"The Way You Make Me Feel" was also performed during the
    first leg of Jackson's Dangerous World Tour from June 1992 to
    November 1993. The Dangerous tour was suppose to be longer, but
    was canceled due to Jackson's health concerns and stress from
    the child sexual abuse accusations made against him. The next,
    and what would be the last concert performance of the song, was
    during Jackson's world concert series tour, HIStory. The song
    was performed during selected concerts from September 1996 to
    June 1997. The last performance of the song was at the Michael
    Jackson: 30th Anniversary Special in 2001 at Madison Square
    Garden on September 7 and September 10, 2001. The video footage
    from the performance (which included Britney Spears) was
    featured on CBS in November 2001, as a two-hour television
    special. Since March 2009, Jackson was preparing to perform
    "The Way You Make me Feel'" during his This Is It concert
    series from 2009 to 2010. Following Jackson's death in June of
    the same year, video footage of Jackson rehearsing the song was
    featured in the 2009 concert documentary film, 
    <i>Michael Jackson's This Is It</i>. The video rehearsal
    footage was also featured on the films DVD in January 2010.</p>
      <p>"The Way You Make Me Feel" has been covered by multiple
    artists since its release, and the song's music video has been
    influential on other artists' material as well. In 2003, the
    music group Shakaya covered "The Way You Make Me Feel" and
    released their version as a non-album single. The song only
    charted on Australian charts, peaking at number 21 on the
    country's music charts. After Jackson's death in June 2009,
    John Legend and a visibly emotional Stevie Wonder did a cover
    of the song as a tribute to Jackson at the Rock and Roll Hall
    of Fame 25th Anniversary Concert held at Madison Square Garden
    for a HBO television special in December 2009.</p>
      <p>In December 2009, Stacey Solomon, a contestant on the 
    <i>X Factor</i>in the United Kingdom, performed a cover of the
    song during the show's semi-finals, which was received by mixed
    opinions by the show's judges. In January 2010, The Jonas
    Brothers band member Nick Jonas performed a cover of "The Way
    You Make Me Feel" during a concert at the Warner Theatre in
    promotion for his 
    <i>Nick Jonas and the Administration</i>album. Dave McKenna, a
    writer for 
    <i>The Washington Post</i>, commented on Jonas' performance of
    the song that "whatever spots of trouble his ambition got him
    into" citing Jonas' "falsetto faltered" cover of "The Way You
    Make Me Feel", as well as another song, were able to be
    "carried through" by Jonas' band members.</p>
      <p>In February 2010, Whitney Houston performed "The Way You
    Make Me Feel", along with Jackson's 
    <i>Thriller</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s "Wanna Be Startin'
    Somethin'", during her I Look to You Tour. Pop singer Justin
    Bieber and rapper Ludacris stated that the music video for "The
    Way You Make Me Feel" was very influential of the music video
    for their 2010 single "Baby". Bieber, a fan of Jackson,
    commented that the video, similar to "The Way You Make Me
    Feel"s video, "will capture the song's message of trying to woo
    back a girl." Ludacris said that the video "is like a 2010
    version of Michael Jackson's "The Way You Make Me Feel".
    Despite the plot of "Baby"
    <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s music video being
    similar to "The Way You Make Me Feel", the video is nearly
    three times shorter than Jackson's video.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
