<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_or_White_(Michael_Jackson_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_or_White_(Michael_Jackson_song)</songId>
   <title>Black or White</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Michael Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1991-12-07</week>
      <week>1991-12-14</week>
      <week>1991-12-21</week>
      <week>1991-12-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/74/MJ_-_Black_or_White.jpg/200px-MJ_-_Black_or_White.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Michael-Jackson+Black-or-White.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Dangerous</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 11, 1991</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1990</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:22 (single version)</length>
      <length>4:15 (album version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Michael Jackson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Michael Jackson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Black or White" is the lead single from Michael Jackson's 
    <i>Dangerous</i>album. It was released on October 11, 1991 as
    the album's lead single. "Black or White" is a mix of rock, and
    dance-pop. It was written, composed, and arranged by Jackson
    with the rap lyrics by Bill Bottrell, the song promotes racial
    harmony. The song's introduction and main riff are performed by
    Bill Bottrell.</p>
      <p>The song peaked at number one on the US Billboard Hot 100,
    the UK Singles Chart and in 20 other countries. It shot #1 on
    every singles chart in 1991.</p>
      <p>To prepare the audience for the special occasion of the
    televised premiere of the "Black or White" video, Epic records
    released the song (without the accompanying images) to radio
    stations just two days in advance. In a period of twenty-four
    hours, "Black or White", described by the record company as "a
    rock 'n' roll dance song about racial harmony", had been added
    to the playlists of 96 percent of 237 of the United States of
    America's top forty radio stations the first day of
    release.</p>
      <p>"Black or White" was the first single off of 
    <i>Dangerous</i>, produced by Michael Jackson and Bill
    Bottrell, it began to be promoted on radio stations the first
    week of November 1991 in New York and Los Angeles. "Black or
    White" was officially released one week later. It was written
    and composed by Jackson with rap lyrics by Bill Bottrell, the
    song's introduction and main riff were played by Guns N' Roses
    guitarist Slash and Bill Bottrell.</p>
      <p>"Black or White" is also described as a mix of hard rock,
    dance and rap, hard rock elements such as Slash and Bill
    Bottrell's guitars and Jackson's vocal style. These songs are
    also compared by Rolling Stone's Allan Light in his Dangerous
    review, he says about it, "Neither this slow-burn solo nor the
    Stones-derived riff on 'Black or White' offers the catharsis of
    Eddie Van Halen's blazing break on 'Beat It'".</p>
      <p>"Black or White" stormed into Billboard's Hot 100 at number
    thirty five. A week later it shot up to number three and on its
    third week, December 7 1991, it ascended to number one, making
    it the fastest chart topper since the Beatles' "Get Back" also
    won the Hot 100 in just three weeks in 1969. It achieved the
    year at number one, and remained at the top of the singles
    chart into 1992, for a total of seven weeks, making Michael
    Jackson the first artist to get number one popular hits in the
    1970s, 1980s and 1990s.</p>
      <p>The single also made an extraordinary and amazing debut in
    the UK, where it became the first single by an American to go
    into the singles chart at number one since 1960, when "It's Now
    Or Never" by Elvis Presley did in the same manner. Around the
    world, "Black or White" hit number one in the US, UK, Mexico,
    Cuba, Zimbabwe, Australia, New Zealand, Austria, Belgium,
    Denmark, Finland, France, Israel, Italy, Norway, Spain,
    Sweeden, Switzerland and the Euro Chart Hot 100, number two in
    Germany and number three in Holland. The single was certified
    platinum in the US, selling over one million copies. Actually,
    the hard rock "Black or White" is considered one of the 100
    greatest rock songs of the 1990s and the meaning behind the
    lyrics is rock solid in this song.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Black or White" was first broadcast on
    MTV, BET, VH1, and Fox (giving them their highest Nielsen
    ratings ever) on November 14, 1991. Along with Jackson, it
    featured Macaulay Culkin, Tess Harper, and George Wendt. It
    helped usher in morphing as a new technology in music videos,
    pioneered by Godley &amp; Creme's "Cry" video in 1985 (the
    sequence begins with extra, Let Mon Lee, and features
    supermodel Tyra Banks). The video was directed by John Landis,
    who previously directed 
    <i>Thriller</i>. It premiered simultaneously in 27 countries,
    with an audience of 500 million viewers, the most to ever watch
    a music video.</p>
      <p>The first few minutes of the video featured an extended
    version of the song's intro (reminiscent of an 80's synthesized
    guitar riff), in which a young kid (Macaulay Culkin) is playing
    loud music in his bedroom at night, and is yelled at by his
    enraged father (George Wendt), who demands he stop playing the
    music and go to bed. Culkin decides to forgo his father's
    request to go to sleep by setting up large speaker cabinets
    behind his father's reclining chair, donning leather gloves and
    sunglasses, and playing an extremely loud power chord on an
    electric guitar. The sound then shatters the house's windows
    and sends his father (seated in his chair) halfway around the
    world, where the actual song begins. The kid's mother (Tess
    Harper, initially thought to be Peggy Lipton) declares that his
    father will be "very upset" upon his return. The song from the
    CD does not use Culkin's nor Wendt's voice; they are replaced
    by voice actors performing a similar intro. Wendt winds up in
    Africa, and Jackson begins to sing "Black or White", surrounded
    by various cultures scene-by-scene.</p>
      <p>A young Tyra Banks, just beginning her career as a
    supermodel, is seen dancing to the song in the ending of the
    video, as well as actress Cree Summer.</p>
      <p>Jackson's niece, Brandi Jackson, daughter of Jackie Jackson
    also makes a cameo appearance in the video. Wade Robson also
    made an appearance in this music video.</p>
      <p>The video shows scenes in which Maasai tribesmen begin
    dancing like Jackson; so do, in sequence, Thais, American
    Indians, a woman from India and a set of Russians. Jackson
    walks through visual collages of fire (defiantly declaring "I
    ain't scared of no sheets; I ain't scared of nobody"),
    referring to KKK torch ceremonies before a mock rap scene
    shared with Culkin and other children. The group collectively
    states, "I'm not gonna spend my life being a color." At the end
    of the song, different people dance as they morph into one
    another (shown as "talking heads"), which is reminiscent of the
    earlier music video for the Godley &amp; Creme song "Cry". This
    technique, known as morphing, had been previously used only in
    films such as 
    <i>Willow</i>and 
    <i>Terminator 2</i>. The morphing visual effects were created
    by Pacific Data Images.</p>
      <p>Controversy was generated concerning the last four minutes
    of the original music video. Jackson walks out of the studio as
    a black panther and then morphs into himself. Then he walks
    outside to perform some of his most physically complicated
    dance techniques, in a similar way to "Billie Jean". This part
    contained sexually suggestive scenes when Jackson starts to
    grab his crotch, and then zips his pants up. In the original
    version, Jackson is seen smashing windows, destroying a car and
    causing an inn (called the "Royal Arms") to explode. Jackson
    later apologized saying that the violent and suggestive
    behavior was an interpretation of the animal instinct of a
    black panther, and MTV and other music video networks removed
    the last four minutes from subsequent broadcasts. To make the
    vandalism more palatable to viewers, racist graffiti was
    digitally added to the windows that Jackson smashes (reading
    "KKK Rules", "Nigger Go Home", "Hitler Lives" and "No More
    Wetbacks").</p>
      <p>To date, the uncut version has generally been seen in the
    United States on MTV2 only between the hours of 01:00 and
    04:00, as part of their special uncensored airing of the "Most
    Controversial Music Videos" of all time. The extended version
    is also available on Jackson's DVDs. The original version
    (without graffiti) is available on the VHS cassette 
    <i>HIStory - The Video Greatest Hits</i>, and online at
    MTVMusic.com. On Sunday, November 29, 2009, the FUSE cable
    channel aired the original version of "Black or White" (without
    graffiti) on its two-hour 
    <i>Remember His Time</i>tribute wherein most of Jackson's music
    videos were played. The DVD with the same name contains only
    the "graffiti version". The video was parodied by the sketch
    comedy TV show 
    <i>In Living Color</i>, and by the band Genesis in their video
    for "I Can't Dance" in which Phil Collins imitates Michael's
    'panther' fit in front of a stark white background. It was
    still shown in its entirety for some years in Europe. Indeed,
    it was seen on VH1 in the UK as recently as October 11, 2008,
    though most recent airings have omitted the last portion of the
    video, which also included a brief cameo by Bart and Homer
    Simpson before the "prejudice is ignorance" image. The version
    available in the iTunes Music Store contains neither the
    panther scene nor the Simpsons cameo, and is cut after the
    morphing sequence.</p>
      <p>Starting in 1992, Nocturne Video Productions began playing
    the "Panther Segment" of the video as an interlude during
    Michael's Dangerous World tour. The clip is 20 seconds shorter
    than the original with all the violence and the sexually
    suggestive scenes removed. However, the part where he re-zipped
    his pants was kept in.</p>
      <p>On March 28th, 2009, the Australian Broadcasting
    Corporation's music video program rage aired the uncensored,
    non-graffiti original version in its entirety in a 720p digital
    broadcast.</p>
      <p>The short, censored version continues to air periodically to
    this day.</p>
      <p>Black or White was remixed in 1992. In addition to the usual
    cassette and CD single, a appropriate selection of mixes of
    "Black or White" was released with five versions of the song
    re-mixed by Robert Clivilles and David Cole, better known as
    "Black or White (The Clivillés &amp; Cole (C&amp;C) Remixes)"
    or simply as "Black or White (Remixes)", they were also known
    as the C&amp;C of C&amp;C Music Factory. The single was
    released in 1992 in several European countries, charting in the
    UK, where it reached #14, and in Ireland, peaking at #11. The
    single also surprisingly peaked at #18 in Australia. Despite
    the favourable European response to this remix, it was never
    included on a Michael Jackson album or compilation, except on
    the third disc of the French version of Jackson's greatest hits
    album 'King Of Pop'.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
