<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_Am_I_Supposed_to_Live_Without_You 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_Am_I_Supposed_to_Live_Without_You</songId>
   <title>How Am I Supposed to Live Without You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Bolton</artistId>
      <artistName>Michael Bolton</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1990-01-20</week>
      <week>1990-01-27</week>
      <week>1990-02-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/5b/LauraBranigan_HowAmISupposed.jpg/200px-LauraBranigan_HowAmISupposed.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Michael-Bolton+How-Am-I-Supposed-to-Live-Without-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Branigan 2</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 22, 1983 (U.S.) January 8, 1984 (U.K.)</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Adult Contemporary</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:29</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jack White</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"How Am I Supposed to Live Without You" is a song originally
    recorded by Laura Branigan in 1983. The song was recorded later
    the same decade by its writer, Michael Bolton.</p>
      <p>The second single from Branigan's second solo album 
    <i>Branigan 2</i>spent three weeks at number one on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Adult Contemporary chart and peaked at number
    twelve on the Hot 100. Branigan's single also hit the
    number-one spot on the Adult Contemporary chart in Canada. This
    success came without benefit of a music video. Branigan
    performed the song on the syndicated music countdown show 
    <i>Solid Gold</i>in late 1983 and on the popular holiday
    special 
    <i>Dick Clark's New Year's Rockin' Eve</i>.</p>
      <p>Michael Bolton co-wrote the song, and Branigan's record was
    his first major hit as a songwriter. Bolton, whose own
    recording career would not take off until 1987, went on to
    co-write the rock ballad "I Found Someone" for Branigan's 
    <i>Hold Me</i>album in 1985, and she also recorded his song
    "It's Been Hard Enough Getting Over You" in 1993 for 
    <i>Over My Heart</i>. Though 
    <i>Branigan 2</i>went out of print in 2004, Branigan's original
    version appears on the albums 
    <i>The Best of Branigan</i>(1995), 
    <i>The Essentials: Laura Branigan</i>(2002) and 
    <i>Laura Branigan: The Platinum Collection</i>(2006).</p>
      <p>The single's B-side was a newly-written song over the music
    to the Italian song "Mama", by Giancarlo Bigazzi and Umberto
    Tozzi. Branigan's first major hit had been with "Gloria",
    another English song written to an Italian hit by the duo. She
    would go on to have hits with "Self Control", co-written by
    Bigazzi, and "Ti Amo", an English song written by Diane Warren
    over an Italian song by Bigazzi and Tozzi.</p>
      <p>Since Branigan introduced "How Am I Supposed to Live Without
    You", the ballad has been recorded by dozens of artists around
    the world, in English and Spanish, becoming something of a
    modern pop standard. Instrumental versions of the song have
    been recorded featuring variously the piano, guitar, saxophone,
    pan flute, steel drum, and music box. A salsa version appears
    on Miguel Martin's 1995 Sony International album 
    <i>Salsa with the Oldies</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1989, Bolton recorded his own version of the song and it
    became his biggest hit, reaching number one on both the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 and Adult Contemporary charts in 1990.
    This marked the second time the song had topped the U.S. AC
    chart. The song appears on his album 
    <i>Soul Provider</i>and on 
    <i>Michael Bolton: Greatest Hits (1985-1995)</i>. Other male
    singers to record ballad versions of the song include Charlie
    Roots, Wayne Denton, and Korean star Se7en.</p>
      <p>British singer Newton has recorded a dance version of the
    track. In 2004, J Costa did a dance version of "How Am I
    Supposed to Live Without You" with Mr Mig and DJ Holland doing
    successful club remixes. Other dance versions include a 2008
    version by In Bliss.</p>
      <p>A Spanish language translation of the song, "Como He de
    Vivir Sin Tu Cariño", has been recorded by numerous artists.
    Latin Pop singer Danny Rivera recorded the translation for his
    1990 album 
    <i>Canto a La Humanidad</i>. Other Spanish artists to record
    the song include Paloma San Basilio, who featured the song on
    her Sony International album 
    <i>Escorpio</i>in 2001 and Rosa López, who featured the song on
    her Gold 2008 Universal Music album 
    <i>Promesas</i>. Italian singer Filippa Giordano recorded the
    Spanish version for her album 
    <i>Prima Donna</i>in 2005.</p>
      <p>The ballad was one of several hits covered in the Finnish
    language, as "Kerro Kuinka Rakkaudesta Toipuu", by Virve Rosti
    on her Edel Records album 
    <i>Vicky Rock Vol. 1</i>.</p>
      <p>Filipina superstar Sharon Cuneta featured the song on her
    Platinum album 
    <i>When I Love</i>in 1999. Asian singer Julie Su recorded the
    song on a 1989 album covers released by Warner Music Taiwan.
    Other female artists to perform the song include American
    singer Vicki Carr, and German singers Stephanie de Kowa, who
    recorded the song with the Filmorchester Babelsberg for her
    album 
    <i>Two Faces</i>, and Joana Zimmer, on her 2008 Universal Music
    album 
    <i>Showtime</i>. The song appears on actress/singer Ingrid
    Saxon's 2004 CD of pop and Broadway standards, 
    <i>A Lot of Livin' to Do</i>. That year, Dutch jazz-pop singer
    Laura Fygi included the song on her album 
    <i>Song Book: 20 Jazz Greatest Hits</i>.</p>
      <p>Lisa Hartman performed the song in character as a rising pop
    singer on the nighttime soap opera 
    <i>Knots Landing</i>in an early 1980s episode. Characters
    played by Elizabeth Berkley and Mario Lopez duetted to the song
    on an early 1990s episode of the teen sitcom 
    <i>Saved by the Bell</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
