<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maniac_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maniac_(song)</songId>
   <title>Maniac</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Sembello</artistId>
      <artistName>Michael Sembello</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1983-09-10</week>
      <week>1983-09-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/46/Maniac_sembello.jpg/200px-Maniac_sembello.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Michael-Sembello+Maniac.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Bossa Nova HotelFlashdance soundtrack</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1983</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Synthpop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:12</length>
      <length>4:21 (album version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>EMI</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Dennis Matkosky and Michael Sembello</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Phil Ramone</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Maniac" is a synthpop song performed by Michael
    Sembello.</p>
      <p>The song was used in the 1983 film 
    <i>Flashdance</i>and was inspired by the 1980 horror film 
    <i>Maniac</i>. The film 
    <i>Maniac</i>was about a serial killer who stalks his victims
    in New York City. The song's performer and co-writer Michael
    Sembello recalls that an early version of the chorus was:</p>
      <p>At the suggestion of the record's producer Phil Ramone, the
    lyrics were rewritten to describe a girl with a passion for
    dancing. The lyrics became:</p>
      <p>"Maniac" appears during an early scene in 
    <i>Flashdance</i>and is used as the backing track of a montage
    sequence showing Alex (Jennifer Beals) training strenuously in
    her converted warehouse.</p>
      <p>The song was included in 
    <i>Flashdance</i>after Sembello's wife sent a tape to
    executives at Paramount Pictures who were looking for music to
    use in the film.</p>
      <p>Greek Power Metal band, Firewind do a cover of the song on
    their album The Premonition. The French avant-garde metal band
    Carnival in Coal also covered the song on their album French
    Cancan, and the song was also covered by the band Evergreen
    Terrace on their album Writer's Block.</p>
      <p>"Maniac" reached number one in the Billboard Hot 100 for two
    weeks in September 1983, and is one of the highest grossing
    songs ever written for a film. In addition to producing
    "Maniac", Phil Ramone produced the song that would dethrone it
    from the top spot, Billy Joel's "Tell Her About It". The
    Original Soundtrack of won the 1984 Grammy Award for Best Album
    of Original Score Written for A Motion Picture or a Television
    Special.</p>
      <p>The song was nominated for an Academy Award, but it was
    disqualified since the original version had not been written
    for the film. Michael Sembello states on the website Songfacts
    that the decision "pisses me off to this day." Another song
    from the film, "Flashdance... What a Feeling" performed by
    Irene Cara, won the Academy Award for Best Original Song in
    1984.</p>
      <p>The Simpsons episode Simpsoncalifragilisticexpiala(Annoyed
    Grunt)cious had Groundskeeper Willie perform a one-man-band
    version of the song.</p>
      <p>Scrubs episode My Way Home had The Worthless Peons perform
    an a cappella version of the song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
