<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Just_Can%27t_Stop_Loving_You 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Just_Can%27t_Stop_Loving_You</songId>
   <title>I Just Can't Stop Loving You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Michael Jackson with Siedah Garrett</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-09-19</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e6/Ijcsly.jpg/200px-Ijcsly.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Michael-Jackson-with-Siedah-Garrett+I-Just-Can-t-Stop-Loving-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Bad</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 20, 1987</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1987</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop / R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:11</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Michael Jackson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Michael Jackson and Quincy Jones</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>I Just Can't Stop Loving You is a popular ballad by singer
    Michael Jackson featuring a duet with Siedah Garrett. Written
    and composed by Jackson, it was originally intended to be a
    duet between Jackson and his woman of choice: either Barbra
    Streisand or Whitney Houston. Even Aretha Franklin and Agnetha
    Fältskog (formerly of ABBA) were offered the song, but all four
    had other obligations.</p>
      <p>However, songwriter and Quincy Jones protege Garrett, who
    wrote Jackson's song "Man in the Mirror", volunteered to sing
    with Jackson thus giving Garrett her first hit since Dennis
    Edwards' 1984 hit, "Don't Look Any Further". Garrett is quoted
    in 
    <i>The Billboard Book of Number One Hits</i>by Fred Bronson
    that she was unaware she would be singing the song - although
    she had received a tape of it - until the day of the recording
    session, when Jones told her to step up to the microphone and
    sing it with Jackson.</p>
      <p>The song became the first of five consecutive number-one Hot
    100 singles from Jackson's 
    <i>Bad</i>album. It also reached number one on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>R&amp;B and adult contemporary charts. It was
    Jackson's second number-one song on the AC chart (his first,
    coincidentally, had also been a duet: 1982's "The Girl Is Mine"
    with Paul McCartney). It was released without an accompanying
    music video.</p>
      <p>Originally, the album version featured a spoken intro by
    Jackson backed with a longer version of the opening music. This
    intro was mixed out on future releases of the album.</p>
      <p>"I Just Can't Stop Loving You" was the lead single off of
    Jackson's much-anticipated 
    <i>Bad</i>album. The single debuted on the U.S. Billboard Hot
    100 singles chart at #37, the week of August 8, 1987. The
    single was the highest debuting single of 1987, and quickly
    traveled to the top quarter of the Hot 100, advancing to #16 in
    its second week, and soaring to #1 in its seventh week on the
    tally, the week of September 19, 1987.</p>
      <p>However, due to the album title song's quick release as a
    single (it debuted on the Hot 100 at #40 in the same week that
    "I Just Can't Stop Loving You" hit number one), the duet had a
    relatively short chart run and fell out of the top 40 just five
    weeks after topping the chart, spending a total of 11 weeks in
    the top 40. Billboard ranked it as #43 on the year-end Hot 100
    chart for 1987.</p>
      <p>The track spent three weeks at number one on Billboard's
    Adult Contemporary singles chart, becoming only the second
    Michael Jackson single to top that chart and the last one to
    date (although "Man in the Mirror" would come close to topping
    the chart when it reached #2 in 1988). It also reached #1 in
    the UK Singles Chart for the week of August 11, 1987 and ranked
    #30 on the year-end UK tally.</p>
      <p>In his autobiography, , Jackson stated the song was not
    written with someone in mind, but that he had been thinking of
    someone when singing the song live.</p>
      <p>Jackson performed the song on his Bad Tour with background
    singer Sheryl Crow and on his Dangerous Tour with Siedah
    Garrett. He would have performed it on This Is It with Judith
    Hill, but the concert series was cancelled due to his sudden
    death. However, this is a featured song in the movie 
    <i>Michael Jackson's This Is It</i>. As a result of Jackson's
    death, Hill recorded and released a "sequel" to the song,
    entitled "I Will Always Be Missing You."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
