<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bad_(Michael_Jackson_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bad_(Michael_Jackson_song)</songId>
   <title>Bad</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>Michael Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-10-24</week>
      <week>1987-10-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/09/Bad.jpg/200px-Bad.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Michael-Jackson+Bad.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Bad</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 7, 1987  (1987-09-07)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>7" Single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1987</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Dance</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:07</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Michael Jackson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Michael Jackson and Quincy Jones</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Bad" is a song by American songwriter and recording artist
    Michael Jackson. "Bad" was released by Epic Records in
    September 1987, as the second single from Jackson's seventh
    studio album of the same name. The song was written by Jackson
    and produced by Jackson and Quincy Jones. Jackson stated that
    the song was influenced by a real life story he'd read about.
    Musically, the song is a pop song with a dance groove tempo
    with R&amp;B and funk musical styles. Lyrically, the song is
    about proving to people that you are tough, with Jackson asking
    "who's bad?" in a repeating lyric in the song.</p>
      <p>"Bad" was generally well received by contemporary music
    critics, with some critics noting that "Bad" helped Jackson's
    image become more edgier during the 
    <i>Bad</i>-era. The song peaked at number one on the Hot 100,
    and remained at the top position of the chart for two weeks,
    becoming Jackson's 
    <i>Bad</i>albums second number one single, and Jackson's
    seventh number one entry on the chart. Internationally, the
    song was also commercially successful, charting within the top
    ten in eleven countries as well as charting within the top five
    in the United Kingdom, France, Italy, Norwegian, Switzerland
    and Swedish charts. The song peaked at number one on the
    Netherlands and European charts.</p>
      <p>A music video for "Bad" was directed by Martin Scorsese and
    released in late 1987. In the video, Jackson and a group of
    background dancers are shown doing dance routines throughout a
    subway station. The music videos choreographer stated that the
    plot and video of the background was strongly influenced by the
    "Cool scene in 
    <i>West Side Story</i>. The music video received one nominated
    from for the Video Music Awards in 1988. The music video has
    also been influential on other artists material, such as Lady
    GaGa. The song was performed by Jackson on all of his concert
    tour as a solo artist, as well at awards shows, such as the
    1988 MTV Video Music Awards. Jackson had also planned to
    perform "Bad" during his This Is It Tour from 2009 to 2010, but
    after his death, footage of his rehearsals of the song were
    shown in the documentary 
    <i>Michael Jackson's This Is It</i>. "Bad" has been covered and
    parodied by multiple artists since it's release as well as
    becoming a frequent song used during tributes to Jackson after
    his death in June 2009.</p>
      <p>"Bad" is a song that was recorded by Michael Jackson in 1987
    for his seventh studio album of the same name. The song was
    written by Jackson and produced by Jackson and Quincy Jones.
    "Bad" was originally intended to be a duet between Jackson and
    musician Prince; although the plans were not followed-up on. In
    Jackson's 1988 autobiography 
    <i>Moonwalk</i>, Jackson discussed the concept of "Bad",
    elaborating that,</p>
      <p>In a 1988 interview with 
    <i>Ebony</i>and 
    <i>Jet</i>magazines (which was released on Hulu shortly after
    his death), Jackson said that he had gotten the idea for "Bad"
    from a true story that he had read about, stating, "This kid
    who went to school upstate [New York], in the country,
    whatever, who is from the ghetto and he tried to make something
    of his life and he would leave all his friends behind and when
    he came back, on spring break or whatever, Thanksgiving break,
    his friends became so envious, jealous of him they killed him.
    But in the film [Bad's music video] I don't die of course. So
    it was a true story that was [...] we had taken from 
    <i>Time</i>or 
    <i>Newsweek</i>magazine, and he's a black kid like me and [...]
    it's a sad story."'</p>
      <p>"Bad" is credited as being a pop song with R&amp;B and Funk
    musical styles. "Bad" is performed in an insistent pop groove.
    The song is written in the key of C Major with a time signature
    in common time. Jackson's vocal range spans from E4 to C6.
    "Bad" has a tempo of 120 beats per minute. The song has a basic
    sequence of D3-B3-F3-G3 as its cord progression. The song opens
    with Jackson singing the lyrics, "your butt is mine, gonna tell
    you right." "Bad" was viewed as a rived "Hit the Road, Jack"
    progression. Davitt Sigerson, a writer for 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine, commented on "Bad"
    <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s lyrical content
    while reviewing 
    <i>Bad</i>, "When Jackson declares that 'the whole world has to
    answer right now,' he is not boasting but making a statement of
    fact regarding his extraordinary stardom. If anything, he is
    scorning the self-coronation of lesser funk royals and inviting
    his fickle public to spurn him if it dare. Not since the 'Is it
    good, ya?' of Godfather Brown has a more rhetorical question
    been posed in funk." Lyrically, "Bad" pertains to proving to
    people that you are tough boasting, with Jackson asking "who's
    the best?" and "who's bad?" in a repeating lyric in the songs
    chorus.</p>
      <p>"Bad" was generally well-received by contemporary music
    critics. Some critics noted that "Bad" helped Jackson's image
    become more edgier during the 
    <i>Bad</i>-era. Davitt Sigerson, a writer for 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine, commented that "Bad" needs no
    "defense" and he generally praised Jackson's vocal performance
    in the song. Stephen Thomas Erlewine of Allmusic listed "Bad",
    along with two other songs from 
    <i>Bad</i>, as being track picks from the album's eleven
    tracks. In separate review of the song, Erlewine commented that
    Jackson's vocals "sounded like [he was] the love child of James
    Brown and Mavis Staples" and added that "musically speaking, in
    this case, 'Bad' is very good". He also noted that "Bad"
    <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s "authority and
    boasting helped to humanize" Jackson and "changed his image",
    remarking that it was "fun hearing him talking trash and being
    his own bigger booster". Jennifer Clay of Yahoo Music noted
    that while Jackson's new edgier image was a "little hard to
    swallow", the image worked musically on the albums songs "Bad",
    "Man in the Mirror", and "Dirty Diana".</p>
      <p>"Bad" charted within the top ten, at number eight, on the
    Hot 100 on the chart's issue date of October 10, 1987. After
    two weeks of charting within the top ten on the chart, the song
    peaked at number one on October 24, 1987. "Bad" stayed at the
    top position for two consecutive weeks. "Bad" was Jackson's 
    <i>Bad</i>album's second number one single on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100, and Jackson's seventh number one entry
    on the chart. "Bad" also charted on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot R&amp;B Singles and 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Dance Club Play at number one. "Bad" was
    commercially successful internationally, generally charting
    within the top ten, as well as reaching the top position, on
    music charts. "Bad" debuted within the top five, at number
    five, on the United Kingdom charts on the charts' issue date of
    September 26, 1987. The following week, the song charted at its
    peak position of number three, where it remained for two
    consecutive weeks. "Bad" remained within the chart's top ten
    positions for four weeks, and charted within the top 100 for a
    total of eleven weeks in 1987. "Bad" peaked at number five on
    Canadian music charts on the charts' issue date of November 7,
    1987. "Bad" peaked at number four in Sweden on October 14,
    1987. The song spent four weeks within the chart's top ten. On
    October 3, "Bad" debuted at number nine in France, and after
    six weeks of charting within the top ten, the song peaked at
    number four on November 14. "Bad" debuted on New Zealand music
    charts at number four on October 18, and the following week
    moved to its peak position of number two. "Bad" charted within
    the top fifty positions for fifteen weeks in 1987 and 1988.</p>
      <p>The song also charted at number two in Norwegian in the
    thirty-ninth week of 1987, and charted within the top ten
    positions for eight weeks in 1987. The song was less successful
    on Australian music charts, peaking within the top thirty at
    number twenty seven, respectively. "Bad" debuted within the top
    ten on Austrian charts at number ten on November 1, 1987. The
    following week the song charted out of the top ten and the next
    week returned to the top ten at number nine, which was its peak
    position. "Bad" debuted at number eighty-seven in Dutch on
    September 9, 1987. The following week, the song moved up to
    number eleven, which was seventy-three positions higher than
    its previous week. The following week, the song peaked at
    number one, and remained at the top position for two
    consecutive weeks. In 2006, Jackson's music re-entered charts
    following his music being re-issued for his 
    <i>Visionary</i>album. "Bad" entered Spanish charts for the
    first time on April 4, 2006; the song debuted at the top
    position. "Bad" remained within the top twenty positions for
    nine consecutive weeks. "Bad" debuted at its peak position at
    number five in Italy on April 6. After Jackson's death in June
    2009, his music re-entered charts again worldwide. In July,
    "Bad" peaked at number eleven in Italy, number twenty in Spain,
    number twenty-five in Sweden, number thirty-seven in Denmark
    and number forty in the United Kingdom.</p>
      <p>The full music video for "Bad" is an 18-minute short film
    written by novelist and screenwriter Richard Price and based on
    the case of Edmund Perry. The video was directed by Martin
    Scorsese. The video has many references to the 1961 film 
    <i>West Side Story</i>, especially the "Cool" sequence. Not
    only does it show a street gang dancing in an urban setting,
    but there are also some parts of the choreography that were
    influenced by it. The choreographer Jeffrey Daniel confirmed
    the influence, although they intended to do a more contemporary
    version of it. Daniel commented, "It's like a train coming
    across the screen [...] and that's the effect I was looking for
    and it worked".</p>
      <p>Daryl arrives to find his house empty (his mother is played
    by Roberta Flack, albeit in voiceover), but is greeted by his
    old friends, led by Mini Max (an emerging Wesley Snipes) and
    spends an evening with them. At first relations are friendly,
    if slightly awkward, but the situation deteriorates once the
    rest of the gang realize how much Daryl has changed, and in
    particular how uncomfortable he has become with their
    tendencies towards petty crime. In an attempt to show his
    friends he is still "bad", Daryl takes the gang to a subway
    station (The Hoyt Schermerhorn Station in Brooklyn) where he
    attempts to mug an elderly man but changes his mind at the last
    minute. Mini Max berates Daryl and tells him that he's no
    longer bad. After more abuse from Mini Max, the video jumps
    from black and white to color and Daryl, now dressed head to
    foot in black leather and joined by a crowd of dancing punks,
    sings "Bad" and dances his moves. (it is at this point that is
    the edited video generally begins when played on television).
    His insistence that Max is headed for a fall are nearly Daryl's
    undoing, but eventually his friend accepts that, and, after a
    final handshake, heads off leaving Daryl. The scene shifts back
    to black and white as Daryl, alone and back in his tracksuit,
    watches them leave.</p>
      <p>The music video received one nomination at the 1988 MTV
    Video Music Awards Ceremony. The video, alongside Jackson's
    '"The Way You Make Me Feel" video, was nominated for Best
    Choreography, but lost to Jackson's younger sister Janet's
    video "Pleasure Principle". After Jackson's death on June 2009,
    City Councilwoman Letitia James began trying to convince the
    agency to rename or co-name the station or to hang a plaque at
    the station in Jackson's honor, but her request was denied by
    the Metropolitan Transportation Authority of New York in
    September 2009. James stated that she plans to organize a
    petition drive to pressure the agency into reconsidering their
    decision. James commented, "Having Michael Jackson visit and
    moonwalk at this station was a huge deal not only for Brooklyn,
    but all of New York in the '80s [...] And renaming this station
    in his honor would put it on the map and help ensure that
    people don't forget." A source from the MTA commented that no
    subway stations in the MTA system are named or co-named after
    individuals, mostly because it could confuse riders.</p>
      <p>Jackson performed "Bad" on all three of his solo world
    concert tours. During performances of "Bad", Jackson would
    often wear military-styled clothes. "Bad" was first performed
    during both tour legs of Jackson's Bad World Tour, which lasted
    from from 1987 to 1989. The concerts had 123 concerts, which
    were attended by over four million people worldwide. Jackson,
    who received two nominations from the MTV Video Music Awards in
    1988, performed "Bad" at the award shows ceremony on September
    7, of the same year. "Bad" was also performed during 12
    concerts on Jackson's second world tour, entitled the Dangerous
    Tour, which was attended by an estimated 3.5 million
    people.</p>
      <p>Notable parody versions include "Weird Al" Yankovic, who had
    previously recorded a parody of Jackson's song "Beat It"
    (1982), recorded a parody of "Bad", entitling his version "Fat"
    in 1988 for his album 
    <i>Even Worse</i>. "Fat"s single cover and title also parodied
    the cover of Jackson's 
    <i>Bad</i>album and the music video which parodies many
    elements of the original. Jackson allowed Yankovic to use the
    same set as that of the video for his own parody of the song,
    "Badder" (from the 
    <i>Moonwalker</i>film). Pop singer Lady Gaga's music video for
    her 2009 single "LoveGame" has strong similarities to "Bad"
    <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s music video. Strong
    similarities between the two videos are that both their main
    settings are in a subway station and they have similar opening
    scenes in their videos.</p>
      <p>After Jackson's death in June 2009, "Bad" was performed
    (usually in a medley with other of Jackson's songs) as a
    tribute to Jackson. At the 2009 MTV Video Music Awards tribute
    to Jackson, dancers performed dance routines from Jackson's
    music videos while the music to the song was played in the
    background. The songs that were chosen were "Bad", "Thriller"
    (1982) and "Smooth Criminal" (1987). In January 2010, a video
    of Filipino inmates dancing to a medley of Jackson's songs,
    such as "Bad" and "They Don't Care About Us" was released. The
    dance routine was filmed so it could be an extra on the 
    <i>Michael Jackson's This Is It</i>DVD, but it was not
    completed in time to appear on the disc, but was instead
    released to promote the films DVD.</p>
      <p>Michael Jackson "Bad" music video at Youtube.com</p>
      <p>How To Play Bass To Bad</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
