<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/When_a_Man_Loves_a_Woman_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/When_a_Man_Loves_a_Woman_(song)</songId>
   <title>When a Man Loves a Woman</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Bolton</artistId>
      <artistName>Michael Bolton</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1991-11-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>When a Man Loves a Woman</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1966</released>
   <formats>
      <format>12" vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>February 17, 1966 in Sheffield, Alabama</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:51</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Percy Sledge</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Marlin Greene</producer>
      <producer>Quin Ivy</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"When a Man Loves a Woman" is a song recorded by Percy
    Sledge in 1966 at Norala Sound Studio in Sheffield, Alabama. It
    made number one on both the Billboard Hot 100 and R&amp;B
    singles charts. . It was listed 54th in the List of 
    <i>Rolling Stone magazine's</i>500 greatest songs of all time.
    The sidemen for this recording included Spooner Oldham, organ;
    Marlin Greene, guitar; Albert "Junior" Lowe, bass and Roger
    Hawkins, drums. The song is credited to Calvin Lewis and Andrew
    Wright, who played bass and keyboards with Sledge. However, the
    song was in fact written by Percy Sledge himself, but he gave
    it to Lewis and Wright.</p>
      <p>It was later covered by Michael Bolton in 1991, whose
    version also reached number one on the U.S. pop and adult
    contemporary singles charts (Bolton also received a Grammy
    Award for this song). Barbara Mandrell recorded a Country
    version of the song that same year. The song has also been
    recorded by Art Garfunkel and Luba.</p>
      <p>Sledge's version was also a top ten hit in the UK peaking at
    number four on its initial release and peaking at number two in
    1987 after it was featured in a Levi's Jeans commercial. The
    song makes use of a commonly used descending bass line chord
    progression as in Bach's "Air on a G String".</p>
      <p>Other noteworthy versions of the song, besides Michael
    Bolton's, include renditions by Joe Cerisano 1983 under the
    name of Silver Condor on Columbia Records featuring Clarence
    Clemons on saxophone, Bette Midler (US #35, 1980, from her
    movie 
    <i>The Rose</i>), Esther Phillips (US #73, 1966, in a
    reverse-gender version, "When A Woman Loves A Man"), and
    Canadian singer Luba. Also notable are versions recorded by
    country singer Kenny Rogers in 1997 on his multi-million
    selling album "Always and Forever" and a version by Spencer
    Davis Group featuring Steve Winwood on "Autumn 66". A version
    by Jerry Lee Lewis appears on his "The Hits" album. Australian
    rock singer Jimmy Barnes released a live version as a single
    from his 1988 album 
    <i>Barnestorming</i>that was a #3 hit in Australia. It was also
    recorded by Mae West on her album 
    <i>Way Out West</i>(1966). Jack Grayson took a cover to #18 on
    the Hot Country Songs charts in 1981, and in the same year the
    Headpins used the song in their debut on a live compilation
    album, Vancouver Seeds 2</p>
      <p>The song was also used at the start of the
    critically-acclaimed 1992 film 
    <i>The Crying Game</i>and During Kevin and Winnie's First Kiss
    in the Pilot episode of the TV series 
    <i>The Wonder Years</i>.</p>
      <p>Michael Lynche performed this song season 9 during the
    Billboard Top 100 week on American Idol.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
