<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man_in_the_Mirror 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man_in_the_Mirror</songId>
   <title>Man in the Mirror</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Michael Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1988-03-26</week>
      <week>1988-04-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/8d/Mjmitm.jpg/200px-Mjmitm.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Michael-Jackson+Man-in-the-Mirror.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Bad</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 9, 1988  (1988-01-09)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>7" Single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1987</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:20 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>5:03 (Single Version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Siedah Garrett</writer>
      <writer>Glen Ballard</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Michael Jackson and Quincy Jones</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Man in the Mirror" is a song by Michael Jackson. It peaked
    at number one in the United States when released as a single in
    early 1988 off his seventh solo album, 
    <i>Bad</i>. It is one of Jackson's most critically acclaimed
    songs and it was nominated for Record of the Year at the Grammy
    Awards. The song topped the Hot 100 for two weeks. It was only
    a moderate hit in the UK at the time of its release, peaking at
    number 21 and becoming the only single from 
    <i>Bad</i>not to reach the UK Top 20 on first release. However,
    in 2009, following the news of Jackson's death, the song peaked
    at number two in the official UK Singles Chart, behind
    Cascada's "Evacuate the Dancefloor," having re-entered the
    chart at 11 the previous week.</p>
      <p>The song was composed by Siedah Garrett (who can be heard
    singing in the background with Jackson) and Glen Ballard.
    Jackson added background vocals from Garrett, The Winans and
    the Andrae Crouch Choir, which gave the song its distinctive
    sound. The song is said to be one of his favorite songs.</p>
      <p>Garrett had the idea for the song when she was driving to
    the recording session for "I Just Can't Stop Loving You". On
    her way, she saw a face in the mirror of her car, and this gave
    her the idea to write a song titled "Man In The Mirror" as an
    addition to Jackson's upcoming album.</p>
      <p>Arranged with a Gospel choir, a year after David Bowie used
    the same device for "Underground", from the fantasy film 
    <i>Labyrinth</i>, other popular artists at the time who had
    tracks featuring gospel choirs include Debbie Gibson and Guns
    N' Roses. Jackson would utilize a gospel choir again several
    years later on his hit "Will You Be There". Siedah Garrett also
    sang on Jackson's "I Just Can't Stop Loving You".</p>
      <p>Jackson performed a live, extended version of the song at
    the 1988 Grammy Awards. He also performed the song as the
    ending of the concert during the Bad World Tour's second leg,
    and regularly during the Dangerous World Tour. On July 16,
    1996, Jackson also performed "Man in the Mirror" at the Royal
    Concert Brunei for the last time prior to the United We Stand
    benefit concert.</p>
      <p>There are two music videos for the song. One of the videos
    is a notable departure from Jackson's other videos mainly
    because Jackson himself does not appear in the video (aside
    from a brief clip toward the end of the video in which he can
    be seen donning a red jacket and standing in a large crowd).
    Instead, it featured a montage of footage from various major
    news events such as nuclear explosions, the John F. Kennedy and
    Robert Kennedy shootings, the Iranian hostage crisis, Live Aid,
    Farm Aid, and notable people including Martin Luther King, Lech
    Wałęsa, Mother Teresa, Desmond Tutu, John Lennon and Yoko Ono,
    Mahatma Gandhi, Anwar El Sadat, Menachem Begin, Jimmy Carter,
    Mikhail Gorbachev, Rosa Parks, Ronald Reagan, Pieter Willem
    Botha, and Adolf Hitler.. An alternate video was included at
    the beginning of his film Moonwalker featuring a live
    performance of the song during the Bad World Tour</p>
      <p>The song was quoted by Jermaine Jackson during 
    <i>Celebrity Big Brother 2007</i>, while confronting several
    housemates who had been bullying an Indian housemate, the
    Bollywood actress Shilpa Shetty. The song was played into the
    house the following morning as an alarm.</p>
      <p>The song is played in the key of G Major at a tempo of
    100bpm. The vocal range is Ab3-C6.</p>
      <p>An instrumental version was played at the end of Jackson's
    memorial service, while his coffin was being carried out. A
    spotlight shone on an empty space behind a microphone,
    signalling Michael's absence. The song is also featured as the
    final number in 
    <i>Michael Jackson's This Is It</i>.</p>
      <p>Richard Corliss, writing in Time Magazine in 2009, described
    the song as "toweringly indulgent but well-meaning", praising
    it as one of Jackson's most powerful vocal performances and
    "accessible social statements" as well as noting its "fleeting
    glimpse of autobiography."</p>
      <p>"Man In The Mirror" was the fourth consecutive number-one
    single for Jackson's 
    <i>Bad</i>in the United States. The single debuted on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 at #48 on February 6, 1988, and reached
    #1 by its eighth week on the chart, on March 26, 1988, where it
    remained for two weeks.</p>
      <p>It originally charted at #21 in the United Kingdom on 1988.
    However, following Jackson's death on June 25, 2009, "Man in
    the Mirror" re-entered the UK Singles Chart at number 11, and
    the following week the song peaked at #2, held off by Cascada.
    The chart had also contained over 12 Michael Jackson songs in
    the Top 40. This song had been at top 100 for 15 consecutive
    weeks in this chart.</p>
      <p>In Australia the song originally charted at 39. After the
    singer's death the song re-entered the chart and peaked at
    number 8, much higher than its original release.</p>
      <p>The single sleeve incorrectly lists the running time for the
    single mix and instrumental as 4:55.</p>
      <p>In 1990, an instrumental version for acoustic guitar was
    recorded by Tuck Andress.</p>
      <p>Siedah Garett recorded a more stripped down acoustic version
    of the song for her 2004 album 
    <i>Siedah</i>.</p>
      <p>The song is sampled by Brooklyn MC Papoose during the summer
    of 2006 on his "Gonna Make a Change." The song describes his
    rough upbringing and his struggles. Later the song was
    freestyled by rapper Rhymefest with Michael singing the chorus
    &amp; singing part of his second verse.</p>
      <p>The song has been performed on 
    <i>The X Factor</i>by contestant Diana Vickers in 2008, after
    which the song re-entered the UK singles charts the week after
    at 43, and by Danyl Johnson in 2009. American Idol Season 8
    winner Kris Allen sang the song during the semi-finals. With
    this performance, he advanced to the finals. It has also been
    performed on Australian Idol (season 5) by winner Natalie
    Gauci.</p>
      <p>In 2006 the song was covered by Redd Angel</p>
      <p>In 2009, following Jackson's death, rock group U2 started
    adding a portion of the song at the end of their song 'Angel of
    Harlem' during their live concerts.</p>
      <p>Following Jackson's death, The Fray performed the chorus at
    2 live concerts, during "Never Say Never" the day he died, and
    during "Look After You" exactly the month after.</p>
      <p>Whitney Houston performed the song during her concert at the
    Olimpiyskiy on the I Look to You Tour.</p>
      <p>The song was the Grand Finale at the 2009 Nobel Peace Prize
    Concert.</p>
      <p>It was also covered by Eddie Razaz on Idol 2009 (Sweden),
    and released on the Swedish Idol Compilation 2009.</p>
      <p>Singer/Song Writer Amy Studt covered this song in her 2009
    acoustic tour.</p>
      <p>On the deluxe version of James Morrison's second album Songs
    for You, Truths For Me there is a version of this song</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
