<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Stop_%27Til_You_Get_Enough 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Stop_%27Til_You_Get_Enough</songId>
   <title>Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Michael Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1979-10-13</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/32/DontStopTilYouGetEnoughMichaelJackson.jpg/200px-DontStopTilYouGetEnoughMichaelJackson.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Michael-Jackson+Don-t-Stop-Til-You-Get-Enough.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Off the Wall</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 28, 1979</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1979</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
      <genre>Jazz</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>6:05 (Album version)</length>
      <length>4:11 (Video edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Michael Jackson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Michael Jackson</producer>
      <producer>Quincy Jones</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" is a single by American
    recording artist Michael Jackson. Released under Epic Records
    on July 28, 1979, the song is the first single from Jackson's
    fifth studio album, entitled 
    <i>Off the Wall</i>. Written by Jackson, it is in the key of B
    major and in common time signature, the song was the first solo
    recording over which Jackson had creative control. Jackson said
    that the song's lyrics were not a reference to sex, but could
    be about whatever people wanted them to be about.</p>
      <p>"Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" was Jackson's first single
    to peak at number-one on the United States 
    <i>Billboard</i>s Hot 100 chart in seven years, and his first
    number-one song on the soul singles chart. The song charted
    within the top-ten on worldwide charts. Within a few months of
    release, the song was certified gold, and eventually certified
    platinum.</p>
      <p>"Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" was generally well-received
    by contemporary music critics. An accompanying music video for
    the song was released in October 1979. The video shows Jackson
    dancing, as well as being shown in a triplicate, in different
    color backgrounds. The song also won Jackson his first solo
    Grammy and American Music Awards. "Don't Stop 'Til You Get
    Enough" is considered to be the first song to showcase
    Jackson's talent as a solo artist, both as a singer and
    songwriter. "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" was performed by
    Jackson during four concert tours; in 1979, 1981, 1984 and
    1996-7.</p>
      <p>In 1978, Jackson starred as the Scarecrow in 
    <i>The Wiz</i>, an urbanized retelling of L. Frank Baum's 
    <i>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</i>. After the filming, Jackson,
    who was still a member of The Jackson 5, approached the film's
    musical director, Quincy Jones, to ask if he knew of any
    producers to help with Jackson's future solo endeavors. Jones
    suggested himself, and the two began work on 
    <i>Off the Wall</i>. After listening to hundreds of demos, the
    two decided upon the ones to record. These included "Workin'
    Day and Night", "Get on the Floor" and "Don't Stop 'til You Get
    Enough". The song was recorded in Los Angeles recording
    studios.</p>
      <p>Jackson claimed that when the melody of "Don't Stop 'Til You
    Get Enough" came to him, he couldn't shake it off. He found
    himself humming and singing it while walking through the
    Jacksons' Encino home. As Michael could not play, he had his
    brother Randy perform the melody on a piano in the family's
    recording studio. When Jackson's mother, a devout Jehovah's
    Witness, heard the song, she was shocked by the lyrical
    content. Katherine pointed out that the title could be
    misconstrued as pertaining to sexual activity. Jackson
    reassured her that the song was not a reference to sex, but
    could mean whatever people wanted it to. Upon playing the
    recording to Jones, it was agreed that the song would be
    featured on 
    <i>Off the Wall</i>.</p>
      <p>Musically "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" is credited as a
    disco/pop/funk song. The song's full length on 
    <i>Off The Wall</i>is just over 6 minutes. "Don't Stop 'Til You
    Get Enough" has been described as having a "libidinous tone".
    "Don't Stop 'til You Get Enough" introduced Jackson's falsetto
    voice and vocal hiccups, which would become one of Jackson's
    signature vocals. Along with Jackson's vocal hiccups, Jackson
    voice in the song was described as having vocal tics—from the
    hiccups, a "grunt", and "the 'oho!'". "Don't Stop 'Til You Get
    Enough" is played in the key of B major and in common time
    signature. In the song, Jackson's voice range is from F#4 to
    D#5. Instruments for "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" include a
    piano and guitar. The song's tempo is moderately slow and it's
    metronome is 112 beats per minute. "Don't Stop 'Til You Get
    Enough" begins with Jackson speaking, before singing the songs
    lyrics'.</p>
      <p>"Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" was well received by
    contemporary critics. Stephen Holden, of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>, described the song as "one of a handful
    of recent disco releases that works both as a dance track and
    as an aural extravaganza comparable to Earth, Wind and Fire's
    'Boogie Wonderland'". William Ruhlmann, author of 
    <i>The All-Music Guide to Rock</i>, praised "Don't Stop 'til
    You Get Enough" as an "irresistible dance track". John Lewis,
    author of 
    <i>1001 Albums You Must Hear Before You Die</i>, noted that the
    "jittery, frenetic opening track" is the centerpiece of 
    <i>Off the Wall</i>. He concluded that "Jackson's falsetto
    hollers and frisky yelps serve as an obbligato to the lead
    line, punctuating Ben Wright's thrilling string arrangement and
    Jerry Hey's tight horn charts". Jason Elias, a writer for
    Allmusic, noted that "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" presents
    a "new Michael Jackson" that was "sexual, [an] adult, and
    aggressive. Elias commented that "Like the best of Jones'
    late-'70s, early-'80s work, this [song] wasn't quite disco,
    couldn't be hardcore funk - it was an amalgam of styles with
    the all-important pop accessibility."</p>
      <p>Jackson's biographers also praised the song. J. Randy
    Taraborrelli described Jackson's unveiling of a "sexy, playful
    falsetto" that "no one had ever heard from him before". Nelson
    George stated that the argument for Jackson's greatness began
    with the arrangements of "Don't Stop 'til You Get Enough". He
    noted that the percussion and backing vocals were "artfully
    choreographed" to "create drama and ecstasy on the dance
    floor". He concluded, "It's one thing to make a dance record-it
    is another to instill that track with an epic, celebratory
    quality as Michael does here". James Montgomery, of MTV, noted
    that 
    <i>Off The Wall</i>contained a "masterful mixture of fiery
    disco tracks", specifying "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" and
    "Workin' Day and Night". "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" won
    Jackson his first American Music Award, the song received the
    award for Favorite Soul/R&amp;B Single. Jackson also won his
    first solo Grammy Award, taking home the award for Best Male
    Vocal Performance in the genre of R&amp;B.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Don’t Stop 'til You Get Enough" was
    directed and produced by Nick Saxton and made its world
    premiere in October 1979. It was Jackson's first music video as
    a solo artist. The music video features a smiling Jackson
    floating over a in front obackground of abstract, geometric
    figures, and performing dance techniques while singing "Don't
    Stop 'Til You get Enough" in a black and white tuxedo with a
    black bowtie. At one stage, Jackson is seen dancing in
    triplicate, which was considered innovative at the time.</p>
      <p>The music video begins with Jackson speaking the opening
    lyrics of "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough", he then begins
    singing the lyrics while standing in front of a purple
    background while wearing a black and white tuxedo, with a
    bow-tie. Shortly after, Jackson begins dancing while the
    background changes to orange and blue, while objects, which
    appear to be ice-cubes and bubbles, are floating behind
    Jackson. The background then briefly changes to pyramids made
    out of bricks and then changes to a reddish background with
    objects made out of glass, which shows Jackson dancing in
    triplicate. The video ends with Jackson dancing in a
    background, that continuously changes colors, with large
    marbles.</p>
      <p>"Don’t Stop 'Til You Get Enough" was released on July 28,
    1979, under Epic Records; Jackson's first solo album away from
    Motown Records. Within three months of its release, the song
    was at the top of the charts and had been certified gold.
    Reaching number-one on 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Hot 100 and Hot Soul Singles charts in the
    United States; it was Jackson's first solo number-one single
    since "Ben", seven years prior. Reaching the top of the charts
    in Australia, New Zealand, Norway and South Africa, the song
    peaked within the top-ten, charting at number-three, in the
    United Kingdom. "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough"s least
    successful charting countries was in Switzerland, placing at
    number-four. "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" charted within
    the top-ten in all major countries. Following the single being
    certified gold ten years previously, the song was awarded
    platinum certification by the Recording Industry Association of
    America in 1989.</p>
      <p>In 2006, "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" reached
    number-sevteen in the United Kingdom, following the 
    <i>Visionary</i>campaign, whereby twenty of Jackson's hit
    singles were reissued in several European countries. Following
    Jackson's death in June 2009, his music saw an increase in
    popularity. "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" peaked at
    number-seven on 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s "Hot Digital Songs Chart, peaking at number
    seven on the charts issue date July 11, 2009. "Don't Stop 'Til
    You Get Enough" charted within the top-ten, placing at
    number-nine, in France, and charted within the top-twenty in
    Portugal and Switzerland, placing at number eighteen and
    twenty. The song also charted at number-twenty-one in
    Australia, thirty-seven in the United Kingdom, and fifty in
    Swedish, respectively. "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough"s least
    successful country was Japan, peaking at number-seventy-seven.
    "Don’t Stop 'Til You Get Enough" was certified gold in
    Australia by Australian Recording Industry Association in 2009
    for the shipments of 35,000 units.</p>
      <p>"Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" was performed by Jackson
    during two of the The Jackson's concert tours. The song was
    first performed by Jackson during The Jackson's concert tour,
    entitled Destiny Tour, which lasted from January to February
    1979. The second, and would be last performance of the song,
    was during The Jackson's fourth tour, entitled the Triumph
    Tour; they only toured in the United States and the tour began
    in July 1981, and finished in September of the same year.
    Jackson did not perform the song on any of his three
    solo-artist world tours from 1987 to 1997; although he did sing
    a bit of the song during the 1987 Bad World Tour. The song was
    performed by Jackson during the Bad Tour during performances of
    extended version of "Shake Your Body". While "Don't Stop 'Til
    You Get Enough" was not frequently performed by Jackson during
    concert tours, other songs from 
    <i>Off The Wall</i>were. Jackson also performed the song in his
    HIStory World Tour along with Rock With You and Off The Wall in
    certain concerts. Jackson would have used a sample of "Don't
    Stop 'Til You Get Enough" for the "Shake Your Body" performance
    in "This Is It".</p>
      <p>"Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" has been covered by
    multiple artists since its release in 1979. The American
    pop—rock band Shivaree covered "Don't Stop 'til You Get Enough"
    on their 2007 album of cover versions, entitled, 
    <i>Tainted Love: Mating Calls and Fight Songs</i>. The song was
    covered by Rod Hanna, on his album of covers entitled, 
    <i>Rod Hanna Live: Discofesta 70's Superhits - Rod Hanna</i>,
    and the song was covered by BB Band in 1999 on their album
    entitled, 
    <i>The Detroit Sound</i>. The song was also covered by James
    Chance on his 2005 album, which included both a recorded and
    live version of "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough". "Don't Stop
    'Til You Get Enough" was covered by Melissa Forbes on her 2005
    album entitled, 
    <i>No More Mondays</i>.</p>
      <p>Following Jackson's death in June 2009, the band U2 began
    their world tour, entitled U2 360° Tour, with renditions of two
    of Jackson's songs, "Don't Stop 'Til You Get Enough" and "Man
    In The Mirror" (from Jackson's 1987 album 
    <i>Bad</i>) on June 30, 2009. After Jackson's death, in late
    June 2009, Cookin Soul did a remix cover of the song, entitled,
    "Don’t stop ‘Til You Get Enough feat. Jay-Z". The remixed
    version was performed during Cookin Souls Shade45 show, and the
    song was made available as a digital download track. Amos
    Barshad and Nick Catucci, of NYMag.com, commented that the
    remix version was a "surprisingly great meeting of music and
    lyrics, connecting MJ and rap without overstating the shared
    DNA".</p>
      <p>James Montgomery, of MTV, noted that "Don't Stop 'Til You
    Get Enough", along with 
    <i>Off The Wall</i>s other three singles, "showcased (or, more
    specifically, unleashed) Jackson's talents as a entertainer, a
    vocalist, a writer and, most importantly, as a leading man."
    After Jackson's death, AOL's Radio Blog released a list,
    entitled "10 Best Michael Jackson Songs", which placed "Don't
    Stop 'Til You Get Enough" at number-ten on the list. Jason
    Elias, a writer for Allmusic said of the song,</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
