<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rock_with_You_(Michael_Jackson_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rock_with_You_(Michael_Jackson_song)</songId>
   <title>Rock with You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Michael Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1980-01-19</week>
      <week>1980-01-26</week>
      <week>1980-02-02</week>
      <week>1980-02-09</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/ea/Rock_With_You.jpg/200px-Rock_With_You.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Michael-Jackson+Rock-with-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Off the Wall</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 3, 1979</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1979</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:39 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>3:23 (Single/Video Mix)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Rod Temperton</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Michael Jackson and Quincy Jones</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Rock with You" was released on November 3, 1979, as the
    second single from Michael Jackson's fifth solo LP and
    breakthrough album, 
    <i>Off the Wall</i>. Written by Heatwave group member and
    songwriter Rod Temperton, who also wrote Jackson's song . The
    song helped Jackson score one of the first 
    <i>Billboard</i>number-one singles in the 1980s. It reached
    number one on both the pop and R&amp;B singles chart and became
    one of Jackson's most-loved songs. A video for the song shows a
    smiling Jackson dancing in a sequined suit against a background
    laser. According to Billboard, the song was the fourth biggest
    single of 1980. It is also considered one of that last big hits
    of the disco era</p>
      <p>It was re-released as a single on February 27, 2006, as part
    of the 
    <i>Visionary: The Video Singles</i>box set.</p>
      <p>The song was later covered by singer Brandy in 1995 for
    Quincy Jones' album, 
    <i>Q's Jook Joint</i>. It was also covered by Ashanti in 2003
    as a remix to her single "Rock wit U (Awww Baby)" and performed
    at the BET Awards. The song was covered by the company
    Wavegroup for the game Karaoke Revolution Presents: American
    Idol. Brazilian singer Fernanda Abreu performed a version on
    the record Um Barzinho Um Violao 4, issued in 2005. House music
    Japanese band Cargo made a cover of the song in their 2007
    album "Jewel". Chris Brown performed it on the Essence Music
    Festival in New Orleans in 2007. Jackson performed the song on
    the Jacksons Destiny Tour on the second leg. He also performed
    the song on the Jacksons Triumph Tour, Victory Tour, Bad World
    Tour, and HIStory World Tour but only part of the Off the Wall
    Medley on certain concerts. He also would have performed it on
    This Is It, but the show was cancelled, due to his sudden
    death. Kelly Clarkson performed the song with Eric Hutchinson
    on her All I Ever Wanted tour in 2009.</p>
      <p>In 2008, Michael's sister, Janet, released "Rock with U" (a
    house / club number), from her 
    <i>Discipline</i>album. Although similar in name, the songs are
    completely different in lyrics and music.</p>
      <p>After his death, R&amp;B singer Frankie J recorded a cover
    version, which was released on his MySpace. Mariah Carey also
    performed this song along with Trey Lorenz in her concert "Live
    At The Pearl" in Vegas in September and October 2009.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
