<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben_(song)</songId>
   <title>Ben</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Michael Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1972-10-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/62/Ben_Michael_Jackson.jpg/200px-Ben_Michael_Jackson.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Michael-Jackson+Ben.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Ben</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 12, 1972</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1971</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
      <genre>Pop Rock / R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:48</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Motown</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Don Black and Walter Scharf</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>The Corporation : Freddie Perren</producer>
      <producer>Alphonzo Mizell</producer>
      <producer>Deke Richards and Berry Gordy</producer>
      <producer>Jr</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Ben" is a song written by Don Black and Walter Scharf and
    recorded by Michael Jackson for the Motown label in 1972. The
    theme song of 1972 the horror film 
    <i>Ben</i>, it is a melancholy ballad to the film's title
    character, a killer rat – a choice critics have noted as
    singularly odd. It was initially released as a single, and
    later appeared as the title track to 
    <i>Ben</i>, Jackson's second solo album. The song was Jackson's
    first number-one hit as a solo artist on the American pop
    charts, and also performed well overseas, reaching number one
    in Australia and number seven in the United Kingdom. Cover
    versions were later recorded by Marti Webb and Akon, and the
    original featured in the 2003 film 
    <i>Willard</i>, a remake of the film to which 
    <i>Ben</i>was a sequel.</p>
      <p>Originally written for Donny Osmond, "Ben" was offered to
    Jackson as Osmond was on tour at the time and unavailable for
    recording. The single, theme of a 1972 film of the same name
    (the sequel to the 1971 killer rat movie 
    <i>Willard</i>), spent one week at the top of the U.S. pop
    chart. It also reached number-one on the Australian pop chart,
    spending eight weeks at the top spot. The song also later
    reached a peak of number seven on the British pop chart..</p>
      <p>The song became the first of 13 number-one pop hits for
    Jackson in the United States and his first number-one as a solo
    artist; it was later included on Jackson's album of the same
    name.</p>
      <p>"Ben" won a Golden Globe for Best Song. It was also
    nominated for an Academy Award for Best Original Song in 1973;
    Jackson performed the song in front of a live audience at the
    ceremony.</p>
      <p>Although Jackson had already become the youngest artist to
    ever record a number-one ("I Want You Back" with The Jackson 5,
    in 1970), "Ben" made him the third-youngest solo artist, at
    fourteen, to score a number-one hit single. Only Stevie Wonder,
    who was thirteen when "Fingertips, Pt. 2" went to number one,
    and Donny Osmond, who was months shy of his fourteenth birthday
    when "Go Away Little Girl" hit number one in 1971 were
    younger.</p>
      <p>The song is one of Jacksons most re-released, having
    appeared on The Jackson 5 Anthology, The Best of Michael
    Jackson, Michael Jackson Anthology, Jackson 5: The Ultimate
    Collection, The Essential Michael Jackson, Michael Jackson: The
    Ultimate Collection, Hello World: The Motown Solo Collection,
    Number Ones and King Of Pop. A live recorded version was
    released on the 1981 album The Jacksons Live! and remixed
    versions have appeared on The Remix Suite and Michael Jackson:
    The Stripped Mixes. After Jackson's death, singer Akon released
    a remix of the song with his own background vocals and
    Jackson's original voice.</p>
      <p>In 1985, the song became a top ten hit again in the UK when
    covered by Marti Webb as a tribute to Ben Hardwick, a young
    liver transplant patient. This version reached #5 in the UK
    charts and was one of the singer's biggest hits. The co-writer
    of the song Don Black was at that time Webb's manager.</p>
      <p>The song is played in the key of F Major at a tempo of
    88bpm. The vocal range is B3-D5.</p>
      <p>Michael Jackson performed the song on The Sonny and Cher
    Comedy Hour in the early 1970s, and again in 1976 on The
    Jacksons.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
