<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dirty_Diana 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dirty_Diana</songId>
   <title>Dirty Diana</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Jackson</artistId>
      <artistName>Michael Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1988-07-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e6/Dirty_Diana.jpg/200px-Dirty_Diana.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Michael-Jackson+Dirty-Diana.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Bad</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 18, 1988  (1988-04-18)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1987</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hard Rock</genre>
      <genre>Glam Metal</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:52 (original version)</length>
      <length>4:40 (single version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Michael Jackson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Michael Jackson and Quincy Jones</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Dirty Diana" is a song by American songwriter and recording
    artist Michael Jackson that is featured on Jackson's seventh
    studio album, 
    <i>Bad</i>. The song was released by Epic Records on April 18,
    1988 as the fifth single from 
    <i>Bad</i>. The song presented a harder rock sound similar to
    that of "Beat It" from the album 
    <i>Thriller</i>. "Dirty Diana" was written by Jackson and
    produced by Jackson and Quincy Jones. The songs lyrics pertain
    to groupies, and has a moderate tempo.</p>
      <p>"Dirty Diana" was generally well received by contemporary
    music critics. The song was also a commercial success worldwide
    in 1988, charting at number one on the United States Hot 100,
    The song also charted within the top ten in multiple
    territories internationally, including the United Kingdom,
    France, Italy and New Zealand. "Dirty Diana" was the fifth and
    final number-one single on the Hot 100 from 
    <i>Bad</i>. In 2009, after Jackson's death in June, the song
    re-entered charts, mainly due to digital download sales. A
    music video for "Dirty Diana" was filmed in front of a live
    audience and was released in 1988.</p>
      <p>"Dirty Diana" was written by Jackson and produced by Jackson
    and Quincy Jones and appeared on Jackson's 1987 studio album, 
    <i>Bad</i>. The song was released as the albums fifth single.
    After "Beat It", "Dirty Diana" was the second hard rock song of
    his solo career and it is specifically a hard rock ballad with
    lyrics that are about a persistent groupie. Jackson hired Billy
    Idol's former guitarist Steve Stevens to back him on the track.
    Initial reports at the time suggested the song was inspired by
    an alleged affair between Jackson and his close friend Diana
    Ross, however this was later denied. In an interview from the
    special edition of 
    <i>Bad</i>, Jones later confirmed that the songs lyrics were
    about groupies. Jackson also confirmed this during an interview
    with Barbara Walters and he stated that it is not about
    Princess Diana, though he was told personally by Princess Diana
    that it was her favorite song by Jackson.</p>
      <p>In his 
    <i>Bad</i>review, Los Angeles Times' writer Richard Cromelin
    describes "Dirty Diana" as "trying to be this year's 'Beat
    It'--a hard-rock song about a tenacious groupie that's sent
    into orbit by a Steve Stevens guitar solo". All Music Guide's
    Stephen Thomas Erlewine also considers "Dirty Diana" as a hard
    rock song, observing on the album that, "This meant that he
    moved deeper into hard rock, deeper into schmaltzy adult
    contemporary, deeper into hard dance -- essentially taking each
    portion of Thriller to an extreme" and qualifying the track as
    the, "misogynistic 'Dirty Diana'".</p>
      <p>Jon Pareles, a writer for 
    <i>The New York Times</i>viewed "Dirty Diana" as a song about a
    "groupie who latches onto the narrator, mixes the sexual fears
    of 'Billie Jean' with the hard-rock lead guitar of 'Beat It'".
    "Dirty Diana" is written in common time and moves at a moderate
    tempo of 104 beats per minute. Jackson's vocals are sung on a
    range of Bb3 to G5. The instrumentation consists of guitar and
    piano, and is played in the a key of Bb Major.</p>
      <p>"Dirty Diana" received mixed reviews by contemporary music
    critics. Stephen Thomas Erlewine, a writer for Allmusic, felt
    that "Dirty Diana" and "Man In The Mirror" were "showcasing
    Jackson at his worst" on 
    <i>Bad</i>. Music critic Robert Christgau viewed "Dirty Diana"
    as a "misogynistic as any piece of metal suck-my-cock". Jon
    Pareles described "Dirty Diana" as 'reducing" Jackson to a
    "terrified whimper". Davitt Sigerson of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>gave the song a more positive review,
    describing "Dirty Diana" as being 
    <i>Bad</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s "filler",
    commenting that the song, along with "Speed Demon" is what
    makes 
    <i>Bad</i>"richer, sexier, better than 
    <i>Thriller</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s forgettables".
    Sigerson noted that "Dirty Diana" was a "substantial recording"
    because of its "insubstantial melody." Jennifer Clay of Yahoo!
    Music commented that while Jackson's more edgier image was a
    "little hard to swallow", the image, musically, worked on the
    songs "Bad", "Man in the Mirror" and "Dirty Diana", but was not
    "to the degree of 
    <i>Thriller</i>".</p>
      <p>"Dirty Diana", similar to 
    <i>Bad</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s previous singles,
    charted within the top twenty and top ten worldwide. "Dirty
    Diana" peaked at number one on the United States Hot 100 on
    July 2, 1988, after nine weeks on the chart. "Dirty Diana" was
    the album's third consecutive single to peak at number one on
    the Hot 100. Internationally, "Dirty Diana" charted within the
    top thirty in all of its major territories. The song peaked at
    number one on the Spanish charts, having topped the chart for
    one week. The song also charted within the top five in Denmark,
    New Zealand, and the Netherlands, peaking at number two, three
    and five. The song entered the United Kingdom charts on July
    16, 1988 at number fourteen, and the following the song charted
    at number four, where it peaked for two weeks.</p>
      <p>"Dirty Diana" peaked at number six in Italy, number seven in
    Austria, and charted at number nine in France. The song charted
    at number seventeen in Norwegian, as well as charting within
    the top thirty, peaking at number twenty-nine and thirty, in
    Sweden and Australia, respectively. Following Jackson's death
    in June 2009, his music experienced a surge in popularity. In
    July 2009, "Dirty Diana" saw a strong chart increase, mainly
    due to digital download sales. The song charted at number
    eighteen on the French Digital Singles Chart on July 4, 2009.
    On July 12, the song peaked at number thirteen on the Swiss
    Singles Chart. "Dirty Diana" re-entered the United Kingdom
    charts on July 4, 2009 at number fifty, and the following week
    peaked at number twenty-six; the song began falling off the
    charts in the following weeks.</p>
      <p>The accompanying music video was filmed in early 1988 in
    front of a live audience during Jackson's Bad World Tour. The
    seven minute long music video was directed by Joe Pytka. The
    video starts with the screen saying "Pepsi Presents Michael
    Jackson Tour 1988" in front of a white background for forty
    seconds; "Pepsi" is written in its logo. After showing a black
    screen, the video starts to show Jackson, who is shown from a
    distance, performing in front of an audience with the only
    source of light being blue lights. During Jackson's performance
    he is dressed in a white coat, black pants and has metal rims
    on his pants while singing and dancing. In between Jackson's
    performance from a distance, there are clips of him performing
    up-close while singing into a microphone, as well as clips of
    his female guitarist performing behind him. Jackson then begins
    dancing and singing to the female before walking down a
    cat-walk and dancing near a male guitarist. Jackson's
    performance is then shown from distance again and the video
    ends with Jackson finishing his performance and the lights
    turning blue.</p>
      <p>The music video won the "Number One Video In The World" at
    the 2nd World Music Awards held on April 14, 1989.</p>
      <p>"Dirty Diana" was performed during Jackson's World Tour
    concert series from 1987 to 1989, but only in the second leg,
    as the 10th song in the setlist. According to Jackson in an
    interview with Barbara Walters, "Dirty Diana" was scheduled for
    a live 1988 performance at Wembley Stadium during the Bad World
    Tour; however, Jackson felt the song would be an insult to
    Princess Diana, who was in attendance, so he had it removed.
    After Diana informed him the song was actually one of her
    personal favorites, Jackson stated that he re-added the song to
    the set list.</p>
      <p>According to This Is It concert series choreographer, Kenny
    Ortega, stated in an interview, "Dirty Diana" was going to be
    performed by Jackson for the concerts from 2009 to 2010. Ortega
    said that Jackson had rehearsed the song before he died, but he
    would be working on the end of the performance on the day he
    died. The song was apparently going to be performed before Beat
    It. The set up for the song would include an expert pole dancer
    who would lure Jackson onto a giant steel bed which she
    performed acrobatic feats on, then after chaining him to the
    bedposts they would be engulfed by curtains ready to perform
    the next song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
