<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Living_Years_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Living_Years_(song)</songId>
   <title>The Living Years</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mike_%2B_The_Mechanics</artistId>
      <artistName>Mike + The Mechanics</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1989-03-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/86/TheLivingYears.jpg/200px-TheLivingYears.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Mike-+-The-Mechanics+The-Living-Years.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Living Years</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 27, 1988 (UK); January 22, 1989 (US)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Cassette Single</format>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1988</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:32</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic , WEA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mike Rutherford and B. A. Robertson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Christopher Neil and Mike Rutherford</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Living Years" is a popular song written by Mike
    Rutherford and B. A. Robertson.</p>
      <p>It was first released as a single by Mike + The Mechanics,
    becoming a top ten chart hit around the world. It peaked at
    number one on the Billboard Hot 100 in the USA on March 25,
    1989. It also spent four weeks at the top of the U.S. adult
    contemporary chart. It reached #1 in Canada and Australia and
    #2 in the UK.</p>
      <p>The 
    <i>Mike + The Mechanics</i>version was initially promoted to
    give the impression the lyrics described the disagreements
    between Rutherford and his father. In an interview with Mike +
    The Mechanics - (The Sun Online) 2004, Mike Rutherford
    said:</p>
      <p>“The lyrics were written by BA and the song is about
    something he went through. He lost his Dad and it's about the
    lack of communication between him and his father before he
    died. There's also the irony of him having a baby just after
    losing his father. I had exactly the same thing happen to me at
    the same time, so it meant a lot to me too.”</p>
      <p>There are dozens of known recordings of the song,
    instrumental as well as vocal, reggae to classical crossover,
    from artists as diverse as American country rock band Alabama,
    West End theatre star Michael Ball, Marcia Hines, Engelbert
    Humperdinck, James Last, The LSO, Christian Artist Russ Lee,
    John Tesh, Russell Watson, and the London Community Gospel
    Choir.</p>
      <p>There is even a comedic interpretation by Big Daddy, where
    the song gets recast as the death-rock classic "Leader of the
    Pack", by The Shangri-Las.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Mike + The Mechanics</i>band member Paul Carrack who
    performed the original lead vocal has made a number of solo
    interpretations. Carrack lost his own father in an industrial
    accident when he was eleven. It is still a mainstay of
    Carrack’s live performances today.</p>
      <p>The song also enjoys a motley collection of foreign language
    covers, including the Tokyo Broadcasting System’s (TBS) Drama,
    “Hotel”, where it was performed, half in English, half in
    Japanese by one of the show’s stars.</p>
      <p>B.A. Robertson finally recorded his own version of the song
    - in Abbey Road Studios - in 2009, featuring backing vocals
    from The Gospel Truth Choir.</p>
      <p>In an interview with 
    <i>Mojo</i>(1996), Burt Bacharach stated “The Living Years is
    one of the finest lyrics of the last 10 years”.</p>
      <p>In 1990 the song was nominated Song of the Year at the
    Grammy Awards in Los Angeles. It won the Ivor Novello Award in
    London for Best Song Musically &amp; Lyrically.</p>
      <p>In 2004 it was awarded a 4 Million-Air citation by BMI.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
