<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lovin%27_You_(Minnie_Riperton_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lovin%27_You_(Minnie_Riperton_song)</songId>
   <title>Lovin' You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minnie_Riperton</artistId>
      <artistName>Minnie Riperton</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1975-04-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f8/Perfect_Angel_%C2%A91974.jpg/200px-Perfect_Angel_%C2%A91974.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Minnie-Riperton+Lovin-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Perfect Angel</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 13, 1975</released>
   <recorded>1974</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:44</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic , 32561</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Minnie Riperton</writer>
      <writer>Richard Rudolph</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Stevie Wonder</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Lovin' You" is a 1975 hit single by Minnie Riperton. The
    song became a #1 hit on the Billboard Hot 100 on April 5, 1975,
    #2 in the UK, and #3 on the R&amp;B charts in the US. The song
    is especially noteworthy due to the unusually high pitches that
    Riperton reaches during the song. It's also noteworthy for the
    sound of the chirping songbirds, that are heard throughout the
    song.</p>
      <p>It was the fourth single from the album 
    <i>Perfect Angel</i>(1974). The song is notable for Riperton's
    use of the whistle register. While it is believed that "Lovin'
    You" was the first song to reach number one without the help of
    a percussion instrument, "Yesterday" by The Beatles
    accomplished this feat ten years earlier.</p>
      <p>According to the liner notes from Riperton's compilation CD 
    <i>Petals</i>, the melody for "Lovin' You" was created as a
    distraction for her daughter (Maya Rudolph) when she was a baby
    so that Minnie and her husband Richard could hang out. Maya was
    in the studio with her mother on the day the song was recorded
    and Riperton can be heard singing her daughter's name at the
    end of the song, but only in the unedited or album version of
    the song. The song fades out early in the single edit, because
    the disc jockeys felt that the repeated "MAYA" was being
    overdone and too misunderstood, thinking that it was a "Mayan
    Chant".</p>
      <p>The song has been covered several times, notably by R&amp;B
    singer Shanice who sang it twice, first time in 1991 for her
    album 
    <i>Inner Child</i>and then again in 2006 for her comeback album
    
    <i>Every Woman Dreams</i>. Leona Lewis also recorded a version
    with producer Marley J Wills, at the age of 15. Reggae and Ska
    pioneer Alton Ellis covered the song for his LP 
    <i>Mr Ska Bean'a</i>. Another reggae singer, Janet Kay also
    covered the song. In 1980 Polish singer Ewa Kuklińska released
    a cover version with Polish lyrics entitled "Wino z win (Wine
    from our faults)" which became a notable hit for her. In 1998 a
    trance and 5 others dance versions was released by UBM with the
    brazilian singer Andrea Rincon. The song has also appeared in
    several movies and TV-shows, such as 
    <i>South Park</i>, 
    <i>Disturbia</i>, 
    <i>Bridget Jones: The Edge of Reason</i>(2004), 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>, 
    <i>Everybody Loves Raymond</i>, 
    <i>American Idol</i>, 
    <i>The Nutty Professor</i>(performed by Eddie Murphy while
    trying to show off to an offensive comic played by Dave
    Chappelle), 
    <i>Vegas Vacation</i>(Wayne Newton covers the song during a
    Wayne Newton show at the MGM Grand), as well as a commercial
    for Visa featuring the Pittsburgh Steelers, where the song is
    supposed to be 
    <i>Who Let the Dogs Out?</i>by the Baha Men. Singer Chante
    Moore performs the song during William's and Yvonne's ill-fated
    wedding on an episode of 
    <i>Girlfriends</i>. The song is also used in a sketch featuring
    a man spanking a woman with a spacehopper, in the Chris Morris
    comedy show 
    <i>Blue Jam</i>. On an episode of 
    <i>The Steve Harvey Show</i>, Romeo's father serenades his
    mother with his version of "Lovin' You" to woo her back (she
    had left him and moved in with Romeo and Steve). Additionally,
    it was used in a Burger King commercial promoting Cini-Minis.
    Singers Mariah Carey and Leona Lewis are highly influenced by
    Minnie and continue to pay homage and plan to record cover
    versions in the near future.</p>
      <p>The song was also sampled heavily by Dubstep artist Coki in
    a track entitled "Ruff Lovin'". This song is also featured on
    Justin Lo's debut Cantonese album 
    <i>Justin</i>in 2005. In 2007 the Japanese rock band Electric
    Eel Shock covered the song on their album 
    <i>Transworld Ultra Rock</i>.</p>
      <p>The Orb's single "A Huge Ever Growing Pulsating Brain That
    Rules from the Centre of the Ultraworld", also known as "Loving
    You", was based around a sample of the Riperton original.</p>
      <p>Jazz saxophonists Roland Kirk and Lou Donaldson also covered
    the song.</p>
      <p>Shanice's cover of the song was released in the summer of
    1992 months after the success of her hit single "I Love Your
    Smile." It only achieved minor success on the R&amp;B chart
    peaking at #59, and also peaked at #54 on the UK charts. The
    music video for the song is set on a beach. In 2005, she
    recorded another cover of the song for her 2006 album 
    <i>Every Woman Dreams</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
