<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hound_Dog_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hound_Dog_(song)</songId>
   <title>Hound Dog "/ " Don't Be Cruel " Elvis Presley</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>"My Prayer" The Platters</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1956-08-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>March 1953</released>
   <formats>
      <format>78 RPM 10" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>August 13, 1952 Los Angeles</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rhythm And Blues</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:52</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Peacock Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jerry Leiber and Mike Stoller</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Johnny Otis</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Hound Dog" is a twelve-bar blues written by Jerry Leiber
    and Mike Stoller and originally recorded by Willie Mae "Big
    Mama" Thornton in 1952. Other early versions illustrate the
    differences among blues, country, and rock and roll in the mid
    1950s. The 1956 remake by Elvis Presley is the best known
    version. This is the version that is #19 on Rolling Stone's
    list of The 500 Greatest Songs of All Time. "Hound Dog" was
    also recorded by 5 country singers in 1953 alone, and over 26
    times through 1964. . From the 1970s onward, the song has
    appeared, or is heard, as a part of the soundtrack in numerous
    motion pictures, most notably in blockbusters such as 
    <i>American Graffiti</i>, 
    <i>Grease</i>, 
    <i>Forrest Gump</i>, 
    <i>Lilo &amp; Stitch</i>, 
    <i>A Few Good Men (film)</i>and 
    <i>Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull</i>.</p>
      <p>The blues singer Big Mama Thornton's biggest hit was Jerry
    Leiber and Mike Stoller's "Hound Dog", which she recorded in
    1952. Thornton’s "Hound Dog" was the first record Leiber and
    Stoller produced themselves. They took over the session because
    their work had sometimes been misrepresented, and on this one
    they knew how they wanted the drums to sound; Johnny Otis was
    supposed to produce it, but they wanted him on drums. Otis
    received a writing credit on all 6 of the 1953 pressings. This
    1953 Peacock Records release (#1612) was number one on the
    Billboard rhythm and blues charts for seven weeks.</p>
      <p>Thornton gave this account of how the original was created
    to Ralph Gleason. “They were just a couple of kids, and they
    had this song written on the back of a paper bag.” She added a
    few interjections of her own, played around with the rhythm
    (some of the choruses have thirteen rather than twelve bars),
    and had the band bark and howl like hound dogs at the end of
    the song. In fact, she interacts constantly in a call and
    response fashion during a one minute long guitar "solo" by Pete
    Lewis . Her vocals include lines such as: "Aw, listen to that
    ole hound dog howl.. OOOOoooow", "Now wag your tail", and "Aw,
    get it, get it, get it".</p>
      <p>Thornton's delivery has flexible phrasing making use of
    micro-inflections and syncopations. Over a steady backbeat, she
    starts out singing each line as one long upbeat. When the words
    change from "You ain't nothin' but a HOUND Dog", she begins to
    shift the downbeat around: You TOLD me you was 
    <i>high</i>-class / but I can SEE through that, You ain't
    NOTHIN' but a 
    <i>hound</i>dog. Each has a focal accent which is never
    repeated..</p>
      <p>The other musicians on this recording are Devonia Williams
    (piano), Albert Winston (bass), and Leard Bell (drums), and are
    listed as "Kansas City Bill &amp; Orchestra". Habanera and
    Habanera-mambo variations can be found in this recording.</p>
      <p>A live TV recording of Hound Dog by Thornton from the
    European tour of the American Blues and Folk Festival (1965)
    has Buddy Guy playing guitar</p>
      <p>Peacock released Thornton's version in March 1953. Five
    versions of the song were recorded on several different labels
    by "country" groups the very next month (April 1953):</p>
      <p>Bernie Lowe suspected that "Hound Dog" could potentially
    have greater appeal, and asked Freddie Bell of Freddie Bell and
    the Bellboys to rewrite the lyrics to appeal to a broader radio
    audience. "Snoopin' round my door" was replaced with "cryin'
    all the time", and "You can wag your tail, but I ain't gonna
    feed you no more" was replaced by "You ain't never caught a
    rabbit, and you ain't no friend of mine." This new version of
    "Hound Dog" was recorded on Lowe's Teen Records in 1955 (TEEN
    101 with "Move Me Baby" on the flip side,[3] two of four songs
    the group did with Lowe that year). The regional popularity of
    this release, along with the group's showmanship, yielded both
    a tour, and an engagement in the Las Vegas Sands Hotel's Silver
    Queen Bar. The Bellboys' Vegas version of the song was a
    comedy-burlesque with show-stopping va-va-voom
    choreography.</p>
      <p>Others were also performing the song at that time. Ralph
    Jones, who joined Bill Haley and His Comets in the fall of
    1955. told of performing the song when given the spotlight at
    live performances. "I used to do "Hound Dog". Haley would get
    mad at me if I'd do that. This was even before Presley did it.
    Haley didn't like those guys from Philadelphia that wrote the
    song."</p>
      <p>Elvis Presley's first, apparently not very successful,
    appearance in Las Vegas, as an “extra added attraction”, was in
    the Venus Room of the New Frontier from April 23 through May 6,
    1956. Freddie Bell and the Bellboys were the hot act in town,
    and Elvis went to the Sands to take in their show. Elvis not
    only enjoyed the show, but also loved their reworking of 'Hound
    Dog' and asked Freddie if he had any objections to him
    recording his own version. By May 16 Elvis had added “Hound
    Dog” to his live performances. The song was done as comic
    relief, and Presley based the lyrics, which he sometimes
    changed, and "gyrations" on what he had seen at the Sands. The
    song always got a big reaction and became the standard
    closer.</p>
      <p>Drummer D.J. Fontana put it this way. "We took that from a
    band we saw in Vegas, Freddie Bell and the Bellboys. They were
    doing the song kinda like that. We went out there every night
    to watch them. He'd say: "Let's go watch that band. It's a good
    band! That's where he heard "Hound Dog", and shortly thereafter
    he said: "Let's try that song".</p>
      <p>Presley first performed "Hound Dog" to a nation wide
    television audience on The Milton Berle Show on June 5, 1956,
    his second appearance with Berle. By this time Scotty Moore had
    added a guitar solo, and DJ Fontana had added a hot drum roll
    between verses of the song. Presley appeared for the first time
    on national television sans guitar. Before his death, Berle
    told an interviewer that he had told Elvis to leave his guitar
    backstage. "Let 'em see you, son", advised Uncle Miltie.</p>
      <p>An upbeat version ended abruptly as Presley threw his arm
    back. Then began to vamp at half tempo, "You ain't-a nuthin'
    but a hound dog, cuh-crying all the time." "You ain't never
    caught a rabbit..." A final wave signaled the band to stop.
    Elvis pointed threateningly at the audience, and belted out,
    "You ain't no friend of mine." Presley's movements during the
    performance were energetic and exaggerated. The reactions of
    young women in the studio audience were enthusiastic, as shown
    on the broadcast.</p>
      <p>Over 40,000,000 people saw the performance and the next day
    controversy exploded. Berle's network received many letters of
    protest. The various self appointed guardians of public
    morality attacked Elvis in the press. TV critics began a
    merciless campaign against Elvis making statements that; he had
    a "caterwalling voice and nonsense lyrics", he was an
    "influence on juvenile deliquency", and began using the
    nickname "Elvis the Pelvis".</p>
      <p>Elvis next appeared on national television singing "Hound
    Dog" on the July 1 Steve Allen Show. Steve Allen wrote: "When I
    booked Elvis, I naturally had no interest in just presenting
    him vaudeville-style and letting him do his spot as he might in
    concert. Instead we worked him into the comedy fabric of our
    program...We certainly didn't inhibit Elvis' then-notorious
    pelvic gyrations, but I think the fact that he had on formal
    evening attire made him, purely on his own, slightly alter his
    presentation." As Allen was notoriously contemptuous of rock
    'n' roll music and songs such as Hound Dog, he smirkingly
    presented Elvis "with a roll that looks exactly like a large
    roll of toilet paper with, says Allen, the 'signatures of eight
    thousand fans' " and the singer had to wear a tuxedo while
    singing an abbreviated version of Hound Dog to an actual top
    hat-wearing basset hound. Although by most accounts Presley was
    a good sport about it, according to Scotty Moore, the next
    morning they were all angry about their treatment the previous
    night.</p>
      <p>The morning after the "Steve Allen Show" performance, the
    studio version was recorded for RCA Victor by Elvis' regular
    band of Scotty Moore on lead guitar (with Elvis usually
    providing rhythm guitar), Bill Black on bass, D.J. Fontana on
    drums and backing vocals from the Jordanaires. Presley recorded
    this version along with "Don't Be Cruel" and "Any Way You Want
    Me" on July 2, 1956 at RCA's New York City studio. The
    producing credit was given to RCA's Steve Sholes, however the
    studio recordings reveal that Elvis produced the songs (as well
    as most of the RCA recording sessions) himself, which is
    verified by the band members. Presley insisted on getting the
    song exactly the way he wanted it, recording 31 takes of the
    song.</p>
      <p>Don't Be Cruel (G2WW-5936) was the flip side of the "Hound
    Dog" single (G2WW-5935), released on July 13, 1956. Both sides
    of the record topped the charts independently, a rare feat. The
    single also topped all three extant Billboard charts: pop,
    country &amp; western, and rhythm &amp; blues, the first record
    in history to do so.</p>
      <p>On September 9, with the song topping the US charts, Presley
    performed an abbreviated version of "Hound Dog" on the Ed
    Sullivan Show hosted by Charles Laughton. After performing
    "Ready Teddy", he introduced the song with the following
    statement, “Friends, as a great philosopher once said...”
    Elvis's first time on the Sullivan show was an event that drew
    some 60 million TV viewers. During his second Sullivan Show
    appearance, October 28, he introduced the song thusly (although
    unable to keep a straight face). “Ladies and gentlemen, could I
    have your attention please. Ah, I’d like to tell you we’re
    going to do a sad song for you. This song here is one of the
    saddest songs we’ve ever heard. It really tells a story
    friends. Beautiful lyrics. It goes something like this.” He
    then launched into a full version of the song. Elvis was shown
    in full during this performance. Again, Presley drew more than
    60 million viewers.</p>
      <p>Presley's "Hound Dog" sold over 4 million copies in the
    United States on its first release. It was his best selling
    single and starting in July 1956, it spent a record eleven
    weeks at #1. It stayed in the #1 spot until it was replaced by
    "Love Me Tender", also recorded by Elvis.</p>
      <p>In March, 2005, magazine placed Presley's version at number
    55 in its list of the Q Magazine's 100 Greatest Guitar Tracks. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine ranked it #19 on their list of the
    500 Greatest Songs of All Time- the highest ranked of Presley's
    eleven entries.</p>
      <p>A partial list of “cover” versions of Hound Dog includes:
    [4]</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
