<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Somethin%27_Stupid 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Somethin%27_Stupid</songId>
   <title>Somethin' Stupid</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nancy_Sinatra</artistId>
      <artistName>Nancy Sinatra and Frank Sinatra</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1967-04-15</week>
      <week>1967-04-22</week>
      <week>1967-04-29</week>
      <week>1967-05-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/93/Somethin%27_Stupid_...jpg/200px-Somethin%27_Stupid_...jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Nancy-Sinatra-and-Frank-Sinatra+Somethin-Stupid.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The World We Knew</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1967</released>
   <formats>
      <format>vinyl record (7")</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Reprise Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>C. Parks</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Somethin' Stupid" is a song written by C. Carson Parks and
    originally recorded in 1966 by Parks and his wife Gail Foote,
    as "Carson and Gaile". It is best known in the hit version by
    Frank Sinatra and his daughter, Nancy Sinatra.</p>
      <p>In the early 1960s, Carson Parks was a folk singer in Los
    Angeles. He was an occasional member of The Easy Riders, and
    also performed with The Steeltown Three, which included his
    younger brother Van Dyke Parks. In 1963 he formed the Greenwood
    County Singers, later known as The Greenwoods, who had two
    minor hits and included singer Gaile Foote. Before the
    Greenwoods disbanded, Parks and Foote married and, as Carson
    and Gaile, recorded an album for Kapp Records, 
    <i>San Antonio Rose</i>, which included the track "Something
    Stupid". The recording was then brought to the attention of
    Frank Sinatra.</p>
      <p>The most successful and best known version of the song was
    issued by Frank and Nancy Sinatra on Frank's album 
    <i>The World We Knew.</i>Frank Sinatra played Parks' recording
    to his daughter Nancy's producer, Lee Hazlewood, who recalled 
    <i>"He asked me, 'Do you like it?' and I said, 'I love it, and
    if you don't sing it with Nancy, I will.' He said, 'We're gonna
    do it, book a studio.'"</i>Their rendition was recorded on
    February 1, 1967. Al Casey played guitar on the recording.</p>
      <p>The song spent four weeks at #1 on the US Billboard Hot 100
    chart and nine weeks atop the adult contemporary chart,
    becoming Mr. Sinatra's second gold single as certified by the
    RIAA and Ms. Sinatra's third. It was the first and only
    instance of a father-daughter number-one song in America. The
    single also reached #1 on the UK Singles Chart the same
    year.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered many times in the years since the
    song was originally released.</p>
      <p>British singer Robbie Williams recorded "Somethin' Stupid"
    as a duet in 2001 with Academy Award-winning actress Nicole
    Kidman. The song appeared on Williams' 2001 album, 
    <i>Swing When You're Winning</i>, and it topped the UK Singles
    Chart at the end of the year. The song became Williams' first
    Christmas Number-One single in the United Kingdom, and fifth as
    a featured artist. The single sold 98,506 copies in its first
    week and 366,000 copies over all earning a Silver Certification
    by the BPI. The song was the 30th best selling single of 2001
    in the UK. The song also became another number-one single for
    Williams in New Zealand, being certified Gold, and became, at
    the time, his best selling single in Europe charting inside the
    top ten in most countries. In Australia, it became Williams'
    fourth top ten single, earning a Gold certification for over
    35,000 copies sold. These are the formats and track listings of
    major single releases of "Somethin' Stupid".</p>
      <p>UK CD, (Released December 10, 2001)</p>
      <p>UK DVD, (Released December 10, 2001)</p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">One More for the Rogue Tour
      / For a Few Dollars More... Tour (1998-1999) ʥ</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Robbie Williams North
      American Tours (1999) ʥ</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">The Sermon on the Mount Tour
      (2000-2001) ʥ</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Weddings, Barmitzvahs &amp;
      Stadiums Tour / Sing When You're Pacific Rimming Tour (2001)
      ʥ</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Weekends of Mass Distraction
      Tour / Cock of Justice/Aussie Typo Tour (2003) ʥ</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Close Encounters Tour (2006)
      ʥ</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">TBA (2010)</span>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
