<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/These_Boots_Are_Made_for_Walkin%27 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/These_Boots_Are_Made_for_Walkin%27</songId>
   <title>These Boots Are Made for Walkin'</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nancy_Sinatra</artistId>
      <artistName>Nancy Sinatra</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1966-02-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/93/S64237.jpg/200px-S64237.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Nancy-Sinatra+These-Boots-Are-Made-for-Walkin.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Boots</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 1966</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:42</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Reprise Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lee Hazlewood</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Lee Hazlewood</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"These Boots Are Made for Walkin'" is a pop song musically
    composed by Lee Hazlewood and first written and recorded by
    Nancy Sinatra. It was released in February 1966 and hit #1 in
    the United States and United Kingdom Pop charts. Subsequently,
    many cover versions of the song have been released in a range
    of styles: metal, pop, rock, punk rock, country, dance, and
    industrial (see selected list below). Jessica Simpson made #14
    in the United States in 2005 with her version based on the
    movie: 
    <i>The Dukes of Hazzard</i>. Geri Halliwell and Jewel also
    released remakes of the song.</p>
      <p>The song is often incorrectly listed as "These Boots",
    "These Boots Were Made for Walkin'" and "These Boots Are Made
    for Walking."</p>
      <p>Nancy Sinatra was encouraged by Lee Hazlewood to sing the
    song as if she were a sixteen-year-old girl giving the
    brush-off to a forty-year-old man. Sinatra's recording of the
    song was made with the help of notable Los Angeles session
    musicians known as the Wrecking Crew. This session included Hal
    Blaine on drums, Al Casey, Tommy Tedesco, and Billy Strange on
    guitars, Ollie Mitchell, Roy Caton and Lew McCreary on horns,
    Carol Kaye on electric bass, and Chuck Berghofer on double
    bass, providing the notable bass line.</p>
      <p>According to Carol Kaye, 
    <i>"Arranger Billy Strange believed in using the two basses
    together. Producer Lee Hazlewood asked Chuck to put a sliding
    run on the front of the tune. Chuck complied by playing notes
    about three tones apart (4-6 frets apart), but Lee stopped the
    take. "No Chuck, make your sliding notes closer together", and
    that is what you hear."</i>
      </p>
      <p>According to Al Casey, 
    <i>"Well, Lee and I had been friends forever, and he said,
    "I've got this song I'm working on, and I want the guitar to
    play this." And he showed me, because there's a little bit more
    than banging on an 'E-chord', which is what most people do.
    There's more to it than that. He said, "I want you to do this
    on the song.", and he sang the song and played the rhythm
    guitar lick,</i>
         <i>"and I went "Oh, that's cute!", little suspecting it was
    gonna be huge."</i>
      </p>
      <p>The second single taken from her debut album 
    <i>Boots</i>, and follow-up to the minor hit "So Long, Babe,"
    the song became an instant success. In late February 1966, the
    song topped the Billboard Hot 100 chart, a move it replicated
    in similar charts across the world.</p>
      <p>When the single was first released, some thought it had to
    do with the subway strike in New York. That same year, Sinatra
    recorded an early music video for the song. It was produced by
    Color-Sonics, and played on Scopitone video jukeboxes. In 1986,
    for the song's twentieth anniversary, cable station VH1 played
    this music video.</p>
      <p>The song was adopted by troops in the Vietnam War when they
    marched, and Sinatra traveled there in the mid- to late-1960s
    to perform for the U.S. soldiers. It was used on the soundtrack
    to Stanley Kubrick's 
    <i>Full Metal Jacket</i>(1987). Sinatra also sang it on an
    episode of 
    <i>China Beach</i>in the late-1980s. In 2005, Paul Revere &amp;
    the Raiders recorded a revamped version of the song using
    Sinatra's original vocal track. It appeared on the CD 
    <i>Ride to the Wall, Vol. 2</i>, with proceeds going to help
    Vietnam veterans.</p>
      <p>In addition, the Fembots were introduced to the strains of
    the opening and closing notes of the song in 
    <i>Austin Powers: International Man of Mystery</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2006, Pitchfork Media selected it as the 114th best song
    of the 1960s. Critic Tom Breihan described the song as "maybe
    the finest bitchy kiss-off in pop history".</p>
      <p>Goodyear Tire and Rubber used portions of the song for its
    1960s' ad campaign promoting its "wide boots" tires. Nancy
    Sinatra unsuccessfully sued Goodyear for using the song,
    claiming that it had violated her publicity rights. Sinatra v.
    Goodyear Tire &amp; Rubber Co., 435 F.2d 711 (9th Cir. 1970),
    http://www.altlaw.org/v1/cases/882392.</p>
      <p>Megadeth covered the song on their 1985 debut album 
    <i>Killing Is My Business... And Business Is Good!</i>, which
    is track four on the original release, and eight on the 2002
    re-release. Their version was more of a parody than a cover,
    featuring alternate lyrics and titled 
    <i>"These Boots"</i>on the release. When the album started
    selling well, the writer of the song, Lee Hazlewood, began
    demanding that the song be omitted, due to its being a
    "perversion of the original". Dave Mustaine made the point that
    Hazlewood had been paid royalties for years before his
    complaint, but eventually omitted the song anyway. A censored
    version of the track can be found on the album's 'deluxe
    edition' released in 2002.</p>
      <p>In the 1995 documentary film 
    <i>Dika: Murder City</i>, the 74-year-old Dika Newlin, dressed
    in leather and backed by the band Apocowlypso, performed a punk
    rock version of the song in a concert sequence.</p>
      <p>Hardcore ska-punk band Operation Ivy (Rancid's Tim Armstrong
    and Matt Freeman's previous band) covered the song, titled "One
    Of These Days" on their only LP, Energy. Fast-paced and
    ska-style, the song has yelled vocals by Jesse Michaels.</p>
      <p>Jessica Simpson recorded her own version of "These Boots Are
    Made for Walkin'" (and added her own lyrics) for the soundtrack
    to the film 
    <i>The Dukes of Hazzard</i>(2005). Simpson's cover was
    co-produced by Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis, and was released as
    the soundtrack's first single in 2005). It became Simpson's
    fifth top-twenty single in the United States and its music
    video drew some controversy because of its sexual imagery.</p>
      <p>Simpson's version of the song is performed from the point of
    view of her character in 
    <i>The Dukes of Hazzard</i>, Daisy Duke, and it has several
    major differences from Sinatra's version. The song's lyrics
    were changed almost completely as Simpson felt that they did
    not accurately convey the feelings needed for the film; in the
    original Sinatra dealt with a cheating boyfriend, while in the
    new version Simpson version explore Daisy Duke's personality
    and experiences. She rewrote the majority of the lyrics
    herself, although some elements were retained such as the
    opening line "You keep saying you got something for me..." and
    the spoken "Are you ready, boots? Start walkin'".</p>
      <p>Simpson also added some new music to her version of the
    song. Whereas the original version did not have a bridge, she
    created one for the cover. A risqué rap-like/spoken breakdown
    was added after the bridge. Because of the legalities of
    songwriting, Simpson has not been credited for the new music or
    lyrics that she wrote. The production of the song was altered
    as well. Producers Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis gave the cover a
    country-inspired production because of its relationship to the
    film 
    <i>The Dukes of Hazzard</i>, but they also added a more hip
    hop-like beat. "These Boots Are Made for Walkin'" is the
    production duo's second song to contain elements of country
    music, after Janet Jackson's "Someone to Call My Lover."</p>
      <p>In a current interview with GAC Nights, Jessica stated that
    her record label did not want to promote the song because of
    its country feel, even though the song is more pop than
    country. She said that she told the label "It's a great song
    and Willie Nelson's on it with me" and she said the label told
    her pop radio wouldn't understand that importance.</p>
      <p>"These Boots Are Made for Walkin'" peaked at fourteen on the
    U.S. Billboard Hot 100, and in late 2005 the RIAA certified the
    single Gold for 500,000 legal downloads or more. Its digital
    downloads were high, but radio airplay was low. It reached the
    top ten on Billboard's Pop 100 chart, and was Simpson's first
    single to appear on the chart. On 11 December, 2006 the single
    was certified Gold by the RIAA again, this time by Epic
    Records. In total, the single has received 1 million digital
    downloads.</p>
      <p>Internationally, was a success, reaching top 5 in several
    European countries. It became her biggest hit in Australia,
    where it reached number two and remained in the top forty for
    twenty-four weeks. In Ireland was another biggest hit peaking
    the number 2. The song also cracked the top five in the UK,
    where it reached number four and is to date, her highest
    peaking single in that territory. It reached the top ten in the
    chart European Hot 100 Singles, Belgium, and New Zealand and
    the top twenty in Austria, Switzerland and Germany.</p>
      <p>The video, directed by Brett Ratner, has caused some
    controversy because of its sexual imagery. The scene was well
    publicized, with Simpson admitting to the public and the media
    that she went on the South Beach diet to achieve her well toned
    look in the video. Because of its sexual imagery, the music
    video is banned in all Middle Eastern and North African nations
    except Algeria, Israel, Iraq, Lebanon, and Turkey. In Malaysia,
    it was occasionally edited with some of the scenes removed.</p>
      <p>The video begins with Simpson (as Daisy Duke) climbing out
    of the 
    <i>General Lee</i>(the famous car owned by the Duke family)
    into a bar. Simpson, a waitress at the bar, flirts with
    customers as she grinds and dances on the bar stand, and shakes
    her buttocks to a customer. After another customer slaps her
    butt with his hand, Simpson smiles and turns to the customer
    acting as if she likes it. She then says the verse "You believe
    you’ve stopped me for a reason"..."Now I’m pretending my
    bending's(bends over and rubs her butt against his crotch) just
    for fun"..."These double DDs breasts". She then punches him and
    the man's fall causes a fight to break out between the bar
    patrons. Unfazed, Simpson sings the song with the assistance of
    Willie Nelson on guitar and backup vocals, and several female
    dancers join her during the song's "Can I get a handclap..."
    spoken/rapped breakdown. After recovering from their injuries,
    the men join Simpson and the dancers in a line dance. This
    scene is intercut with shots of a figure entering a barn, and
    at the video's end it is revealed the figure is Simpson wearing
    nothing but a skin-tight, revealing pink bikini. She then
    grinds and washes the 
    <i>General Lee</i>. The music video also features Jessica
    Simpson belly dancing. It was parodied as "The Dukes Are Not
    Worth Watching" by 
    <i>MADtv</i>, with Nicole Parker portraying Simpson.</p>
      <p>The video ranked the #44 in the countdown of MTV Latin
    America's 100+ Pedidos del 2005.</p>
      <p>The song had an official remix witch was called "These Boots
    Are Made For Walkin' " (Bimbo Jones Radio Edit).,</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
