<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mona_Lisa_(Nat_King_Cole_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mona_Lisa_(Nat_King_Cole_song)</songId>
   <title>Mona Lisa</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nat_King_Cole</artistId>
      <artistName>Nat King Cole</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1950-07-15</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1950</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Traditional Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ray Evans</writer>
      <writer>Jay Livingston</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Mona Lisa" is an Academy Award-winning song written by Ray
    Evans and Jay Livingston for the Paramount Pictures film 
    <i>Captain Carey, U.S.A.</i>(1950). The arrangement was by
    Nelson Riddle and the orchestral backing was played by Les
    Baxter and his Orchestra. The soundtrack version by Nat King
    Cole spent eight weeks at number one in the singles chart in
    1950. Also, Cole's version of the song was inducted into the
    Grammy Hall of Fame in 1992. The Billboard sales charts of 1950
    also showed significant sales on versions by Dennis Day and
    Harry James. In 1986, it was used as the theme to the British
    film 
    <i>Mona Lisa</i>. An uncredited version of 
    <i>Mona Lisa</i>plays in the background of one scene in Alfred
    Hitchcock's 
    <i>Rear Window</i>(1954). The song was used in the wedding
    scene of the NBC mini-series, 
    <i>Witness to the Mob</i>, in 1998.</p>
      <p>Various artists, including Elvis Presley, Willie Nelson, Art
    Lund, Shakin' Stevens, Me First and the Gimme Gimmes, and Nat
    King Cole's daughter Natalie Cole, have released cover versions
    of this song. Bruddah Iz (Israel Kamakawiwo'ole) also covered
    the song on the album 
    <i>Alone in IZ World</i>. Harry Connick, Jr. included the song
    on his 2009 album, 
    <i>Your Songs</i>.</p>
      <p>A rockabilly version of "Mona Lisa" (b/w/ "Foolish One") was
    released by Carl Mann on Phillips International Records (#3539)
    in March 1959 and reached number 25 on the Billboard Hot 100.
    Conway Twitty recorded a version of "Mona Lisa" in February
    1959 but planned to release it only as an album cut (on an EP
    and an LP by MGM Records). Sam Phillips signed Carl Mann to
    record his version of the song after the Twitty version began
    getting radio play in early 1959. This was the most successful
    single in Mann's career. The melody is slightly different, and
    the lyrics are also mostly the same as in the original version
    by Nat King Cole, though a few more phrases are added in that
    elaborate more on the girl he likes.</p>
      <p>The singer Don Cherry recorded a version backed by the
    Victor Young Orchestra which reached #7 in 1952.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
