<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/So_Sick 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/So_Sick</songId>
   <title>So Sick</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ne-Yo</artistId>
      <artistName>Ne-Yo</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2006-03-18</week>
      <week>2006-03-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/ff/SoSickNeYo.jpg/200px-SoSickNeYo.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Ne-Yo+So-Sick.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>In My Own Words</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 24, 2006</released>
   <formats>
      <format>12" single</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2005</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:27</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Def Jam</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mikkel S. Eriksen</writer>
      <writer>Tor Erik Hermansen</writer>
      <writer>Shaffer Smith</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Stargate</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"So Sick" is an R&amp;B–pop song by American
    singer-songwriter Ne-Yo. The track was produced by Norwegian
    production team Stargate for Ne-Yo's debut album 
    <i>In My Own Words</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was released as the second single from the album.
    It was successful on charts worldwide, reaching #1 in the
    United States and the United Kingdom. It's also Ne-Yo's biggest
    hit so far although the single also battled through
    controversy. It won the race to the UK #1 spot, beating
    "Nature's Law" by Embrace which only reached #2 due to a large
    count of legal download sales of "Nature's Law" which didn't
    register in the official charts.</p>
      <p>Ne-Yo met Norwegian production team, Stargate, consisting of
    Mikkel S. Eriksen and Tor Erik Hermansen, in a hallway at Sony
    Music Studios on West 54th Street, New York City after the duo
    had settled there in the spring of 2005. After finding out they
    produced R&amp;B-oriented tracks, among others, they started on
    writing songs for his debut album 
    <i>In My Own Words</i>. They produced six songs, including "So
    Sick".</p>
      <p>Mikkel S. Eriksen and Tor Erik Hermansen of Stargate
    composed the music for the song, while Ne-Yo composed the
    lyric. "So Sick" centers on a character, who is tired of
    hearing love songs playing on the radio, as they remind him of
    his last relationship and breakup.</p>
      <p>Ne-Yo has said he got the idea for the song from an old
    girlfriend he used to have. He really did love her but he
    listened to the advice of his friends and wound up cheating on
    her. They broke up when she found out but shortly after he
    started repeatedly hearing a song on the radio that she used to
    love, which was unusual because the song wasn't new and it
    hadn't had much airplay until that point. Every time he heard
    the song he was reminded of how he lost his girlfriend and
    wanted to turn the radio off but he would always keep listening
    to it because it also reminded him of how much he loved her and
    all the good times they shared.</p>
      <p>"So Sick" received generally positive responses from
    contemporary critics. Bill Lamb of About stated that the smooth
    instrumental of the song makes it stand out and appropriate to
    listen during mid-winter season. He was pleased with the vocals
    of Ne-Yo, but noted that "more emotional involvement would have
    made his performance more memorable", while calling
    "restrained". A review from Contactmusic.com echoed the
    latter's comment, saying that his vocal rendition is
    "stunning", while complimenting the production a "melodic
    masterpiece".</p>
      <p>The video for "So Sick", directed by Hype Williams, saw
    heavy rotation on BET and MTV. Two versions of the song's video
    were shot. The original version of the music video ended up
    being scrapped for various reasons. The newer version appealed
    to the current weather conditions of the winter season with the
    video being filmed in the snowy mountains.</p>
      <p>There are currently 5 "So Sick" remixes. One features Jin.
    The official remix features LL Cool J and also samples Michael
    Jackson's song, "Human Nature". This remix is on LL Cool J's
    11th album, 
    <i>Todd Smith</i>. Another remix features labelmate Jay-Z.
    Another remix which is sung by Patrick Stump from Fall Out Boy
    has also been known to cover the song. In 2007, saxophonist Kim
    Waters covers the song on Track #1 on 
    <i>You Are My Lady</i>. There is also one with 2Pac. There is
    also a version that uses the "Seasons" riddim.</p>
      <p>Side A</p>
      <p>Side B</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
