<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dilemma_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dilemma_(song)</songId>
   <title>Dilemma</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kelly_Rowland</artistId>
      <artistName>Nelly featuring Kelly Rowland</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2002-08-17</week>
      <week>2002-08-24</week>
      <week>2002-08-31</week>
      <week>2002-09-07</week>
      <week>2002-09-14</week>
      <week>2002-09-21</week>
      <week>2002-09-28</week>
      <week>2002-10-19</week>
      <week>2002-10-26</week>
      <week>2002-11-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/61/Nelly_featuring_Kelly_Rowland_-_Dilemma_CD_cover.jpg/200px-Nelly_featuring_Kelly_Rowland_-_Dilemma_CD_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Nelly-featuring-Kelly-Rowland+Dilemma.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Nellyville and Simply Deep</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 25, 2002</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:49 (Album version)</length>
      <length>3:55 (Radio edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Universal , Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Cornell Haynes Jr.</writer>
      <writer>Patti LaBelle</writer>
      <writer>Kelendria Rowland</writer>
      <writer>Jermaine Dupri</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>BAM &amp; Ryan</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Dilemma" is a song by the American rapper Nelly, duet with
    R&amp;B singer Kelly Rowland. The single was released in 2002
    from the album 
    <i>Nellyville</i>. In the 50th Anniversary of the Hot 100 issue
    of 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine, the song was ranked at number 64 on
    the all-time Hot 100 songs while at the end of 2009 was named
    the 11th most successful song from 2000 to 2009, on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade. The song won a
    Grammy Award for Best Collaboration at the 45th Grammy
    Awards.</p>
      <p>St. Louis producer Bam handed Nelly a skeleton track which
    samples and contains elements from Patti LaBelle's "Love, Need
    and Want You" from her 1983 album 
    <i>I'm In Love Again</i>. Upon hearing the beat, he began
    writing lyrics and then wrote a song out from it. Nelly decided
    to make the song a last-minute addition to his second album 
    <i>Nellyville</i>, which had already been completed prior to
    Bam giving him the track.</p>
      <p>Once Nelly returned to the studio to record the track, his
    vision changed, wanting to add a female vocal onto it. He
    instantly thought of girl group Destiny's Child member Kelly
    Rowland, whom he had met during the 
    <i>TRL</i>tour in 2001. Nelly called Rowland by phone and
    agreed. After a few days of recording, during which Rowland
    rerecorded her part many times to achieve it "just right",
    "Dilemma" was completed.</p>
      <p>Once 
    <i>Nellyville</i>was released in the United States on June 25,
    2002, radio programmers started playing "Dilemma". By July
    2002, the track had reached the top ten of the Hot 100 based on
    airplay alone. This prompted Nelly to release it as the album's
    second single, although it was not the original plan. The
    single was released on July 30, 2002.</p>
      <p>The decision affected the early plans for Destiny's Child
    members, whose members were held on hiatus to pursue solo album
    releases. As part of their strategy, each member's albums were
    to be staggered with member Beyoncé Knowles releasing in
    October 2002 and Rowland's album expected in early 2003. Their
    management rescheduled the dates: Rowland eventually released
    her debut solo album, 
    <i>Simply Deep</i>, on October 28, 2002, ahead of the other two
    members of the group. "Dilemma" was released as the first
    single off the album, which served as a propeller for her solo
    career. "Dilemma" is Rowland's first international solo single
    away from the group: she had previously appeared on R&amp;B
    singer Avant's single "Separated", which was released in the
    United States in July 2000.</p>
      <p>"Dilemma" was generally well received by critics. Allmusic
    reviewer Jason Birchmeier noted it as one of the "three
    well-calculated, standout" tracks in the album. In her review
    for 
    <i>Simply Deep</i>, Caroline Sullivan of 
    <i>The Guardian</i>wrote: "Thanks to the ubiquitous Dilemma, a
    song that practically peeled off its clothes on the spot,
    Destiny's Child's Kelly Rowland is no longer a mere backing
    vocalist for Beyoncé Knowles."</p>
      <p>"Dilemma" was nominated for Best Rap/Sung Collaboration and
    Record of the Year at the Grammy Awards of 2003, winning the
    former.</p>
      <p>The song was the 22nd best-selling single of the 2000 decade
    in UK.</p>
      <p>The song appears on the game 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Presents: American Idol</i>.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Dilemma" was filmed on Colonial Street,
    part of Universal Studios backlot. The same location is used
    during filming of 
    <i>Desperate Housewives</i>. Nelly can actually be seen sitting
    on the stairs of the Johnson Home (which is Susan's house in
    the series), while Rowland arrives to, and sits at the stairs
    of, the Morrison Home. Delta House and Allison House
    (accordingly, on the show as Ida Greenberg's and the Solis
    family's houses) can be seen in the background during night
    shots of Rowland and Nelly dancing together. New York Knicks'
    guard Larry Hughes makes a cameo in the video as Rowland's
    boyfriend. Nelly's track "Nellyville" from the same album is
    played as the intro to the video during the first seconds.</p>
      <p>Patti LaBelle also plays a part in the music video, as
    Rowland's mother.</p>
      <p>The official remix is produced by Jermaine Dupri and
    features Kelly Rowland &amp; Ali of the St. Lunatics. It is
    included in Nelly's remix album, "Da Derrty Versions: The
    Reinvention".</p>
      <p>On December 16th, 2009 Nelly recorded a new track titled
    ‘Gone’ with Kelly Rowland which he dubbed "Dilemma Part 2" the
    sequel to the smash hit. The track is produced by Jim Jonsin
    and written by Rico Love and is intended to be put of Nelly's
    latest album.</p>
      <p>It is the most successful song of Nelly's career, giving him
    his first number-one single in many countries, such as the
    United Kingdom, Australia, Belgium, Germany, Ireland, The
    Netherlands, Switzerland.</p>
      <p>The single became a hit in the late summer/early fall of
    2002 in the US. Before "Hot In Herre" had even peaked on the
    charts, radio stations already began playing "Dilemma" in July
    2002. It quickly climbed up the US charts and replaced "Hot in
    Herre" at number one after seven weeks on the Hot 100, giving
    Nelly his second consecutive number one from 
    <i>Nellyville</i>. The song had already reached number one on
    the Hot 100 before a video was ever shot as Nelly's record
    label did not expect the song to explode so fast and expected
    they could take their time with the video.</p>
      <p>These are the major formats for "Dilemma" :</p>
      <p>US Vinyl, 12", Promo</p>
      <p>UK Promo CD</p>
      <p>UK Maxi-CD</p>
      <p>UK Vinyl, 12"</p>
      <p>Europe Single</p>
      <p>Europe Maxi-CD</p>
      <p>Europe Maxi-CD #2</p>
      <p>The song has been a merengue version of the song in Spanish
    done by Papi Sanchez, under the title "Dilema". This version
    was released in March 2005 as second single form his album 
    <i>Enamorame</i>. It was a minor hit in comparison with the
    original version.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
