<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Promiscuous_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Promiscuous_(song)</songId>
   <title>Promiscuous</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nelly_Furtado</artistId>
      <artistName>Nelly Furtado featuring Timbaland</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2006-07-08</week>
      <week>2006-07-15</week>
      <week>2006-07-22</week>
      <week>2006-07-29</week>
      <week>2006-08-05</week>
      <week>2006-08-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/5d/NellyPromiscuous.jpg/200px-NellyPromiscuous.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Nelly-Furtado-featuring-Timbaland+Promiscuous.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Loose</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 2006  (2006-04) , (See release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
      <format>vinyl single</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Miami , Florida ; 2005</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rap</genre>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:02 (album version)</length>
      <length>3:41 (radio edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Geffen</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Nelly Furtado</writer>
      <writer>Timothy Clayton</writer>
      <writer>Nate Hills</writer>
      <writer>Tim Mosley</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Timbaland</producer>
      <producer>Danja</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Promiscuous" (also known as "Promiscuous Girl") is a song
    recorded by singer Nelly Furtado and Timbaland for Furtado's
    third album, 
    <i>Loose</i>(2006). Furtado, Timothy "Attitude" Clayton,
    Timbaland and Danja wrote the song, and Timbaland and Danja
    produced it. The song lyrics feature a conversation between a
    man and woman who call each other a "promiscuous" boy or
    girl.</p>
      <p>"Promiscuous" was released as the first single from 
    <i>Loose</i>in North America in early 2006, and as the second
    single elsewhere in mid-2006 except in Latin America, where the
    single was released as the third single in late 2006. The song
    received positive reviews and became Furtado's first number-one
    single in United States. It won in the Best Pop Song category
    at the 2006 Billboard Music Awards, was nominated for the Best
    Pop Collaboration with Vocals Grammy Award at the 49th Annual
    Grammy Awards and won Single of the Year at the 2007 Juno
    Awards. The song got a number 3 on the Billboard Year-End Hot
    100 singles of 2006. It is the most recent track to top both
    the Billboard Hot 100 and Billboard Dance Club Play charts
    simultaneously.</p>
      <p>The lyrics of "Promiscuous" describe the two sides of the
    relationship that the song's protagonist deals with. It was one
    of the first songs Furtado wrote with labelmate Timothy
    "Attitude" Clayton. Furtado called their teamwork something she
    "had never done before" because she saw the writing process as
    "extremely freeing" because of his different approach and
    style. Clayton helped Furtado experiment with interpreting the
    "promiscuous girl" character and the two-sided relationship she
    is in. Furtado also described that in the process of writing
    lyrics "we were actually flirting, which is why the song is so
    playful" and that she and Clayton nicknamed the song "'The
    BlackBerry Song', because everything we say in the song you
    could text-message to somebody".</p>
      <p>Because of the preponderant musical influence of artists
    such as Talking Heads, Blondie, Madonna, The Police and
    Eurythmics, whom producers Timbaland and Danja listened to
    during the writing of the album, "Promiscuous" takes
    inspiration from pop music of the 1980s. The sexuality was
    based on the "strong women in control" of the 1990s, such as
    Queen Latifah, MC Lyte, Yo-Yo, Salt-N-Pepa and TLC.</p>
      <p>A reference to basketball player Steve Nash in the song's
    lyrics led to speculation that he and Furtado were romantically
    involved, but both deny the link, with Nash commenting, "I'm
    flattered that she put me in her song, but I'm completely in
    love with my wife and two little baby girls". Furtado decided
    to include him because she and Nash are both from Victoria,
    British Columbia, and due to frequent citations of
    basketballers in songs, she decided to "give him the
    props".</p>
      <p>In one of the verses Timbaland introduces himself as Thomas
    Crown. 
    <i>The Thomas Crown Affair</i>is a film about wealthy
    businessman who plays a cat-and-mouse/flirting game with an
    insurance investigator.</p>
      <p>Timbaland only performed the song live on special occasions,
    such as Furtado's appearance on 
    <i>Saturday Night Live</i>, and the 2006 MuchMusic Video
    Awards. Starting with Furtado's show at the 94th Grey Cup on
    November 19, 2006, and extending into the Get Loose Tour,
    Timbaland's part is filled in by Canadian rapper Saukrates.</p>
      <p>"Promiscuous" was well received by music critics. Rob
    Sheffield of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>considered it a highlight in Loose.
    Timbaland's appearance received particular praise, which added
    Furtado's "high-school musical vocals" over his eighty beats
    according to Sheffield. 
    <i>Allmusic</i>reviewer Stephen Thomas Erlewine compared it to
    "vintage Prince", citing "Promiscuous" as a highlight of
    Furtado's makeover. However, Erlewine believed that no matter
    how much Furtado sings about sex, she does not sound sexy and
    does not "generate much carnal heat."</p>
      <p>IGN review considered the song "simultaneously annoying and
    yet catchy beyond belief" and listed as one of 
    <i>Loose's</i>"Definitely Downloads", Pitchfork Media called it
    "one of the best vocal performances of his [Timbaland's]
    career", and 
    <i>Billboard</i>called the duo of Furtado and Timbaland "a
    surprisingly good match".</p>
      <p>The song was also included in three lists of best songs of
    2006: fourth on 
    <i>Blender</i>, sixth at 
    <i>The Village Voice'</i>s Pazz &amp; Jop, and 56th on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>.</p>
      <p>In Canada, the song's music video debuted on MuchMusic's 
    <i>MuchOnDemand</i>after an interview with Furtado on May 8,
    2006. On May 4, 2006, "Promiscuous" debuted inside the top five
    on the Canadian Singles Chart, and on June 1, it became
    Furtado's second Canadian number-one single. After descending
    from the top ten, it reascended to number two after the release
    of 
    <i>Loose</i>. "Promiscuous" spent twenty-five weeks on the
    Canadian Singles Chart, but was the year's shortest-running
    number-one single,but it became one of the biggest selling
    singles . The song peaked at number two on the BDS Airplay
    Chart and became one of Furtado's most successful single
    releases in her home country since "I'm Like a Bird", released
    in 2000.</p>
      <p>In the U.S. "Promiscuous" entered the Hot 100 at number
    sixty-four, the week's highest debut. It topped the chart for
    six weeks, from July 8, 2006, and it became Furtado's first
    U.S. number-one single. The song topped 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Hot Dance Club Play and Pop 100 charts and
    reached the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs top forty. On the 
    <i>Billboard</i>year-end chart it was ranked third, the highest
    placing for a single by a female artist. As of August, 2009,
    the song has so far sold over 2,504,000 digital downloads in
    the United States.</p>
      <p>"Promiscuous" debuted at number five on the Australian ARIA
    Charts and peaked at number two in its third week. It was
    released in Europe on August 18, 2006 and reached number three
    in the UK. On December 31, 2006 BBC Radio 1 reported that
    "Promiscuous" was the thirty-eighth highest selling single in
    the UK in 2006. The single re-entered the UK Singles Chart at
    number sixty-six in January 2007 because of The Official UK
    Charts Company's new rules. It made the top ten in most
    European nations.</p>
      <p>In Latin America, the single was released as the official
    third single, and in some countries the song was leaked to
    radio (in Peru, Colombia and Mexico). On December 4, 2006,
    "Promiscuous" won "Best Pop Single of the Year" at the 2006
    Billboard Music Awards, beating Daniel Powter's "Bad Day" and
    Sean Paul's "Temperature". The song was nominated for the "Best
    Pop Collaboration with Vocals" at the 49th Annual Grammy
    Awards, losing to Tony Bennett &amp; Stevie Wonder's "For Once
    in My Life".</p>
      <p>The song's music video was directed by Little X and features
    cameo appearances by Keri Hilson, Bria Myles and Justin
    Timberlake. It does not follow a storyline and per Furtado's
    request, focuses on scenes with dancing and flirting because
    she wanted to recreate the song's indicative vibe, and took the
    opportunity to film a club video for the first time. Furtado
    said of the video, "It's that whole dance that goes on. There's
    that mystery there, the fun, playful sexiness, the verbal
    Ping-Pong game". Furtado and Timbaland cannot decide whether
    they want to begin dating or instead flirt with others on the
    dance floor. Their single performances are intercut with
    several scenes of a dancing crowd, and the lighting changes
    between blue, green, red, and yellow colors.</p>
      <p>"Promiscuous" premiered on MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>on May 3, 2006, where it reached
    number one after spending twenty-one days on the countdown.
    After its debut on MuchMusic's 
    <i>Countdown</i>, it ascended to number one for the week of
    July 28, 2006. At the 2006 MTV Video Music Awards, it was
    nominated for the Best Dance, Female and Pop Video Awards. The
    video was parodied by 
    <i>MADtv</i>in a segment entitled "Syphilis Girl"; in the
    video, Furtado (Nicole Parker) is comically portrayed as having
    given Timbaland (Jordan Peele) the sexually transmitted
    disease, as well as on YouTube by the comedic group Train of
    Thought Sketch Comedy, where the video is parodied by troupe
    member Kaci and features a puppet version of Timbaland.</p>
      <p>These are the formats and track listings of major single
    releases of "Promiscuous".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
