<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Say_It_Right 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Say_It_Right</songId>
   <title>Say It Right</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nelly_Furtado</artistId>
      <artistName>Nelly Furtado</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2007-02-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/4b/SayitfightNF.jpg/200px-SayitfightNF.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Nelly-Furtado+Say-It-Right.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Loose</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 31, 2006 , (see release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>12" single</format>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
      <format>vinyl single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>The Hit Factory , Miami, Florida</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Urban Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:43 (Album version)</length>
      <length>3:34 (Radio edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Geffen</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Nelly Furtado</writer>
      <writer>Tim Mosley</writer>
      <writer>Nate Hills</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Timbaland</producer>
      <producer>Danja</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Say It Right" is a single released by Canadian singer Nelly
    Furtado. It was written by Nelly Furtado, Timothy "Timbaland"
    Mosley and Nate "Danja" Hills for Furtado's third album, 
    <i>Loose</i>(2006). It was co-produced by Timbaland and Danja
    and released as the album's third single in North America and
    Australia (see 2006 in music). The song served as the album's
    fourth single in certain European and Asian countries. It was
    released digitally in the United Kingdom in March 2007. It was
    the album's fifth single in Latin America.</p>
      <p>"Say It Right" received positive reviews from critics
    praising its high quality production as well as commenting on
    the lyrical content and Furtado's vocal performance. The song
    attained worldwide success, topping the charts in more than
    thirty countries including the United States, Spain, France,
    New Zealand, Canada and many European countries. The
    accompanying music video for the song portrays Furtado singing
    it in various costumes and various locations. The song has been
    performed on a number of live appearances by Furtado including
    her third headlining Get Loose tour.</p>
      <p>The process of creating the song began in the recording
    studio one morning at around 4:00 a.m., when Timbaland
    recommended that Furtado go home because she was tired.
    Furtado, who had heard that the band U2 (a band she says she
    deeply admires) wrote many of their songs in the studio control
    room, said "Really? I'll show you", put on her hoodie and began
    to "jam". Nate Hills and Timbaland soon joined her, writing and
    producing as they went, and according to Furtado, this process
    intensified as she sang. The team used four microphones in the
    live room and moved them around during recording, about which
    Furtado said, "...when you listen to it—there's a lot of
    dimension. It kind of sounds like [Timbaland is] in another
    country". Afterwards, they picked the best vocals and
    "perfected" them, before inserting "reverbs and weird alien
    sounds" onto them. "[W]e experimented a lot with depth and
    different sounds", Furtado said of the making of the song.
    "[It] affected my vocals a whole lot." "Say It Right" is
    performed with a moderate techno groove and is written in F
    minor. It is set in common time; in 4/4 count. The chord
    progression is Fm–E♭–D♭–B♭m. Furtado's vocal range spans from
    Ab3 to F5. Furtado has cited the "spooky, keyboard-driven pop
    sound" of the band Eurythmics, particularly their 1983 song
    "Here Comes the Rain Again", as an influence on "Say It Right"
    and other tracks on 
    <i>Loose</i>. "I'm not 100 percent sure what ["Here Comes the
    Rain Again" is] about, but it always takes me away to another
    place, and I love it", she said.</p>
      <p>In fact the song deals with mystic or transcendental
    experiences as she explains in an interview in 2007. "It is a
    kind of a magical song. It has a mystery to it, that I have not
    quite figured out. It has a haunting twist to it." In other
    interviews she said that she does not really know what "Say It
    Right" is about, "but it captures the feeling I had when I
    wrote it, and it taps into this other sphere." In an interview
    for 
    <i>The Sunday Times</i>, it was mentioned that it is about her
    breakup with DJ Jasper Gahunia, the father of her daughter.</p>
      <p>Bloc Party covered the song on Jo Whiley's radio show on
    April 11, 2007. The song was played during the Miss Universe
    2007 Introductory Ceremony, the 2006 American Music Awards, and
    Concert for Diana.</p>
      <p>Dummies, Friscia &amp; Lamboy, Menage Music and Peter
    Rauhofer produced dance remixes of "Say It Right". Juan
    Martinez of Universal Music Group, the A&amp;R person who
    enlisted the producers of the remixes for each single from 
    <i>Loose</i>, said that the "Say It Right" remixes had received
    "the strongest reaction".</p>
      <p>Marie Digby did an acoustic version of "Say It Right", along
    with "All Good Things (Come to an End)". The videos are posted
    in YouTube. Bloc Party also did a cover version for "Say It
    Right". "Strictly Physical", a 2007 single by German pop group
    Monrose, has been compared to "Say It Right" and there have
    been countless mash-ups that successfully mix the two songs
    together. There is also a 'Reggae Main Mix' of "Say It Right",
    featuring reggae singer Courtney John. MTV Mash-Ups Volume 1
    features a mash-up of Robert Miles' Children with the Furtado's
    Say It Right lyrics, produced my Martinn. The track is titled
    "Robert Miles vs. Nelly Furtado - Children Say It Right
    [Martinn]"</p>
      <p>The music video for "Say It Right" was directed by British
    duo Rankin &amp; Chris and filmed in Los Angeles, California in
    late October 2006. It was shot back-to-back with the video for
    "All Good Things (Come to an End)", the album's third single in
    Europe. Furtado called the video her "first action thing" since
    the video for her 2000 single, "I'm like a Bird", and said that
    it featured her experiencing what she called "a total rock-star
    moment. It's so iconic." The mini-feathered cocktail dress
    Furtado wears at the opening of the video was designed
    specifically for her by Australian designer Alex Perry, who
    said, "It's so cool because she's just undergone a bit of a
    revamp from what her previous image was; she's become a little
    more sexy and glamorous."</p>
      <p>The clip starts with a helicopter landing on a black helipad
    bearing Furtado's name on top of a building, and Furtado
    getting out. She is shown on the roof of the building
    throughout the video, with the Los Angeles skyline in the
    background. The video features mostly face shots of her and
    Timbaland intercut with shots of dancers, under the careful
    guidance of internationally acclaimed Puerto Rican
    choreographer Gabriel Rivera. Furtado described the clip as "a
    throwback to the '80s ... the more surreal side" because the
    shots of her and Timbaland reminded her much of those of Annie
    Lennox and Dave Stewart in videos for Eurythmics' singles, and
    "the strange relationship [they] had, where ... you get this
    intense vibe from it. And Tim and me, we're partners, we vibe
    on a serious creative level, so the video captures that
    energy." The video ends with Furtado climbing back into the
    helicopter, which flies off.</p>
      <p>The video debuted on MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>in the U.S. on November 6 and on
    Canada's MuchMusic in the week ending November 16. It reached
    number nine on the 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>top ten video countdown on November 8,
    its first day on the countdown; it returned to the countdown on
    December 14 and peaked at number one twice. The video reached
    number one on the MuchMusic series 
    <i>Countdown</i>for the week ending February 16. The "Say It
    Right" video was retired from 
    <i>TRL</i>after spending forty days on the countdown. At the
    2007 MTV Video Music Awards, Furtado was nominated in the
    category of Female Artist of the Year for "Say It Right" and
    "Maneater". "Say It Right" was nominated for the MuchMoreMusic
    Award and in the Best International Video by a Canadian
    category at the 2007 MuchMusic Video Awards. MTV International
    certified the "Say It Right" video platinum for more than 6,000
    plays on the MTV network.</p>
      <p>"Say It Right" received positive reviews from critics
    praising its high quality production as well as commenting on
    the lyrical content and Furtado's vocal performance. Billboard
    magazine called the song "a Pussycat Dolls-inspired contempo
    jam, high on hooks and of-the-moment production. Well done, if
    in the most generic sense." About.com's Bill Lamb gave the song
    4/5 stars, saying that with "Say It Right", "many pop music
    fans are likely to take a second look at purchasing [
    <i>Loose</i>]". He described the song as "the foundation of 
    <i>Loose</i>" and "a welcomed presence in the pop top 40". IGN
    Music calls the song "...one of the brightest moments on the
    album" and "another throwback to the '80s" which "...lets loose
    with the most hypnotic chorus". Allmusic's Stephen Thomas
    Erlewine considered the song "a dark meditative piece that
    would have fit on [Furtado's] previous records". 
    <i>The New York Times</i>described the song as "building a
    groove from hard drums and ghostly, multitracked voices, and
    Ms. Furtado sings a melancholy chorus she doesn't quite
    believe", comparing the coda, with music getting louder and
    then slowly fading, "the way the best — and worst — nights out
    often do". John Jobling of Mansize.com suggests that "[I]t
    would take a man of stone to resist the song’s hypnotic pull,
    with the alien like synths, spooky reverb effects and
    Timbaland’s signature space hop percussion creating a
    gloriously atmospheric soundscape where the carnal and
    spiritual coexist in perfect harmony." Also, DJ Z's reviewed
    the song as "the only single in the world to work at both a
    club in Manhattan, and on an safari through the natives land of
    (fill in the blank)." UK music.com described the track as "an
    expectional track, that is filled with addictive beats and
    atmospheric synths."</p>
      <p>The song received a nomination for Best Female Pop Vocal
    Performance at the 50th Annual Grammy Awards, losing to Amy
    Winehouse's "Rehab". It was also nominated for and two
    MuchMusic Video Awards.</p>
      <p>In the United States, the song was made available for
    airplay at mainstream contemporary hit radio stations on
    October 30, 2006. Geffen Records withdrew from radio the second
    single from 
    <i>Loose</i>, "Maneater", before promoting "Say It Right". The
    song debuted on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Bubbling Under Hot 100 Singles chart at number
    twenty-two in the issue dated November 18. It entered the Hot
    100 in late-November at number ninety-three, and it reached
    number one in its fourteenth week, becoming Furtado's second
    number-one single after "Promiscuous" (2006). The song stayed
    at number one for one week, in the top ten for fourteen weeks
    and on the Hot 100 for thirty weeks. "Say It Right" contributed
    to sales of the album 
    <i>Loose</i>, and was credited as being responsible for its
    return to the top ten on the U.S. 200. According to Nielsen
    Broadcast Data Systems, "Say It Right" was the second
    most-played song on U.S. radio in 2007 with 364,000 plays
    through December 2, and it was at number four on 
    <i>R&amp;R</i>magazine's 2007 year-end all-format top 100 songs
    list. On the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 year-end chart, it was ranked ninth.
    The RIAA certified "Say It Right" platinum in December 2007. To
    date, "Say It Right" has been listened to more than 4 billion
    times in the U.S alone.</p>
      <p>"Say It Right" peaked at number one for ten weeks on the
    Canadian BDS Airplay Chart, which it entered in early December,
    becoming Furtado's second Canadian number-one single. According
    to BDS, it was the fourth most-played song of 2007 on Canadian
    radio, amassing around 56,900 detections. The song charted on
    the BDS Airplay Chart for sixty-two weeks. In April 2007, it
    became Furtado's second number-one single on the Canadian Dance
    Chart (after "Maneater"). "Say It Right" peaked at number two
    for three consecutive weeks on the Australian ARIA Singles
    Chart, giving 
    <i>Loose</i>a "second wind" on the albums chart, according to
    the 
    <i>Herald Sun</i>; ARIA accredited it as a platinum single.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom, "Say It Right" was issued as a
    digital download without the accompaniment of a physical
    release. 
    <i>Music Week</i>wrote that the concurrent download-only
    releases of "Say It Right" and Pink's "Leave Me Alone (I'm
    Lonely)" "[suggest] a trend of singles far into an album
    campaign being released digital-only", noting that "Say It
    Right" was the fourth single from 
    <i>Loose</i>and Pink's single was the fifth from its parent
    album. According to Universal Music Group commercial director
    Brian Rose, "Say It Right" was not released as a physical
    single because it was the fourth single from 
    <i>Loose</i>and there was not high demand from retailers for a
    physical release, but both parties were aiming for album sales.
    The single reached number ten on the UK Singles Chart in March
    2007, and by doing so, it broke the record for the highest
    chart placing for a download-only single, after chart
    regulations were changed to allow songs not accompanied by a
    physical format to chart. Since then, the record was broken by
    the Coldplay with their number-one hit "Viva la Vida". The
    popularity of "Say It Right" contributed to sales of 
    <i>Loose</i>in the UK, according to 
    <i>Music Week</i>, helping the album reach its highest chart
    position since its first week of release. The song was the
    twenty-ninth best-selling single of 2007 in the UK. The song
    also spent 37 weeks on the UK Singles Chart, which is twice as
    long as any other of Furtado's songs (23 of those in the top
    40).</p>
      <p>In France, the song debuted at number one with 8,100 copies
    sold on its release, becoming the lowest selling number-one in
    a week. In Germany, it debuted at number two, where it stayed
    for nine non-consecutive weeks, behind DJ Ötzi and Nik P.'s Ein
    Stern (...der deinen Namen trägt) which topped the German chart
    for several months. It became the fifth most successful song of
    2007 in Germany. In Russia, it peaked at number six on Russian
    Airplay Chart, remained in the chart for 80 weeks and have
    494,714 total plays. It was the most successful single of 2007
    in the European Hit Radio. In Spain, the song enjoyed a great
    success, reaching number one on the singles chart for
    two-consecutive weeks. The song became her fourth number one
    hit on the country after "Fotografía, "Te Busqué" and "All Good
    Things (Come to an End)".</p>
      <p>"Say It Right" is Nelly Furtado's most successful song in
    Australia, Austria, Romania, Russia, Switzerland and Sweden. It
    is Furtado's second most successful single in Norway, the
    Netherlands, France (after "All Good Things (Come to an End)").
    New Zealand (after "Turn Off the Light"), and United States
    (after "Promiscuous").</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
