<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Without_You_(Badfinger_song)#Harry_Nilsson_version 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Without_You_(Badfinger_song)#Harry_Nilsson_version</songId>
   <title>Without You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_Nilsson</artistId>
      <artistName>Nilsson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1972-02-19</week>
      <week>1972-02-26</week>
      <week>1972-03-04</week>
      <week>1972-03-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>No Dice</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 9, 1970  (1970-11-09)</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Power Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:43</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Apple</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Geoff Emerick</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>No Dice</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Without You" is a song written by musicians Pete Ham and
    Tom Evans of British rock group Badfinger. According to ASCAP,
    the ballad has been recorded by more than 180 artists and has
    made many appearances on the Billboard Hot 100, including the
    number one position. Beatle Paul McCartney once described the
    ballad as "...the killer song of all time.".</p>
      <p>First recorded by the rock group Badfinger, the song was
    composed by two of its members. Pete Ham had written a song
    originally titled "If It's Love" but it had lacked a strong
    chorus. Tom Evans had written a song during this same period
    but he was disappointed with the verse section, so the duo
    fused their pieces together. The protagonist of this ballad
    lets a lover know that he "can't live if living is without
    you." Both Ham and Evans said they did not consider the song to
    have much potential at the time Badfinger recorded it, and the
    track was slotted to close Side A of their 1970 
    <i>No Dice</i>album. Badfinger's recording of the song, which
    is more brusque than its successors' versions, was never
    released as a single. In parallel to the song lyrics, both Ham
    and Evans later committed suicide.</p>
      <p>Harry Nilsson, at the time best known for his hit
    "Everybody's Talkin'" and for composing such hits as Three Dog
    Night's "One", heard Badfinger's recording of "Without You" at
    a party, and mistook it for a Beatles song. After realizing it
    was not, he decided to cover the song for his album 
    <i>Nilsson Schmilsson</i>in 1971; it stayed at number 1 on the
    U.S. pop chart for four weeks, from February 13 to March 11,
    1972. The song also spent five weeks atop the U.S. adult
    contemporary chart. In the UK, the song spent five weeks at
    number 1 on the British pop chart, beginning on March 11, and
    sold almost 800,000 copies. The single was produced by Richard
    Perry, who later explained, "It was a different record for its
    time. It was a big ballad with a heavy backbeat, and although
    many artists have cut songs like it since, no one was doing it
    then." Gary Wright, then known as a member of the British group
    Spooky Tooth, and later a successful solo artist in his own
    right, played piano on the recording.</p>
      <p>While Nilsson rarely performed live, he did perform the song
    with Ringo Starr and his All-Starr Band at Caesar's Palace in
    Las Vegas in September 1992, and also performed the song with
    the house band, Liverpool, at various Beatlefest fan
    conventions.</p>
      <p>Mariah Carey's version was released as the third single off 
    <i>Music Box</i>in the first quarter of 1994, and in the United
    States it was released on January 24, 1994, just over a week
    after Nilsson had died following a heart attack on January 15,
    1994. In the U.S. it was promoted as a double A-side with
    "Never Forget You". In the song Carey dips into her lower
    register and is accompanied by backup singers (including
    herself) magnified to sound like a mighty gospel chorus. Carey
    said that she decided to cover the song when she heard it in a
    restaurant. Her version has been considered very popular on
    talent shows. "Without You" was later included on some non-U.S.
    pressings of her compilation album 
    <i>#1's</i>(1998).</p>
      <p>"Without You" reached number 3 on the Billboard Hot 100,
    remaining in the top forty for twenty-one weeks and on the
    chart for twenty-three. It reached number 2 on the Billboard
    Hot 100 Airplay and number 3 on the Hot 100 Singles Sales. Both
    radio airplay and sales were strong, and it was certified gold
    by the RIAA. It was ranked 16 on the Hot 100 1994 year-end
    charts.</p>
      <p>"Without You" remains Carey's biggest hit outside the U.S.,
    being largely successful across Europe. It became her first UK
    number 1 single, and still remains her only number 1 there as a
    solo artist. It debuted at number 1 on the chart and stayed at
    number 1 for four weeks. It was also her first chart-topper in
    Italy, but was most successful in Switzerland (with ten
    non-consecutive weeks at number 1) and the Netherlands (twelve
    weeks). It also topped the singles chart in Germany for four
    weeks and Austria for eight weeks, where Carey's success had
    previously been limited. It also topped the Swedish Singles
    Chart for eight weeks, was number 1 in Ireland for five weeks
    and in New Zealand for one week. It was able to make the top
    three in Canada, France, Norway and Australia. It was certified
    platinum in Australia by ARIA and in Germany and Austria by
    IFPI. It was also certified gold in the United Kingdom by BPI,
    in New Zealand by RIANZ and in France by SNEP.</p>
      <p>On 15 May 1995, ASCAP held its twelfth annual Pop Music
    Awards in Beverly Hills, California, and "Without You" was
    recognized as one of the 50 most-played songs of 1994 (due
    largely to Carey's recording). Discrepancies in ASCAP's books
    incorrectly attributed the song as being composed not only by
    Ham and Evans, but also by Badfinger's other bandmembers, Mike
    Gibbins and Joey Molland, and their former manager, Bill
    Collins. This designation and a lack of correction by ASCAP
    prompted the Ham Estate to boycott the ceremony. The song was
    also nominated for "Song Of The Year" in London at the Ivor
    Novello Awards.</p>
      <p>Worldwide CD single</p>
      <p>European maxi-CD single #1</p>
      <p>European maxi-CD single #2</p>
      <p>In the film 
    <i>The Rules of Attraction</i>, a college girl commits suicide
    in a bathtub while this song plays on the soundtrack.</p>
      <p>Nilsson's version of "Without You" was also used as the
    opening tune to 1979's 
    <i>Porridge</i>feature film.</p>
      <p>In the film 
    <i>Casino</i>, the Harry Nilsson version is playing during one
    of Ginger's manic episodes.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
