<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_Purple_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_Purple_(song)</songId>
   <title>Deep Purple</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nino_Tempo</artistId>
      <artistName>Nino Tempo and April Stevens</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1963-11-16</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Deep Purple" [1] was the biggest hit written by pianist
    Peter DeRose, who broadcast, 1923 to 1939, with May Singhi as
    "The Sweethearts of the Air" on the NBC radio network. "Deep
    Purple" was published in 1933 as a piano composition. The
    following year, Paul Whiteman had it scored for his suave "big
    band" orchestra that was "making a lady out of jazz" in
    Whiteman's phrase. "Deep Purple" became so popular in sheet
    music sales that Mitchell Parish added lyrics in 1938:</p>
      <p>Larry Clinton and His Orchestra recorded the one of the most
    popular versions of the song. Featuring vocalist Bea Wain, the
    Clinton version was a huge hit. Released in December 1938 on
    Victor Records, the Clinton recording was number one on the
    U.S. popular music charts for nine consecutive weeks in 1939.
    The next one popular version was made Artie Shaw with vocalist
    Helen Forrest. The song is a sentimental ballad. The tune was a
    favorite of Babe Ruth, and Peter DeRose performed the song at
    Ruth's birthday parties for about a decade. The song remained a
    traditional pop favourite, recast in 1957 as a doo wop classic
    by The Dominoes with vocals by Eugene Mumford. Screamin' Jay
    Hawkins (best remembered for his song "I Put A Spell On You")
    also released his version of "Deep Purple" on his 1958 album,
    "At Home with Screamin' Jay."</p>
      <p>The second most popular version, which hit number one on the
    U.S. pop charts in November 1963 and also won that year's
    Grammy for best rock &amp; roll record, was recorded by Nino
    Tempo &amp; April Stevens (who were brother and sister). This
    version of the song is notable for April Stevens' speaking the
    lyrics in a low and sweet voice during the second half of the
    song while her brother sings. According to the 
    <i>Billboard Book of Number One Hits</i>by Fred Bronson, when
    the duo first recorded the song as a demo, Tempo forgot the
    words, and Stevens spoke the lyrics to the song to remind him.
    The record's producers thought Stevens' spoken interludes were
    "cute" and should be included on the finished product, but
    according to Stevens, her brother was not as easily convinced:
    "He didn't want anyone talking while he was singing!"</p>
      <p>Interestingly, the Nino Tempo/April Stevens version was
    intended to be the flip side of a song called "I've Been
    Carrying A Torch For You So Long That I Burned A Great Big Hole
    In My Heart." However, radio stations preferred "Deep Purple,"
    and according to Bronson, "I've Been Carrying A Torch..." holds
    the distinction of being the longest title of a flip side of a
    Billboard number one record. Despite being considered "rock and
    roll," the song did also reach number one on Billboard's Adult
    Contemporary singles chart in 1963.</p>
      <p>Another brother-and-sister team, Donny and Marie Osmond,
    revived "Deep Purple" in March 1976 and took it into the Top
    20, peaking at #14 on the Billboard Hot 100 with Marie intoning
    the balmy lyrics during the break, as April Stevens had done in
    the Nino Tempo/April Stevens version. As an interesting aside,
    the song that succeeded the Tempo/Stevens version of "Deep
    Purple" at number one on the Billboard chart, "I'm Leaving It
    Up To You" by Dale &amp; Grace, was also a hit over a decade
    later in a cover version by Donny &amp; Marie (in 1974).</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
