<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_Rollercoaster 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_Rollercoaster</songId>
   <title>Love Rollercoaster</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ohio_Players</artistId>
      <artistName>Ohio Players</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1976-01-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Honey</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1975</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:52 (Single version)</length>
      <length>4:50 (Album version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Mercury Records</label>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Honey</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Love Rollercoaster" is a song by American funk/R&amp;B band
    The Ohio Players, originally featured on their 1975 album 
    <i>Honey</i>. The song was a hit upon its initial release,
    reaching the top of both the R&amp;B and pop charts, and still
    sees wide airplay on classic funk and R&amp;B stations. The
    song uses the roller coaster, a common theme park attraction,
    as a metaphor for the ups and downs of dating and romantic
    relationships.</p>
      <p>While the song is known within the music community for its
    distinctive and influential sound, within the popular
    imagination it remains best identified with a persistent urban
    legend. During an instrumental portion of the song, a
    high-pitched scream is heard (between 1:24 and 1:28 on the
    single version, or between 2:32 and 2:36 on the album version);
    this was Billy Beck, but according to the most common legend,
    it was the voice of an individual being murdered live while the
    tape was rolling. The "victim's" identity varies greatly
    depending on the version. The supposed sources of the scream
    have included an individual who was killed at some prior time,
    her scream inexplicably recorded and looped into the track.
    Another version tells of a rabbit being killed outside the
    studio whose scream was accidentally picked up by the band's
    recording equipment - highly implausible, since professional
    recording studios are soundproof. The most widespread version
    of the myth, however, tells that Ester Cordet, who appeared
    nude on the 
    <i>Honey</i>album cover, had been badly burned by the
    super-heated honey used for the photo shoot, which occurred
    simultaneous with the recording session, and her agonized
    screams were inadvertently captured on tape. A further
    variation had Cordet suffering permanent disfigurement due to
    the burns; she interrupted the band's recording session,
    threatening to sue, at which point the band's manager stabbed
    her to death in the control room. Both of the latter two
    scenarios, however, are impossible as Ester Cordet is still
    alive.</p>
      <p>Casey Kasem reported the urban myth of the woman being
    killed in the studio recording booth on his radio show,
    American Top 40, when the song was on the charts in 1976.</p>
      <p>Jimmy "Diamond" Williams explained that the scream was
    nothing eerie or disturbing:</p>
      <p>"Love Rollercoaster" was covered by the Red Hot Chili
    Peppers in 1996, with lead singer Anthony Kiedis adding a rap
    to the song, and the horn section replaced with an
    approximation played on kazoos. Their version appeared on the
    soundtrack of the animated film 
    <i>Beavis and Butt-head Do America</i>. There was also an
    animated music video that was made for the song, featuring
    Beavis, Butt-head, and the band riding an amusement park roller
    coaster, intercut with scenes from the film. The song is played
    early in the movie itself, when Beavis and Butt-head arrive in
    Las Vegas. In the dance hall scene, a fictional funk band is
    shown performing the song live (the one appearing on the
    background of the single cover).</p>
      <p>The song was featured briefly in the film 
    <i>Urban Legend</i>, where a reference is made to the myth
    associated with it.</p>
      <p>It makes a more prominent appearance in the third film where
    Ashley (Chelan Simmons) and Ashlyn (Crystal Lowe) are listening
    to it on an iPod, during the scene where the two characters are
    killed in a tanning salon. It references the fateful
    rollercoaster ride that begins the film, a ride they should
    have died on.</p>
      <p>The Red Hot Chili Peppers version of the song was featured
    in the movie 
    <i>After The Sunset</i>.</p>
      <p>This song was used in the Nickelodeon series 
    <i>The Adventures of Pete &amp; Pete</i>during a band
    scene.</p>
      <p>The song was also in 
    <i>The Bernie Mac Show</i>episode "Now You Got It" during the
    scene where Bryana was having her party and the kids were
    passing germs along the way.</p>
      <p>This song is played in the movie Johnson's Family Vacation,
    when the family is being stalked by a Pampers Semi-Truck.</p>
      <p>A cover version of the song, based on the Red Hot Chili
    Peppers version, is featured in the Nintendo Wii game 
    <i>Boogie</i>. Some of the more sexually suggestive lyrics were
    changed.</p>
      <p>The song was sampled by Rodney O &amp; Joe Cooley in their
    1991 song 
    <i>Get Ready to Roll</i>, by Da Hool in 
    <i>Meet her at the Love Parade</i>, by TTC in 
    <i>Travailler</i>, by Federico Franchi in 
    <i>Cream</i>, and by Pitbull in 
    <i>Krazy</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was also played in the movie Semi-Pro.</p>
      <p>The original version featured on the 2004 video game 
    <i>Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas</i>soundtrack on the game's
    funk radio station Bounce FM, where the DJ claims the scream in
    the song is the result of him "exposing himself".</p>
      <p>The Ohio Players' version was used in a Suzuki Jimny advert
    during the mid 2000s.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
