<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physical_(Olivia_Newton-John_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Physical_(Olivia_Newton-John_song)</songId>
   <title>Physical</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Olivia_Newton-John</artistId>
      <artistName>Olivia Newton-John</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1981-11-21</week>
      <week>1981-11-28</week>
      <week>1981-12-05</week>
      <week>1981-12-12</week>
      <week>1981-12-19</week>
      <week>1981-12-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/e/ed/Physical.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Olivia-Newton-John+Physical.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Physical</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 1981</released>
   <recorded>January 1981</recorded>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:45</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Steve Kipner and Terry Shaddick</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>John Farrar</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Physical" is a 1981 song written by Steve Kipner and Terry
    Shaddick and performed by Olivia Newton-John.</p>
      <p>Recorded in early 1981, it first rose to number one on the
    Billboard Hot 100 in America in November 1981 and stayed there
    for 10 weeks, until near the end of January 1982. In terms of
    chart placement, it was the most popular single of her career,
    as well as her final number-one (to date). Billboard ranked it
    as the number one pop single of 1982 (since the chart year for
    1982 actually began in November 1981), and it was also the most
    successful song on the Hot 100 during the entire decade of the
    1980s. The famous guitar solo is performed by Toto's guitarist
    Steve Lukather.</p>
      <p>"Physical" was both preceded and followed in the #1 chart
    position by recordings of the duo Hall &amp; Oates. "Private
    Eyes" yielded its top spot to "Physical" in November 1981, and
    "Physical" yielded to "I Can't Go for That (No Can Do)" the
    following January.</p>
      <p>The single, slightly edgier than she had been known for in
    the past (such as her songs from 
    <i>Grease</i>and her country-pop ballad "I Honestly Love You"),
    proved to be immensely popular both in America and in the
    United Kingdom, despite the fact that the song was censored and
    even banned by some radio stations, particularly Adult
    Contemporary stations; in spite of Newton-John's status as the
    reigning queen of soft-rock music at the time, "Physical"
    peaked at only number twenty-nine on the AC chart (its
    follow-up, the slightly softer-edged "Make a Move on Me," found
    more acceptance at AC radio and went to number six AC as well
    as number five pop.) The song was a big dance hit and spawned a
    music video. The revamped acoustic version of the song was
    released on the 2002 Olivia duet album 
    <i>(2)</i>as a bonus track.</p>
      <p>The song ranks at #6 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top 100.</i>[1]</p>
      <p>After more than 28 years from its official release, the song
    was ranked #1 on Billboard's 
    <i>Top 50 Sexiest Songs Of All Time.</i>
      </p>
      <p>The video featured a lusty Olivia, dressed in a tight
    leotard, working out in a gym with several overweight men, who
    eventually transform into attractive muscular young men. The
    gym setting may have been partly an attempt to divert attention
    from the overt sexual connotations of the term "physical". This
    was further emphasised by the twist comedy ending of the video,
    when the transformed men who are now oblivious to Newton-John's
    advances are ultimately revealed to be gay (this was also a
    source of controversy; MTV frequently cut the ending when it
    aired the video, and the sometimes sensuous nature of the video
    also led to it being banned outright by some broadcasters in
    Canada and the United Kingdom). The video won a Grammy Award
    for Video Of The Year in 1983. The song was banned in South
    Africa for its suggestive lyrics.</p>
      <p>Like her first number-one single, "Physical" sold over two
    million copies, being certified platinum.</p>
      <p>The video was featured on 
    <i>Pop-Up Video</i>on VH1.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
