<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/(Sittin%27_On)_The_Dock_of_the_Bay 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/(Sittin%27_On)_The_Dock_of_the_Bay</songId>
   <title>(Sittin' On) The Dock of the Bay</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Otis_Redding</artistId>
      <artistName>Otis Redding</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1968-03-16</week>
      <week>1968-03-23</week>
      <week>1968-03-30</week>
      <week>1968-04-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/5/55/Dockofthebay.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Otis-Redding+Sittin-On-The-Dock-of-the-Bay.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Dock of the Bay</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 8, 1968</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl record</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Stax Studios, Memphis, Tennessee : November 22 and December 8, 1967</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:38</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Volt / Atco , V-157</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Otis Redding</writer>
      <writer>Steve Cropper</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Steve Cropper</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"(Sittin' On) The Dock of the Bay" is a song co-written by
    soul singer Otis Redding and guitarist Steve Cropper. It was
    first recorded by Otis Redding in 1967, shortly before his
    death. It was released posthumously on Stax Records' Volt label
    in 1968, becoming the first posthumous number-one single in
    U.S. chart history.</p>
      <p>While on tour with the Bar-Kays in August 1967, Redding
    wrote the first verse of the song, under the abbreviated title
    "Dock of the Bay," on a houseboat at Waldo Point in Sausalito,
    California. He had come off his famed performance at the
    Monterey Pop Festival just months earlier in June 1967. While
    touring in support of the LPs 
    <i>King &amp; Queen</i>(collaborations with female vocalist
    Carla Thomas) and his live set 
    <i>Live in Europe</i>, he continued to scribble lines of the
    song on napkins and hotel paper. In November of that year he
    joined producer and guitarist Steve Cropper at the Stax
    recording studio in Memphis, Tennessee.</p>
      <p>In a 1990 interview on NPR's 
    <i>Fresh Air</i>, Cropper explained the "origins" of the
    song:</p>
      <p>Together, they completed the music and melancholy lyrics of
    "(Sittin' On) The Dock of the Bay." From those sessions emerged
    Otis Redding's final recordings, including "Dock of the Bay,"
    which was recorded on November 22, with additional overdubs on
    December 8. Redding's restrained yet emotive delivery is backed
    by Cropper's memorably succinct guitar playing. The song is
    somewhat different in style from most of Redding's other
    recordings, but one with which he was very pleased. While
    discussing his latest song with his wife, Redding stated that
    he wanted to "be a little different" with "The Dock of the Bay"
    and "change his style". There were concerns that "The Dock of
    the Bay" had too much of a pop feel for an Otis Redding record,
    and contracting Stax gospel act The Staples Singers to
    recording backing vocals was discussed, but never carried
    out.</p>
      <p>Redding continued to tour after the recording sessions and,
    on December 10, the charter plane which was carrying him
    crashed into Lake Monona, outside Madison, Wisconsin. Redding
    and six others were killed. Only one passenger survived, Ben
    Cauley of The Bar-Kays. Redding's body was recovered from the
    lake the day after the crash.</p>
      <p>"(Sittin' On) The Dock of the Bay" was released in January
    1968 amid the fall-out of Redding's death. R&amp;B stations
    readily added the song to their playlists, which had been
    saturated with Redding's previous hits. The song shot to number
    one on the R&amp;B charts in early 1968. By early summer of
    that year, "Dock of the Bay" topped the pop charts. The album,
    which shared the song's title, was released and became his
    largest selling to date, peaking at number four on the Pop
    Albums chart. "Dock of the Bay" went on to gain success in
    countries across the world, and brought Redding the greatest
    success of his career. The song went on to win two Grammy
    Awards: Best R&amp;B Song (for songwriting) and Best Male
    R&amp;B Vocal Performance (for vocals).</p>
      <p>Redding's body of work at the time of his death was immense,
    including a backlog of archived recordings and the recordings
    done in November and December 1967 just before his death. In
    mid-1968, Stax Records severed its distribution contract with
    Atlantic Records, who retained the label's back catalog and the
    rights to the unreleased Otis Redding masters. Through its Atco
    and Reprise subsidiaries (Atco had distributed Otis Redding's
    releases from Stax's Volt label), Atlantic issued three more
    albums of new Redding material, two live albums, and eight 45
    RPM singles between 1968 and 1970. Both studio albums and
    anthologies sold well in America and abroad. Redding was
    especially successful in the United Kingdom, where 
    <i>The Dock of the Bay</i>went to number one, and the following
    album, a greatest hits LP entitled 
    <i>History of Otis Redding</i>, reached number two (in the
    U.S., 
    <i>History of Otis Redding</i>preceded 
    <i>The Dock of the Bay</i>in release order).</p>
      <p>"The Dock of the Bay" itself has been immensely popular,
    even after its stay at the top of the charts. It has been
    featured on various soundtracks, including the 1986 blockbuster
    
    <i>Top Gun</i>. The song has come to represent the decade of
    its creation, and it has been covered by many artists, from his
    peers like Glen Campbell, Percy Sledge and Sam &amp; Dave to
    artists of various genres, including Jimmy Velvit (whose cover
    version was included on his 2001 Grammy nominated album 
    <i>Sun Sea &amp; Sand)</i>, Widespread Panic (2006), Willie
    Nelson, Kenny Rankin, Dennis Brown, Michael Bolton (whose cover
    version of the song reached #11 on the Billboard Hot 100 chart
    in 1988), Pearl Jam, The Format, Brent Smith of Shinedown
    (during an acoustic set in 2008), Sammy Hagar (1979), Justin
    Nozuka (2007) and Sara Bareilles (2008). Cat Power's "You May
    Know Him" (from her 1998 album 
    <i>Moon Pix</i>) seems to be inspired by the melody of "The
    Dock of the Bay." In 1999, BMI named the song as the sixth-most
    performed song of the 20th century, with about six million
    performances. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>ranked Redding's album, 
    <i>The Dock of the Bay</i>number 161 on its 500 Greatest Albums
    of All Time, the third of five Redding albums that made the
    list. "(Sittin' On) The Dock of the Bay" was ranked
    twenty-eighth on Rolling Stone's 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time, the second highest of four Redding songs on the list,
    after "Respect".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
