<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ms._Jackson 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ms._Jackson</songId>
   <title>Ms. Jackson</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OutKast</artistId>
      <artistName>OutKast</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2001-02-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/37/Ms._Jackson.jpg/200px-Ms._Jackson.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/OutKast+Ms-Jackson.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Stankonia</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 2, 2001</released>
   <formats>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2000</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Alternative Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:30 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>4:03 (Radio Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Arista</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>André Benjamin</writer>
      <writer>Antwan Patton</writer>
      <writer>David Sheats</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Earthtone III</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Ms. Jackson" is a song by OutKast and the second single
    from their fourth album 
    <i>Stankonia</i>. It topped the U.S. charts for the week of
    February 17, 2001, and won a 2002 Grammy Award for Best Rap
    Performance by a Duo or Group. It also reached number one in
    Germany and number two in the United Kingdom, held from the top
    spot by Atomic Kitten's "Whole Again".</p>
      <p>The titular "Ms. Jackson" is the real-life mother of Erykah
    Badu, André 3000's ex-girlfriend and the mother of his son
    Seven. The song discusses the problems that break-ups,
    separation, and divorce can have on a couple, and the animosity
    that a woman's mother can have for her daughter's former
    boyfriend or husband.</p>
      <p>The single helped sell the album following mixed reaction to
    the lead single "B.O.B.", which failed to chart on the U.S. Hot
    100 and only reached #69 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs chart.</p>
      <p>The song samples "Strawberry Letter 23" by The Brothers
    Johnson (with pitch shifting and reversing) and features an
    altered version of a tune from "Bridal Chorus" from the opera 
    <i>Lohengrin</i>by German composer Richard Wagner (also known
    as the "wedding march"), played on piano.</p>
      <p>OutKast performed the song for pop singer Janet Jackson in
    tribute to her on MTV's 
    <i>MTV Icon</i>in 2001, replacing the lyric "I'm sorry, Ms.
    Jackson" with "We love you, Ms. Jackson".</p>
      <p>The video for "Ms. Jackson", directed by F. Gary Gray,
    features the two members of Outkast in an old house. Big Boi is
    cleaning a car, and Andre is making home improvements. The
    house is overrun with pets, mostly dogs, a cat, a snapping
    turtle, and an owl that, at times, seem to contribute to the
    song. Through camera effects, the pets are made to nod their
    heads to the song.</p>
      <p>Soon it begins to rain, spoiling Big Boi's hard work. The
    light rain rapidly turns into a storm, lightning strikes the
    car and it explodes. Meanwhile, Andre attempts to keep the
    house, which has a roof littered with leaks, dry with the use
    of buckets. Big Boi attempts to climb the roof and fix the
    holes in the rain.</p>
      <p>The lights go out in the house, creating yet another problem
    for Andre, who runs about trying to fix it. Big Boi, in a
    yellow raincoat, is on top of the roof and getting considerably
    more annoyed with his inability to complete the repairs.</p>
      <p>The lights however, eventually return. Big Boi climbs down
    and joins Andre, helping with the rainwater. But the storm,
    ironically, clears almost instantly. The two stare up through a
    ceiling hole torn open by the storm, at the bright blue sky and
    shining sun.</p>
      <p>The video works as a possible metaphor for the two artists'
    "stormy" relationships with the mothers of their children and
    their families (themes expressed by both artists in the song).
    The storm theme is alluded to in the song, particularly by
    Andre 3000:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
