<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hey_Ya! 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hey_Ya!</songId>
   <title>Hey Ya!</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OutKast</artistId>
      <artistName>OutKast</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2003-12-13</week>
      <week>2003-12-20</week>
      <week>2003-12-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e4/OutkastHeyYa.jpg/200px-OutkastHeyYa.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/OutKast+Hey-Ya.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Speakerboxxx/The Love Below</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 9, 2003  (2003-09-09)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
      <format>12" vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2002: Stankonia Studios, Tree Sound Studios, Larrabee Sound Studios</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:55</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>LaFace</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>André 3000</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>André 3000</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Hey Ya!" is a song written and produced by André 3000 for
    his 2003 album 
    <i>The Love Below</i>, part of the hip hop duo OutKast's double
    album 
    <i>Speakerboxxx/The Love Below</i>. The song takes influence
    from funk and rock music. A music video was produced featuring
    André 3000 as eight different versions of himself, playing on
    comparisons to The Beatles by mimicking their 1964 performance
    on 
    <i>The Ed Sullivan Show</i>. The song received praise from
    contemporary music critics, and it won a Grammy Award for Best
    Urban/Alternative Performance at the 46th Grammy Awards.</p>
      <p>Along with "The Way You Move", recorded by OutKast's other
    member Big Boi, "Hey Ya!" was released by LaFace Records in
    September 2003 as one of the album's two lead singles. It
    became a commercial success, reaching the top five of most of
    the charts it entered, and topping the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 and the ARIA Singles Chart, among
    others. Later it was named the 20th most successful song of the
    2000s, on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade. The song
    popularized the phrase "shake it like a Polaroid picture" in
    popular culture, and the Polaroid Corporation used the song to
    revitalize the public's perception of its products.</p>
      <p>André 3000 first began work on "Hey Ya!" in December 2002 at
    Stankonia Studios in Atlanta, Georgia. He used an acoustic
    guitar for accompaniment, inspired by bands such as the
    Ramones, Buzzcocks, and The Smiths. Already having visualized
    most of the song, he recorded the introduction, the first
    verse, and the hook. André began recording the vocals during
    this time, doing several dozen takes. He returned to work on
    the song several evenings later, with session musician Kevin
    Kendricks performing the bassline on a synthesizer.</p>
      <p>Several months later, André 3000 worked with Pete Novak at
    the Larrabee Sound Studios in Los Angeles, California. André
    improvised the lyrics based on a screenplay that he had
    written. They experimented with various sound effects,
    including singing through a vocoder, and did 30 to 40 takes for
    each line.</p>
      <p>"Hey Ya!" is a song in the key of G major. Each cadential
    six-measure phrase is constructed using a change of meter on
    the fourth measure and uses a I–IV–V–VI chord progression. G
    major and C major chords are played for one and two 4/4
    measures respectively. André 3000 then uses a deceptive cadence
    after a 2/4 measure of the dominant D major chord, leading into
    two 4/4 measures of an E major chord. The song moves at 160
    beats per minute, and André's vocal range spans more than an
    octave and a half, from B
    <sub>3</sub>to G
    <sub>5</sub>.</p>
      <p>The song opens with three upbeats as André 3000 counts "one,
    two, three" and then leads into the first verse. The lyrics
    begin to describe the persona's concerns and doubts about a
    romantic relationship. He wonders if they are staying together
    just "for tradition," as in the lines "But does she really
    wanna [mess around] / But can't stand to see me / Walk out the
    door?" André 3000 commented, "I think it's more important to be
    happy than to meet up to…the world's expectations of what a
    relationship should be. So this is a celebration of how men and
    women relate to each other in the 2000s." The song then leads
    into the chorus, which consists of the line "Hey ya!" repeated
    eight times, accompanied by a synthesizer performing the
    bassline.</p>
      <p>During the second verse, the persona gets cold feet and
    wonders what the purpose of continuing the relationship is,
    pondering the question, "If they say nothing is forever…then
    what makes love the exception?" After repeating the chorus, the
    song leads into a call and response section. André 3000 jokes,
    "What's cooler than being cool?", and the "fellas'" response,
    an overdubbed version of his vocals, is "Ice cold", a reference
    to one of André Benjamin's stage names. He then calls to the
    "ladies", whose response is overdubbed from vocals by Rabeka
    Tuinei, who was an assistant to the audio engineer.</p>
      <p>The song's breakdown coined the phrase "shake it like a
    Polaroid picture," a reference to an erroneous technique used
    by some photographers to expedite instant film. Early versions
    of the film needed to be dried, and shaking the picture helped
    it to dry faster. The breakdown also namechecks singer Beyoncé
    and actress Lucy Liu. The song closes by repeating the chorus 
    <i>ad libitum</i>and gradually fading out.</p>
      <p>"Hey Ya!" received very positive reviews from music critics.
    
    <i>PopMatters</i>described the track as "brilliantly rousing"
    and "spazzy with electrifying multiplicity". 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>highlighted it as the catchiest song
    on the double album, and 
    <i>Stylus Magazine</i>identified it as one of the best songs in
    OutKast's history. "Hey Ya!" topped the 2003 Pazz &amp; Jop
    list, a survey of several hundred music critics conducted by
    Robert Christgau, with 322 mentions, beating runner-up Beyoncé
    Knowles' "Crazy in Love" by 119. It was listed at number
    fifteen on 
    <i>Blender</i>'s 2005 list of "The 500 Greatest Songs Since You
    Were Born".</p>
      <p>The song's unusual arrangement drew comparisons to artists
    from a variety of genres. Pitchfork Media referred to it as the
    apex of the album and added that it successfully mixed Flaming
    Lips-style instrumentation with the energy of Prince's 1983
    single "Little Red Corvette". Subsequently, Pitchfork Media
    gave it the number two slot in its "The Top 100 Singles of
    2000-2004" feature in January 2005, bested only by OutKast's
    own "B.O.B.". 
    <i>Blender</i>described it as a mix of soul music by Ike Turner
    and New Wave music by Devo and later as an
    "electro/folk-rock/funk/power pop/hip-hop/neo-soul/kitchen sink
    rave-up". 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>compared André 3000's vocals to those of
    "an indie-rock Little Richard" and the backing arrangement to
    The Beatles' 1969 album 
    <i>Abbey Road</i>, later including the song in its 500 Greatest
    Songs of All Time. 
    <i>New York</i>also likened it to The Beatles and found it to
    be one of the best singles of 2003. Allmusic described it as an
    "incandescent" mix of electro, funk, and soul music. 
    <i>NME</i>likened trying to classify the song as "akin to
    trying to lasso water" and described it as "a monumental barney
    between the Camberwick Green brass band, a cruise-ship cabaret
    act, a cartoon gospel choir and a sucker MC hiccuping '
    <i>Shake it like a polaroid pic-chaaaa!</i>' backed up by the
    cast of an amateur production of The Wizard of Oz. Sort of."
    This song was number four on 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s 2009 list of the 50 Best Songs of the
    Decade.</p>
      <p>"Hey Ya!" was successful in North America, topping the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 for nine weeks, from December 6, 2003
    to January 31, 2004. The digital sales topped the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Digital Tracks for nineteen weeks. The song
    performed well in urban contemporary markets, topping the
    Rhythmic Top 40 chart and reaching number nine on the Hot
    R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Singles &amp; Tracks. It was also successful in
    mainstream music, topping the Top 40 Mainstream and Top 40
    Tracks and reaching number thirteen on the Adult Top 40. The
    song's pop rock origins allowed it some crossover success, and
    it reached number sixteen on the Modern Rock Tracks. In
    September 2005, the Recording Industry Association of America
    certified the single triple platinum for shipping three million
    copies. At the 46th Grammy Awards, the song won Best
    Urban/Alternative Performance and was nominated for Record of
    the Year, but lost to Coldplay's "Clocks". "Hey Ya!" also
    topped the Canadian Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>The song performed well in Europe, though not as strong as
    in the U.S. In the United Kingdom, it debuted at number six on
    the UK Singles Chart and peaked at number three after twelve
    weeks, remaining on the chart for a total of twenty-one weeks.
    "Hey Ya!" topped the Norwegian singles chart for seven weeks,
    and it reached the top in Sweden for the first week of 2004. It
    performed well across the continent, reaching the top ten in
    Austria, Finland, France, Germany, Ireland, and
    Switzerland.</p>
      <p>"Hey Ya!" debuted at number seventeen on Australia's ARIA
    Singles Chart, eventually topping the chart for two consecutive
    weeks. The song remained on the chart for sixteen weeks and was
    certified double platinum by the Australian Recording Industry
    Association. The song charted at number sixty-one for the 2003
    end of year chart and was listed at number fifteen on the 2004
    chart and number five on the 2004 urban chart. It was also
    successful in New Zealand, reaching number two and staying on
    the RIANZ Singles Chart for twenty-three weeks.</p>
      <p>The lyric "shake it like a Polaroid picture", along with the
    song's commercial success, helped to revitalize the Polaroid
    Corporation. Because current Polaroid film is sealed behind a
    clear plastic window, casually waving the picture has no effect
    on the film's development. Vigorously shaking the film may
    actually distort the image by causing the film to separate
    prematurely and creating blobs in the final image.
    Nevertheless, Polaroid sought to market off of the allusion,
    hiring Ryan Berger of the Euro RSCG advertising agency.
    Polaroid sponsored parties for OutKast, where Euro RSCG
    distributed Polaroid cameras. OutKast made a deal to hold
    Polaroid cameras during some of its performances. Polaroid does
    not release sales figures, but its public image, previously in
    decline with the growing popularity of digital cameras, was
    bolstered by the song.</p>
      <p>The song's music video, directed by Bryan Barber, is based
    on The Beatles' landmark appearance on 
    <i>The Ed Sullivan Show</i>on February 9, 1964, but sets the
    action in London. The beginning and end of the video blend with
    those of "The Way You Move" so that the two can be watched in
    either order, and a "The Way You Move/Hey Ya!" video combining
    both clips with a bridging sequence was released on the 
    <i>OutKast: The Videos</i>DVD. In the video, André 3000 plays
    eight members of The Love Below: keyboardist Benjamin Andre,
    bassist Possum Jenkins, vocalist Ice Cold 3000, drummer Dookie
    Blasingame, three backing vocalists The Love Haters, and
    guitarist Johnny Vulture. The video opens with the band's
    manager Antwan talking to Ice Cold 3000 and Dookie Blasingame
    backstage. Meanwhile, the television presenter, portrayed by
    Ryan Phillippe, tries to calm a crowd of screaming girls on a
    show being broadcast live in black-and-white. The band performs
    while the girls in the audience scream loudly; one girl is
    carried off by security after rushing the stage, and another
    faints. A family is shown dancing to the broadcast at home.
    When André 3000 instructs to "shake it like a Polaroid
    picture", some of the girls begin taking pictures and shaking
    them. Ice Cold 3000 dances with one of the girls on stage, and
    the video closes with several friends of the band watching and
    discussing the performance.</p>
      <p>The music video was filmed in two days in August 2003 on a
    sound stage at Universal Studios in Los Angeles, California.
    The cast consisted of over one hundred girls. Each of André
    3000's parts was shot several times from different angles, and
    he performed the song 23 times during the course of filming.
    Because releasing "Hey Ya!" as a single was a last minute
    decision, André did not have time to choreograph the parts, and
    all of the dancing was improvised. Ice Cold 3000's sequences
    were the first filmed, resulting in the character's energetic
    performance, and Johnny Vulture's were the last, so André,
    exhausted from the previous takes, sat on a stool for those
    sequences.</p>
      <p>The music video proved to be a success. The video debuted on
    MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>on September 5, 2003 at number ten. It
    topped the countdown for nineteen days and retired at number
    eight on November 24, having spent fifty days on the program.
    At the 2004 MTV Video Music Awards, the video won four awards
    for Video of the Year, Best Hip-Hop Video, Best Special
    Effects, and Best Art Direction. It was also nominated for Best
    Direction but lost to Jay-Z's "99 Problems". "Hey Ya!" was
    nominated for Best Short Form Music Video at the 46th Grammy
    Awards, but it lost to Johnny Cash's cover of Nine Inch Nails'
    "Hurt". In Canada, the video topped MuchMusic's 
    <i>Countdown</i>for four weeks, and it won the award for Best
    International Group at the 2004 MuchMusic Video Awards. In
    2006, 
    <i>Stylus Magazine</i>listed it at number seventy-two on its
    "Top 100 Music Videos of All Time", comparing André 3000's
    dancing to James Brown's performances in the early 1970s.</p>
      <p>The rock influences of "Hey Ya!" have allowed many other
    artists to release cover versions of the song. One of the first
    covers of the song was by indie rock band Razorlight, who
    performed the song with the London Community Gospel Choir for a
    BBC Radio 1 session, later releasing their version as a B-side
    for their single "Vice". In a similar vein, Will Young, also on
    the station, recorded a slower piano version of the song, which
    became the B-side for his single "Friday's Child". Young's
    version also appears on the compilation album 
    <i>Radio 1's Live Lounge</i>. Richard Cheese and Lounge Against
    the Machine recorded a lounge version of the song for their
    2004 album 
    <i>I'd Like a Virgin</i>. Country band The BossHoss, Latin pop
    singer JD Natasha, punk rock band Pennywise, Indie pop band
    Tilly and the Wall, and rock and roll band The Supersuckers
    have also recorded cover versions.</p>
      <p>In 2006, Mat Weddle, frontman of the unsigned folk band
    Obadiah Parker, performed an acoustic cover of the song at a
    local open mike night, and a friend of his posted a video of
    the performance on YouTube. The video gained popularity on the
    Internet, soon becoming a viral video, and was viewed by over
    one million people. Inspired by slowcore band Red House
    Painters, Weddle's version moves at a much slower tempo backed
    by a rhythmic guitar strum and converts the breakdown into a
    "staccato chime". The cover received international airplay and
    spawned many other copycat acoustic versions.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
