<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Night_Chicago_Died 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Night_Chicago_Died</songId>
   <title>The Night Chicago Died</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paper_Lace</artistId>
      <artistName>Paper Lace</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-08-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Night Chicago Died" is a song by the British group
    Paper Lace, written by Peter Callander and Mitch Murray. The
    song reached number one on the Billboard Hot 100 chart for one
    week in 1974 and also reached number 3 in the UK charts. It is
    about a fictional shoot-out in Chicago between gangsters tied
    to Al Capone and the Chicago Police. The narrator retells his
    mother's anguish while awaiting news of the fate of her
    husband, a Chicago policeman.</p>
      <p>"The Night Chicago Died" was Paper Lace's follow-up single
    to "Billy, Don't Be A Hero", a #1 hit in the U.K. but virtually
    unheard in the U.S. where Bo Donaldson and the Heywoods' cover
    reached #1. Callander and Murray wrote both songs.</p>
      <p>The U.S. single received a Platinum certification from the
    Recording Industry Association of America, signifying sales of
    at least one million copies. Though the song's story is set in
    America, Paper Lace were unable to perform the song live in the
    U.S. at the height of its popularity because of contractual
    issues.</p>
      <p>"The Night Chicago Died" is a work of fiction. Although it
    references the notorious Chicago mobster Al Capone and his gang
    by name, no such massive police shootout took place during
    Capone's reign as the head of the city's organized crime
    syndicate. In fact, Capone's criminal career ended quietly in
    1931, when he was convicted of income-tax evasion and weapons
    possession.</p>
      <p>The song's events supposedly take place "on the East Side of
    Chicago." Unlike the North, West, and South Sides, which divide
    the city into three general and commonly referred-to regions,
    East Side is, in reality, a small local neighborhood several
    miles south of downtown Chicago, not far from where Al Capone
    lived (at 7244 South Prairie Avenue).</p>
      <p>Elements of the story may have been inspired by the famous
    St. Valentine's Day Massacre of 1929. However, that encounter
    was between Capone's men and a rival Chicago gang rather than
    the police, and it took place on the city's North Side in
    February instead of "in the heat of a summer night."</p>
      <p>The songwriters said in interviews—most notably on 
    <i>Beat Club</i>shortly after the song's release—that they had
    never been to Chicago, and that their knowledge of the city and
    that period of its history had been based on gangster
    films.</p>
      <p>Paper Lace did send the song to Mayor Richard Daley, who was
    not impressed with the song and greatly disliked it.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
