<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moody_River 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moody_River</songId>
   <title>Moody River</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pat_Boone</artistId>
      <artistName>Pat Boone</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1961-06-19</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>June 1961</released>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:41</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Dot Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Gary D. Bruce</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Moody River" is a number-one Billboard Hot 100 song from
    June of 1961 by Pat Boone. It was written by and originally
    performed by country rockabilly singer Chase Webster (real name
    Gary Daniel Bruce, not to be confused with Gary Bruce of The
    Knack). Webster was a labelmate of Boone's at Dot Records.</p>
      <p>This was the title track from one of Boone's better-selling
    albums. Boone sang this song as if he were in pain. It was
    covered some years later by Frank Sinatra and also by Johnny
    Rivers. In August of 2009, John Fogerty of Creedence Clearwater
    Revival fame covered the song in the album entitled The Blue
    Ridge Rangers Rides Again.</p>
      <p>The song tells the story of a man who goes to meet his love
    at the river, by the old oak tree, and finds that she has
    committed suicide. A note on the riverbank explains that she
    has cheated on him and that "No longer can I live with this
    hurt and this sin. I just couldn't tell you that guy was just a
    friend." He then looks into the river and sees his own
    reflection on the river looking back, ever hauntingly, at him.
    He is the "lonely, lonely face just lookin' back at me". So
    with "Tears in his eyes, and a prayer on his lips, and the
    glove of his lost love, at his fingertips".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
