<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tennessee_Waltz 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tennessee_Waltz</songId>
   <title>The Tennessee Waltz</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patti_Page</artistId>
      <artistName>Patti Page</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1950-12-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Tennessee Waltz" is a popular/country music song
    written by Redd Stewart and Pee Wee King in 1947.</p>
      <p>Originally recorded by Roy Acuff, it was later popularized
    by Patti Page and by Les Paul and Mary Ford in 1950.</p>
      <p>The popularity of this song also made it the fourth official
    song of the state of Tennessee in 1965. It was adopted by
    Senate Joint Resolution 9 of the 84th General Assembly.</p>
      <p>Like "Ignition (Remix)", and "Crocodile Rock", "The
    Tennessee Waltz" is a self-referential song, i.e. a song about
    the song itself.</p>
      <p>The 1949 Roy Acuff &amp; The Smoky Mountain Boys recording
    was issued by Columbia as catalog number 20551.</p>
      <p>The song was originally written by Jimmy Wilkinson (Jimmy
    Wilson) and sold to Pee Wee King who made it popular. Jimmy
    Wilkinson was the upright bass player for Pee Wee King's Golden
    West Cowboys.</p>
      <p>Patti Page was familiar with "Tennessee Waltz" as it was a
    favorite song of her father's. She made her recording of the
    song to be the B-side of a seasonal single "Boogie Woogie Santa
    Claus" issued by Mercury Records as catalog number 5534; it was
    radio disc jockeys who chose to play "Tennessee Waltz" boosting
    the track into the pop music chart on November 10, 1950 for a
    30 week chart run with a #1 peak. A #2 C&amp;W hit, "Tennessee
    Waltz" became Page's career record.</p>
      <p>The success of the Patti Page version led to covers by Les
    Paul with Mary Ford (Capitol 1316) and Jo Stafford (Columbia
    39065) both of which reached the Top Ten (Stafford's at
    #7).</p>
      <p>Other recordings were made by Guy Lombardo and his Royal
    Canadians (Decca 27336) and, for the UK market, by Petula
    Clark.</p>
      <p>On the charts, "Tennessee Waltz" reached #1 on December 30,
    1950 with the Patti Page, Jo Stafford, Guy Lombardo and
    LesPaul/Mary Ford versions being given a tandem ranking; as
    such "Tennessee Waltz" remained #1 in 
    <i>Cash Box</i>through the February 3, 1951 chart.</p>
      <p>"Tennessee Waltz" returned to the charts in the fall of 1959
    via a rockabilly version recorded by both Bobby Comstock &amp;
    the Counts and Jerry Fuller: on the Hot 100 the versions
    respectively reached #52 and #63 while 
    <i>Cash Box</i>assigned both versions a joint ranking on its
    Top 100 Singles chart with a peak position of #42.</p>
      <p>In 1964 "Tennessee Waltz" was recorded in a rock and roll
    ballad style by Alma Cogan; this version hit the German Top Ten
    and spent five weeks at #1 in Sweden. The success of Cogan's
    version has inspired remakes by Swedish singers Kikki
    Danielsson and Lotta Engberg and by German singer Heidi
    Brühl.</p>
      <p>Sam Cooke included an upbeat version of "Tennessee Waltz" on
    the final album he recorded: the 1 March 1964 release 
    <i>Ain't That Good News</i>: originally the B-side of the track
    "Good Times", "Tennessee Waltz" became popular enough in itself
    to reach #35. The "Good Times/ Tennessee Waltz" double A-side
    single would be the last Sam Cooke single released during the
    singer's lifetime.</p>
      <p>In 1966, Otis Redding recorded a version of "Tennessee
    Waltz" featuring Booker T &amp; the MGs on his classic R&amp;B
    album .</p>
      <p>Johnny Jones - a native of Atlanta who had briefly replaced
    Sam Cooke in the Soul Stirrers before Johnnie Taylor joined the
    group - reached #49 R&amp;B in 1968 with his deep soul
    rendition of "Tennessee Waltz" cut for producer Bobby
    Robinson's Fury Records.</p>
      <p>In 1980 Lacy J. Dalton hit #18 on the C&amp;W chart in 
    <i>Billboard</i>with her gritty reworking of "Tennessee
    Waltz".</p>
      <p>In 1983 the song was featured on James Brown's 
    <i>Bring It On</i>album that was released on the Churchill
    record label.</p>
      <p>Norah Jones performed "Tennessee Waltz" as an encore during
    a live show at the House of Blues in New Orleans on August 24th
    2002. It is featured as extra material on the following
    DVD-release of the show.</p>
      <p>Leonard Cohen recorded "Tennessee Waltz" - one of the few
    covers he's ever cut - for his 2004 album 
    <i>Dear Heather</i>; this version featured an additional verse
    written by Cohen himself.</p>
      <p>Other artists who've recorded "Tennessee Waltz" (with the
    parent album): Eva Cassidy (
    <i>Imagine</i>2002), Holly Cole (
    <i>Don't Smoke in Bed</i>1993), Connie Francis, Emmylou Harris
    (
    <i>Cimarron</i>1981), Tom Jones backed by The Chieftans (
    <i>Long Black Veil</i>1995), (1995), Pete Molinari (
    <i>Today, Tomorrow and Forever</i>2009), Anne Murray (
    <i>Let's Keep It That Way</i>1978), Elvis Presley and Billie Jo
    Spears (
    <i>Country Girl</i>1981). [1]</p>
      <p>The 3 August 1966 broadcast of 
    <i>The Merv Griffin Show</i>featured an impromptu performance
    of "Tennessee Waltz" by Monti Rock with go-go dancing
    accompaniment by Jayne Mansfield.</p>
      <p>The marching bands of several state funded universities
    perform the song at the end of every home football game. These
    include The University of Tennessee Pride of the Southland
    Band, and The Middle Tennessee State University Band of Blue.
    The University of Chattanooga Marching Mocs perform the
    "Tennessee Waltz March" during pre-game of every home football
    game, as well as at other athletic events. Outside of
    Tennessee, Baylor University Golden Wave Band in Waco TX, and
    The Appalachian State University Marching Mountaineers in Boone
    NC, also play the song at home football games.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
