<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/On_My_Own_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/On_My_Own_(song)</songId>
   <title>On My Own</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patti_LaBelle</artistId>
      <artistName>Patti LaBelle and Michael McDonald</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-06-14</week>
      <week>1986-06-21</week>
      <week>1986-06-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/56/Onmyown.jpg/200px-Onmyown.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Patti-LaBelle-and-Michael-McDonald+On-My-Own.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Winner in You</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 22, 1986</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Maxi single</format>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1985</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
      <genre>Adult Contemporary</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Ballad</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:50</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Burt Bacharach</writer>
      <writer>Carole Bayer Sager</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"On My Own" was a hit duet by singers Patti LaBelle and
    Michael McDonald when it was released as a single in 1986. It
    was released from LaBelle's first platinum album, 
    <i>Winner in You</i>and was written and produced by Burt
    Bacharach and his former wife Carole Bayer Sager. The song was
    based on a relationship that had reached its end with both
    parties going their separate ways in a melancholy state with
    the occasional option of coming back together again one
    day.</p>
      <p>It was often stated the two performers were in separate
    cities when they recorded their individual parts which were
    then "married" during mastering. This was reflected in the
    music video produced to promote the song, which depicted
    LaBelle and McDonald performing the song simultaneously on
    different coasts. The singers were shown on separate sides of a
    split screen, each singing the song while walking through
    apartments which had identical layouts but different decor and
    furniture. The views from their respective porches, where they
    finished the song, made clear their separation by the
    continent.</p>
      <p>The song became the biggest single ever for both singers,
    both of whom were members of respective funk/R&amp;B groups in
    the 1970s: LaBelle and The Doobie Brothers - as it hit number
    one on the 
    <i>Billboard magazine</i>pop, for 3 weeks, the R&amp;B and
    Adult Contemporary charts, as well as number two in the UK
    singles chart, going gold - (it was the 22nd best-selling
    single of 1986 in the UK). The song was initially not intended
    to be a duet at all, but LaBelle decided to invite McDonald to
    help her turn the song into a duet, as she stated: 
    <i>"The song was sent to me and I did a version of it but
    somehow it just didn't quite work. We were going over things
    I'd done and we talked about turning it into a duet. Someone
    asked, 'If you could do it with anyone, who would you sing it
    with,' and Michael was my first choice..."</i>
      </p>
      <p>In 1995, country music sinnger Reba McEntire covered the
    song on her 1995 album 
    <i>Starting Over</i>. Her version, featuring guest vocals from
    Martina McBride, Linda Davis, and Trisha Yearwood peaked at #20
    on Hot Country Singles &amp; Tracks chart, although only
    McEntire received chart credit for it. Its music video was
    directed by Dominic Orlando and was filmed on the Chaplin
    Stage.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
