<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opposites_Attract 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opposites_Attract</songId>
   <title>Opposites Attract</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paula_Abdul</artistId>
      <artistName>Paula Abdul with The Wild Pair</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1990-02-10</week>
      <week>1990-02-17</week>
      <week>1990-02-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/1a/Paula_abdul_opposites_attract_single.jpg/200px-Paula_abdul_opposites_attract_single.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Paula-Abdul-with-The-Wild-Pair+Opposites-Attract.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Forever Your Girl</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 28, 1989</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD maxi</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" maxi</format>
      <format>Cassette</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1988, 1989</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>New Jack Swing</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:46</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Virgin</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Oliver Leiber</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Oliver Leiber</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Opposites Attract" is a song recorded by Paula Abdul,
    featured on her debut album 
    <i>Forever Your Girl</i>. It was written and produced by Oliver
    Leiber, who came up with the title after browsing a bookstore.
    Vocals on the song, in addition to Abdul, were provided by
    Bruce DeShazer and Marv Gunn, aka 'The Wild Pair'. "Opposites
    Attract" was the sixth and final single from the album, and
    achieved success in many countries, including the US and
    Australia where it was a #1 hit.</p>
      <p>The lyrics are about a couple who love each other despite
    being different in just about every way possible.</p>
      <p>The song is distinctive for its colorful music video created
    and directed by Candace Reckinger &amp; Michael Patterson, in
    which Paula dances with cartoon character MC Skat Kat, voiced
    by 'The Wild Pair'. The music video adds an intro rap performed
    by Romany Malco. An additional rap was provided by Derrick
    'Delite' Stevens for the Street mix version of the song, which
    was edited for the 7"/video.</p>
      <p>The idea of MC Skat Kat came from the Gene Kelly movie 
    <i>Anchors Aweigh</i>, where Kelly dances with Jerry, the mouse
    from the 
    <i>Tom and Jerry</i>cartoon series. Paula even choreographed
    the animated character's moves to match her live-action dance
    moves in the video. MC Skat Kat was animated by members of the
    Disney animation team, working outside the studio between major
    projects, under the direction of Chris Bailey. Also shown in
    the video are Micetro, Taboo, and Fatz, yet their names weren't
    revealed until the release of The Adventures of MC Skat Kat and
    the Stray Mob.</p>
      <p>The video won Abdul a Grammy award in 1991 for "Best Short
    Form Music Video".</p>
      <p>The song was covered by American indie band Mirror Ball
    Associates for the album 
    <i>Covers Vol. 1</i>, which features Paul Durham (lead singer
    of Black Lab) on vocals.</p>
      <p>This video was later parodied by the 
    <i>Family Guy</i>episode "The Father, the Son, and the Holy
    Fonz" with Peter Griffin "dressed like a cat", taking the place
    of MC Skat Kat. Paula herself actually appears in the sequence.
    According to the DVD commentary, Abdul rerecorded her vocals
    specifically for the episode.</p>
      <p>The song was also featured in hit comedy TV show 
    <i>Sabrina, The Teenage Witch</i>in the Season 4 episode
    "Aging, Not So Gracefully".</p>
      <p>The Australian sketch comedy show 
    <i>Fast Forward</i>parody of the song had Humphrey B. Bear in
    place of MC Skat Kat.</p>
      <p>The song also appeared in the television version of the
    political thriller A Very British Coup.</p>
      <p>"Opposites Attract" became one of the most popular R&amp;B
    and dance-pop singles of 1990. The single initially rose from
    #72 to #47 the week of December 23, 1989, and landed at #1 the
    week of February 10, 1990, where it remained for three weeks,
    matching the run of "Straight Up". It became Abdul's fourth #1
    single on the Billboard Hot 100 and made her only the fourth
    artist in music history to score four #1 hits from a single
    album, after Whitney Houston, George Michael and Michael
    Jackson. Although the single was released at the end of 1989,
    the song itself is considered one of the first popular songs of
    the 1990s. "Opposites Attract" also topped the charts in
    Australia, and peaked at #2 in the UK. It failed to enter the
    German Top 10, peaking at #13.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
