<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Say_Say_Say 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Say_Say_Say</songId>
   <title>Say Say Say</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_McCartney</artistId>
      <artistName>Paul McCartney and Michael Jackson</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1983-12-10</week>
      <week>1983-12-17</week>
      <week>1983-12-24</week>
      <week>1983-12-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/93/SaySaySay.jpg/200px-SaySaySay.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Paul-McCartney-and-Michael-Jackson+Say-Say-Say.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Pipes of Peace</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>3 October 1983</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1981</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:55</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Parlophone (UK), Columbia (US)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Paul McCartney</writer>
      <writer>Michael Jackson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Say Say Say" is a pop song that was written and performed
    by Paul McCartney and Michael Jackson. The track was produced
    by George Martin for McCartney's fifth solo album, 
    <i>Pipes of Peace</i>(1983). The song was recorded during
    production of McCartney's 1982 
    <i>Tug of War</i>album, about a year before the release of "The
    Girl Is Mine"—the pair's first duet from Jackson's
    record-breaking album, 
    <i>Thriller</i>(1982). After its release in October 1983, "Say
    Say Say" became Jackson's seventh top-ten hit inside a year. It
    was a number one hit in the United States, Norway, and Sweden,
    reached number two in the United Kingdom, and peaked within the
    top ten in Australia, Austria, New Zealand, the Netherlands and
    Switzerland.</p>
      <p>Certified platinum by the Recording Industry Association of
    America, the song was promoted with a music video directed by
    Bob Giraldi. The video, filmed in Santa Ynez Valley,
    California, featured cameo appearances by Linda McCartney and
    La Toya Jackson. The short film centers around two con artists
    called "Mac and Jack" (played by McCartney and Jackson), and is
    credited for the introduction of dialogue and storyline to
    music videos. The video was considered by the National
    Coalition on Television Violence to be too violent for
    broadcast in the US.</p>
      <p>McCartney had already collaborated with Jackson on "The Girl
    Is Mine", from the latter's 
    <i>Thriller</i>, and in return Jackson agreed to work on "Say
    Say Say" for McCartney's 
    <i>Pipes of Peace</i>. McCartney biographer Ray Coleman
    asserted that the majority of the song's lyrics were written by
    Jackson, and given to McCartney the next day. "Say Say Say" was
    recorded at Abbey Road Studios between May and September 1981.
    At the time, McCartney was recording 
    <i>Tug of War</i>, the former Beatle's first solo album after
    the disbandment of his group Wings. Jackson stayed at the home
    of McCartney and his wife Linda during the recording sessions,
    and became friends with both. While at the dining table one
    evening, Paul McCartney brought out a booklet that displayed
    all of the songs to which he owned the publishing rights. "This
    is the way to make big money", the musician informed Jackson.
    "Every time someone records one of these songs, I get paid.
    Every time someone plays these songs on the radio, or in live
    performances, I get paid." McCartney's words influenced
    Jackson's later purchase of the Northern Songs music catalogue
    in 1985.</p>
      <p>McCartney played several instruments on "Say Say Say",
    including percussion, synthesiser, guitar and bass guitar. The
    harmonica was played by Chris Smith, and the rhythm guitar was
    played by David Williams. The song was engineered by Geoff
    Emerick. The production of "Say Say Say" was completed in
    February 1983, after it had been refined and overdubbed at
    Cherokee Studios in California. George Martin, who had worked
    with The Beatles, produced the song. He said of his experience
    with Jackson, "He actually does radiate an aura when he comes
    into the studio, there's no question about it. He's not a
    musician in the sense that Paul is ... but he does know what he
    wants in music and he has very firm ideas." Jackson also spoke
    of the experience in his autobiography, 
    <i>Moonwalk</i>. The younger singer revealed that the
    collaboration boosted his confidence, as Quincy Jones—producer
    of 
    <i>Thriller</i>—was not present to correct his mistakes.
    Jackson added that he and McCartney worked as equals, stating,
    "Paul never had to carry me in that studio."</p>
      <p>"Say Say Say" is cited as a pop song on the sheet music
    published on Musicnotes.com by Alfred Music Publishing. The
    song was performed in common time, with a dance beat of
    116 beats per minute. It was composed in a B
    <span class="music-symbol"
               style="font-family: Arial Unicode MS, Lucida Sans Unicode;">
♭
</span>minor key, and sung in a vocal range from F4 to B♭5. The
lyrics to "Say Say Say" reflect an attempt to "win back" a girl's
affection; 
    <i>Deseret News</i>considered the song to be a "pleading kind
    of love song".</p>
      <p>Following the release of 
    <i>Thriller</i>and most of its singles, "Say Say Say" was
    released on 3 October 1983 by Parlophone Records in the UK and
    Columbia Records in the US. It remained atop s Hot 100 for six
    weeks and became Jackson's seventh top ten hit of 1983,
    breaking a record that until then was held jointly by The
    Beatles and Elvis Presley. Also in the US, "Say Say Say"
    reached number two on the R&amp;B chart and number three on the
    Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks chart. Although the song had
    peaked at number ten in the UK, it began to fall steadily;
    McCartney subsequently held an early weekday live television
    interview, where he discussed the song's music video. This,
    along with screenings of the video on 
    <i>Top of the Pops</i>(which normally played only singles that
    were rising in the charts), 
    <i>The Tube</i>and Noel Edmonds' 
    <i>The Late, Late Breakfast Show</i>, helped propel the song to
    number two on the UK Singles Chart. "Say Say Say" reached
    number one in Norway and Sweden, and the single also reached
    the top ten in Austria, Australia, New Zealand, the
    Netherlands, and Switzerland. With wholesale shipments of at
    least one million units, the single was later certified
    platinum by the Recording Industry Association of America.</p>
      <p>"Say Say Say" received mixed reviews from music critics. The
    lyrics were named the worst of 1983 by 
    <i>The Buffalo News</i>'s Anthony Violanti, while the 
    <i>Lexington Herald-Leader</i>stated in a review of 
    <i>Pipes of Peace</i>that, aside from "Say Say Say" and "The
    Man", "McCartney waste[d] the rest of the album on bathos and
    whimsy". 
    <i>Los Angeles Times'</i>Paul Grein also reviewed the McCartney
    album and opined that the singer had redeemed himself with the
    success of the "spunky" song "but plunged back into wimpdom
    with 'No More Lonely Nights'". Journalist Whitney Pastorek
    compared the song to McCartney's 1982 duet with Stevie Wonder,
    "Ebony and Ivory". She asserted that "Say Say Say" was a better
    song, and had a better "though slightly more nonsensical" music
    video, adding that the song had no "heavy-handed social
    content". Penn State's 
    <i>The Daily Collegian</i>described the track as a good song,
    despite its ad nauseam broadcasts.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Deseret News</i>stated that the "pleading love song" had a
    "masterful, catchy hook". In a 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>review, the track was described as an
    "amiable though vapid dance groove". The reviewer, Parke
    Puterbaugh, added that it was an "instantly hit-bound
    froth-funk that tends, after all, toward banality". Music
    critic Nelson George stated that "Say Say Say" would not have
    "deserved the airplay it received without Michael Jackson".
    Salon.com later described the song as a "sappy duet". The
    online magazine concluded that McCartney had become a "wimpy
    old fart". 
    <i>Billboard</i>ranked the song third in its list of top tracks
    for 1984. In a 2007 article, a writer the magazine 
    <i>Vibe</i>listed "Say Say Say" as the 22nd greatest duet of
    all time. The writer commented that the song was "a true
    falsetto fantasy" and that it was "still thrilling to hear the
    sweet-voiced duo trade harmonies on the chorus". In 2006, Dutch
    musicians Hi Tack sampled "Say Say Say" on their debut single,
    "Say Say Say (Waiting 4 U)". The song featured Jackson's vocals
    from the original recording.</p>
      <p>The music video (or "short film") for "Say Say Say" was
    directed by Bob Giraldi, who had previously directed Michael
    Jackson's "Beat It". The McCartney-Jackson collaboration
    featured cameo appearances by the former's wife Linda, and the
    latter's older sister La Toya. To accommodate Jackson's busy
    schedule the video was filmed at Los Olivos in the Santa Ynez
    Valley, California. McCartney flew in specially for filming.
    The video cost $500,000 to produce.</p>
      <p>In the short film, the duo play "Mac and Jack", a pair of
    conmen who sell a "miracle potion". The salesman (McCartney)
    offers Jackson the potion, and claims that it is "guaranteed to
    give you the strength of a raging bull". Jackson drinks the
    potion and challenges a large man to arm wrestle. Unbeknownst
    to a watching crowd, the man—along with Linda—is also in on the
    scam. After Jackson wins the rigged contest, the crowd of
    people surge forward and buy the potion. Mac and Jack then
    donate all of the money earned from the scam to an orphanage.
    Later, while in a hotel, Jackson enters the bathroom as
    McCartney shaves. The latter playfully dabs shaving foam on
    Jackson's cheek, despite the fact that the younger man does not
    need a shave. After this scene, McCartney and Jackson star as
    vaudeville performers who sing and dance at a bar. On stage,
    the duo appear in clown makeup at one point and quickly go
    through a number of costume changes. Jackson's love interest,
    with whom he flirts, was played by his sister La Toya. The
    video ends with Paul, Linda and Michael as drive they off into
    the sunset. La Toya, who was handed a bunch of flowers by
    McCartney, is left at the roadside.</p>
      <p>Director Giraldi said of Jackson and McCartney, "Michael
    didn't outdance Paul, and Paul didn't outsing Michael". He
    added that production of the video was hard work because "the
    egos could fill a room". The video introduced both dialogue and
    storyline, an element extended upon in 
    <i>Michael Jackson's Thriller</i>. After its release, the US
    National Coalition of Television Violence classified the music
    video as too violent to be aired. They also classified 
    <i>Thriller</i>and more than half of the 200 videos surveyed
    from MTV as being overly violent. The coalition included
    physical and verbal suggestions of violence, as well as acts of
    abuse, in their observings of around 900 music videos. In a
    list compiled by 
    <i>Billboard</i>at the end of 1984, the music video was named
    the fourth best of the year, and the rest of the top four were
    also short films by Jackson.</p>
      <p>
         <i>The Manchester Evening News</i>later described the "Say Say
    Say" video as an "anarchic caper" that "plays out like an Emir
    Kusturica feature". PopMatters stated that the music videos of
    "Say Say Say" and "Goodnight Tonight" turned "a pair of
    otherwise forgettable songs into something worth watching".
    Steven Greenlee of 
    <i>The Boston Globe</i>reflected that the video was both
    "horrifying and compelling", and stated the ridiculousness of a
    potion which could aid Jackson in beating somebody at arm
    wrestling. He added, "It's even harder to believe that the two
    of them didn't get the pulp beaten out of them in that bar for
    dressing like a pair of Chess King employees". The "Say Say
    Say" video was later included on the DVD 
    <i>The McCartney Years</i>.</p>
      <p>Two authors later reviewed the short film and documented two
    central themes. The first is a "Child/Man" theme; the role of
    both a boy and an adult, which writer James M. Curtis states
    Jackson plays throughout the music video for "Say Say Say".
    Curtis writes that the bathroom scene involving the shaving
    foam is reminiscent of boys copying their fathers. He adds that
    the scene marks "the distinction between Michael's roles as a
    Child and as a Man". The writer also highlights the part where
    the singer supposedly becomes strengthened with a miracle
    potion, a further play on the "Child/Man" theme. Furthermore,
    Curtis observes that Paul and Linda McCartney seem to act as if
    they are Jackson's parents in the short film. The author also
    notes that in a scene where Jackson is handed a bouquet of
    flowers from a girl, it is a reversal of one from 
    <i>City Lights</i>, a 1931 film starring Charlie Chaplin, whom
    the singer greatly adored.</p>
      <p>The second of the two main themes in the music video is of
    African American history and culture, as some of the vaudeville
    scenes in the short film acknowledge minstrel shows and
    blackface. Author W. T. Lhamon writes that the video is set in
    the Californian Depression, and that McCartney and Jackson
    "convey a compactly corrupt history of blackface" as they con
    their way to riches with the Mack and Jack show. Lhamon was
    critical of the pair and of the video because he felt that the
    African American theme had not been made explicitly known. The
    author expressed his view that aspects of the short film were
    historically out-of-synch with interracial relations. He
    stated, "Nearly everything in the video is backward. Mack's
    white hand continually helping black Jack on board, for
    instance, reverses the general process I have shown of blacks
    providing whites with their sustaining gestures." Lhamon added,
    "In a just world, Jackson should be pulling McCartney onto the
    wagon, not the other way around."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
