<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27amour_est_bleu 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27amour_est_bleu</songId>
   <title>Love Is Blue</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Mauriat</artistId>
      <artistName>Paul Mauriat</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1968-02-10</week>
      <week>1968-02-17</week>
      <week>1968-02-24</week>
      <week>1968-03-02</week>
      <week>1968-03-09</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"L'amour est bleu" (English title: "Love Is Blue") is a song
    whose music was composed by André Popp, and whose lyrics were
    written by Pierre Cour, in 1967. Brian Blackburn later wrote
    English-language lyrics for it. First performed in French by
    Greek-German singer Vicky Leandros (appearing as 
    <i>Vicky</i>) as the Luxembourgian entry in the Eurovision Song
    Contest 1967, it has since been recorded by many other
    musicians, most notably French orchestra leader Paul Mauriat,
    whose familiar instrumental version became the only number-one
    hit by a French artist to top the Billboard Hot 100 in
    America.</p>
      <p>The song describes the pleasure and pain of love in terms of
    colours (blue and grey) and elements (water and wind). The
    English lyrics ("Blue, blue, my world is blue …") focus on
    colours only (blue, grey, red, green, and black), using them to
    describe elements of lost love. An odd twist in the lyric uses
    the word "gone" in the same pattern used to introduce each
    colour, just like in Fred Ebb and John Kander's "My Coloring
    Book"; "colour him gone".</p>
      <p>The song was performed second during the 1967 Eurovision
    Song Contest. At the close of voting, it had received 17
    points, placing 4th in a field of 17, behind "Il doit faire
    beau là-bas" (France), "If I Could Choose" (Ireland) and the
    winning song, "Puppet on a String" (United Kingdom). Some forty
    years after its original release, "L'amour est bleu", along
    with Domenico Modugno's "Nel blu dipinto di blu" (better known
    as "Volare") and Mocedades' "Eres tú", still counts as one of
    very few non-winning Eurovision entries ever to become a
    worldwide hit.</p>
      <p>Greek-born Leandros recorded the song both in French and
    English, and had a modest hit in Europe with it, but in Japan
    and Canada she had a big hit with this song. She subsequently
    recorded it in Greek, German (as "Blau wie das Meer"), Italian
    ("L'amore è blu"), Spanish and Dutch ("Liefde is zacht") as
    well. The song has since become a favourite of Contest fans,
    most notably appearing as part of a medley introducing the
    semi-final of the Eurovision Song Contest 2006 in Athens, one
    of only two non-winning songs to be involved (the other being
    "Dschinghis Khan").</p>
      <p>It was succeeded as Luxembourgian representative at the 1968
    Contest by Chris Baldo &amp; Sophie Garel with "Nous vivrons
    d'amour". Vicky Leandros went on to win the Contest five years
    later with the song "Après toi", again representing
    Luxembourg.</p>
      <p>In late 1967, Paul Mauriat conducted an orchestral "easy
    listening" version that was a number-one hit in the USA for
    five weeks in February and March 1968, becoming the only
    performance by a French artist ever to top the Billboard Hot
    100. Not surprisingly, the song spent 11 weeks atop 
    <i>Billboard's</i>Easy Listening survey, and held the
    longest-lasting title honours on this chart for 25 years. It is
    the best-known version of the song in the United States.</p>
      <p>Mauriat's version was featured repeatedly in an episode of
    Chris Carter's television series 
    <i>Millennium</i>titled 
    <i>"A Room With No View,"</i>which originally aired on April
    24, 1998 on the Fox Network. During the episode, the
    omnipresent melody is used by a kidnapper to brainwash a group
    of youths. His version is also briefly heard in 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>episode "There's No Disgrace Like Home."</p>
      <p>"L'amour est bleu"/"Love is Blue" is noted as one of the
    most-covered and biggest-selling Eurovision Songs ever, and
    remains a widely familiar melody due in part to its continued
    recurrence in pop-culture mediums. Jeff Beck, Claudine Longet,
    The Dells, Ed Ames, Johnny Mathis, Marty Robbins, Al Martino,
    Frank Sinatra, Lawrence Welk, Chara, Michèle Torr, and Future
    Bible Heroes are among the artists who have covered it.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
