<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coming_Up_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coming_Up_(song)</songId>
   <title>Coming Up (Live at Glasgow)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_McCartney_%26_Wings</artistId>
      <artistName>Paul McCartney &amp; Wings</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1980-06-28</week>
      <week>1980-07-05</week>
      <week>1980-07-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/2e/McCartneyComingUp.jpg/200px-McCartneyComingUp.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Paul-McCartney-Wings+Coming-Up-Live-at-Glasgow.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>McCartney II</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>11 April 1980</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Funk Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Parlophone / EMI (UK) , Columbia (US)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Paul McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Paul McCartney</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Coming Up" was the opening track from Paul McCartney's 
    <i>McCartney II</i>album, written by McCartney and released in
    1980. Like the rest of the album, the song had a minimalist
    synthesized feel to it. It featured humorously-processed lead
    vocals from McCartney, who played all the instruments and
    shared harmonies with his wife Linda McCartney.</p>
      <p>John Lennon had liked the song, crediting it for driving him
    out of retirement to resume recording.</p>
      <p>A live version of the song was recorded in Glasgow, Scotland
    on 17 December 1979 by Wings during their tour of the UK. This
    version had a much fuller sound and was included as one of the
    two songs on the B-side of the single; the other B-side was
    also a Wings song, "Lunchbox/Odd Sox", that dated back to the 
    <i>Venus and Mars</i>sessions. Both B-sides were credited to
    Paul McCartney &amp; Wings (see the alternate cover), the first
    time this credit had been used for a Wings record since
    "Junior's Farm."</p>
      <p>In the US, radio stations bypassed the McCartney solo A-side
    and played the live Wings B-side. To help sales of 
    <i>McCartney II</i>, a special single-sided 7" 33⅓ rpm
    promotional white-label copy of the Wings version was included
    with the album in North America.</p>
      <p>The live Wings version has since appeared on various
    McCartney best-of compilations. For example, on the McCartney
    and Wings greatest hits album 
    <i>Wingspan</i>, the live Wings version is included on the
    US/Canada releases, while the McCartney solo studio version is
    included on the UK release.</p>
      <p>A different live Wings recording of "Coming Up" appears on
    the album version of the 
    <i>Concerts for the People of Kampuchea</i>, with an additional
    verse that was edited out of the Glasgow release.</p>
      <p>"Coming Up" is also well known for its video. It is an early
    example of electronic trickery, with Paul McCartney playing ten
    roles and Linda McCartney playing two. The "band" (identified
    as "The Plastic Macs" on the drum kit—a nod to Lennon's
    "Plastic Ono Band") features Paul and Linda's imitations of
    various rock musician stereotypes, as well as a few
    identifiable musicians. In his audio commentary on the 2007
    video collection 
    <i>The McCartney Years</i>, McCartney identified the four
    characters that were impersonations of specific artists: Hank
    Marvin (guitarist from The Shadows), Ritchie Blackmore from
    Rainbow / Deep Purple, Ron Mael of Sparks (keyboards), the
    drummer, Ginger Baker from Cream, and a 'Beatlemania-Era'
    version of himself. While others such as author Fred Bronson
    have suggested that there are other identifiable impersonations
    in the video, such as Andy MacKay, Frank Zappa and Neil Young,
    McCartney said the other roles were simply comic relief.</p>
      <p>The B-side, the live Wings version of "Coming Up", became a
    #1 U.S. Hot 100 hit in June 1980. The A-side, the McCartney
    solo version, reached #2 in the UK.</p>
      <p>"Coming Up" is the only Paul McCartney song to hit the top
    of the U.S. 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 chart that was officially credited by 
    <i>Billboard</i>to McCartney as a solo artist, despite the fact
    that the "Live At Glasgow" version of "Coming Up" that actually
    topped the U.S. chart was performed by (and credited to)
    McCartney &amp; Wings. All other 
    <i>Billboard</i>number-one singles involving McCartney after
    The Beatles are officially credited to either Paul &amp; Linda
    McCartney ("Uncle Albert/Admiral Halsey"), Paul McCartney &amp;
    Wings ("My Love," "Band On The Run"), Wings ("Listen To What
    The Man Said", "Silly Love Songs," "With A Little Luck"), Paul
    McCartney &amp; Stevie Wonder ("Ebony &amp; Ivory") and Paul
    McCartney &amp; Michael Jackson ("Say, Say, Say"). That oddity
    makes McCartney the ex-Beatle to top the charts both the most
    (in conjunction with Wings and others) and the least (by
    himself) after the band's breakup. Ringo Starr and John Lennon
    each registered two U.S. pop number-one hits, while George
    Harrison had three, all of which were credited to them
    alone.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
