<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cold_Hearted 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cold_Hearted</songId>
   <title>Cold Hearted</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paula_Abdul</artistId>
      <artistName>Paula Abdul</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1989-09-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/5/55/E739346vw40.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Paula-Abdul+Cold-Hearted.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Forever Your Girl</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 22, 1989 (US)</released>
   <recorded>1988</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>New Jack Swing</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>Album version 3:51</length>
      <length>Single edit 3:36</length>
      <length>UK single remix 3:35</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Virgin</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Elliot Wolff</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Elliot Wolff</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Cold Hearted" (often mistitled "Cold Hearted Snake") is a
    single from Paula Abdul's album 
    <i>Forever Your Girl</i>, written and co-produced by Elliot
    Wolff. It hit number one on the Billboard Hot 100, becoming the
    album's third song to top the US chart. "Cold Hearted" became
    one of Abdul's best known songs for its then streetwise lyrics
    and provocative music video.</p>
      <p>The video for "Cold Hearted" was inspired from Bob Fosse's
    erotica dance sequence from the movie 
    <i>All That Jazz</i>. In the video, Abdul dances for music
    executives with a group of semi-nude dancers. The "cold hearted
    snake" may refer to one continually bored male executive who
    replies to Paula's request for a critque simply with "very
    nice". She turns away, makes a face, the screen goes dark, and
    something happens to make the dancers laugh. The dance floor
    includes scaffolding where Abdul and her dancers hang and
    grind. Abdul's choreography for this video was very sexual and
    intricate, showing her more naughty side. The video was
    directed by David Fincher (of 
    <i>Fight Club</i>fame), and spent more than three weeks on top
    of MTV's video rotation list.</p>
      <p>It is notable for featuring both female/male and male/male
    dancer combinations. In the video, Paula performs a rap
    interlude; this is included on some variations of the single.
    In 1999, Christina Aguilera shot the video for her second
    single "What a Girl Wants" in the same place and with a similar
    plot to Abdul's video for "Cold Hearted".</p>
      <p>"Cold Hearted" topped the Billboard Hot 100 chart for one
    week in September 1989, ending Richard Marx's three week run at
    the summit with "Right Here Waiting". "Cold Hearted" became one
    of the biggest hits of the year and was ranked sixth in the
    "Top 100 hits of 1989". Due to the single's enormous
    popularity, it was slow to descend from the chart, spending a
    total of eight weeks (2 months) in the Billboard Top 10
    alone.</p>
      <p>"Cold Hearted" was the final UK release from 
    <i>Forever Your Girl</i>in 1990. It was issued in remixed form
    unlike in the US and elsewhere, where an edit of the album
    version was released instead. It charted on 29 September 1990
    at #55, going on to peak at #46 the following week. This
    remixed version was the follow to the Shep Pettibone remix of
    "Knocked Out" which had reached #21 three months
    previously.</p>
      <p>US/Euro 12"/Euro CD single</p>
      <p>UK CD single</p>
      <p>American indie band sBACH covered the song. An audio sample
    can be heard on their official MySpace page.</p>
      <p>Uzbek singer Vicki Vaka recorded a cover of the song in 1999
    and included it on her second compilation album in 2003.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
