<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Song_from_Moulin_Rouge 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Song_from_Moulin_Rouge</songId>
   <title>The Song from Moulin Rouge (Where Is Your Heart)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Percy_Faith</artistId>
      <artistName>Percy Faith</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1953-05-16</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Song from Moulin Rouge" (also known as "Where Is Your
    Heart") is a popular song that first appeared in the 1952 film 
    <i>Moulin Rouge</i>.</p>
      <p>The music was written by Georges Auric. The original French
    lyrics were by Jacques Larue, the English words by William
    Engvick. However, in the film the song is called "It's April
    Again", and there is no mention of the phrase "Where Is Your
    Heart". A similar instance occurred in 
    <i>Romeo and Juliet</i>, in which the love theme was entitled
    "What Is a Youth?" in the film, but became "A Time For Us" when
    recorded as a popular song.</p>
      <p>In 
    <i>Moulin Rouge</i>, the theme song was sung by Muriel Smith,
    dubbing for Zsa Zsa Gabor who lip-synched to Smith's
    singing.</p>
      <p>The most popular version of the song was made by Percy
    Faith's Orchestra, with a vocal by Felicia Sanders. The
    recording by Faith and Sanders was made on January 22, 1953 and
    released by Columbia Records as catalog number 39944. It first
    reached the Billboard charts on March 28, 1953 and lasted 24
    weeks on the chart, peaking at #1.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom, the version by Mantovani was the
    biggest hit. This version also charted in the U.S. The
    recording by Mantovani was released in the U.S. by London
    Records as catalog number 1328. It first reached the Billboard
    chart on May 16, 1953 and lasted 5 weeks on the chart, peaking
    at #13. However, in the United Kingdom Mantovani's version of
    the track reached number one in the UK Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>The song also reached #1 on the Cash Box chart, which
    combined all versions, in 1953. Both Faith's and Mantovani's
    versions sold over a million copies.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
