<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Let_the_Stars_Get_in_Your_Eyes 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Let_the_Stars_Get_in_Your_Eyes</songId>
   <title>Don't Let the Stars Get in Your Eyes</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perry_Como</artistId>
      <artistName>Perry Como</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1953-01-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Don't Let the Stars Get in Your Eyes" is an off meter
    ballad concerning a man away from home worried that his
    paramour may unwittingly stray from their relationship. The
    song was recorded in many different styles by many artists. It
    was written by Winston L. Moore (whose stage name was Slim
    Willet) and was published in 1952. The title comes from the
    opening refrain:</p>
      <p>The song was first recorded by Slim Willet and the Brush
    Cutters (4 Star 11614, reaching #1) and then by Ray Price
    (Columbia 4-21025, reaching #5). Skeets McDonald followed with
    a Western swing hit, reaching #1 and staying on the charts 18
    weeks. His version was released by Capitol Records as catalog
    number 2216 with the flip side “Big Family Trouble".</p>
      <p>The best selling performance was a pop version recorded by
    Perry Como on November 4, 1952 and released in the following
    versions:</p>
      <p>The song was also covered by Eileen Barton in a recording
    issued by Coral Records as catalog number 60882, with the flip
    side “Tennessee Tango”, and by country music artist k.d. lang
    on her 1988 album, 
    <i>Shadowland</i>.</p>
      <p>It was spoofed by Homer and Jethro on their album 
    <i>America's Song Butchers: The Weird World of Homer and
    Jethro</i>in a song entitled "Don't Let the Stars Get in Your
    Eyeballs", the lyrics of which are also found in a Steve
    Goodman song entitled "Talk Backwards".</p>
      <p>The song was recorded in 2008 by Australian singer and
    composer Alfio for his album 
    <i>Classic Rewinds</i>which pays tribute to Perry Como, Dean
    Martin and 13 other popular Italian-American singers.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
