<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/West_End_Girls 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/West_End_Girls</songId>
   <title>West End Girls</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pet_Shop_Boys</artistId>
      <artistName>Pet Shop Boys</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-05-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/fb/WestEndGirls.jpg/200px-WestEndGirls.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Pet-Shop-Boys+West-End-Girls.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Please</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>9 April 1984 (1st release) , 28 October 1985 (2nd release)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Unique Studios, New York 1984</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Synthpop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:14 (original 7" mix)</length>
      <length>3:59 (1985 7" version)</length>
      <length>4:45 (album version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic , Parlophone</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bobby Orlando (1984)</producer>
      <producer>Stephen Hague (1985)</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"West End Girls" is a song by British pop duo Pet Shop Boys.
    Written by Neil Tennant and Chris Lowe, the song was released
    twice as a single. It is a synthpop song, influenced by hip hop
    music. The lyrics focus on class, and inner-city pressure, and
    were inspired by T.S. Eliot's poem 
    <i>The Waste Land</i>. It was generally well received by
    contemporary music critics and has been frequently cited as a
    highlight in the duo's career.</p>
      <p>The first version of the song was produced by Bobby Orlando
    and was released in April 1984, becoming a club hit in the
    United States and some European countries. After the duo signed
    with EMI, the song was re-recorded with producer Stephen Hague,
    for their first studio album, 
    <i>Please</i>. In late 1985, the song was re-released, reaching
    number one in the United Kingdom and the United States in 1986.
    In 1987, the song won for Best Single at The BRIT Awards, and
    Best International Hit at the Ivor Novello Awards. In 2005,
    20 years later after its release, the song was awarded
    Song of The Decade between the years 1985 and 1994, by the
    British Academy of Composers and Songwriters.</p>
      <p>Neil Tennant, an editor of the British pop magazine 
    <i>Smash Hits</i>, and Chris Lowe, an architecture student, met
    at an electronics shop in London in August 1981, they became
    friends, and started to write and record songs together. In
    1983, Tennant met producer Bobby Orlando, while on an
    assignment in New York interviewing Sting for 
    <i>Smash Hits</i>. After listening to some demos, Orlando
    offered to produce for the duo.</p>
      <p>In 1984, the duo recorded three songs with Orlando, at
    Unique Studios in New York, "West End Girls", "Opportunities
    (Let's Make Lots of Money)", and "One More Chance". Orlando
    played most of the instruments in the song, including the jazz
    riff at the end. Lowe played one chord and the bassline. It
    included a drum part lifted from Michael Jackson's "Billie
    Jean", and an arrangement involving what Tennant called "Barry
    White chords". Orlando was thrilled by the song's production;
    his idea was to make a rap record in a British accent.</p>
      <p>In April 1984, "West End Girls" was released, becoming a
    club hit in Los Angeles and San Francisco, and a minor dance
    hit in Belgium, and France, but was only available in the
    United Kingdom as a 12" import. In March 1985, after long
    negotiations, Pet Shop Boys cut their contractual ties with
    Orlando, and hired manager Tom Watkins, who signed them with
    EMI. They re-recorded "West End Girls" with producer Stephen
    Hague, and re-released the song in late 1985, topping the
    charts in both the UK and the U.S.</p>
      <p>"West End Girls" is a synthpop song, influenced by hip hop
    music. The song's socially conscious streak, as well as the
    propulsive bass line, derives from Grandmaster Flash's protest
    rap song "The Message". Lowe and Hague created a "snaky,
    obsessive rhythm punch" for the music, replacing the song's
    previously sparse beats and minimal keyboard lines.</p>
      <p>Tennant started to write the song when he was staying at his
    cousin's house in Nottingham while watching a gangster film.
    Just when he was going to sleep, he came up with the lines:
    "Sometimes you're better off dead, there's a gun in your hand
    and it's pointing at your head". The lyrics were inspired by
    T.S. Eliot's poem 
    <i>The Waste Land</i>, particularly in the use of different
    narrative voices and arcane references. The song's lyrics
    mainly focus on class and inner-city pressure, introducing
    existential anxiety, and urban neurosis to the melody. Tennant
    later said that the commonly accepted vision of the song being
    about rough trade was not intended.</p>
      <p>"West End Girls" has been generally well received by music
    critics. Stephen Thomas Erlewine from Allmusic in a review of
    the album 
    <i>Please</i>called the song "hypnotic", adding that "it's not
    only a classic dance single, it's a classic pop single". In a
    review for the group's second studio album 
    <i>Actually</i>, Rob Hoerburger from 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine commented that "West End Girls"
    was "as catchy as anything on the radio in 1986", praising "its
    enticing bass line and foreboding synth riffs", but felt that
    it was almost "nullified by peevish spoken asides and the
    cryptic posturing of the duo's lyrics". In a review of the live
    album 
    <i>Concrete</i>, Michael Hubbard from musicOMH said that "West
    End Girls" was one of the songs that "round out a collection
    that never feels too long or superfluous", adding that it help
    "installing Tennant and Lowe as national treasures".</p>
      <p>Nitsuh Abebe from Pitchfork Media, in a review of their
    compilation album 
    <i>Pop Art: Pet Shop Boys - The Hits</i>commented that in the
    song "we meet Tennant not as a singer, but as a speaker",
    adding that "he mumbles the verses to us not like a star, but
    like a stranger in a raincoat, slinking alongside you and
    pointing out the sights". LAUNCHcast's Jamie Gill in a review
    of the same compilation album said that "West End Girls" is
    "still as sleek, smart and modern as it sounded in 1985".</p>
      <p>In 1987, "West End Girls" won for Best Single at The BRIT
    Awards, and for Best International Hit at the Ivor Novello
    Awards. In 2005, the British Academy of Composers and
    Songwriters gave to "West End Girls" the Ivor Novello Award for
    Song of The Decade between the years 1985 and 1994.</p>
      <p>The video was directed by Andy Morahan and Eric Watson, and
    consists of shots of the duo around London. At the beginning of
    the video, noises from the city can be heard, a camera passes
    Lowe on the street, and focus on two vintage dolls in a shop
    window. Then appears a sequence of quick cuts with shots of the
    city's different sub-cultures, the video freezes and cuts to
    Tennant and Lowe, who walk through an empty Berwick Street in
    Soho. They stand in front of a red garage door, Tennant is in
    front dressed with a long coat addressing directly to the
    camera, Lowe stands behind him with a blank expression.</p>
      <p>Then the video shows shots of people walking into the London
    Underground metro system, and as the chorus starts the duo
    appears on the boarding platform. In slow motion, the camera
    passes through a shopping mall in central London, followed by
    the duo walking along the concourse at Waterloo Station. It
    cuts to a brief shot of a red double-decker bus, and black and
    white shots of the Tower Bridge, Westminster and the Big Ben
    from the sky. The duo poses on the South Bank of the River
    Thames in a pastiche of a postcard image, with the Houses of
    Parliament as a background.</p>
      <p>The camera shows shots of young women, and passes through
    arcades and movie theaters in Leicester Square. The camera now
    passes the South Africa House, showing protestors in an
    anti-apartheid vigil. The video cuts to a closeup of Tennant
    singing the chorus, with a purple neon sign passing across his
    face. At the end the camera passes again through Leicester
    Square, where people queue to see 
    <i>Fletch</i>and 
    <i>Desperately Seeking Susan</i>. The video was nominated for
    Best New Artist in a Video at the 1986 MTV Video Music Awards,
    but lost to a-ha's "Take on Me".</p>
      <p>"West End Girls" was first released in April 1984 through
    writer and producer Bobby Orlando's label. The song was a club
    hit in the United States, and in some European countries like
    Belgium, where it debuted at number 24 on the VRT Top 30 chart
    on 28 July 1984, peaking at 17 four weeks later. Having signed
    with EMI the group released their first major label single
    "Opportunities (Let's Make Lots of Money)", but it failed to
    attract attention. The Pet Shop Boys then decided to release
    "West End Girls" for the second time. Producer Stephen Hague
    then reworked the song and the single was re-released in late
    1985.</p>
      <p>"West End Girls" was released in the United Kingdom in
    October 1985, debuting on the UK Singles Chart at number 80,
    and within eight weeks of its release, it had reached the top
    of the chart. It maintained the number one position for two
    weeks and received a gold certification by the British
    Phonographic Industry (BPI) in January 1986. Across Europe,
    "West End Girls" also topped the singles chart in Norway, as
    well as peaking in the top three in Belgium, Germany, Ireland,
    the Netherlands, Sweden, and Switzerland.</p>
      <p>In Canada, "West End Girls" first entered the 
    <i>RPM</i>singles chart in April 1985, reaching a peak position
    of 81 in June 1985. In March 1986, the song re-entered the
    chart, peaking at number one for one week on 17 May 1986. In
    the United States, "West End Girls" debuted on the Hot 100 at
    number 71, reaching the number one position on 10 May 1986, and
    remained on the chart for 20 weeks. The song also peaked at
    number one on 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Hot Dance Music/Club Play chart for two
    weeks.</p>
      <p>The titles "Nouvelle version" and "Original 7" version" do
    not appear on any releases. They are names created by fans in
    order to distinguish the different versions.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
