<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sledgehammer_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sledgehammer_(song)</songId>
   <title>Sledgehammer</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Gabriel</artistId>
      <artistName>Peter Gabriel</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-07-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/c/cf/Sledgehammer_Cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Peter-Gabriel+Sledgehammer.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>So</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 1986</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1985</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:16</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Geffen</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Daniel Lanois</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Sledgehammer" is a hit song by Peter Gabriel from his 1986
    album 
    <i>So</i>. It peaked at number one in Canada for four weeks on
    21 July 1986, number one on the Hot 100 chart in the United
    States on 26 July 1986, and number four in the UK singles
    chart, thanks in part to a popular and influential music video.
    It was his biggest hit in North America and ties with "Games
    Without Frontiers" as his biggest hit in the United
    Kingdom.</p>
      <p>The song was influenced by 1960s soul music, in particular
    the music made by the Memphis label Stax. The distinctive horn
    track was provided by the Memphis Horns, house musicians at
    Stax. The opening horn riff is similar to the beginning of John
    Coltrane's "Chronic Blues" from the 
    <i>Coltrane</i>album. The song also features a synthesized
    shakuhachi flute.</p>
      <p>The lyrics are a mosaic of sexual innuendos, with references
    to steam train, bumper cars, Big Dipper (roller coaster) and
    fruit cage as metaphors for male and female sexual organs and
    references to pollination, fruit and bees as metaphors of
    sexual act.</p>
      <p>"Sledgehammer" was Peter Gabriel's first and, to this date,
    only number-one hit in the United States. It replaced
    "Invisible Touch" by his former band Genesis, which had its
    only number-one U.S. hit the previous week. "Sledgehammer" also
    achieved chart success on other 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts in 1986, spanning the range between
    Album Rock Tracks (two weeks at the summit in May and June) and
    Hot Dance Club Play (one week atop this chart in July).
    (Original Length: 5:09) The single release also included a
    previously unreleased track called "Don't Break This Rhythm"
    and an "'85 Remix" of his 1982 single "I Have the Touch." U.S.
    versions of the single contained an extended dance remix of
    "Sledgehammer." It was among the first singles released on
    compact disc.</p>
      <p>The TV series 
    <i>Sledge Hammer!</i>was also popular when the song was
    released, although the two are not related.</p>
      <p>In 1991, rappers 3rd Bass borrowed the Tony Levin bass line
    from the song for their hit "Pop Goes the Weasel." The 1993
    Naughty By Nature song "Hip Hop Hooray" also samples the
    shakuhachi intro. In 2000, the song was sampled for "I've Got
    to Have It" by Jermaine Dupri, Monica and Nas, which appeared
    on the soundtrack for the motion picture 
    <i>Big Momma's House.</i>The instrumental of such song is used
    by independent wrestler Claudio Castagnoli as an entrance
    theme.</p>
      <p>In 1993, the song appeared on a British television
    commercial for the Vauxhall Cavalier, followed by the guitar
    riff from Eric Clapton's "Layla."[1]</p>
      <p>In 2007, Finnish Symphonic Epic Metal Northern Kings
    featuring Jarkko Ahola from Teräsbetoni, Marco Hietala from
    Nightwish and Tarot, Tony Kakko from Sonata Arctica and
    Juha-Pekka Leppäluoto from Charon covered the song on their
    album 
    <i>Reborn</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2008, R&amp;B singer Maiysha did a sensual rendition of
    "Sledgehammer" for her album "This Much Is True"</p>
      <p>In 2009, composer Gavin Castleton released a video of a solo
    looping rendition of "Sledgehammer" on his youtube channel.</p>
      <p>Dave Matthews Band began covering this song during the 2008
    tour.</p>
      <p>In 2009, the song was played during Sam Newman's entrance on
    an episode of The Footy Show, seeing as Sam was dressed in a
    Sledgehammer costume to somewhat represent Matthew Lloyd.</p>
      <p>In 2009, the song was assigned to be covered by a capella
    group Nota on NBC's The Sing-off.</p>
      <p>"Sledgehammer" spawned a widely popular and influential
    music video directed by Stephen R. Johnson. Aardman Animations
    and the Brothers Quay provided claymation, pixilation, and stop
    motion animation that gave life to images in the song. The
    video ended with a large group of extras jerkily rotating
    around Gabriel, among them: Gabriel's daughters Anna and
    Melanie, the animators themselves, and director Stephen
    Johnson's girlfriend. Also included were six women who posed as
    the back-up singers of the song. Gabriel lay under a sheet of
    glass for 16 hours while filming the video one frame at a
    time.</p>
      <p>In 1987, it won nine MTV Video Music Awards, a record which
    still stands as of 2008. It ranked at number four on MTV's 
    <i>100 Greatest Music Videos Ever Made</i>(1999). MTV later
    announced that "Sledgehammer" is the most played music video in
    the history of the station. "Sledgehammer" has also been
    declared to be MTV's number one animated video of all time.</p>
      <p>The video was also voted number seven on TMF's 
    <i>Ultimate 50 Videos You Must See</i>- first aired 24 June
    2006. It ranked at number 2 on VH1's "Top 20 Videos of the
    80's" as well as being named the #1 "Amazing Moment in Music"
    on the Australian TV show 
    <i>20 to 1</i>in 2007.</p>
      <p>The portion of the song featuring the synthesized flute solo
    was realized in the video by first one and then two oven-ready
    turkeys, headless and featherless, animated using stop-motion.
    These were animated by Nick Park (of 
    <i>Wallace and Gromit</i>fame) who, at that time was refining
    his work in plasticine animation.</p>
      <p>The video won Best British Video at the 1987 Brit Awards.
    Also, the video was nominated for the Best Music Video category
    for the first annual Soul Train Music Awards in that same
    year.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
