<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Downtown_(Petula_Clark_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Downtown_(Petula_Clark_song)</songId>
   <title>Downtown</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Petula_Clark</artistId>
      <artistName>Petula Clark</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1965-01-23</week>
      <week>1965-01-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/9a/Downtownsleeve.jpg/200px-Downtownsleeve.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Petula-Clark+Downtown.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Downtown</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 1964</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>16 October 1964</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:05</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Pye 7N 15722 , ( United Kingdom ) , Warner Bros. 5494 , ( United States ) , Vogue EPL.8301 ( France ) , Vogue DV 14297 ( Germany ) , Vogue STU 42207 ( Denmark ) , Vogue US-105 ( Japan )</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Tony Hatch</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Tony Hatch</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Downtown" is a pop song composed by Tony Hatch which as
    recorded by Petula Clark became an international hit - #1 in
    the US - early in 1965.</p>
      <p>Tony Hatch recalls: "'Downtown' was written on the occasion
    of my first visit to New York. I was staying at a hotel on
    Central Park and I wandered down to Broadway and to Times
    Square and, naively, I thought I was downtown. Forgetting that
    in New York especially downtown is a lot further downtown
    getting on towards Battery Park. I loved the whole atmosphere
    there and the song came to me very, very quickly."[1]</p>
      <p>Hatch had originally intended to present "Downtown" to The
    Drifters, but when British singer Petula Clark heard the
    incomplete tune, she proposed that if he could write lyrics to
    match the quality of the melody, she would be interested in
    recording it.</p>
      <p>"Downtown" was recorded 16 October 1964 at the Pye Studios
    in Marble Arch. Thirty minutes before the session was
    scheduled, Hatch was still touching up the song's lyrics in the
    studio's washroom. Hatch always insisted on recording all the
    personnel on his productions actually performing together as
    would be heard on the finished track: the large number of
    personnel contributing to the "Downtown" session necessitated
    that two studios be utilized for the track's recording, with a
    closed-circuit television connection allowing Hatch to conduct
    the personnel in both the studio in which he was physically
    present and the auxiliary studio.[2] The session personnel on
    "Downtown" included guitarists Vic Flick, Jimmy Page and Big
    Jim Sullivan,[3] and also drummer Bobby Graham[4] and the
    Breakaways vocal group.[5]</p>
      <p>"Downtown" entered the UK Top 50 dated the week 14 November
    1964 ending a virtual two year UK chart absence for Clark; of
    the ten singles she'd had released in the UK during that period
    only one: "Chariot", #39 the spring of 1963, had appeared in
    even the lower charts. "Downtown" rose to #2 that December
    remaining there for three weeks, kept out of the #1 position by
    the Beatles' "I Feel Fine". Certified a Gold record for sales
    in the UK of 400,000, "Downtown" also reached #2 in Ireland and
    #1 in Australia, New Zealand, Rhodesia and South Africa, and
    was also a hit in India (#3) and Norway (#8).</p>
      <p>However "Downtown" had its greatest significance in the
    reception it was afforded in the US. Warner Bros. a&amp;r man
    Joe Smith was scouting in London for records with American hit
    potential, the musical British Invasion of the US then going
    strong. Smith wanted to release Clark's "Downtown" in the US
    and when a surprised Hatch asked if Smith didn't consider
    "Downtown" to be "a very English record" he recalls Smith's
    reply as: "It's perfect. It's just an observation from outside
    of America and it's just beautiful and just perfect." [6]</p>
      <p>Warner Bros. released "Downtown" in the US in December of
    1964: the track appeared near the bottom of the national charts
    the week before Christmas and despite the Christmas season
    traditionally being the worst time to break a new hit
    "Downtown" shot up to the Top Ten in five weeks and the next
    week - 23 January 1965 - was #1. "Downtown" retained that
    position a further week before being overtaken by the
    ascendancy of the Righteous Brothers' "You've Lost That Lovin'
    Feelin'". Clark became the first UK female artist to have a US
    #1 hit during the rock and roll era and the second in the
    annals of US charted music, Vera Lynn having hit #1 US with
    "Auf Wiederseh'n Sweetheart" in 1952. "Downtown" also made
    Clark the first UK female artist to have a single certified as
    a Gold record for US sales of one million units. "Downtown"
    would be the first of fifteen consecutive hits Clark would
    place in the US Top 40 during a period when she'd have
    considerably less chart impact in her native UK, there reaching
    the Top 40 eight times.</p>
      <p>Clark, who had been playing to her French speaking fans in
    small venues in Quebec when "Downtown" entered the US charts,
    swiftly cut non-English versions of the song for the markets in
    France, Italy and Germany; the absence in each region's
    language of a two-syllable equivalent of "downtown"
    necessitated a radical lyric recasting for the versions aimed
    at France ("Dans le temps"), Italy ("Ciao Ciao") and Spain
    ("Chao Chao") which respectively charted at #6, #2 and - for
    three weeks - #1. "Dans le temps" also reaching #18 in the
    Wallonia region of Belgium. The title and lyric "Downtown" was
    retained for an otherwise German version which was the most
    successful foreign language version reaching #1 in Germany and
    also reaching #5 in Austria and #11 on the charts for the
    Flanders region of Belgium.</p>
      <p>Petula Clark has re-recorded the "Downtown" four times, in
    1976 (with a disco beat), in 1984 (with a new piano and trumpet
    intro that leads into the song's original opening), in 1988
    with Dutch producer Eddy Ouwens for the album "My Greatest" for
    release in the UK, Germany and Benelux only, and in 1996. In
    addition, the original 1964 recording was remixed and
    re-released in 1988, 1999, and 2003.</p>
      <p>Following 9/11, New York City adopted Clark's version of
    "Downtown" as the theme song for a series of commercials
    encouraging tourism to Lower Manhattan. The song has been used
    by other metropolitan areas — including Chicago, Indianapolis,
    and Singapore — for promotional purposes as well.</p>
      <p>"Downtown" has been covered numerous times by other artists
    since Clark's original recording, notably by Dolly Parton in
    1984. After she recorded the track in December 1983, "Downtown"
    appeared on Parton's album of cover versions, 
    <i>The Great Pretender</i>. It was followed by a single release
    of the track on RCA Records in April 1984 and proved to be a
    moderate success, peaking at number eighty-seven on the
    Billboard Hot 100 pop chart and number twenty-seven on the Hot
    Country Songs chart in the United States. Parton's version
    altered some of the lyrics: "Listen to the rhythm of a gentle
    bossa nova" became "Listen to the rhythm of the music that
    they're playing".</p>
      <p>Emma Bunton's remake of "Downtown" was released in 13
    November 2006. Bunton, whose admiration for Petula Clark was
    evident on the 2004 
    <i>Free Me</i>album, had recorded "Downtown" at AIR Studios
    {Lyndhurst) with Simon Franglen producing; the orchestra for
    the track was recorded at Angel Studios with Gavin Wright
    conducting. Bunton's "Downtown" was selected as the 2006 BBC
    Children in Need single, with all proceeds from the release
    going to the charity and Bunton performed "Downtown" on the
    2006 
    <i>Children in Need</i>telethon which began broadcast that 17
    November. The single debuted on the UK singles chart dated 25
    November 2006 at #24. Centralfm.com noted Bunton's chart debut,
    declaring "Downtown" "the song she was born to cover...One of
    the all time great pop songs, ["Downtown"] was long overdue for
    a revival and Emma Bunton pays it the respect it deserves."</p>
      <p>Centralfm predicted "Downtown" would rise to the Top 3 in
    its second week and the single did indeed jump to #3 on the
    chart for 2 December 2006: the mid-week stats had ranked
    "Downtown" at #2 behind "Patience" by Take That but on the
    chart for the full week Bunton was bested not only by Take That
    at #1 but by the previous week's #1 "Smack That" by Akon which
    outsold "Downtown" by fifty-seven copies. In fact "Downtown"
    was Bunton's highest charting single since her #1 solo debut
    "What Took You So Long?" in 2001. However "Downtown" proved to
    have little staying power, spending only three weeks in the Top
    20, performances by Bunton on a Christmas Day broadcast of 
    <i>Top of the Pops</i>and 
    <i>New Year Live</i>failing to significantly buoy its
    popularity.</p>
      <p>These are the formats and track listings of major single
    releases of "Downtown".</p>
      <p>UK Sales: 77,039</p>
      <p>Directed by Harvey &amp; Carolyn, (the directors who also
    directed her video for her single "Maybe") the sexually
    suggestive music video for the single is set in a hotel bedroom
    featuring Bunton as a maid. It includes appearances from
    contestants from the BBC's reality television show 
    <i>Strictly Come Dancing</i>and features cameos from Matt
    Dawson, Louisa Lytton, Carol Smillie, Spoony, Mark Ramprakash,
    Claire King, Peter Schmeichel, Craig Revel Horwood, Anton du
    Beke, Brendan Cole, Erin Boag, Lilia Kopylova, Karen Hardy, and
    Darren Bennett. Though the lyrics are innocuous, in the video
    Bunton's body language clearly twists the song title into a
    euphemism for sexual activity. Bunton, however, has denied this
    repeatedly, for example in this interview with online music
    magazine Popjustice:</p>
      <p>Popjustice: "The dancers in the 'Downtown' video seem to
    know you very well indeed. So well that they are all pointing
    at your fanny. Was this your idea?", Bunton: "I don't
    understand where this has come from. It is a dance routine and
    it is nothing to do with anything like that. It is everyone
    else's dirty little minds. Especially yours. It worries me
    because it is a classic and you can't make classics rude."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
