<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sussudio 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sussudio</songId>
   <title>Sussudio</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phil_Collins</artistId>
      <artistName>Phil Collins</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1985-07-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/20/Phil_Collins_Sussudio.jpg/200px-Phil_Collins_Sussudio.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Phil-Collins+Sussudio.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>No Jacket Required</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 9, 1985</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1984</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:23 (album version)</length>
      <length>6:36 (extended version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic Records , Virgin , WEA</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Phil Collins</producer>
      <producer>The System</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Sussudio" is a pop song by Phil Collins, released as a
    single in February 1985. The song is also the first track on
    Collins' third album, 
    <i>No Jacket Required,</i>released in January of the same year.
    The song entered frequent rotation on MTV in May, and by July
    6, both the single and the album reached number one on their
    respective U.S. Billboard charts. The music video, which was
    filmed in a pub owned by Richard Branson, featured Collins
    playing the song to a crowd that is bored at first, but gets
    excited and starts dancing when Collins begins performing.</p>
      <p>The main lyric came about as Collins was improvising lyrics
    to a drum machine track he had programmed: "suss-sussudio" was
    a working wording that scanned properly. After trying to find
    an alternative word to fit the rhythm, the singer decided to
    keep "Sussudio" as the song title and lyric. The song is about
    a normal crush that a schoolboy may have on a girl and that by
    saying "suss-sussudio" may raise speculations about the boy
    having a stutter. The song was received mostly positively, and
    has been mentioned in numerous moments in pop culture.</p>
      <p>Collins has said that he "improvised" the lyric. Collins was
    just playing around with a drum machine, and the lyric
    "sus-sussudio" was what came out of his mouth. "So I kinda knew
    I had to find something else for that word, then I went back
    and tried to find another word that scanned as well as
    "sussudio", and I couldn't find one, so I went back to
    "sussudio"," Collins said. According to Collins, the lyrics are
    about a schoolboy crush on a girl at school. Collins' older
    daughter has a horse named "Sussudio".</p>
      <p>The music video for the song was filmed at a pub owned by
    Richard Branson in London. The accompanying music video
    features Collins, as well as long-time collaborators Daryl
    Stuermer and Chester Thompson. It begins with an outdoor shot
    of a pub, then cuts to Collins and his band playing for a
    uninterested crowd. The crowd slowly migrates toward the band
    as the song progresses, leaving them cheering at the end.
    Renowned bass player Lee Sklar also appears in the video,
    however neither Sklar nor Thompson played on the actual studio
    recording.</p>
      <p>Reception for the song was mostly positive. Keegan Hamilton
    of the 
    <i>Riverfront Times</i>said that the song was the best track on
    the album, saying that it's "catchy gibberish." "Even though
    this song isn't on the Flashdance soundtrack, it makes me want
    to put on some goofy legwarmers and kick out an aerobics
    routine. Where the vast majority of artists from this era try
    out the synthesizer/keyboard/horn section soup and fail
    miserably, Collins seems to have the recipe down to a science,"
    Hamilton adds. However, Geoff Orens of Allmusic believes that
    the song is "dated." Robert Hilburn of 
    <i>The Los Angeles Times</i>thought the song had a "friskier
    R&amp;B style" as compared to Collins' other songs, and agreed
    that it sounded very much like a Prince song.</p>
      <p>Michael R. Smith of 
    <i>The Daily Vault</i>believed that "Sussudio" was the best
    track on the album, calling it a "monster track," also adding
    that "This is a song that chugs and churns along at a gingerly
    pace, set to a beat that is sure to get car speakers thumping.
    At the time, it was like nothing you had ever heard before on
    the radio. The word 'Sussudio' may not have meant anything, but
    the song itself was pure magic." David Fricke of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>was not a fan, saying that songs like
    "Sussudio", with the heavy use of a horn section, were
    "beginning to wear thin."</p>
      <p>It is one of Collins' more famous songs and is referenced in
    many different media, including books, stand-up comedy acts and
    television shows. Collins has said that this is the song people
    most often sing to him when they spot him on the street.. The
    protagonist of the novel and film adaption of American Psycho,
    Patrick Bateman, briefly discusses the song, before engaging in
    sexual intercourse with two prostitutes while it plays loudly
    from his CD player in the background, amongst other work by
    Phil Collins. It was heavily criticized for sounding too much
    like Prince's song "1999", a claim which Collins does not deny,
    saying that he is a big fan of Prince's work.</p>
      <p>"Sussudio" was the first track released as a single in the
    UK, and the second to be released in the US. In the UK the song
    reached number 12 on the UK charts. In the US, the song entered
    frequent rotation on MTV in May, and by 6 July, both the single
    and the album had reached number one on their respective US 
    <i>Billboard charts</i>. A remix of the song appeared on
    Collins' 
    <i>12"ers</i>album.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
