<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Thing_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Thing_(song)</songId>
   <title>The Thing</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phil_Harris</artistId>
      <artistName>Phil Harris</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1950-12-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Thing" is a hit novelty song by Charles Randolph Grean
    which received much airplay in 1950.</p>
      <p>The most popular version of the song was recorded by Phil
    Harris on October 13, 1950 and released by RCA Victor Records
    as catalog number 20-3968. The record first reached the 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts on November 17, 1950. It lasted 14 weeks
    on the chart, peaking at #1.</p>
      <p>Other versions were recorded by Danny Kaye, Ray Charles,
    Teresa Brewer and Australian orchestra leader Les Welch. The
    Danny Kaye recording was made on December 1, 1950 and released
    by Decca Records as catalog number 27350. The Ray Charles
    recording was made on July 13, 1963 and released by
    ABC-Paramount Records in the album "Have A Smile With Me", as
    catalog number ABC 495 (mono) / ABCS 495 (stereo). The Teresa
    Brewer recording was made in October 1950, and released by
    London Records as catalog number 873. The Les Welch recording
    was made in January 1951 and released by Pacific Records, an
    Australian company, as catalog number 10-0051.</p>
      <p>The lyrics take the form of a first-person narration,
    describing the discovery on a beach of a box. Whatever is in
    the box is never revealed, nor is it called "The Thing" in the
    lyrics. When the lyrics call for The Thing to be named, the
    vocals simply pause for three percussive beats. For example,
    the first verse ends, "I discovered a [
    <i>three drum-beats</i>], right before my eyes!" (The listener
    could substitute any three-syllable phrase his imagination
    might invent, such as "dog-gone thing".)</p>
      <p>Initially, the narrator is overjoyed by his discovery and
    tries to sell it. Instead, he is thrown out by a proprietor
    with a threat to call the police. Undaunted, the narrator
    decides to give it to his wife, who also kicks him out and
    requests he never return with it. After going through life
    unable to rid himself of the Thing, the narrator dies and
    arrives in Heaven where Saint Peter tells him to take it "down
    below" to Hell. In the final verse, the narrator warns the
    listener not to open boxes on the beach as he did.</p>
      <p>The song aired on radio concurrently with a series of teaser
    ads which ran weekly in 
    <i>Collier's</i>promoting Howard Hawks' science fiction movie, 
    <i>The Thing from Another World</i>. The Hawks film was
    released April 6, 1951. While the song had no connection with
    the movie, some suspect it was a clever marketing tool to
    increase interest in seeing the film.</p>
      <p>Edward G. Robles, Jr. wrote a short science fiction story
    partially based around the song. It involved several hobos who
    find an object like the one described in the song. In the
    story, the object is discovered to be an alien disguised as
    something nobody wants. It was originally copyrighted by Galaxy
    Publishing Corp. in 1954.</p>
      <p>Chicago Coin made a pinball game in 1951 called THING with
    backglass and playfield art that got its inspiration from the
    song "The Thing". Roy Parker was the artist.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
