<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Groovy_Kind_of_Love 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Groovy_Kind_of_Love</songId>
   <title>Groovy Kind of Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phil_Collins</artistId>
      <artistName>Phil Collins</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1988-10-22</week>
      <week>1988-10-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/5f/MindbendersAGKoL.jpg/200px-MindbendersAGKoL.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Phil-Collins+Groovy-Kind-of-Love.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>A Groovy Kind of Love</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1965  (1965)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Classic Rock</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>1:57</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Fontana</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Carole Bayer Sager</writer>
      <writer>Toni Wine</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"A Groovy Kind of Love" is a pop song written by Toni Wine
    and Carole Bayer Sager for the Screen Gems music publishing
    company. It is heavily based on the Rondo movement of Sonatina
    in G major, op. 36 no. 5 by Muzio Clementi. The song was
    released first by Diane &amp; Annita in 1965, and several
    covers have since appeared on worldwide music charts.</p>
      <p>The song title was an early use of the then-new slang word
    "groovy". Wine, who was 17 years old when the song was written,
    says, "Carole came up with "Groovy kinda… groovy kinda…
    groovy…" and we're all just saying, "Kinda groovy, kinda
    groovy, kinda…" and I don't exactly know who came up with
    "Love," but it was "Groovy kind of love." And we did it. We
    wrote it in 20 minutes. It was amazing. Just flew out of our
    mouths, and at the piano, it was a real quick and easy song to
    write.</p>
      <p>The Mindbenders released a 1965 cover which reached number
    two on the Billboard Hot 100 and on the UK Singles Chart. The
    song was the only solo hit for Les Gray (lead vocalist with
    Mud); his version made it to #34 in the UK in 1977. Phil
    Collins released a 1988 version which hit #1 in both the U.S.
    and UK charts.</p>
      <p>Other covers include:</p>
      <p>In 1979 Italian artist Ivan Graziani recorded "Agnese", his
    own adaptation of Clementi's Rondo, which has the same song
    structure.</p>
      <p>The song is played on violins in the 
    <i>Friends</i>television episode "The One with the Wedding Part
    2".</p>
      <p>Jack McGraw, who ran the London Screen Gems offices, thought
    the Wine/Bayer Sager song was a perfect match for the new group
    The Mindbenders, who recorded their cover of "A Groovy Kind of
    Love" in 1965. They liked the result so much that they named
    their first album 
    <i>A Groovy Kind of Love</i>and released the song to radio as
    their debut single. It soon reached number two in the UK, and
    did the same in the United States when it was released there a
    year later.</p>
      <p>Phil Collins recorded a new version of "A Groovy Kind of
    Love" in 1988. He had originally suggested the song as a good
    one for collaborator Stephen Bishop to record, with Collins
    producing, but decided to record it himself when he took a
    starring role in the film 
    <i>Buster</i>, which had a 1960s setting. The song was
    originally released on 
    <i>Buster: The Original Motion Picture Soundtrack</i>, and also
    appeared on his Serious Hits… Live! album, as well as several
    Phil Collins compilation albums.</p>
      <p>This version went the Mindbenders release one better,
    hitting #1 in both the U.S. and UK charts, and it remains the
    only Collins single to top the charts in both countries. It
    also reached #1 on the U.S. Adult Contemporary chart. The song
    earned Collins a nomination for Grammy Award for Best Male Pop
    Vocal Performance in 1989; he lost to Bobby McFerrin's song
    "Don't Worry, Be Happy".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
