<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Against_All_Odds_(Take_a_Look_at_Me_Now) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Against_All_Odds_(Take_a_Look_at_Me_Now)</songId>
   <title>Against All Odds (Take a Look at Me Now)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phil_Collins</artistId>
      <artistName>Phil Collins</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1984-04-21</week>
      <week>1984-04-28</week>
      <week>1984-05-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/6b/Phil_Collins_Against_All_Odds_single_cover.jpg/200px-Phil_Collins_Against_All_Odds_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Phil-Collins+Against-All-Odds-Take-a-Look-at-Me-Now.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Against All Odds soundtrack</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 1984 (USA) , March 31, 1984 (UK)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1983</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:23</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Phil Collins</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Arif Mardin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Against All Odds (Take a Look at Me Now)" (also simply
    titled "Against All Odds") is a song originally written and
    recorded by British singer Phil Collins. The song was the main
    theme for the 1984 film of the same name, and first appeared on
    its soundtrack. It is a ballad in which its protagonist
    implores his/her ex-lover to "take a look at me now," knowing
    that reconciliation is "against all odds" but worth a try. It
    has been covered by several artists.</p>
      <p>Originally titled "How Can You Just Sit There?", the song
    was initially from the sessions for Collins' debut solo album 
    <i>Face Value</i>(1981), and it was one of about a dozen
    written for his first wife, who left him. Phil Collins released
    the song on the soundtrack to the film 
    <i>Against All Odds</i>, and it was produced by Arif Mardin.
    Rob Mounsey played piano and keyboard bass, Collins sang and
    played the drums with his (and Hugh Padgham's) trademark gated
    reverb sound, and a string arrangement by Mardin completed the
    production.</p>
      <p>According to Collins in a 1985 interview with Dan Neer; "We
    recorded the song in two days: One day in New York, the other
    in Los Angeles. The mixes were done by phone and the song went
    to Number 1. I couldn't believe it." It peaked at number 2 in
    the UK upon its release as a single] in 1984 and became
    Collins' third top ten single there, and it peaked at number 1
    on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 for three weeks, from 15 April to
    5 May 1984. It replaced "Footloose" by Kenny Loggins, and was
    replaced by Lionel Richie's "Hello." It is the first of six
    songs by Collins written specifically for a film soundtrack to
    appear on the Hot 100. It also became Collins' only number 1
    single on the Hot Mainstream Rock Tracks chart as a solo
    artist, although he would achieve two other number ones on this
    chart with his band, Genesis.</p>
      <p>"Against All Odds" won the Grammy Award for Best Male Pop
    Vocal Performance in 1985, and it was also nominated for the
    Academy Award for Best Original Song. Collins was the only
    nominee in the category not invited to sing his song on stage,
    and sat in the audience as Ann Reinking performed it. His
    perceived negative reaction shown on the telecast is considered
    to be one of the most awkward moments in the history of the
    ceremony, and has been a favourite reference for Dennis Miller
    to relate someone reacting in a horrified fashion.</p>
      <p>When another song Collins performed for a movie, "Separate
    Lives" was being nominated for an Academy Award, in interviews
    about the original snub by the Academy for "Against All Odds,"
    Collins would jokingly say "the hell with him - I'm going up
    too," referring to if the Stephen Bishop written song were to
    win the award.</p>
      <p>Collins lost to the Stevie Wonder song "I Just Called to Say
    I Love You." The song was first included on a Collins album on
    the 1998 compilation 
    <i>Hits</i>, and it also appeared on his compilation 
    <i>Love Songs: A Compilation... Old and New</i>(2004).</p>
      <p>A live performance of the song also appears on the 
    <i>Serious Hits… Live!</i>album. The live version was recorded
    in 1990 on the B-side of the single "Do You Remember?."</p>
      <p>The song's music video, directed by Taylor Hackford, and
    produced by Jeffrey Abelson, was an early example of a highly
    conceptual approach to creating hybrid movie/music-videos that
    producer Abelson pioneered. Echoing the love triangle theme of
    the film, Collins is seen performing in front of a wall of
    rainwater that is alternately lit red, blue, and green—each
    colour representing one of the three main characters in the
    film. It is this colour schematic that is used as an organic
    segue to and from character-specific scenes in the movie. The
    final scene pulls back from Collins to reveal him standing in
    the middle of a water-filled triangle formed from neon tubes in
    the same three colours—completing the visual concept as the
    three main characters are superimposed around the neon
    triangle's three sides. The concept for the video was created
    by Keith Williams, a Welsh-born writer who had already worked
    with Abelson on the video for "Dancin' With Myself" (Billy
    Idol) and would go on to also create concepts for "Holding Out
    for a Hero" (Bonnie Tyler) and "Ghostbusters" (Ray Parker, Jr.)
    for the same producer as well as "Say You Say Me" (Lionel
    Richie) from "White Nights" which Taylor Hackford also
    directed.</p>
      <p>A number 1 MTV video for several weeks, MTV ranked it as
    number 4 in its 1984 year-end top 20 video countdown.</p>
      <p>Collins discussed the song in a phone interview as an
    example for break-up songs in act one of 
    <i>This American Life</i>, episode 339 "Break-Up" on 24 August
    2007.</p>
      <p>American pop/R&amp;B singer Mariah Carey co-produced her
    version of the song with Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis for her
    sixth studio album 
    <i>Rainbow</i>.</p>
      <p>Carey co-produced the single edit of the song with Steve
    Mac. The song was released as the third single from 
    <i>Rainbow</i>. Although the song was promoted as part of
    Carey's 
    <i>Rainbow</i>in the United States, it was not released as a
    commercial or radio single there. It was initially released in
    some markets in early 2000.</p>
      <p>The song received moderate success only, although it reached
    Top 20 in several countries. The highest peak of the song was
    #2 in Norway.</p>
      <p>European CD single</p>
      <p>European CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>Japanese CD single</p>
      <p>The video for the Carey version of the song, directed by
    Paul Misbehoven, consists of a montage of clips of Carey
    singing the song from her various Rainbow World Tour stops to
    cullings from her 
    <i>Homecoming</i>special.</p>
      <p>Mariah Carey later re-recorded "Against All Odds (Take a
    Look at Me Now)" as a duet with Irish boyband Westlife. This
    version was released as the first single from Westlife's second
    album 
    <i>Coast to Coast</i>. The song was released in September 2000,
    a few months after Carey's solo version.</p>
      <p>Carey did not re-record her vocals for the duet however, the
    instrumental track was reproduced with a more organic sound
    complete with violins. The single was more successful than the
    original in the UK and Ireland where it peaked at number 1,
    giving Westlife their sixth consecutive number 1 entry in the
    UK charts. It also gave Carey her second number 1 single in the
    UK; however, to date she has only managed one solo UK number 1,
    "Without You".</p>
      <p>The song has received a silver sales certification in the UK
    for 200,000 copies shipped. The song was also the 28th best
    selling of 2000 in the UK.</p>
      <p>UK CD1</p>
      <p>UK CD2</p>
      <p>European CD</p>
      <p>Australian CD</p>
      <p>Japanese CD</p>
      <p>The video of this version was more popular than the video of
    Mariah Carey solo version. The video shows Carey and Westlife
    recording the song and exploring the island of Capri by
    boat.</p>
      <p>American indietronica band The Postal Service covered
    "Against All Odds" for the soundtrack to the 2004 film 
    <i>Wicker Park</i>. The cover was later named as one of the
    best cover songs of all time by the 
    <i>New York Post</i>.</p>
      <p>A music video was aired on MTV containing scenes from the
    movie and odds disappearing in a room.</p>
      <p>Against All Odds is the debut single by British 
    <i>X Factor</i>winner Steve Brookstein. It was released in 2004
    by Syco Records. The single charted at number 1 in the UK and
    number 11 in Ireland.</p>
      <p>In 2004, Steve Brookstein won the televised UK talent
    competition 
    <i>The X Factor</i>, and recorded a cover of "Against All Odds"
    as his debut single. It entered the UK Singles Chart at number
    1, a position it held for one week from 2 January 2005 to 8
    January 2005. It replaced "Do They Know It's Christmas?" by
    Band Aid 20, and was replaced by Elvis Presley's "Jailhouse
    Rock." It was later included on Brookstein's debut album 
    <i>Heart and Soul</i>.</p>
      <p>The music video for the song shows Steve's highlights from
    the show through to the moment he was announced X Factor
    winner, in a similar manner to other winner's videos from both
    The X Factor and Pop Idol. No original footage was recorded for
    the video.</p>
      <p>Seattle music columnist, Megan Seling began an experiment on
    Monday, 6 July 2009 wherein she vowed to listen to Collins'
    "Against All Odds" at least once every hour that she was awake
    for an entire week and chronicled the journey here.</p>
      <p>I've done dumber things. 
    <cite>- Megan Seling</cite>
      </p>
      <p>This song is on the video game 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Volume 3</i>. It is also downloadable
    content for the game 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Presents: American Idol Encore</i>.</p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Brian McFadden •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Simon Cowell •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Louis Walsh •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Ronan Keating •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Steve Mac •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Wayne Hector</span>, 
    <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Cecelia Ahern •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Jodi Albert •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Kevin McDaid •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Kerry Katona</span>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
