<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Another_Brick_in_the_Wall 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Another_Brick_in_the_Wall</songId>
   <title>Another Brick in the Wall (Part II)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pink_Floyd</artistId>
      <artistName>Pink Floyd</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1980-03-22</week>
      <week>1980-03-29</week>
      <week>1980-04-05</week>
      <week>1980-04-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>The Wall</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>30 November 1979 (UK) , 8 December 1979 (US)</released>
   <recorded>April-November, 1979</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Progressive Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>8:24 (All three parts)</length>
      <length>3:10 (Part I)</length>
      <length>3:59 (Part II)</length>
      <length>1:14 (Part III)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Harvest (UK) , Columbia (US) , Capitol (US)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Roger Waters</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bob Ezrin</producer>
      <producer>David Gilmour</producer>
      <producer>Roger Waters</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>The Wall</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Another Brick in the Wall" is the title of three songs set
    to variations of the same basic theme, on Pink Floyd's 1979
    rock opera, 
    <i>The Wall</i>, subtitled Part I (work title Reminiscing) ,
    Part II (work title Education), and Part III (work title
    Drugs), respectively, all of which were written by Pink Floyd's
    bassist and then lead songwriter, Roger Waters. It has become
    one of the most famous Pink Floyd songs.</p>
      <p>Part II is a protest song against rigid schooling in general
    and boarding schools in particular, which has led to the song
    being banned in South Africa. It was also released as a single
    and provided the band's only number one hit in the UK, the US,
    West Germany and many other countries. In the UK, it was their
    first single since 1968's "Point Me at the Sky", the song was
    also the final number one single of the 1970s. For Part II,
    Pink Floyd received a Grammy nomination for Best Performance by
    a Rock Duo or Group and lost to Bob Seger's "Against the Wind".
    In addition, Part II was number 375 on Rolling Stone's 500
    Greatest Songs of All Time list. The single sold over 4 million
    copies worldwide. In Israel Part II was chosen as the best rock
    song of the 1980s (although it was issued before 1980), in a
    survey by one of the main radio stations Israel Army Radio held
    at the end of 1989.</p>
      <p>The single, as well as the album 
    <i>The Wall</i>, were banned in South Africa in 1980 after the
    song was adopted by supporters of a nationwide school boycott
    protesting racial inequities in education.</p>
      <p>Each of the three parts have a similar, if not the same,
    tune and lyrical structure (though not lyrics, aside from the
    "all in all" refrain), and each is louder and more enraged than
    the one before, rising from the sadness of Part I to the
    protesting Part II to the furious Part III. This tune is
    repeated in almost every song on the album, albeit in a
    different form each time.</p>
      <p>Part I of the song is very quiet dynamically and features a
    long, subdued guitar solo. The vocals are softer and gentler in
    tone than in Parts II and III, although there is a short, sharp
    rise in dynamics and tone for a brief period towards the end of
    the lyrical portion. Sniffing, shouting, wailing, calling, and
    children can be faintly heard in the background, along the
    lines of "You! Stand still, laddie!"</p>
      <p>The Thin Ice discussed during the previous song breaks when
    Pink becomes older and learns of the death of his father. Pink
    is devastated by this reality and begins to build The Wall.</p>
      <p>Pink's mother is seen praying in a church after the death of
    her husband overseas. Pink, however, is, at this point,
    oblivious of his death, and can be seen playing with a toy
    airplane. The song continues with Pink playing in a public park
    after his mother leaves him to go shopping. He sees a man who
    he takes a liking to in the absence of his own father. The man
    gives Pink a lift onto a ride, and it's clear Pink feels as if
    this man is his real father. Pink follows the man's son around,
    copying him, but doesn't understand why the other boy's father
    isn't paying attention to him. He grabs the man's hand but is
    shooed away, only to grab the man's hand again. The man pushes
    Pink away again, and dejectedly he sits on a swing.</p>
      <p>In the album version of 
    <i>The Wall</i>, "Another Brick in the Wall, Part II" segues
    from "The Happiest Days of Our Lives", with a trademark Roger
    Waters scream. The song has strong drums, a well-known bass
    line and distinctive guitar parts in the background with a
    smooth, yet edgy guitar solo. The song also features a group of
    school children for lead vocals in the second verse: as the
    song ends, the sounds of a school yard are heard, along with
    the teacher who continues to lord it over the children's lives
    by shouting such things as "Wrong! Do it again!" which somehow
    sounds mocking, and "If you don't eat yer meat, you can't have
    any pudding! 
    <i>How</i>can you have any pudding if you don't eat yer
    meat?!", and "You! Yes! You behind the bikesheds! Stand still,
    laddie!", all of it dissolving into the dull drone of a phone
    ringing and ending with a deep sigh.</p>
      <p>For "Part II", Pink Floyd needed a school choir, and
    producer Bob Ezrin requested that sound engineer Nick Griffiths
    find one. Griffiths approached music teacher Alun Renshaw of
    Islington Green School, around the corner from their Britannia
    Row Studios. Though the school received a lump sum payment of
    £1000, there was no contractual arrangement for royalties from
    record sales. Under 1996 UK copyright law, they became eligible
    for royalties from broadcasts, and after royalties agent Peter
    Rowan traced choir members through the website Friends Reunited
    and other means, they claimed their payments. Contrary to press
    reports, this did not involve suing Pink Floyd. Music industry
    professionals estimated that each student would be owed around
    £500.</p>
      <p>After being insulted by the teacher, Pink dreams that the
    kids in his school begin to protest against their abusive
    teachers.</p>
      <p>Following "The Happiest Days of Our Lives" Pink starts to
    daydream during his class. He imagines several students
    marching in unison to the beat of the song, following a path
    until they fall blindly into an oversized meat-grinder to
    re-emerge as putty-faced clones void of individual distinction.
    Starting with Gilmour's guitar solo, the children destroy the
    school building using hammers (foreshadowing the subsequent
    neo-fascist Nazi-like animated sequence with its marching
    hammers) and crowbars, creating a bonfire, dragging their
    teacher out of the burning school kicking and screaming. The
    song ends with Pink rubbing his hand, which the teacher slapped
    with a ruler in the previous song.</p>
      <p>During the song, the teacher's "meat and pudding" lines are
    folded into the first few lines of the school choir's lines,
    and are performed by the teacher in the film, played by Alex
    McAvoy.</p>
      <p>Prior to the film, the first video for the track, directed
    by Alan Parker, depicted students running in a playground and
    the teacher puppet from 
    <i>The Wall</i>concerts was used. The video also mixed in some
    animated scenes later used in "The Trial" and "Waiting for the
    Worms". The children who sang on "Another Brick in the Wall
    (Pt. II)" were not allowed to appear in the video as they
    didn't hold Equity Cards.</p>
      <p>Once the film was completed, the actual scenes of "The
    Happiest Days of Our Lives" and "Another Brick in the Wall,
    Part II" were combined into a new video, which now represents
    the music video for "Another Brick in the Wall".</p>
      <p>The song is dynamically loud, and features the once subtle
    bass line, now much louder, to express Pink's rage. It is also
    the shortest 'part' of "Another Brick In The Wall".</p>
      <p>Pink decides to finish this wall as a result of his rage
    after his wife's betrayal. He states that he has seen the
    "writing on the wall". He concludes that he no longer needs
    anything at all, dismissing the people in his life as just
    "bricks in the wall".</p>
      <p>In the film, the song is accompanied by a montage of events
    that contributed to the construction of the wall.</p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Awards  ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Discography  ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Emotional Syphon Recordings
       ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Korn's Groovy Pirate Ghost
      Mystery"  ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Members  ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Nightmare Revisited
       ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Project page  ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">soundtrack  ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Solo projects</span>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
