<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/So_What_(Pink_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/So_What_(Pink_song)</songId>
   <title>So What</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pink_(singer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Pink</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2008-09-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f3/Pinksowhatcover.jpg/200px-Pinksowhatcover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Pink+So-What.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Funhouse</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 15, 2008  (2008-08-15) , (see Release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Synthpop</genre>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:36</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>LaFace</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Pink</writer>
      <writer>Max Martin</writer>
      <writer>Shellback</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Max Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"So What" is a song written by American pop rock singer
    Pink, Max Martin and Shellback. It was released as the first
    single from Pink's fifth studio album 
    <i>Funhouse</i>.</p>
      <p>"So What" was performed by Pink at the 2008 MTV Video Music
    Awards, on September 7, 2008, and was used to promote the 2008
    MTV Video Music Awards Latin America. Pink performed "So What"
    on MTV Europe Music Awards 2008 on November 6, 2008. In
    September 2008, the song became Pink's first solo number-one
    hit in her native USA. It has also reached #1 in twenty-five
    other countries. It is also the fourth song to reach number one
    in all four major music markets.</p>
      <p>It will be one of the songs played in the upcoming music
    game 
    <i>Lego Rock Band</i>and the upcoming video games for 
    <i>Dance Dance Revolution</i>. It is also featured as a
    downloadable song on 
    <i>Guitar Hero: World Tour</i>and 
    <i>SingStar</i>. It is also a song on the DS version of 
    <i>Band Hero</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was written by Pink, Max Martin and Shellback.
    Martin also produced the track. Pink and Martin are responsible
    for their hit songs from Pink's previous album, including the
    US top-10 hits 
    <i>Who Knew</i>and 
    <i>U + Ur Hand</i>. In interviews, the singer stated that the
    song was not autobiographical, only a few aspects of the song
    were. After reuniting with her husband Carey Hart in May 2009,
    Pink told Ellen deGeneres that she found it "funny" to perform
    the song when he was in the audience and especially enjoyed the
    bit where she sang the line "You're a tool".</p>
      <p>The song was intended to be released to radio in the States
    later than its release date. As the song leaked on the
    internet, La Face Records decided to release the song on radio
    on August 18, 2008, as well as the digital version. The track
    was released on the American CHR on August 18, 2008. It was
    released digitally on American iTunes on August 19, 2008, and
    on September 2, it reached #1 on the store. The track has also
    peaked at #1 on iTunes Canada but they were instructed from
    SonyBMG that they were not to play it due to an international
    embargo on the track.</p>
      <p>Meanwhile, in Australia, the song began receiving actual
    radio airplay from August 7 and was instantly on high rotation
    across both the Austereo and DMG Radio Australia networks. In
    New York, WHTZ "Z100" played the song on the morning show at
    8:45am EST on the Elvis Duran and the Morning Zoo to great
    response. The song was released in the UK on September 29,
    2008.</p>
      <p>It has been questioned whether Pink has something against
    singer Jessica Simpson, as this is the second time Simpson has
    been negatively referenced in a Pink single, the first being
    "Stupid Girls". Pink then said on the matter - "Everyone thinks
    I'm trashing Jessica Simpson, but I'm actually not at all, I'm
    actually saying that she's cooler than me 'cause the waiter
    keeps taking my table and giving it to her." Pink was
    originally going to use "The pilot took my private jet and gave
    it to Haylie Duff" but it "wasn't as funny".</p>
      <p>The song was performed as a group number on the season
    finale of the eighth season of by the Top 13.</p>
      <p>Allison Iraheta, a finalist from the eighth season of 
    <i>American Idol</i>, performed the song during the American
    Idols LIVE! Tour 2009.</p>
      <p>"So What" has been well-received, with the website 
    <i>Popjustice</i>giving it a positive review. 
    <i>Popjustice</i>described the song as 'very amazing'. Chris
    Williams of 
    <i>Billboard</i>gave the track a positive review, enjoying the
    "insatiable melodic verses meant for massive car singalongs and
    a chorus combustion followed by a fist-in-the-air refrain." He
    also called it "an irresistible soundscape that will transform
    listeners into rock stars singing their very own breakup song."
    Ryan Dumble of 
    <i>Blender</i>gave "So What" a 3 out of 5 stars, commenting,
    "The disses are a bit immature ("I'm just fine and you're a
    fool") but there's a voyeuristic allure to the track."</p>
      <p>UK entertainment website 
    <i>Digital Spy</i>also praised the song, calling it "packed
    with attitude" and "terrifically catchy" They gave it 5/5
    stars, and later placed it as their top single of 2008 
    <i>Guide</i>gave a positive review saying: "A singsongy intro
    gives way to a martial beat and chorus that's likely to send
    fists pounding into the air." 
    <i>About.com</i>lauds the track noting that this song is a good
    comeback for the singer; "Pink is back and not to be ignored."
    This song was number 29 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s list of the 100 Best Songs of 2008.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Time</i>critic Josh Tyrangiel named this the #2 song of
    2008.</p>
      <p>VH1's 
    <i>Top 40 Videos of 2008</i>ranked "So What" #3 on their
    list.</p>
      <p>However, there have been a few negative reviews. 
    <i>The New York Times</i>called the song "perfunctory". 
    <i>The Onion's</i>AV Club called the song "so blaring and bad
    as to make 
    <i>Funhouse</i>seem like a lost cause from the start".</p>
      <p>The song was featured in the opening of the second episode
    of 
    <i>Castle</i>. It was played again later in the episode as the
    victim's cell phone ringtone, showing she was in an a location
    the police didn't previously realize before her murder.</p>
      <p>"So What" was nominated for The 51st Grammy Awards for Best
    Female Pop Vocal Performance among: "Chasing Pavements" by
    Adele, "Love Song" by Sara Bareilles, "Mercy" by Duffy, "I
    Kissed a Girl" by Katy Perry, and "Bleeding Love" by Leona
    Lewis. It was beaten by "Chasing Pavements".</p>
      <p>"So What" won the award for MTV's most addictive track. It
    was also nominated for Best Female Video on MTV Video Music
    Awards 2009 alongside "You Belong With Me" by Taylor Swift,
    "Single Ladies (Put a Ring on It) by Beyonce,"My Life Would
    Suck Without You" by Kelly Clarkson, "Hot N Cold" by Katy
    Perry, and "Poker Face" by Lady Gaga. It was beaten by "You
    Belong With Me", with a big controversy.</p>
      <p>"So What" debuted at #9 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 on August 26, 2008, making it Pink's
    highest debut to date on the chart. The song has since peaked
    at #1 on September 16, making it her first solo #1, and second
    overall after "Lady Marmalade", a collaboration with Christina
    Aguilera, Mýa, and Lil' Kim. It is Pink's ninth top-ten hit on
    the chart, and her third consecutive. In its first week the
    song debuted at #4 on the Hot Digital Songs chart with sales of
    116,611 downloads, moving up to #2 on the chart the following
    week. It has sold over three million copies in the U.S. to
    date. For the week ending October 3, 2008, "So What" jumped to
    claim the top spot on the Hot 100 knocking off T.I's single
    "Whatever You Like" from the top spot for two weeks. It also
    peaked at #1 on the Digital Track Chart and the Digital Songs
    Chart. The track has also been well received at dance radio in
    the United States, where it reached number-one on the Hot Dance
    Airplay chart in its December 6, 2008 issue, giving Pink her
    second number-one Dance Airplay single since the week ending
    February 10, 2007, when she first reached that summit with "U +
    Ur Hand". "So What" topped 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Adult Top 40 chart during the chart week of
    December 20, 2008, giving Pink her second #1 there.</p>
      <p>"So What" peaked at #1 on the Canadian Hot 100 and stayed at
    the top of the chart for four consecutive weeks.</p>
      <p>The song opened at #1 on the ARIA Digital Chart and debuted
    at #4 on the ARIA Singles Chart, reaching #1 on September 21.
    It has also been certified 2x Platinum with 140,000 in sales.
    It is Pink's 4th #1 in Australia.. The song peaked at #1 on the
    Australian Airplay Chart, and stayed there for 3 weeks, and is
    the first of 5 consecutive #1 radio airplay hits in
    Australia.</p>
      <p>In Sweden it had Pink's highest debut there, at #9, and has
    climbed to #2, making it her highest charting single there. In
    other Scandinavian countries it also debuted, in Denmark it
    debuted at #14 and in Finland it debuted at #13. In the
    Netherlands, the song debuted at #28 on the official Dutch Top
    40, where it has peaked at #4 so far.</p>
      <p>In Belgium "So What" debuted at #48 in Flanders and at #32
    in Wallonia, and in the combined chart at #36. The next weeks
    "So What" climbed to a number 4 in Flanders. Also in Austria it
    debuted at number #14 on Austrian Top 75, but dropped out the
    chart in the second week. Several weeks later it came back to
    Austrian chart and has since peaked at #1.</p>
      <p>It has reached #1 on the official New Zealand RIANZ chart
    becoming her first number one since "Don't Let Me Get Me" in
    2002 and the first country that "So What" became number one in.
    "So What" spent five consecutive weeks at number one in New
    Zealand and was certified Gold after eight weeks with sales of
    7,500+. It has become her fourth number 1 in New Zealand to
    date. After twenty-two weeks on the chart, "So What" was
    certified Platinum selling over 15,000 copies.</p>
      <p>On September 28, 2008, the song entered the UK Singles Chart
    at #38 on downloads alone based on two days worth of sales.
    After the song's physical release, the following week "So What"
    knocked Kings of Leon's "Sex On Fire" from number one, beating
    the comeback singles from Oasis ("The Shock of the Lightning")
    and Boyzone ("Love You Anyway"). "So What" is Pink's second
    solo number one single in the UK, the first being "Just Like a
    Pill" and third overall, including "Lady Mamalade". It also set
    the record for the biggest jump to number one within the top 40
    as it jumped 37 places to number one, beating last year's 34
    place jump by Sugababes with "About You Now". It sold 4,096
    units when it debuted at number 38 after one day of download
    sales. It sold in its first full week 53,264 copies which is
    the third-biggest #1 sales in the UK in the year 2008. Only
    Duffy sold more with "Mercy" (53,594) and Estelle with
    "American Boy" (60,497). In its second full week it sold 44,037
    copies. It its third full week and fourth overall, its sales
    increased marginally to 44,982, bringing its total sales up to
    146,379 so far. It in fifth week it sold a further 37,986
    totaling 184,365 units. However, due to leaked units or copies
    (it is unknown when they leaked), total sales actually stand at
    185,387 to date, as quoted by 
    <i>MusicWeek</i>. In its sixth week the song moved a further
    35,664 units bringing its sales to 221,051 and therefore being
    eligible for a Silver certification (200,000+ sales).</p>
      <p>It has also become Pink's biggest UK single to date.</p>
      <p>On December 29, 2008, "So What" was announced as the 14th
    biggest selling song in the UK in 2008 with sales of around
    360,000 sold to date.</p>
      <p>"So What" entered the German Singles Chart at #1 (three
    weeks) on the October 11, 2008 chart, making it Pink's first
    solo #1 there as well.</p>
      <p>On October 19, 2008, "So What" was announced #1 for a third
    week in a row in the UK top 40 singles chart.</p>
      <p>Dave Meyers, who is known for having artists giving an
    over-the-top portrayal of celebrities or themselves, directed
    the video for "So What". Pink previously worked with him for
    the videos to "U + Ur Hand" and "Stupid Girls", which earned
    MTV Video Music Award for Best Pop Video. Pink also worked with
    Meyers on the videos for "There You Go", "Most Girls", "You
    Make Me Sick", "Get the Party Started", "Don't Let Me Get Me"
    and the Charlie's Angels: Full Throttle track "Feel Good Time".
    The video was shown on August 22 on 
    <i>FNMTV</i>. The video has premiered on 22 August on the UK
    music site Popjustice.</p>
      <p>Pink posted a message on her website for her fans about what
    it was like to shoot the video:</p>
      <p style="font-size:smaller;text-align: right">
         <cite style="font-style:normal;">—Pink, 
      <i>Pink's official website</i>
         </cite>
      </p>
      <p>The video begins in a tattoo parlour, Pink is getting a
    tattoo of a red void mark on her arm across an existing tattoo
    before the scene cuts to Pink riding down Sunset Boulevard on a
    lawnmower and drinking alcohol. Pink is then shown entering
    Guitar Center browsing guitars. She pretends to play before
    attempting to smash it into the ground, but she is restrained
    by a store clerk which leads to them engaging in a fight. Pink
    is shown cutting down a tree engraved with her real name and
    her ex-husband's names with a chainsaw. She cries on the
    chainsaw, while telling herself that she is all right, right
    before the tree falls and nearly crushes her neighbor (played
    by Will Sasso). After this, Pink is sitting in a bar after
    losing her table to Jessica Simpson, accompanied by a man who
    is playing the drums out of glasses.</p>
      <p>The next scene goes to Pink on a motorbike, while a newly
    wedded couple in a car pull up beside her and wave and smile at
    her. Jealous and outraged at the happy newlyweds, Pink is shown
    throwing objects at the car and popping the blown up condoms
    used to decorate the vehicle, before climbing onto it and
    playfully (albeit violently) attacking the vehicle. Pink is
    then shown stripping on the red carpet, surrounded by
    photographers, she takes off her jacket to reveal her (blurred)
    nude body. The paparazzi all snap photos of her as she does
    choreography from Michael Jackson's video for Thriller naked.
    Then while getting her hair done, her stylist applies
    hairspray, as Pink turns on her cigarette lighter, accidentally
    setting her hair on fire. Also shown are two men urinating in
    wine bottles, which they give to Pink, however Pink passes them
    to two guys walking past her. They drink it and then realizing
    what it is, spit it out in disgust. Finally, Pink is shown
    surrounded by men and women in their underwear engaging in a
    pillow fight. The video then cuts between all the scenes shown
    in the video before ending with Pink poking her tongue at the
    camera with her husband.</p>
      <p>Pink is also shown performing the song in concert near the
    end. Pink's husband Carey Hart makes cameos throughout the
    video, such as a scene where they are talking as newspaper
    headlines flash behind them. Producer Butch Walker also makes a
    cameo. Pink has stated that Hart had not heard the song prior
    to arriving for the video shoot.</p>
      <p>The video was released on Saturday, September 6 on iTunes,
    and quickly jumped to the #1 video spot on the iTunes chart in
    less than 24 hours of it being listed.</p>
      <p>The video was ranked on VH1 as the 3rd best music video of
    2008 on the Top 40 Videos of 2008. On Facebook it was the
    second favorite video of 2008. The scene from the video where
    Pink's hair is set on fire is censored on MTV UK and its sister
    channels. That scene is replaced with other short clips from
    the video.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
