<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baby_Come_Back_(Player_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baby_Come_Back_(Player_song)</songId>
   <title>Baby Come Back</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Player_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Player</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1978-01-14</week>
      <week>1978-01-21</week>
      <week>1978-01-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/73/Baby_Come_Back_Player.jpg/200px-Baby_Come_Back_Player.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Player+Baby-Come-Back.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Player</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1977</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1977</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:13</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RSO Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>J. C. Crowley</writer>
      <writer>Peter Beckett</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Baby Come Back" is a song by 1970s group Player from their
    self-titled second album of the same name. The song was their
    biggest single, hitting number one on the Billboard Hot 100 and
    number 10 on the soul charts, in 1978. It was the breakthrough
    single for the band, gaining them mainstream success, and the
    only number-one hit of their career.</p>
      <p>The song, whose key and structure are reminiscent of Hall
    &amp; Oates' "She's Gone", is notable for its infectious riffs,
    and its memorable hook of "baby come back" during the chorus.
    The bass player is Ronn Moss, who has been appearing since 1987
    on the daytime soap 
    <i>The Bold and the Beautiful</i>(as Ridge Forrester).</p>
      <p>The song was used for humor in the episode "Homer Alone" of 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>. When Homer calls the lost baby hotline to
    report that Maggie is missing, he gets put on hold to the tune
    of "Baby Come Back".</p>
      <p>The song also appeared in the episode "Church Hopping" of 
    <i>King of the Hill</i>. When Hank decides to try Lucky's
    method of worshipping, they both get drunk at a bar and begin
    singing the tune, which plays on the jukebox.</p>
      <p>In the early 1990s, the now-defunct Chemical Bank used the
    song in a commercial.</p>
      <p>In 1999, "Baby Come Back" was featured in the little known
    Charlie Sheen and Christopher McDonald movie titled "Five
    Aces". Chris Martin (played by Charlie Sheen) announces to his
    four best friends that he is engaged to be married and one
    evening in the bar the "Five Aces" (played by Sheen and his
    friends) sing the song during Karaoke.</p>
      <p>The song was also in the 2005 movie 
    <i>Roll Bounce</i>, starring Bow Wow, Chi McBride, Jurnee
    Smollett, Mike Epps, Wesley Jonathan, Meagan Good, and Nick
    Cannon.</p>
      <p>In the 2006 romantic comedy 
    <i>Date Movie</i>, the song was used by Grant after Julia had
    caught him kissing his ex-fiance. The song is also featured in
    the film 
    <i>A Guide to Recognizing Your Saints</i>(2006).</p>
      <p>In 2006, the song's hook was sampled by Vanessa Hudgens in
    her single "Come Back to Me".</p>
      <p>In 2007, the song was used in the film 
    <i>Transformers</i>, in a scene where Bumblebee purposely
    stalled to a nice romantic location so that the protagonist of
    the movie, Sam Witwicky (played by Shia LaBeouf), could have
    some time with his crush, Mikaela Banes (played by Megan Fox).
    When Mikaela was about to leave, Bumblebee eventually restarted
    and played this song.</p>
      <p>In the TV series, 
    <i>Total Drama Island</i>, Geoff sings the song with altered
    lyrics.</p>
      <p>In 2008 and 2009, the song was used in ad campaigns for
    Swiffer's line of cleaning products.</p>
      <p>In 2008, the song was sampled on Lil Rob's single "Let Me
    Come Back".</p>
      <p>The season finale of 
    <i>The Game</i>is titled "Baby Come Back" where Melanie
    confesses her love for Derwin on May 18, 2008.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
