<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Every_Rose_Has_Its_Thorn 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Every_Rose_Has_Its_Thorn</songId>
   <title>Every Rose Has Its Thorn</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poison_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Poison</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1989-01-07</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/d3/Every_Rose_Has_Its_Thorn-Cover.jpg/200px-Every_Rose_Has_Its_Thorn-Cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Poison+Every-Rose-Has-Its-Thorn.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Open Up and Say... Ahh!</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 12, 1988</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Glam Metal</genre>
      <genre>Country Rock</genre>
      <genre>Acoustic Rock</genre>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:20</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bret Michaels</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Tom Werman</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Every Rose Has Its Thorn" is a power ballad/rock song by
    American glam rock band Poison. It was released in 1988 as the
    third single from Poison's second album 
    <i>Open Up And Say...Ahh!</i>. It is the band's first and only
    number-one hit in the U.S., reaching the top spot on Christmas
    Eve in 1988 for three weeks (carrying over into 1989). It was a
    #13 hit in the UK. "Every Rose Has Its Thorn" was named number
    34 on VH1's "100 Greatest Songs of the 80's", #100 on their
    "100 Greatest Love Songs" and #3 on their " Top 25 Power
    Ballads" by MTV and VH1.</p>
      <p>According to singer Bret Michaels, the recording sessions
    for "Every Rose" were fraught with infighting and squabbles
    between band members. "It was like, I totally thought this
    would help us move forward, you know, push the envelope,
    sonically," Michaels has said, "but the others were just not
    into it, you know? I mean, C.C. has always been the metal rawk
    one in the group, and he thought I was a fucking sell-out. He
    hated playing "Every Rose"; the song is one of the reasons he
    refuses to speak to me anymore. Although I think me sleeping
    with his girlfriend of six years didn't help either." C.C.
    Deville would later retort in the Poison biography 
    <i>Sex, Drugs &amp; Rock'n'Roll ... &amp; Sex &amp; Drugs Some
    More: The Poison Story</i>, "Well that's Brett's take, okay?
    And you know what, he's a cunt. That's all I have to say about
    that."</p>
      <p>Poison's lead vocalist, Bret Michaels, wrote the song in
    response to a failed love affair with his then-girlfriend.
    Poison had been playing at a cowboy bar called "The Ritz" in
    Dallas, Texas. In an interview with VH1's Behind The Music,
    Michaels said the inspiration for the song came from a night
    when he was in a laundromat waiting for his clothes to dry, and
    called his girlfriend on a pay phone. Michaels said he heard a
    male voice in the background and was devastated; he said he
    went home and wrote Every Rose Has Its Thorn as a result.
    Michaels wrote the song with an acoustic guitar in a
    laundromat.</p>
      <p>Musically, the song starts quietly and features two
    intricate guitar solos, one mellow and one fast. Among
    guitarists, the song is notable for epitomizing the standard G
    - Cadd9 progression in pop/rock. The song is also recognizable
    for its reference to cowboys in the chorus, and the twang in
    Bret Michaels' vocals, which give the song a country feel not
    often heard in power ballads composed by glam metal bands.</p>
      <p>When asked in 
    <i>Twisted Sister: The Completed Uncensored Story</i>about why
    the glam metal scene came to an end, Dee Snider of Twisted
    Sister said: "Hey man, it was them motherfuckin' "power
    ballads", you know! Bret is gonna kill me for saying this but
    "Every Rose" completely killed the metal in the pop metal scene
    man. All of a sudden, all the heavy metal rock bands got rid of
    their distortion pedals and went fuckin' acoustic." Twisted
    Sister had previously achieved fame primarily for their
    sloganeering rock anthem hit "We're Not Gonna Take It".</p>
      <p>The music video to Every Rose was similar to those filmed
    for other eighties power ballads. It features Michaels sitting
    down, playing the guitar, and singing along to the song,
    interspersed with black and white clips from concerts, and
    color frames of a storyline that follows the song.</p>
      <p>"Every Rose Has Its Thorn" is on the following albums.</p>
      <p>"Every Rose Has Its Thorn" became the group's first (and
    only to date) number-one single on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100; it climbed to the top during the two
    last weeks of 1988 and the first week of 1989.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
