<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Another_One_Bites_the_Dust 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Another_One_Bites_the_Dust</songId>
   <title>Another One Bites the Dust</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Queen_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Queen</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1980-10-04</week>
      <week>1980-10-11</week>
      <week>1980-10-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/4d/Another_one_bites_the_dust.jpg/200px-Another_one_bites_the_dust.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Queen+Another-One-Bites-the-Dust.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Game</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>22 August 1980</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1980</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Funk Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:36</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>EMI , Elektra (US)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>John Deacon</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Queen</producer>
      <producer>Mack</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Another One Bites the Dust" is a song by the English rock
    band Queen. Written by bass guitarist John Deacon, the song
    featured on the group's eighth studio album 
    <i>The Game</i>(1980).</p>
      <p>"Another One Bites the Dust" was a worldwide crossover hit.
    It hit number one on the US Hot 100, number two on the R&amp;B
    charts and the Disco Top 100, and number seven in the UK
    Singles Chart. The song is credited as Queen's best selling
    single, with sales of over 7 million copies. This version was
    ranked at number 34 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top 100</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1998, it was covered by Wyclef Jean, Pras Michel and
    featured Free's rap vocals. "Weird Al" Yankovic parodied the
    song as "Another One Rides the Bus". A short music video of the
    song has also been featured on the Disney Channel's 
    <i>Re-Micks</i>program, synced entirely to clips from the
    cartoon short 
    <i>Touchdown Mickey</i>.</p>
      <p>The bass line was inspired by the song "Good Times" by the
    Disco group Chic. In an interview with 
    <i>New Musical Express</i>, Chic co-founder Bernard Edwards
    stated, "...that Queen record came about because that Queen
    bass player... spent some time hanging out with us at our
    studio".</p>
      <p>Recording sessions were produced by Reinhold Mack at
    Musicland Studios in Munich (West Germany) and consisted of
    Deacon playing almost all the instruments: bass, piano, rhythm
    and lead guitars and handclap percussion. Roger Taylor added a
    drum loop and Brian May contributed some noises with his guitar
    and an Eventide Harmonizer. There are no synthesizers used in
    the song: all effects are created with pianos, guitars, and
    drums, with subsequent tape playback performed in reverse at
    various speeds. Finally, some sound effects were run through
    the harmonizer for further processing. The effect of the
    harmonizer can be heard clearly in the "swirling" nature of the
    sound immediately before the first lyric. During the mix the
    road crew suggested it as a single but the band did not like
    the idea until Michael Jackson recommended it after a concert
    (this anecdote was confirmed by Roger Taylor and Brian May on
    the U.S. radio show 
    <i>In the Studio with Redbeard</i>that spotlighted the album 
    <i>The Game</i>on one episode). Freddie Mercury loved this
    track. Brian May recalled to 
    <i>Mojo</i>magazine: "Freddie sung until his throat bled on
    Another One Bites The Dust. He was so into it. He wanted to
    make that song something special."</p>
      <p>The song garnered Queen its only Grammy nomination, for Best
    Rock Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal. The band lost to
    Bob Seger's album 
    <i>Against the Wind</i>. The "Another One Bites the Dust" music
    video was filmed at Reunion Arena in Dallas, Texas.</p>
      <p>A common urban legend surrounding the chorus is that, when
    played in reverse, will be heard as, "It's fun to smoke
    marijuana." A spokeswoman for Hollywood Records (Queen's
    current US label) has denied that the song contains a backward
    message. Played in reverse, the B-side of the 45, Don't Try
    Suicide, allegedly sounds like "have a snort," "do a snort,"
    and "I must have my speed." In 2008, DJ Lobsterdust released a
    mix of the song called "It's Fun to Smoke Dust" that combines
    the original with a recording of Gary Greenwald's 1982 rant
    about the alleged subliminal message in the song.</p>
      <p>During the administration of chest compressions during CPR,
    it can be difficult to achieve and maintain the recommended
    rate of 100 compressions per minute. The bass line of this song
    is at such a rate; thus it is possible to think or hum this
    song during CPR, to maintain the correct rate.</p>
      <p>In 1998, Wyclef Jean along with Pras Michel, Canibus, and
    Free remixed the song using a new instrumental track and
    samples from the actual song for the 1998 movie 
    <i>Small Soldiers</i>. This version also appeared on Queen's
    compilation 
    <i>Greatest Hits III</i>released in 1999. It enjoyed the most
    success in the UK, where it entered the chart at #5, its
    highest chart position, going on to spend six weeks on the
    chart. It also reached the top ten in Finland. It charted #18,
    #23, #50 and #62 in New Zealand, Austria, Sweden and France,
    respectively.</p>
      <p>It was Pras' third top-10 UK hit as a solo artist following 
    <i>Ghetto Supastar</i>and 
    <i>Blue Angels</i>.</p>
      <p>
         <i>A-side</i>
      </p>
      <p>
         <i>B-side</i>
      </p>
      <p>The song was covered by Queen Factory, a French project of
    Stéphane Durand who was inspired by Mad'House (house covers of
    Madonna) and King of House (house covers of Michael
    Jackson).</p>
      <p>The song was remixed and covered by Greek-American singer
    Kalomoira for her debut self titled album released in Greece
    and Cyprus in September 2004. The album reached number 1 in
    both countries and was certified gold.</p>
      <p>The song was remixed again in 2006 by The Miami Project.</p>
      <p>(3 Weeks)</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
