<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghostbusters_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghostbusters_(song)</songId>
   <title>Ghostbusters</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ray_Parker_Jr.</artistId>
      <artistName>Ray Parker Jr.</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1984-08-11</week>
      <week>1984-08-18</week>
      <week>1984-08-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/3/31/RayParkerJrGhostbusters7InchSingleCover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Ray-Parker-Jr+Ghostbusters.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Ghostbusters OST</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1984</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:04</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Arista Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ray Parker Jr.</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Ray Parker Jr.</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Ghostbusters" is a 1984 song recorded by Ray Parker, Jr. as
    the theme to the film of the same name that starred Bill Murray
    and Dan Aykroyd. It hit number one on the Billboard Hot 100 on
    August 11 in 1984, and stayed there for three weeks. It also
    peaked at number two on the UK Singles Chart on 16 September
    1984, where it stayed for three weeks. The song is performed in
    the key of B major.</p>
      <p>It was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Music,
    Original Song, but lost to Stevie Wonder's "I Just Called to
    Say I Love You".</p>
      <p>According to Parker, he was approached by the film's
    producers to create a theme song for the film. Unfortunately,
    he only had a few days to do so and the film's title seemed
    impossible to include in any lyrics. However, when watching
    television late at night, Parker saw a cheap commercial for a
    local service that reminded him that the film had a similar
    commercial featured for the fictional business. This inspired
    him to write the song as a pseudo-advertising jingle that the
    business could have commissioned as a promotion.</p>
      <p>Parker was later the defendant in a copyright-infringement
    lawsuit which claimed "Ghostbusters" was too similar in musical
    structure to "I Want a New Drug", written and performed by Huey
    Lewis and the News (more specifically, the guitar riff which
    runs through the song). "I Want a New Drug" was a U.S. top-ten
    hit earlier the same year. The two parties settled out of
    court. Details of the settlement (specifically, that Parker
    paid Lewis a settlement) were confidential until 2001, when
    Lewis commented on the payment in an episode of VH1's 
    <i>Behind the Music</i>. Parker subsequently sued Lewis for
    breaching confidentiality; the lawsuit is ongoing. Ironically,
    Lewis had at one point been asked to record a theme song for
    the movie, but turned it down for other commitments.</p>
      <p>In later years, AutoNation adopted the theme for their
    advertising campaign. In the United Kingdom, the song is
    parodied with Parker himself being featured in a commercial
    advertising direct enquiries line 118 118.</p>
      <p>The song re-entered the UK Top 75 on 2nd November 2008 at
    #49.</p>
      <p>Lindsey Buckingham claims to have been approached to write
    the Ghostbusters theme based on his successful contribution to
    Harold Ramis's National Lampoon's Vacation (the song Holiday
    Road). He turned down the opportunity as he didn't want to be
    known as a soundtrack artist. He mentions this on the "Words
    &amp; Music" interview disk.</p>
      <p>A music video for the song featured a young woman, played by
    Cindy Harrell, who was being haunted by a ghost portrayed by
    Parker, roaming a nearly all-black house interior with vibrant
    neon designs outlining the sparse architectural and industrial
    features. It also contained footage from the film 
    <i>Ghostbusters</i>, and featured cameos from many celebrities
    of the day, including Chevy Chase, Irene Cara, John Candy,
    Melissa Gilbert, Nickolas Ashford, Jeffrey Tambor, George
    Wendt, Al Franken, Danny DeVito, Carly Simon, Peter Falk and
    Teri Garr, all of whom exclaim the "Ghostbusters!" line of the
    song when shown.</p>
      <p>The video concludes with Parker and the stars of the film,
    in full Ghostbuster costume, dancing down the streets of New
    York City. The Ghostbusters also performed the similar dance in
    the closing credits to the 
    <i>Real Ghostbusters</i>cartoon series as well as in a trailer
    for the 2009 video game.</p>
      <p>Due to the ongoing legal battle between Parker and Huey
    Lewis, the video has not been included in any release of the
    movie on home video to date.</p>
      <p>The song is referenced in both the films and the cartoon
    series.</p>
      <p>In 
    <i>Ghostbusters II</i>, at one point in the movie, Peter
    Venkman says, "Kitten, I think what I'm saying is that
    sometimes, shit happens, someone has to deal with it, and who
    you gonna call?" There was also a scene where a commercial for
    the company's business featured Janine Melnitz and Louis Tully
    as a couple being bothered by a ghost. Louis picks up a phone,
    Janine asks who he is going to call, and the Ghostbusters
    appear answering "Ghostbusters!" Also, in the birthday party
    scene at the beginning of the movie, Raymond Stantz and Winston
    Zeddemore play and sing along to the song.</p>
      <p>In an episode of 
    <i>The Real Ghostbusters</i>, the Ghostbusters are trapped in
    an alternate reality New York populated by ghosts, where a
    group of ghosts called the Peoplebusters go around the city
    catching human beings. When they are fleeing from the
    Peoplebusters, the GBs pass a ghost dining in an outdoor cafe,
    who witnesses the scene and sings "When there isn't something
    strange/in your neighborhood/Who you gonna
    call?/Peoplebusters!"</p>
      <p>In TokyoPop's 
    <i>Ghostbusters</i>series, Ray, Peter and Egon eat at a diner
    with pictures of famous patrons on the wall. Ray comments on
    the people on the wall, and, finding Ray Parker Jr, remarks
    that he's never heard of him.</p>
      <p>The song appears in 
    <i>Ghostbusters: The Video Game</i>.</p>
      <p>St. Louis CBS station KMOV spoofed the song for its
    mid-1980s "Newsbusters" promos.</p>
      <p>Washington, DC NBC station WRC-TV spoofed the song in 1988
    with "Broncobusters", which is all about the Washington
    Redskins and their, at the time, upcoming match up against the
    Denver Broncos at Super Bowl XXII.</p>
      <p>The British band McFly also performed the song as it is one
    of the lead singer's (Tom Fletcher) favorite songs.</p>
      <p>Professional wrestler Jerry Lawler made a parody of the song
    in Memphis Wrestling entitled "Wimpbusters".</p>
      <p>In the 1995 movie 
    <i>Casper</i>when Carrigan and Dibbs are trying to get the
    ghosts out of the mansion, several pieces of furniture are
    thrown out of the door, and Dan Aykroyd (dressed as his 
    <i>Ghostbusters</i>character, Dr. Raymond Stantz) is seen
    running out. He stops by Carrigan and Dibbs and says, "Who you
    gonna call? Somebody else." He then leaves quickly.</p>
      <p>In the television series 
    <i>Buffy the Vampire Slayer</i>, Spike asks Buffy, "Who you
    gonna call?" then follows it with "God, that line is never
    gonna be usable again, is it?" to which she replies, "Probably
    not."</p>
      <p>Disney produced an abridged music video of the song in the
    special 
    <i>DTV Monster Hits</i>, set entirely to clips from the 1937
    cartoon 
    <i>Lonesome Ghosts</i>.</p>
      <p>A musical number on the Kids' WB! show 
    <i>Histeria!</i>, about Theodore Roosevelt and his anti-trust
    campaign (featured in the episode "The Teddy Roosevelt Show"),
    was sung to the theme.</p>
      <p>In the "Petergeist" episode of 
    <i>Family Guy</i>, Tom Tucker reports that the Griffin family's
    house is infested with ghosts. "Who they gonna call?" he asks.
    His co-anchor, Diane Simmons, suggests "Ghostbusters?" and
    Tucker replies with "No, Diane, their insurance company. That's
    just stupid what you said."</p>
      <p>In an episode of the TV show 
    <i>Max and Paddy's Road To Nowhere</i>, a motor mechanic who
    goes by the name of Mick Bustin has the slogan "When there's
    something strange/Underneath your hood/Who ya gonna call?/Mick
    Bustin" for his business, and Ghostbuster parody logos all over
    his auto shop.</p>
      <p>In the "Bloooo" episode of 
    <i>Foster's Home for Imaginary Friends</i>, when Wilt asks Coco
    what to do for their "ghost" problem, Coco picks up a
    telephone, and Wilt says, "Who you gonna call?" Coco responds
    by saying "Co-coco!" in the same way the word Ghostbusters is
    said in the song. Wilt replies, "Nah, they've been out of
    business for years."</p>
      <p>The BBC children's comedy series 
    <i>Maid Marian and her Merry Men</i>featured a spoof of the
    song entitled "Call The Dentist".</p>
      <p>In 
    <i>Sonic Unleashed</i>(PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360 versions)
    there is an achievement called "I Ain't Afraid of No Ghost",
    which is unlocked by freeing several NPCs from possession. It
    is also the name of an achievement in the Xbox 360 version of
    the Ghostbusters game that is unlocked after the player traps
    the Sloth Ghost.</p>
      <p>A recent advert for UK Directory Enquiries service 118-118
    features Ray Parker Jr. (multiple times in different costumes
    including a mailman, a mechanic, a waiter and a bus conductor)
    in a parody of the song he originally recorded for 
    <i>Ghostbusters</i>. It alters lines slightly such as "If
    there's something strange, going through your head, Who Ya
    Gonna Call? 118!", "Who can you call? 118!" and "I ain't afraid
    of no goats" (shortly after he frees two goats from the back of
    a car). The advert also features giant versions of the 118 men,
    in a parody of the Stay Puft Marshmallow Man.</p>
      <p>Ads for the Maroone car dealerships(Auto Nation affiliate of
    Palm Beach and Broward County, South Florida) featured
    variations on the famous chorus. The variation went: "If you
    need a car/Truck or van/Who you gonna call/MAROONE!". Other
    Auto Nation affiliates (ex: AutoWay of Tampa, Courtesy of
    Orlando) use this song for their advertisements.</p>
      <p>In the 
    <i>Doctor Who</i>episode "Army of Ghosts", a couple lines of
    the song are sung by both The Doctor and Rose Tyler, the Doctor
    carrying equipment that visually resembles the equipment the
    Ghostbusters used.</p>
      <p>A parody version sung by the dead character Nappa ('Ghost
    Nappa') was used to close the first season of 
    <i>That Guy with the Glasses</i>hosted 
    <i>Dragon Ball Z Abridged</i>.</p>
      <p>The song is one of the playable songs in 
    <i>Lego Rock Band</i>, both in the console versions and in the
    Nintendo DS version.</p>
      <p>In the episode "The Gang Solves the Gas Crisis" in the FX
    sitcom 
    <i>It's Always Sunny in Philadelphia</i>, the gang references
    the Ghostbusters a few times during the episode, and drive
    around the city to the theme song.</p>
      <p>John and Edward (Jedward) performed this on X Factor
    November 7, 2009.</p>
      <p>"Ghostbusters" was made a playable song in Beatmania IIDX 14
    Gold. It is also a playable song in LEGO Rock Band.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
