<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Streak 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Streak</songId>
   <title>The Streak</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ray_Stevens</artistId>
      <artistName>Ray Stevens</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-05-18</week>
      <week>1974-05-25</week>
      <week>1974-06-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Boogity Boogity</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 27, 1974</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Novelty</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Barnaby Records</label>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Streak" is a popular song written, produced, and sung
    by Ray Stevens. It was released in 1974. "The Streak"
    capitalized on the then popular craze of streaking.</p>
      <p>One of Stevens' most successful recordings, "The Streak" was
    his second number one on the Billboard Hot 100 singles chart in
    the USA, spending three weeks at the top in May 1974 and
    reached #3 on the Billboard Country singles chart. A major
    international hit it also reached #1 on the UK Singles Chart,
    spending a single week at the top of the chart in June 1974. In
    total it sold over 5 million copies internationally.</p>
      <p>The song's story is a series of three "news flashes"
    featuring the "Action News Reporter" (Stevens) on the scenes of
    reported streaking events: at the supermarket, the gas station,
    and the basketball playoffs. The reporter interviews a man
    (also Stevens) who responds with his views of what happened.
    The responses contain several double entendres, and the man
    tries to warn his wife, Ethel, not to look ("Don't look,
    Ethel!"), but is always too late. After the third interview,
    the man sees the streaker again, but to his horror the streaker
    is joined by his wife, and the man changes his tune: "Ethel,
    you shameless hussy!".</p>
      <p>"The Streak" is one of the songs referenced in another Ray
    Stevens tune, "Dudley Dorite of the Highway Patrol", in which
    Stevens is supposedly pulled over by a patrolman who believes,
    along with his friends and family, that Stevens is deliberately
    misrepresenting them in his songs. The patrolman specifically
    reminisces to Stevens about his wife, Ethel: "You remember
    Ethel, don't ya, boy? That 'shameless hussy'?" The theme of
    "Dudley Dorite" was later used as a central plot in Stevens'
    direct-to-video film, 
    <i>Get Serious</i>, where Stevens (playing a fictionalized
    version of himself) encounters this supposed real-life Ethel,
    who expresses dismay at being portrayed as "some kind of Lady
    Godiva".</p>
      <p>In the 2000s, the 1974 album 
    <i>Boogity-Boogity</i>that contained "The Streak" among other
    novelty songs was re-released in CD format along with Ray's
    1973 album 
    <i>Nashville</i>as a two album on one CD release on
    Collectables Records. The albums will be featured in a box set
    from Collectables Records entitled 
    <i>Only The Best of Ray Stevens</i>which will house all of the
    vinyl on CD re-issues.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
