<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Never_Gonna_Give_You_Up 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Never_Gonna_Give_You_Up</songId>
   <title>Never Gonna Give You Up</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rick_Astley</artistId>
      <artistName>Rick Astley</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1988-03-12</week>
      <week>1988-03-19</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/34/RickAstleyNeverGonnaGiveYouUp7InchSingleCover.jpg/200px-RickAstleyNeverGonnaGiveYouUp7InchSingleCover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Rick-Astley+Never-Gonna-Give-You-Up.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Whenever You Need Somebody</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 1987</released>
   <recorded>October 1986</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:32</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>PWL , RCA Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mike Stock</writer>
      <writer>Matt Aitken</writer>
      <writer>Pete Waterman</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Stock Aitken Waterman</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Never Gonna Give You Up" is a song written by Stock, Aitken
    &amp; Waterman and sung by English singer Rick Astley. The song
    was released as the first single from Astley's multi-million
    selling debut album, 
    <i>Whenever You Need Somebody</i>. The song was a worldwide
    number-one hit, initially in the singer's native United Kingdom
    in 1987, where it stayed at number one for five weeks and was
    the best-selling single of that year.</p>
      <p>The song won Best British Single at the 1988 Brit Awards.
    The music video for the song has become the basis for the
    "Rickrolling" Internet meme.</p>
      <p>In 2008, Rick Astley won the MTV EMA awards for "Best Act
    Ever" with the song "Never Gonna Give You Up", as a result of
    collective voting from thousands of Astley enthusiasts.</p>
      <p>In the "Never Gonna Give You Up" music video, directed by
    Simon West, a smiling Astley sings and dances to the song in
    various outfits and venues in West London, sometimes
    accompanied by backup dancers. A bartender played by Clive
    Clarke gradually shifts from casually noticing Astley's singing
    to being fully engrossed in the song with energetic acrobatic
    moves. The athletic exertion of many of the other dancers also
    becomes more intense over the course of Astley's
    performance.</p>
      <p>"Never Gonna Give You Up" is the subject of a popular
    Internet prank known as "rickrolling" involving misleading
    links redirecting to the song's music video. By May 2007, the
    practice had achieved notoriety on the Internet, and it
    increased in popularity after its use as a 2008 April Fool's
    Day joke by various media companies and websites, including
    YouTube rickrolling all of its featured videos on that day and
    a website allowing people to Rickroll their friends'
    phones.</p>
      <p>In 'a couple of weeks', about 13 million people had been
    'rickrolled' into watching Astley's video, the BBC reported on
    1 April 2008. "I think it's just one of those odd things where
    something gets picked up and people run with it," Astley told
    the Los Angeles Times in late March 2008, adding: "That's
    what's brilliant about the Internet."</p>
      <p>Rick Astley also appeared in the 2008 Macy's Thanksgiving
    Day Parade interrupting a song performed by those on a float
    promoting the Cartoon Network program 
    <i>Foster's Home for Imaginary Friends</i>with a lipsynched
    performance of "Never Gonna Give You Up".</p>
      <p>In several of its protests against Scientology, Anonymous
    has employed The Rickroll.</p>
      <p>Also known as the "Ultimate Rickroll". On December 1, 2008,
    a campaign was started on Facebook in an attempt to make the
    song the 2008 Christmas #1 in the UK as an attempt to
    "rickroll" the country during Christmas. The campaign's purpose
    was to stop the X-Factor from gaining the #1 Christmas spot,
    thereby ending the show's chain of success. The group attracted
    nearly 30,000 people in its first week active. Campaigners were
    encouraged to get as many people as possible to download the
    song from iTunes between the 15th and 20th of December 2008.
    The song only managed to peak at #73; however, this was later
    found to be a deliberate lowering of the song's place (having
    reached #3 a week before it came to its finish) due to the
    company's belief that "the songs [sic] ranking was ridiculous
    and rigging a contest was unfair on other artists". The
    campaigners, Jon and Tracy Morter, were ultimately successful
    the following year with a Rage Against The Machine campaign
    that hit the No.1 spot in December 2009</p>
      <p>The Rickrollerz is a pseudonym used by a group of London
    dance producers that made a house music cover version of Rick
    Astley's 1987 song "Never Gonna Give You Up" on the day, and in
    honor of, the London Liverpool Street Station 
    <i>rickmob</i>on April 11, 2008. In May 2008, the track entered
    the UK Club Charts at number 22.</p>
      <p>On Friday 11 April, 2008 at 6 PM, a group of people made a
    "Rickmob" on the Liverpool Street station, inspired on the 
    <i>rickrolling</i>Internet phenomenon. The song was remixed at
    the same studio as 20 years earlier, the same day.</p>
      <p>The "Rickmob" was a spontaneous gathering where hundreds of
    people dressed as Rick Astley joined on Friday 11 April 2008 in
    Liverpool Street Station for a short rendition of the 80's
    superhit and then quickly dispersed.</p>
      <p>They released their own single of "Never Gonna Give You Up"
    the same day.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
