<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jessie%27s_Girl 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jessie%27s_Girl</songId>
   <title>Jessie's Girl</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rick_Springfield</artistId>
      <artistName>Rick Springfield</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1981-08-01</week>
      <week>1981-08-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/1c/Jessie%27s_Girl.jpg/200px-Jessie%27s_Girl.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Rick-Springfield+Jessie-s-Girl.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Working Class Dog</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 17, 1981</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Power Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:15</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Rick Springfield</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Keith Olsen</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Jessie's Girl" is a Grammy Award-winning rock song written
    and performed by pop singer Rick Springfield. It was released
    on the album 
    <i>Working Class Dog</i>. The song is about unrequited love,
    and centers on a young man in love with his best friend's
    girlfriend (see below for story behind the song).</p>
      <p>Upon its release in 1981 the song became an instant hit,
    reaching #1 on the Billboard Hot 100 for two weeks, and later
    won Springfield a Grammy Award for Best Male Rock Vocal
    Performance. The song was at #1 when MTV launched on August 1,
    1981.</p>
      <p>The song was released in the United Kingdom in March 1984
    and peaked at number 43 on the UK Singles Chart in April
    1984.</p>
      <p>Springfield was taking a stained glass class along with his
    friend Gary and Gary's girlfriend. He initially wanted to use
    the actual name of the friend he was singing about, but instead
    decided to go with a different name — "Jessie". He happened to
    see a girl in a softball jersey with the name "Jessie" on it
    and changed the name from Gary to Jessie, then recorded the
    song. Springfield says that he does not remember the name of
    the girlfriend, and believes that the real woman who inspired
    the song has no idea that she was "Jessie's Girl", telling
    Oprah Winfrey, "I was never really introduced to her. It was
    always just, like, panting from afar." Springfield told
    Songfacts that Oprah's people tried to find her, and they got
    as far back as finding out that Gary had died two years
    previously.</p>
      <p>"Jessie's Girl" remains a staple of many Lite rock and
    Classic Hits FM radio stations. In 2006, it was named #20 on
    VH1's "100 Greatest Songs of the 80s".</p>
      <p>The music video depicts Rick watching a young couple
    (presumably Jessie and his girlfriend) with envy for the girl's
    love. It opens with Jessie (Steve Antin) spray painting
    "Jessie's Girl" onto a brick wall, and then leaving with his
    girlfriend, as Rick watches and gives a monologue in the form
    of the song's first verse. Rick runs into the couple one more
    time on the sidewalk, and he just stares as they walk away from
    him. Later, he goes home and looks in the mirror and mourns
    over why Jessie's girlfriend doesn't like him, and angrily
    smashes the mirror after he sees an illusion of Jessie's
    girlfriend in the mirror.</p>
      <p>It was featured in as a track on 
    <i>Guitar Hero: On Tour</i>and as a downloadable song for 
    <i>Guitar Hero World Tour</i>. The song was featured inside
    Guitar Hero in the 2009 film 
    <i>Couples Retreat</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
