<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disco_Duck 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disco_Duck</songId>
   <title>Disco Duck (Part 1)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rick_Dees</artistId>
      <artistName>Rick Dees and His Cast of Idiots</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1976-10-16</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>The Original Disco Duck</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1976</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" and 12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Memphis, Tennessee</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:17</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Fretone (initial release) , RSO (wide distribution)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Rick Dees</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bobby Manuel</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Disco Duck" is a satirical disco novelty song performed by
    Memphis disc jockey Rick Dees and His Cast of Idiots. It became
    a number-one hit on the Hot 100 for one week in October 1976
    (and ranked #99 out of the 100 most popular songs of the year
    according to 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine). It also made the top 20 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Soul Singles chart, peaking at number 15.
    "Disco Duck" was initially released in the south by Estelle
    Axton's Fretone label but was later released by RSO Records for
    national and international distribution.</p>
      <p>Written by Dees, "Disco Duck" was inspired by a 1960s
    novelty dance song called "The Duck", recorded by Jackie Lee in
    1965. According to Dees, it took one day to write the song, but
    three months to convince anyone to perform it.</p>
      <p>Combining orchestral disco styles with a Donald Duck-esque
    voice as the main plot point, the story within "Disco Duck"
    centers around a man at a dance party who is overcome by the
    urge to get up and "get down" in a duck-like manner. When the
    music stops, he sits down, but when he decides to get up and
    dance again, he finds that everyone in the room is now doing
    his dance.</p>
      <p>A misconception about 
    <i>Disco Duck</i>is that the voice of the duck itself was
    provided by Clarence Nash, the voice of Donald Duck in many
    Walt Disney cartoons, but several times the Disney company said
    Nash had nothing to do with the record. The voice was performed
    by Ken Pruitt, an acquaintance of Dees, as stated on the label
    of the RSO release.</p>
      <p>"Disco Duck" became a nationwide hit in the United States by
    September 1976. On the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 singles chart, it peaked at number one
    on October 16, 1976, for one week, held the number-two spot for
    the following four weeks and remained in the Top 10 for a total
    of ten weeks.</p>
      <p>For all its success, "Disco Duck" was shunned by radio
    stations in Memphis, including WMPS-AM, the station Dees worked
    for at the time. Station management forbade Dees from playing
    the song on his own show and rival stations refused to play it
    for fear of promoting the competition. When Dees talked about
    the song on his show one morning, the program director fired
    him, citing conflict of interest. After a brief mandatory
    hiatus, Dees was hired by WHBQ-AM, WMPS's primary competition
    in Memphis.</p>
      <p>By the time "Disco Duck" become a hit, Dees and his "Idiots"
    started making the rounds of the popular TV music shows to
    promote the song. On 
    <i>American Bandstand</i>and similar shows, Dees lip-synched to
    the recording, alone on stage with an unseen person animating a
    duck hand puppet. But when he appeared on 
    <i>The Midnight Special</i>he gathered together a band, backup
    singers and possibly Pruitt, the voice of the duck on the
    record, and performed the song live.</p>
      <p>"Disco Duck" even made an appearance in the film, 
    <i>Saturday Night Fever</i>, in a dance club scene in which a
    group of senior citizens were learning to dance disco-style. It
    was also featured in a deleted scene added back to the PG
    version. According to Dees, his manager at the time made the
    unwise decision to cancel plans to include the song on the
    film's soundtrack because of fears that it would compete with
    sales of Dees's own album.</p>
      <p>The 1979 Disney-produced album 
    <i>Mickey Mouse Disco</i>, a late entry into the disco genre,
    featured a track called "Macho Duck," (inspired mostly by the
    Village People hit, 
    <i>Macho Man</i>) with the voice of Nash on the track, in
    response.</p>
      <p>"Disco Duck" was covered in 1977 by D.J. Scott and Willem, a
    German Parody Version called "Tarzan Ist Wieder Da".</p>
      <p>Also in 1977, Peter Pan Records put out a series of
    children's records featuring Irwin the Disco Duck.</p>
      <p>"Disco Duck" was referenced in an episode of 
    <i>Animaniacs</i>when the Warner siblings attend a karaoke club
    and Dot Warner flips through the book, saying "See if they have
    Disco Duck."</p>
      <p>In the 
    <i>Beverly Hills 90210</i>episode, "Duke's Bad Boy", Steve
    Sanders insults David Silver's producer by asking if his last
    hit was "Disco Duck".</p>
      <p>DJ Shadow sampled "Disco Duck's" trademark riff on the track
    "Right Thing/GDMFSOB", on his 2002 album 
    <i>The Private Press</i>.</p>
      <p>Live performance by Rick Dees on</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
