<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disturbia_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disturbia_(song)</songId>
   <title>Disturbia</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rihanna</artistId>
      <artistName>Rihanna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2008-08-23</week>
      <week>2008-08-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/1e/Disturbia_Single.jpg/200px-Disturbia_Single.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Rihanna+Disturbia.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Good Girl Gone Bad: Reloaded</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 17, 2008 , (see release history )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2008</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Synthpop</genre>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:59</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>SRP / Def Jam</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Robert Allen</writer>
      <writer>Andre Merritt</writer>
      <writer>Chris Brown</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Brian Kennedy</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Disturbia" is a synthpop song from the re-release of
    Rihanna's third album, 
    <i>Good Girl Gone Bad: Reloaded</i>. It is the third single
    from the re-release, following "Take a Bow" and "If I Never See
    Your Face Again". The song was written by Andre Merritt, Chris
    Brown, and Robert Allen, and produced by Brian Kennedy; it has
    background vocals by Brown and Merritt. The song received a
    nomination for "Best Dance Recording" for the 51st Grammy
    Awards. Pop-punk band The Cab covered the song for the
    compilation album Punk Goes Pop 2.</p>
      <p>"Disturbia" is a moderately fast dance groove composed in
    the key of B minor with 124 beats per minute. The tempo is set
    in common time. Rihanna's vocal range spans from D to E
    <sub>5</sub>. Auto-Tune effects are used throughout the song on
    Rihanna's vocal tracks.</p>
      <p>The song was originally written by Chris Brown and his team
    known as the Graffiti Artizts and was considered for the
    re-release of his album 
    <i>Exclusive</i>. Despite the identical title, the song is
    unrelated to the 2007 suspense film 
    <i>Disturbia</i>. After finishing the song, Brown felt that it
    would be better suited for a female singer; he then forwarded
    it to Rihanna. Def Jam had considered saving the track for
    Rihanna's next album in 2009, because she had already recorded
    "Take a Bow" for the re-release of 
    <i>Good Girl Gone Bad</i>. However, Rihanna and her team felt
    that the song was a summer single and needed to be recorded and
    released as soon as possible. The decision was finally made to
    release the song as the follow up to "Take a Bow". On September
    7, 2008, Rihanna opened the 2008 MTV Video Music Awards with a
    live performance of the song.</p>
      <p>Reviews for the song were generally positive, and many
    commented on its contention as a summer hit. The song has
    received positive reviews: 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>called 
    <i>Disturbia</i>an "awesomely creepy synth-pop mindfunk",
    ranking it #11 in their 
    <i>Best of 2008</i>special on 
    <i>Singles of the Year</i>. Josh Tyrangiel, with 
    <i>TIME</i>magazine, commented on the song's "rubber-ball
    melodies that bounce around your head" but confessed that
    "'Disturbia' ingratiates itself by not trying to be more than
    the silly piece of product that it is." It was a big hit around
    the world.</p>
      <p>On June 26, 2008, "Disturbia" debuted at number eighteen on
    the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100, becoming Rihanna's highest debut on
    the chart to date, as well as her sixth top twenty from 
    <i>Good Girl Gone Bad</i>. The next week, the song rose to the
    eleventh position, but experienced a drop to fifteen the week
    after, staying there for two additional weeks. However, the
    next week after the release of the video and a massive increase
    in sales and radio, the song jumped to number four, making
    Rihanna the seventh female singer (Madonna, Whitney Houston,
    Donna Summer, Mariah Carey, Beyonce, and Ashanti being the
    other six) to have two songs in the top five concurrently, as
    her previous single, "Take a Bow", was at number two that same
    week. It is also her sixth Top 5 single on the Billboard Hot
    100. The following week, the song reached number three,
    surpassing her other hit single, "Take a Bow". For the chart
    week of August 23, 2008, "Disturbia" knocked out Katy Perry's
    "I Kissed a Girl" to become Rihanna's fourth number one hit on
    the Hot 100 and held on the top spot for the week ending 30
    August. It is her third number one from 
    <i>Good Girl Gone Bad: Reloaded</i>, following "Umbrella" and
    "Take a Bow", staying at number one for two weeks. On July 29,
    2008, "Disturbia" jumped to number two on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Digital Songs chart, topping it in the
    following week. "Disturbia" then jumped to number one on 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot Digital Songs chart. Coincidentally, on
    both charts "Disturbia" has peaked on, it knocked off Katy
    Perry's single "I Kissed a Girl" from number one. On the issue
    date September 6, 2008 the song was knocked off by "Whatever
    You Like" by T.I.. It has also topped the Pop 100 chart
    knocking off Chris Brown's "Forever" from the top spot. It
    again reclaimed the top spot after being moved to number 2 by
    "Forever" for a week. For the Billboard issue dated 13
    September, "Disturbia" topped both the Hot Dance Club Play and
    Hot Dance Airplay charts. Rihanna tied with Madonna for the
    most number of Dance Airplay hits, with a total of six, which
    was later broken by Madonna when her single "Miles Away" became
    her seventh number one dance airplay hit. As of 19 December,
    Disturbia has been certified 3x platinum for over 3,000,000
    digital sales by the RIAA. As of February 27, 2009 the single
    has spent over 36 weeks inside the Top 40 of the Billboard Hot
    100, becoming Rihanna's longest lasting Hot 100 hit. It is
    Rihanna's first song to go triple-platinum, and is therefore
    her biggest selling single worldwide.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom, "Disturbia" debuted on the UK Singles
    Chart at number forty-seven due to digital sales. After the
    release of the music video, the song re-entered the chart at
    number forty-seven again and climbed to number thirty-four and
    number nine in the proceeding weeks. The song peaked at number
    three, from digital only sales giving Rihanna her eighth
    British top ten single. Although "Disturbia" hasn't and will
    not receive a physical release the song rose back up the charts
    from number 5 to number 3. It spent 11 weeks in the UK Top 10
    singles chart and held the record for the biggest selling
    download only single selling over 300,000 downloads. The record
    was then beaten by Leona Lewis with her single "Run," but was
    beaten in December 2008, by Alexandra Burke for the single
    "Hallelujah." All in all "Disturbia" was a huge success in the
    UK, and is likely to have reached #1 if it were released in
    physical format also. It is Rihanna's third longest charting
    single in the UK where it has spent 36 weeks in the top 100,
    only being passed by two extra weeks by "Don't Stop the Music"
    and a further 33 weeks with her massive hit "Umbrella".
    "Disturbia" finished as the 13th best selling single of 2008,
    one place above her number 1 hit "Take a Bow". In Spain,
    "Disturbia" topped the charts of the most popular radio
    station, while in the official Spanish Singles Chart peaked at
    number ten and achieved Platinum with sales over 40,000.The
    song was also a massive hit in Ireland where it peaked at
    number four for six consecutive weeks and became the 18th best
    selling single of the year, surpassing a number of top three
    hits. In Switzerland, the song peaked at number eight on
    downloads alone. On the Canadian Hot 100, the song has peaked
    at number two for five weeks. In New Zealand, "Disturbia"
    became Rihanna's third number one single, and her first since
    "Umbrella". It is her fourth top five hit, and fifth top ten
    hit there from 
    <i>Good Girl Gone Bad</i>, since "Hate That I Love You" peaked
    at number six. It was certified Platinum on August 23, 2009,
    selling over 15,000 copies. In Australia, it has climbed to
    number six. The song was the most added song to Australian
    radio in its first week of major radio release. It was
    certified Gold on downloads alone before the physical release
    several weeks later, when it was subsequently certified
    Platinum. "Disturbia" topped the Turkey Top 20 chart for nine
    consecutive weeks, the longest running number one in 2008 on
    the chart. On December 28, 2008, the UK Singles Chart listed
    this as #18 for the end of the year chart show. On January 7,
    2010, UK music channel Smashhits listed "Disturbia" at #3 on
    "Rihanna: Ultimate 10".</p>
      <p>The video for "Disturbia" was filmed on June 29, 2008 and
    was co-directed by Anthony Mandler, along with Rihanna herself.
    After 2007's "Don't Stop The Music," this is Rihanna's second
    video, that she directed herself. The video was choreographed
    by Rihanna's long time choreographer, Tina Landon, who is best
    known for her work with Janet Jackson. The "Disturbia" video
    was released exclusively on iTunes for a 48-hour period. It
    debuted on MTV's 
    <i>TRL</i>and BET’s 
    <i>106 and Park</i>and MuchOnDemand on July 24, 2008 and on VH1
    on July 26. It debuted in the UK on August 1, but in the rest
    of Europe the video debuted on September 8, receiving
    immediately High Rotation on MTV. It peaked at #1 on 
    <i>TRL</i>and 
    <i>MuchOnDemand</i>. The video begins in a surrealistic torture
    chamber where Rihanna is seen smoking and beside a piano. As
    the song starts Rihanna is seen encaged wearing lenses covering
    her eyes, which make her look as if her eyes have rolled into
    the back of her head. Scenes are interspersed with Rihanna
    sitting in a gas-chamber like room and wearing a feathered
    headdress. Later on she is seen tied to a chair struggling. At
    the bridge of the song she performs a 
    <i>Thriller</i>-esque dance routine. As of September 20, 2009
    the official video had been viewed more than 49 million times
    on YouTube, with almost another 40 million views through
    duplicate music videos.</p>
      <p>Rihanna used "Disturbia" as the first performance of the
    2008 MTV Video Music Awards immediately following Britney
    Spears' opening speech. The format of the music video was
    partially preserved, with the zombie dancers present with light
    staffs. The performance was mixed with samples from 'Sweet
    Dreams' by the Eurythmics, and contained a rock solo break from
    the White Stripes song Seven Nation Army. Deleted scenes from
    the video were projected behind the singer.</p>
      <p>Subsequently, Rihanna was interviewed on 
    <i>GMTV</i>and performed the song again, as well as on 
    <i>For One Night Only</i>, 
    <i>This Morning</i>, and 
    <i>Star Academy France</i>. Following her performance on Star
    Academy France, the album soared from #43 to #11 having a sales
    increase of 211%, peaking at #8 the following week, becoming
    Rihanna's first album to reach the top 10 in France.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
