<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SOS_(Rihanna_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SOS_(Rihanna_song)</songId>
   <title>SOS</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rihanna</artistId>
      <artistName>Rihanna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2006-05-13</week>
      <week>2006-05-20</week>
      <week>2006-05-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/69/Sos0su.jpg/200px-Sos0su.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Rihanna+SOS.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>A Girl like Me</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 7, 2006  (2006-02-07) , April 3, 2006  (2006-04-03)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>October 2005</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>Electropop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:00</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Def Jam /SRP</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>J. R. Rotem</writer>
      <writer>Evan "Kidd" Bogart</writer>
      <writer>Ed Cobb</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>J. R. Rotem</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"SOS" is a dance-pop song written by Evan "Kidd" Bogart and
    J. R. Rotem for Barbadian R&amp;B singer Rihanna's second
    studio album, 
    <i>A Girl like Me</i>(2006). It samples the key section, bass
    line, and drum beat from Soft Cell's 1981 single "Tainted
    Love", written by Ed Cobb.</p>
      <p>"SOS" was released as the album's lead single in 2006 (see
    2006 in music). The song reached number one in Australia and
    the United States and the top five in other music markets such
    as Canada, Germany, and the United Kingdom.</p>
      <p>The song was primarily written by producer J. R. Rotem and
    Evan "Kidd" Bogart, son of Casablanca Records founder Neil
    Bogart. Label mate Christina Milian was originally asked to
    record the song for her third album, 
    <i>So Amazin'</i>, but the singer turned it down and Island Def
    Jam CEO L.A. Reid instead offered "SOS" to Rihanna. Milian
    commented that the song was too "pop" for an R&amp;B artist and
    that she wasn't asked to record it, which she confirmed in her
    official forum.</p>
      <p>Inspired by the Rotem's sampling of an 80s classic in Soft
    Cell's 1981 version of "Tainted Love", co-writer Evan Bogart
    'sampled' some of his own favourite 80s songs in the lyrics,
    including A-Ha's "Take On Me", Cutting Crew's "(I Just) Died In
    Your Arms", ABBA's "Head Over Heels", Michael Jackson's "The
    Way You Make Me Feel", Modern English's "I Melt With You" and
    Kim Wilde's "You Keep Me Hanging On".</p>
      <p>The song also references songs from other decades including
    ABBA's "SOS" in the title itself, Elton John's 1971 song "Tiny
    Dancer" with the line "Just hold me close boy cos I'm your tiny
    dancer" and the original sampled song "Tainted Love" with the
    lyric, "You got me tossin' and turnin' and I can't sleep at
    night".</p>
      <p>The song's theme is based around the song's protagonist
    crying out for help as she becomes besotted with a lover
    mentioned in the song. Because she is unaccustomed to feeling
    this way, she believes that she is out of character, and states
    "'cause you on my mind, it's got me losing it."</p>
      <p>Remixes were provided by Jason Nevins, who has produced
    remixes for artists such as Madonna, Fall Out Boy, Good
    Charlotte, Kelly Clarkson, LL Cool J and Pink. This song was
    used in the film, 
    <i>True Confessions of a Hollywood Starlet</i>.</p>
      <p>In the United States, "SOS" hit number one on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100, Pop 100, Hot Dance Music/Club Play,
    Hot Dance Airplay, Hot Digital Songs and Hot Digital Tracks;
    the song also hit number two on the Pop 100 Airplay, but could
    not get past the massive airplay of Sean Paul's single
    "Temperature". The song was made available as a digital
    download upon the release of the album and its first week of
    digital sales prompted a dramatic jump from number thirty-four
    to number-one, becoming one of the biggest jumps to the number
    one position in 
    <i>Billboard</i>history. The single remained at number-one for
    three weeks. The reason for the large jump was that "SOS" was
    kept off most digital download services until her album was
    released to stimulate more album sales.</p>
      <p>Internationally, "SOS" became Rihanna's first number-one hit
    in Australia. It stayed at the top for eight consecutive weeks,
    making it the singer's biggest hit in Australia. The song also
    reached number two on the UK and German singles charts, number
    four on the Dutch chart, and number seven in Italy. In Romania
    the song competed with both "If It's Lovin' That You Want" and
    "Unfaithful" since "SOS" was pushed back due to the good
    performance of "If It's Lovin' That You Want", and when finally
    released, "Unfaithful" had already start gaining heavy radio
    airplay. "SOS" reached number twenty-eight in the Romanian
    Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>"SOS" was removed from the UK charts after thirteen weeks
    because there was a remix of "SOS" contained on the
    "Unfaithful" single. Due to UK chart rules, a new single cannot
    have a remix of a previous single if the original song is still
    charting, which is why the song left the charts at
    twenty-seven. However, the song was still a smash hit, being
    the UK's ninth best-selling single of the year. The song also
    hit number-one for two weeks on ECD:UK.</p>
      <p>The song spawned three music videos; one of them being an
    Agent Provocateur promotional video which features Rihanna
    walking into a hotel which turns into a nightclub. Another
    promotional video was done for Nike, featuring a dance contest
    in a gym. The official version was shot for music and
    music-related television stations and premiered on MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>and MuchMusic's 
    <i>MuchOnDemand</i>on March 23, 2006. The video reached number
    one on 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>for the first time on April 14, 2006
    and stayed on the countdown for twenty days.</p>
      <p>In this clip, directed by Chris Applebaum, Rihanna wears a
    bikini and the video has her telling a guy she's going to call
    for help due to the desperate feelings caused by their
    relationship. She also uses a Nokia 3250 cellular phone, and
    she apparently seems to be listening to "Pon De Replay," and
    "Tainted Love," the song sampled in "SOS", as Soft Cell's album
    cover can be seen on the display.</p>
      <p>These are the formats and track listings of major single
    releases of "SOS". Ironically, in some formats, "Break It Off"
    was released as the B-side to "SOS", even though it ended up
    being released as a single on its own later on.</p>
      <p>Side A</p>
      <p>Side B</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
