<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Umbrella_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Umbrella_(song)</songId>
   <title>Umbrella</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rihanna</artistId>
      <artistName>Rihanna featuring Jay-Z</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2007-06-09</week>
      <week>2007-06-16</week>
      <week>2007-06-23</week>
      <week>2007-06-30</week>
      <week>2007-07-07</week>
      <week>2007-07-14</week>
      <week>2007-07-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f0/Rihanna-jay-z-umbrella.jpg/200px-Rihanna-jay-z-umbrella.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Rihanna-featuring-Jay-Z+Umbrella.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Good Girl Gone Bad</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 29, 2007  (2007-03-29)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>February 2007 , Westlake Recording Studios , ( Los Angeles , CA )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:35 (Album version)</length>
      <length>4:14 (Radio edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Def Jam</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jay-Z</writer>
      <writer>Kuk Harrell</writer>
      <writer>The-Dream</writer>
      <writer>Christopher "Tricky" Stewart</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Tricky Stewart</producer>
      <producer>The-Dream</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Umbrella" is a song by Barbadian R&amp;B singer Rihanna,
    featuring a rap verse by American hip hop artist Jay-Z. The
    song was written by The-Dream, Christopher Stewart, Kuk Harrell
    and Jay-Z, and was produced by Stewart. It was released as the
    lead single for Rihanna's third studio album, 
    <i>Good Girl Gone Bad</i>. The track was released worldwide on
    March 29, 2007, and since its release, "Umbrella" has been
    covered by many artists worldwide and became a zeitgeist hit in
    pop culture.</p>
      <p>The song has also achieved commercial success by topping
    charts in Australia, Canada, Germany, France, the Republic of
    Ireland, Sweden, Switzerland, the United Kingdom, and the
    United States, as well as reaching the top ten in many other
    countries. Following a successful chart performance worldwide
    and a positive reception from critics, the song is listed
    number three on the 100 Best Songs of 2007 published by 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine.</p>
      <p>In 2008, "Umbrella" earned Rihanna and Jay-Z a Grammy Award
    for Best Rap/Sung Collaboration in addition to receiving
    nominations for Record of the Year and Song of the Year. It
    managed to stay at number one in the United Kingdom for 10
    weeks, the longest time spent by a female and in the 21st
    century, the 2000s decade, and on this chart, making it the
    most successful No.1 of the decade in that country.</p>
      <p>American songwriter-producer Christopher "Tricky" Stewart
    and Terius "The-Dream" Nash and Kuk Harrell convened in January
    2007 at the Atlanta-based Triangle Studios to create new
    material. In the studio, Stewart was "messing around with a
    walloping hi-hat sound". With his attention caught by the
    sound, Nash asked Stewart what he was doing: "Oh, my God, what
    is that beat?" When Stewart incorporated chords onto the
    hi-hat, "immediately the word popped into [Nash's] head"; he
    went to the vocal booth and started singing. Nash wrote the
    first two verses and the chorus over Stewart's skeleton track.
    They quickly wrote the lyrics, completing the first verse in 60
    seconds. They continued into writing, adding the hook while
    "Tricky would put the next chord". In a matter of hours, they
    had recorded a demo of the track.</p>
      <p>The song was written with American pop superstar Britney
    Spears in mind, with whom Stewart had previously worked with in
    the 2003 song "Me Against the Music". Stewart and Nash thought
    that Spears, who had "her personal life ... a little out
    of control" at the time, needed a hit as musical comeback.
    Spears was working on her fifth album, 
    <i>Blackout</i>, so they sent a copy of the demo to Spears'
    management. However, Spears did not hear of the song because
    her label rejected it, claiming they had enough songs for her
    to record.</p>
      <p>Following the management's rejection of the track, Stewart
    and Nash dealt it out to other record labels.It was also given
    to UK R&amp;B Singer/Song Writer Taio Cruz. It was Then opted
    Island Def Jam chairman Antonio "L.A." Reid, a friend of
    Stewart who established his first studio. By early February
    2007, the demo was sent to Reid's right-hand woman, A&amp;R
    executive Karen Kwak, who passed it along to Reid with a
    message confirming that they had found a song suited for
    Rihanna, who was working on her third studio album, 
    <i>Good Girl Gone Bad</i>, at the time. Reid immediately sent
    the demo to Rihanna, who was also positive of it: "When the
    demo first started playing, I was like, This is interesting,
    this is weird. ... But the song kept getting better. I
    listened to it over and over. I said, 'I need this record. I
    want to record it tomorrow.'"</p>
      <p>When [Rihanna] recorded the 'ellas,' you knew it was about
    to be the jump-off and your life was about to change if you had
    anything to do with that record.</p>
      <p>However, since it was the Grammy season of 2007, Stewart and
    Nash eyed American R&amp;B singer Mary J. Blige for the demo.
    Upon calling them to set the record aside for Rihanna, Stewart
    had played it to an associate of Blige, subsequently promising
    the song to her. Having heard the move of the writers, Kwak
    began calling Stewart and his manager, Mark Stewart,
    incessantly. Meanwhile, considering Blige's nominations at the
    Grammys, Stewart and Nash agreed to wait for her response.
    However, Blige failed to hear the song in full due to her
    obligations to the Grammys at the time and "had to sign off on
    the record before her reps could accept it". Finally, Reid
    "stepped in, trading on his power-broker status and
    longstanding relationship with Stewart", and admits, "I made
    the producers an offer they couldn't refuse." By the time Reid
    had successfully persuaded Stewart's camp, they "just couldn't
    say no". On giving up the record to Reid's camp, Mark Stewart
    comments, "We knew Rihanna's album would be out in a few
    months. Mary wasn’t even in an album cycle yet. We made the
    sensible business decision."</p>
      <p>Rihanna recorded the song, with vocal production by Thaddis
    "Kuk" Harrell, in a Westlake Recording Studios in Los Angeles.
    Initially, Stewart admitted he was still reluctant as to
    whether Rihanna was the right artist to record the song, but
    following the recording of the "ella, ella" catch phrase, he
    felt they were onto "something". Following Rihanna's recording,
    Def Jam CEO-rapper Jay-Z added his rap. However, Jay-Z rewrote
    his verse without the awareness of Stewart and Nash. Stewart
    could not understand it, but later realized it made "sense"
    instead of the first version. Stewart noted that "from a
    songwriter's standpoint, he just really made it more about the
    song, with the metaphors about umbrellas and about the weather
    versus what he had before".</p>
      <p>"Umbrella" is in the genres pop, contemporary R&amp;B, and
    hip hop. The song's musicscape is based on the hi-hat,
    synthesizers, and a distorted bassline. According to 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>magazine, the song's beat can be
    recreated through a slowed-down drum loop from the Apple
    music-software program GarageBand (Vintage Funk Kit 03). Note
    that the same drum loop was used on Maurice Joshua's remix of
    George Michael's Faith. The song is written in the key of A#
    minor.</p>
      <p>The song's lyrics are written in the traditional
    verse-chorus form. They opens with a rap verse, and the hook
    "ella, ella" follows every chorus. A bridge follows the second
    hook, and the song ends in a fadeout.</p>
      <p>"Umbrella" was released worldwide on March 29, 2007,
    debuting on Rihanna's Def Jam website. The song was released
    digitally in the United Kingdom on May 14, 2007, its physical
    release following two weeks later. An acoustic version of the
    song with a new arrangement was later released a bonus track to
    
    <i>Good Girl Gone Bad</i>in the iTunes Store.</p>
      <p>"Umbrella" received generally positive reviews from critics.
    Andy Kellman of Allmusic commented: "'Umbrella' is [Rihanna's
    best song] to date, delivering mammoth of spacious drums, a
    towering backdrop during the chorus, and vocals that are
    somehow totally convincing without sounding all that
    impassioned — an ideal spot between trying too hard and
    boredom, like she might've been on her 20th take, which only
    adds to the song's charm." For Alex Macpherson of British
    newspaper 
    <i>The Guardian</i>, "Umbrella" is "evidence" that Rihanna's
    "strict work ethic is paying off", adding that she "delivers
    [in the song] an impassioned declaration of
    us-against-the-world devotion". Tom Breihan of Pitchfork Media,
    though he complimented the production, dismissed Rihanna's
    voice which "takes on an unpleasant icepick edge when she tries
    to fill the space between the slow-tempo beats", adding that
    the song is "uncompelling as event-pop, particularly because of
    the disconnect between Rihanna's cold, clinical delivery and
    the comforting warmth of the lyrics".</p>
      <p>The song has earned Rihanna several awards and nominations.
    In 2007, it was nominated at the Teen Choice Awards for Choice
    Music: Single. In 2008, "Umbrella" earned Rihanna and Jay-Z a
    Grammy Award for Best Rap/Sung Collaboration in addition to
    receiving nominations for Record of the Year and Song of the
    Year.</p>
      <p>"Umbrella" has also been recognized in various forms of
    accolades by the music press. The song is listed number three
    on the 100 Best Songs of 2007, published by the music magazine 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>. 
    <i>Time</i>magazine also listed the song number three on their
    Top 10 Songs of 2007. The song is listed number one on 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>magazine's list of the 10 Best
    Singles of 2007, while topping the magazine's poll for the best
    single of 2007. 
    <i>Blender</i>magazine awarded the song Song of the Year in
    their Readers' Poll 2007. The music press has considered
    "Umbrella" as 2007's Song of the Summer, while 
    <i>The New York Times</i>writer Kelefa Sanneh regarded it as
    "arguably 2007's signature slow jam". In 2009 Pitchfork ranked
    the song as the #25 song on list of The Top 500 Tracks of the
    decade. 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>put it on its end-of-the-decade,
    "best-of" list, saying, "In 2007, Rihanna had us all singin' in
    the rain."</p>
      <p>The single was in the top ten &amp; top five throughout the
    charts in the world. Prior to its physical release, "Umbrella"
    achieved the biggest debut in the six-year history of the
    iTunes, breaking a record previously held by Colombian singer
    Shakira and American hip hop artist Wyclef Jean’s "Hips Don't
    Lie". As a digital single, "Umbrella" topped the iTunes Store
    singles chart in more than 17 different countries around the
    world.</p>
      <p>"Umbrella" was a commercial and chart success in the United
    States. On 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine's issue dated June 9, 2007, "Umbrella"
    ascended from number 42 to number one on the Hot 100, based on
    the single's first-week digital sales of over 277,000 units.
    The single became one of the highest digital debut in the
    United States since Nielsen SoundScan began tracking downloads
    in 2003. "Umbrella" is Rihanna's second number-one single after
    "SOS", which was also noted for its huge leap on the
    Hot 100 to the top spot in 2006 based on digital sales
    alone. Significantly sustained by the strong airplay of the
    single and preventing American rap group Shop Boyz' "Party Like
    a Rockstar" to advance on the chart, "Umbrella" spent seven
    consecutive weeks at the top of the Hot 100, until it was
    replaced by American pop rock band Plain White T's' "Hey There
    Delilah". On the 2007 
    <i>Billboard</i>year end chart, "Umbrella" was ranked at number
    two; it was ranked only behind Beyonce's hit single
    "Irreplaceable". The song debuted at number one in Canada,
    becoming the first song to top the recently launched Canadian
    Hot 100, a singles chart in Canada issued by 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine, similar to that of the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100.</p>
      <p>The single performed, most notably, in the United Kingdom,
    breaking a record on the UK Singles Chart. The song debuted at
    number one on the chart based on digital sales alone, becoming
    Rihanna's first chart-topper in the country. During the
    single's fourth week on the chart, it earned Rihanna the
    accolade in the United Kingdom when both the single and album
    topped the UK Singles Chart and UK Albums Chart. Having reached
    nine straight weeks at number one on the chart, it broke the
    record of American group Gnarls Barkley's "Crazy" as the
    longest of the decade. "Umbrella" eventually reached a total of
    ten weeks at number one on the UK Singles Chart, becoming the
    country's longest-running number-one single of the 21st
    century. Rihanna has become the seventh artist in the history
    of the UK Singles Chart to top the chart for ten straight
    weeks. By the end of 2008, "Umbrella" had sold more than
    600,000 units, making it her biggest-selling single to date and
    the second biggest-selling single of 2007 in the United
    Kingdom, only behind Leona Lewis' Bleeding Love. It has since
    been certified platinum by the British Phonographic Industry on
    December 12, 2008. In total, "Umbrella" has amassed 71 weeks on
    the UK Singles Chart and has appeared within the top 100 for
    three consecutive years. In 2007 it peaked at #1, in 2008 at
    #18 and 2009 at #99. It currently stands as the eighth best
    selling song by a female artist in the UK in the 21st century,
    and also the eighth best selling collboration following the
    same criteria.</p>
      <p>As well as topping the charts in the United Kingdom,
    "Umbrella" had a similar success throughout Europe, reaching
    number one in Ireland, Poland, Sweden, Belgium, Austria,
    Norway, Italy, Portugal, Romania, Germany and specially in
    Spain, where the song achieved four times platinum selling
    160,000 units, and topped the charts for five consecutive
    weeks. In Australia, "Umbrella" entered the Australian ARIA
    Singles Chart at number one and spent six consecutive weeks at
    the top. "Umbrella" has been certified platinum in 2007 by the
    Australian Recording Industry Association for over 70,000 units
    shipment of the single, and ended as Australia's third
    best-performing single in 2007. The single peaked at number one
    in the New Zealand charts and was the country's best-performing
    single in 2007. In total, "Umbrella" reached number one on 18
    of its 29 charts released and it reached top 10 on every chart
    at that matter.</p>
      <p>While working on the album, ideas began to circulate
    concerning Rihanna's image, extending into her music videos.
    She asked American music video director Chris Applebaum to send
    her "something" to work on. Def Jam representatives were
    expecting Applebaum of the treatment. In response, Applebaum
    hurriedly made a treatment for the video, one of his first
    ideas being the silver body paint that Rihanna is seen in.
    Applebaum was doubtful whether Rihanna would embrace the idea,
    but her "positive response" following a letter the director
    sent to the artist ensured its approval. Makeup artist Pamela
    Neal mixed a silver paint that would give Rihanna such a look.
    During the session, the paint was re-applied between takes to
    ensure she was completely covered. The set was closed to
    Rihanna, Applebaum and a camera assistant. Rihanna also
    contributed her own ideas towards the video shoot, suggesting
    to Applebaum that she dance en pointe, an idea which he
    accepted.</p>
      <p>The music video premiered on April 26, 2007 at her website.
    Downloads were made available for those in the U.S. only from
    the website for a limited time. The video was officially
    released on the iTunes Store on May 11, 2007, peaking at number
    one for a period of eight weeks. On May 1, 2007, "Umbrella"
    debuted on MTV’s 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>at number 10, before reaching number
    one on May 9 where it remained for fifteen days, making it the
    longest running number one of 2007. The video was well-played
    in MTV during the second half of 2007; it has reached over
    8,000 plays, receiving a platinum recognition at the MTV
    Platinum and Gold Video Awards. Such was the success of the
    promotional video that it received five nominations at the 2007
    MTV Video Music Awards, including "Female Artist of the Year",
    "Video of the Year" and "Monster Single of the Year", going on
    to win the latter two.</p>
      <p>Along with countless amateurs, "Umbrella" has been covered
    by several notable performers from a variety of musical genres,
    including Manic Street Preachers, JLS, Bare Egil, Terra Naomi,
    Jamie Cullum, Mike Shinoda of Linkin Park, The Mint Chicks,
    McFly, Lillasyster, Plain White T's, Carrie Underwood, Keith
    Urban, OneRepublic, Sara Bareilles, Cláudia Leitte, Mandy
    Moore, My Chemical Romance, Tegan and Sara, Amanda Palmer,
    Syesha Mercado, Natalie Gauci, illScarlett, All Time Low,
    Taylor Swift, Bentley Jones, Boyce Avenue, and The Baseballs
    (Swiss Charts Nr. 16 - June 2009, Finnish Single Chart nr. 1 -
    November 2009). Then-upcoming singer Marié Digby recorded an
    acoustic version of "Umbrella" which was released August 3,
    2007 as the debut single from her Hollywood Records 
    <i>Start Here EP</i>and included as the closing track on
    Digby's debut album 
    <i>Unfold</i>. Scottish rock group Biffy Clyro also released an
    acoustic version of the song, while Italian band Vanilla Sky
    went in the opposite direction and released a punk cover of the
    song. For her debut album 
    <i>a.K.a. Cassandra</i>, Filipina singer and actress KC
    Concepcion covered the song in English, while singer Miss Ganda
    recorded a version in Filipino entitled "
    <i>Payong</i>" (means umbrella).</p>
      <p>Pop-punk outfit All Time Low covered the song for the
    Fearless Records compilation album 
    <i>Punk Goes Crunk</i>, and Welsh rock band Manic Street
    Preachers produced their own version of "Umbrella", which was
    originally recorded for the album 
    <i>NME Awards 2008</i>. Produced in celebration of the
    Shockwaves NME Awards 2008 and Big Gig, that album was given
    free with a special souvenir box set of the magazine 
    <i>NME</i>on February 27. Two additional versions (acoustic and
    Grand Slam mix) were later made available on iTunes, and the
    trio now comprise an 
    <i>Umbrella EP</i>; a video for the cover is available on the
    band's official website. British pop rock band McFly performed
    their own version of "Umbrella" during their "Greatest Hits So
    Far Tour" in 2007, and Finnish melodic death metal band
    Children of Bodom performed their 2008 cover live at Wacken
    Open Air.</p>
      <p>There have also been notable mixed versions of the song.
    American rapper Lil Mama recorded a version of "Umbrella" that
    replaced Jay-Z's opening rap verse. An article by 
    <i>Blender</i>magazine, who dismissed Jay-Z's version, said
    "Lil Mama actually seems to understand the song's metaphorical
    themes of protection and loyalty". American punk band Blink-182
    drummer Travis Barker remixed the song, adding to the track
    "quicksilver snare flourishes and... real-life guitars". Singer
    Chris Brown created an answer song titled "Cinderella",
    replacing some of the verses and part of the chorus of
    "Umbrella" with his own lyrics. This version is the official
    remix. This version has been performed as a duet between Brown
    and Rihanna when he joined Rihanna on a late-2008 tour in the
    Asia-Pacific region. R&amp;B/hip-hop singer The-Dream, who
    wrote "Umbrella", recorded the demo with a slightly different
    intro and instrumental. Recently, Korean girl group 2NE1
    covered this song on Music Bank.</p>
      <p>The song's reign at number one in the United Kingdom and
    Ireland occurred as the regions were hit by extreme rainfall
    and flooding, which led 
    <i>The Sun</i>to suggest the two events were related, with the
    media referring to it as the Rihanna Curse. The UK-based
    publication adjudged the single brought bad luck to their
    country, and mentioned the date of the single's video shot
    which was Friday the 13th, adding further coincidence of the
    curse. Before the single's release on May 14, the temperature
    in London, U.K. was relatively high, reaching 20 °C. However,
    just a day after the release, "severe weather warnings hit the
    headlines". In an article run by 
    <i>The Sun</i>, it urged readers to join the campaign in
    knocking the song off the chart's top spot, suggesting the
    readers with several songs to download instead. Coincidentally,
    the precise day the song was dethroned in the chart, the
    weather seemed to improve.</p>
      <p>A similar situation occurred in New Zealand, where the song
    hit number one in the early winter of 2007 as the country was
    experiencing some of the worst storms in its history. During
    the weather conditions, Taranaki, Tauranga, and Auckland had
    experienced tornadoes and flooding in the Far North of the
    country. Once the single was replaced on the top spot, weather
    condition almost in the entire New Zealand pacified, although
    Hawke's Bay was still stormed.</p>
      <p>With the record-breaking success of the single and the
    reported coincidence with the weather, Def Jam's marketing team
    collaborated with British umbrella manufacturer Totes. The
    company produced five types of Rihanna umbrellas, of which was
    a double-colored satin umbrella that Rihanna debuted in public
    during her performance of the song at the 2007 MTV Movie
    Awards. Although manufactured by a UK-based company, the
    collection was made available only to US residents by online
    through the company's website.</p>
      <p>In November 2007 MADtv's Nicole Parker and Keegan-Michael
    Key, who were depicting U.S. Democratic presidential candidates
    Hillary Clinton and Barack Obama respectively, performed a
    parody of "Umbrella".</p>
      <p>"Umbrella" has been featured in the karaoke video games 
    <i>SingStar Pop Volume 2</i>and 
    <i>Lips</i>, both accompanied by the music video. A cover of
    the song is also featured in 
    <i>Dance Dance Revolution Hottest Party 2</i>as a playable
    track.</p>
      <p>"Umbrella" was performed by Rihanna during the 2007 MTV
    Movie Awards on June 3, 2007. In the United Kingdom, she
    performed the song on GMTV and on The Brit Awards in 2008. She
    also performed "Umbrella " during her AOL sessions. In France,
    she performed it on 
    <i>Star Academy</i>. "Umbrella" was added to the setlist of her
    first headlining The Good Girl Gone Bad Tour where it was
    performed as the final song before the Encore.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Sides A &amp; B</i>
      </p>
      <p>
         <i>Side A</i>
      </p>
      <p>
         <i>Side B</i>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
