<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Take_a_Bow_(Rihanna_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Take_a_Bow_(Rihanna_song)</songId>
   <title>Take a Bow</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rihanna</artistId>
      <artistName>Rihanna</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2008-05-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/1/11/TakeABow_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Rihanna+Take-a-Bow.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Good Girl Gone Bad: Reloaded</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 15, 2008 ( U.S. )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
      <format>picture disc</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2008</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:49</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Def Jam</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ne-Yo</writer>
      <writer>T.E. Hermansen</writer>
      <writer>M.S. Eriksen</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Stargate</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Take a Bow" is a song written by R&amp;B singer-songwriter
    Ne-Yo and production-team Stargate for the re-release of
    Rihanna's third studio album 
    <i>Good Girl Gone Bad</i>. It is the fifth single from 
    <i>Good Girl Gone Bad</i>overall, but first single from the
    re-release edition of the album, 
    <i>Good Girl Gone Bad: Reloaded</i>.</p>
      <p>The song premiered on KZZP and KRQQ's 
    <i>JohnJay and Rich in the Morning</i>on March 14, 2008, and
    was made available to media outlets later that same day. It was
    officially released to U.S. top 40 radio on April 15, 2008 and
    to iTunes on May 6, 2008 where it has proven to be immensely
    popular both in the United States and internationally. To date
    the single has reached the number 1 position on iTunes in the
    United States, Canada, United Kingdom, New Zealand, Denmark,
    and Ireland, and has achieved top 10 chartings in over eighteen
    countries across the globe. In U.K the single was release on
    May 12. In Europe it was released a month later on June 6. Due
    to digital downloads, "Take a Bow" charted at number 45 in
    Italy before its official release set for July 28, 2008,
    according to an Italian music channel which has inserted "Take
    A Bow" in its playlist on that date. In France the song has
    been released nearly two months after the European release
    date, set for June 6, 2008, on July 21, 2008.</p>
      <p>Bill Lamb from About.com stated that "Rihanna has the unique
    ability to deliver the lyrics without batting an eyelash, and
    this is another success, if a little lifeless, for the duo.
    Look for it to be Rihanna's 9th, yes 9th, top 10 pop single"
    and "The production [of the song] utilizes brief spoken asides
    by Rihanna to great effect. It's her "please!" and dismissive
    giggle that are likely to be the most memorable elements from
    this effort." He also adds, "The keyboard-based backing of
    "Take a Bow" is, by now, standard Stargate and does not
    challenge their best. However, you are likely to find yourself
    singing along after the first few times through, and that
    should be enough right now to keep Rihanna in good graces with
    pop radio programmers".</p>
      <p>Chuck Taylor from 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine reviewed the song and said: "With
    superstars Stargate and Ne-Yo at the helm, the velvety ballad
    ticks along with well-applied piano and strings, as the
    instantly recognizable singer delivers a convincingly bemused
    vocal, complete with haughty laugh". Nick Levine of Digital Spy
    wrote, "'Take A Bow' does what it sets out to do very well, but
    it's an underwhelming follow-up to the dance floor rush of
    'Don't Stop The Music'."</p>
      <p>In the issue dated May 24, 2008, "Take a Bow" jumped up 58
    spots from number fifty-eight to number-one on the Hot 100.
    This is the sixth-best leap in the chart's history of songs
    climbing to number one. The song also opened with the third
    highest digital sales tally in 
    <i>Billboard</i>Chart history amassing 267,000 units sold in
    one week after being available only on radio. The song has
    become Rihanna's third 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 number-one single after "Umbrella"
    and "SOS," which topped the charts around the same time in 2007
    &amp; 2006, respectively. "Take A Bow" is Rihanna's second
    number-one single from the album 
    <i>Good Girl Gone Bad</i>. The song remained in the top 10 for
    15 weeks, is her longest stay in the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 top 10. The song also shot-up from
    number 70 to 1 on the Canadian chart in the same week, making
    it the biggest jump in the chart's history.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom "Take A Bow" debuted in the Top 10 at
    number-two on the UK Singles Chart, based on downloads alone,
    and the following week ascended to number-one where it remained
    for two consecutive weeks, becoming Rihanna's second UK number
    one following "Umbrella" in 2007. It spent 27 weeks on the UK
    Singles Chart (her fifth longest charting). With sales of
    327,160, it became 2008's twentieth best-selling single in the
    UK and is certified silver.</p>
      <p>The song was also a success in Oceania. "Take A Bow" debuted
    at number-thirty on the Australian ARIA Singles Chart, and the
    following week climbed 17 places to number-thirteen and was
    named a bullet performer for that week. It ascended into the
    top ten at number-ten in its third week and rose to number-six
    in its fourth. "Take A Bow" eventually reached its peak
    position at number-three two weeks later, and is the fourth top
    5 hit from 
    <i>Good Girl Gone Bad</i>there. In New Zealand, the single
    debuted at number-four on the New Zealand RIANZ Singles Chart,
    and has since peaked at number two for five weeks, being kept
    from reaching the top spot by Chris Brown's "Forever".</p>
      <p>The single has become one of Rihanna's biggest radio hits of
    her entire career in the United States, only second to
    "Umbrella", which had the advantage of stronger Urban airplay.
    With the single placing in the top ten on Top 40, Rhythmic, and
    Urban at the same time, it has outpeaked some of her previous
    flagship hits such as "Don't Stop the Music" "SOS" and "Pon de
    Replay". The song has also reached number one on Mediabase,
    becoming Rihanna's second number one on this chart, after
    "Umbrella". In the week July 26, the single reached the top
    spot of Hot 100 Airplay</p>
      <p>The "Take a Bow" music video was directed by Anthony Mandler
    who has directed several of her previous videos. It spent 27
    days on BET's 
    <i>106 &amp; Park</i>, eight of the days spent at #1, and is
    also Rihanna's first #1 video on 
    <i>106 &amp; Park</i>. The video was nominated for Best Female
    Video and Best Direction at the 2008 MTV Video Music
    Awards.</p>
      <p>The video featured Rihanna who had found out her boyfriend
    was cheating on her. She basically tells him to get lost,
    torches his clothes, and leaves him crying for her. This song
    and music video is believed to have a point: you never know
    what you have until it's gone.</p>
      <p>The video has been viewed over 69 million times on the video
    sharing site Youtube, from September 2009.</p>
      <p>"Take a Bow" was released on CD and 12" vinyl commercially
    and as "Take a Bow: Remixes" promotionally and digitally.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Side A &amp; B</i>
      </p>
      <p>A remix was created by Channel 955, a Top 40 radio station,
    during the height of the song's popularity and during the
    height of Detroit's former mayor Kwame Kilpatrick's legal
    problems in the Text Message Scandal, in which anonymously sent
    documents implied his perjury during the Whistleblower lawsuit,
    in addition to frequent, previous stories of his corruption in
    office. His public addresses were incorporated into the song
    and was available for download at the radio station's website,
    but now can only be heard at YouTube.</p>
      <p>A sample of this song was also used in the movie 
    <i>House Bunny</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was also used as the 'goodbye' theme on 
    <i>America's Best Dance Crew</i>season 2.</p>
      <p>On March 20, 2009, the episode of 
    <i>The Game</i>is titled "Take a Bow" where Tasha tries to
    prevent Rick (Played by Rick Fox) from losing his job has been
    referred in season 3.</p>
      <p>Lea Michele sang it in the "Showmance" episode of the TV
    series 
    <i>Glee</i>, and it debuted on Billboard's Hot 100 at number 46
    and UK Singles Chart at 36. This version of the song has sold
    over 85,000 copies so far.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
