<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feel_Like_Makin%27_Love_(Roberta_Flack_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feel_Like_Makin%27_Love_(Roberta_Flack_song)</songId>
   <title>Feel Like Makin' Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roberta_Flack</artistId>
      <artistName>Roberta Flack</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-08-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Feel Like Makin' Love</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1974</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:55</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Eugene McDaniels</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Rubina Flake</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Feel Like Makin' Love" is a song composed by
    singer-songwriter Eugene McDaniels, and recorded originally by
    soul singer-songwriter Roberta Flack. The song has been covered
    by several R&amp;B and jazz artists.</p>
      <p>Released from the album of the same title, the song became
    one of the greatest musical successes of 1974, as well as of
    Roberta Flack's recording career. It scored a week as number
    one on the Billboard Hot 100 singles chart, making it Flack's
    third #1 single. It also scored five weeks at number one on the
    Hot Soul Singles chart. and two weeks as #1 on the Adult
    Contemporary chart. Flack produced the record under the
    pseudonym Rubina Flake. It went on to receive three Grammy
    nominations for Flack: Record of the Year, Song of the Year,
    and Best Pop Vocal Performance, Female.</p>
      <p>"Feel Like Makin' Love" was covered by American R&amp;B and
    neo soul musician D'Angelo for his second studio album 
    <i>Voodoo</i>(2000). It was released April 8, 2000 on Virgin
    Records as the album's fifth and last single. His cover version
    features a quiet storm sound and heavy use of multi-tracking
    for vocals. It was initially planned as a duet with R&amp;B
    singer Lauryn Hill. Although tapes were sent via FedEx between
    the two, the collaboration between D'Angelo and Hill was
    aborted and the song was instead recorded solo. According to
    producer and drummer Questlove, the duet failed to materialize
    due to "too many middle men.... I don't think Lauryn and D ever
    talked face-to-face." Mistakenly, some critics who later
    reviewed the album's track assumed that Lauryn Hill's vocals
    are present in the recording.</p>
      <p>According to Questlove's review of 
    <i>Voodoo</i>at Okayplayer, the song's production was also
    managed by late hip hop producer J Dilla, as Questlove stated
    "jay dee did the lauryn track". Dilla, however, did not receive
    an official credit for the song. As a single, "Feel Like Makin'
    Love" was 
    <i>Voodoo</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s least successful,
    as it only reached the number 109 position on the Hot
    R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Singles &amp; Tracks chart.</p>
      <p>It was covered by other artists such as Bob James (as an
    instrumental for his 1974 album "One"), or George Benson (for
    his 1983 album "In Your Eyes"), both under the title 
    <i>Feel Like Making Love</i>.</p>
      <p>Shirley Bassey covered this song on her 1975 album Good, Bad
    but Beautiful</p>
      <p>Roy Ayers covered this song in his 1974 album "Change up the
    groove"</p>
      <p>Lumidee covered this song in her album Unexpected, released
    in 2007.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
