<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Addicted_to_Love_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Addicted_to_Love_(song)</songId>
   <title>Addicted to Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Palmer_(singer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Robert Palmer</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-05-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/49/Addicted_to_Love.jpg/200px-Addicted_to_Love.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Robert-Palmer+Addicted-to-Love.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Riptide</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1986</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1985</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>6:01 (album version)</length>
      <length>4:04 (single version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Island Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Robert Palmer</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bernard Edwards</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Addicted to Love" is a song by Robert Palmer first released
    in 1986. The song has now become known as his signature song,
    thanks in part to a highly popular video featuring high fashion
    models. Other artists have released versions since.</p>
      <p>This is the third song on the 
    <i>Riptide</i>album. The most commonly heard version runs
    around four minutes, but the full album version runs a little
    over six minutes.</p>
      <p>The song topped the Hot 100 chart, as well as spending two
    weeks atop the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Top Rock Tracks chart, and it peaked at #5 on
    the UK Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>Originally intended to be a duet with Chaka Khan, her record
    company at the time wouldn't grant her a release to work on
    Palmer's label, Island Records. Chaka Khan is still credited
    for the vocal arrangements in the album liner notes.</p>
      <p>The guitar part on the song is played by Eddie Martinez,
    then a member of Palmer's band, and keyboards by Wally Badarou.
    The song is also notable for the unaccompanied drum opening,
    which plays at 7/4. The rest of the song is in common 4/4
    time.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by Terence Donovan, in which
    Palmer's backing band is a group of models whose pale skin,
    heavy makeup, dark hair and seductive expression makes them
    resemble the women in Patrick Nagel paintings.</p>
      <p>The models in the video are (from left to right) Patty
    Kelly, Julie Pankhurst, Mak Gilchrist and Julia Bolino with
    Kathy Davies at the back on drums. Mak Gilchrist recalled to 
    <i>Q</i>magazine:</p>
      <p>“I was 21 and got the part on the strength of my modelling
    book. We were meant to look and “act” like showroom mannequins.
    Director Terence Donovan got us tipsy on a bottle of wine but
    as were having our make-up retouched, I lost balance on my
    heels and knocked the top of my guitar into the back of
    Robert’s head, and his face then hit the microphone."</p>
      <p>Palmer recycled the video's "iconic models" concept for the
    videos of three other songs of his : "I Didn't Mean to
    Turn You On" (also from 
    <i>Riptide</i>), "Simply Irresistible" and the animated "Change
    His Ways" (both from 
    <i>Heavy Nova</i>).</p>
      <p>VH1's 
    <i>Pop-Up Video</i>trivia about the video include the fact that
    a musician was hired to teach the models basic guitar fingering
    techniques, but "gave up after about an hour and left". The
    episode also pointed out several choreographical errors,
    including the models moving out of sync with one another, and
    moving during points with no backbeat, such as the second
    chorus.</p>
      <p>The music video ranked at number 3 on VH1's Top 20 Videos of
    the 1980s and was both the first and last video shown on long
    running UK music programme 
    <i>The Chart Show</i>.</p>
      <p>Tina Turner has made "Addicted to Love" a regular feature of
    her live shows since 1986.</p>
      <p>A live recording from the 1986/1987 
    <i>Break Every Rule Tour</i>of the track was included on her 
    <i>Tina: Live in Europe</i>album in 1988, and was also issued
    as the lead single to promote the album in certain territories
    - instead of "Nutbush City Limits" - and was a Top 20 hit in
    the Netherlands.</p>
      <p>The two singles had the same B-sides; live recordings of
    "Overnight Sensation" and ZZ Top's "Legs" and near identical
    picture sleeves. The version of "Addicted to Love" issued on
    the single was in fact an alternate mix of the track, the
    single mix was later included on the European editions of her
    1991 greatest hits album 
    <i>Simply the Best</i>as well as 
    <i>All the Best</i>in 2004 and 
    <i>Tina!: Her Greatest Hits</i>in 2008.</p>
      <p>Song parodies include:</p>
      <p>Film parodies include:</p>
      <p>The video has either influenced or been parodied by other
    music videos including:</p>
      <p>The Video Models</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
