<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Da_Ya_Think_I%27m_Sexy%3F 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Da_Ya_Think_I%27m_Sexy%3F</songId>
   <title>Da Ya Think I'm Sexy?</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rod_Stewart</artistId>
      <artistName>Rod Stewart</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1979-02-10</week>
      <week>1979-02-17</week>
      <week>1979-02-24</week>
      <week>1979-03-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/0e/Da%27_Ya%27_Think_I%27m_Sexy_single_cover.jpg/200px-Da%27_Ya%27_Think_I%27m_Sexy_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Rod-Stewart+Da-Ya-Think-I-m-Sexy.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Blondes Have More Fun and Greatest Hits, Vol. 1</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 1978</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1978</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:28</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Warner Bros.</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Rod Stewart</writer>
      <writer>Carmine Appice</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Tom Dowd</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Da Ya Think I'm Sexy?" is a 1978 hit song for Rod Stewart.
    It was written by Stewart and Carmine Appice, and produced by
    Tom Dowd.</p>
      <p>"Da Ya Think I'm Sexy?" spent one week at the top of the
    British charts in December 1978 and four weeks at the top of
    the Billboard Hot 100, starting February 10, 1979.</p>
      <p>The song was criticized by many in the rock press as a
    betrayal of Stewart's blues-oriented rock roots due to its
    disco-like arrangement, but Stewart and others were quick to
    point out that other widely respected artists, such as Paul
    McCartney and The Rolling Stones, had also released
    disco-flavoured songs.</p>
      <p>Carmine Appice,who played drums on this song told Songfacts:
    "This was a story of a guy meeting a chick in a club. At that
    time, that was a cool saying. If you listen to the lyrics, 'She
    sits alone, waiting for suggestions, he's so nervous...' it's
    the feelings of what was going on in a dance club. The guy sees
    a chick he digs, she's nervous and he's nervous and she's alone
    and doesn't know what's going on, then they end up at his place
    having sex, and then she's gone."</p>
      <p>In 2004 Rolling Stone ranked the song #301 on their list of
    The 500 Greatest Songs of All Time.</p>
      <p>A 12" disco single of the song was released in 1978. The
    song was remixed by disco producer Jim Burgess. It ran one
    minute longer than the lp version at 6:29 and contained two
    alternate recorded lines and a heavier bass enthused drum
    beat.</p>
      <p>A judgment in a plagiarism lawsuit by Brazilian musician
    Jorge Ben Jor ruled that the song had been derived from his
    composition "Taj Mahal". Stewart agreed to donate all his
    royalties from the song to United Nations Children's Fund.</p>
      <p>"Taj Mahal" is recognisable (and was legally recognised in a
    plagiarism lawsuit) as the source of the melody in Rod
    Stewart's hit "Da Ya Think I'm Sexy?". "Taj Mahal" originally
    appeared on 1972's "Ben" album, becoming a big hit on the
    charts in Brazil that year.</p>
      <p>Stewart performed the song at the Music for UNICEF Concert
    at the United Nations General Assembly in 1979. The song also
    lifts a musical refrain from Bobby Womack's 1975 song, "(If You
    Want My Love) Put Something Down On It".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
