<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maggie_May 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maggie_May</songId>
   <title>Maggie May" / "Reason to Believe</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rod_Stewart</artistId>
      <artistName>Rod Stewart</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1971-10-02</week>
      <week>1971-10-09</week>
      <week>1971-10-16</week>
      <week>1971-10-23</week>
      <week>1971-10-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/3d/Maggiereason.jpg/200px-Maggiereason.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Rod-Stewart+Maggie-May-Reason-to-Believe.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Every Picture Tells a Story</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1971</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Folk Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:15</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Mercury</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Rod Stewart and Martin Quittenton</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Maggie May" is a song written by singer Rod Stewart and
    Martin Quittenton and recorded by Stewart in 1971 for his album
    
    <i>Every Picture Tells a Story</i>.</p>
      <p>"Maggie May" expresses the ambivalence and contradictory
    emotions of a young man involved in a relationship with an
    older woman, and was written from Stewart's own experience. In
    the January, 2007 issue of 
    <i>Q</i>magazine, Stewart recalled: "Maggie May was more or
    less a true story, about the first woman I had sex with, at the
    Beaulieu Jazz Festival." The reference to returning to school
    in "late September" refers to the Michaelmas term, the first
    academic term of the academic year of many British and Irish
    universities.</p>
      <p>It was initially released in the United Kingdom as the
    B-side of the single "Reason to Believe," but DJs became fonder
    of the B-side and, after two weeks on the charts, the song was
    reclassified, with "Maggie May" becoming the A-side. However,
    the single continued to be pressed with "Maggie May" as the
    B-side.</p>
      <p>In October 1971, the song went to number one in the UK and
    simultaneously topped the charts in the United States. 
    <i>Every Picture Tells a Story</i>achieved the same status at
    the same time, a feat achieved by only a handful of performers,
    most notably The Beatles and Simon and Garfunkel.</p>
      <p>The song was Stewart's first substantial hit as a solo
    performer and launched his solo career. It remains one of his
    best-known songs. A famous live performance of the song on 
    <i>Top of the Pops</i>saw The Faces joined onstage by DJ John
    Peel, who pretended to play the mandolin (the mandolin player
    on the recording was Ray Jackson of Lindisfarne). Stewart
    himself was amused by the song's success, saying, "I still
    can't see how the single is such a big hit. It has no melody.
    Plenty of character and nice chords, but no melody."</p>
      <p>The song re-entered the UK charts in December 1976, but only
    reached number 31.</p>
      <p>Oddly, in the days of Top-40 Hit Radio, when songs were
    released for airplay and to the public on 45RPM singles,
    "Maggie May" was not edited in any way or fashion. The full
    5:15 version was pressed to single, even though its multiple
    refrains &amp; 5-bar mandolin solo could have been easily taken
    to edit. Perhaps it was because "Maggie May" was initially only
    meant to be a B-side single, and many B-sides are left intact
    without editing.</p>
      <p>In 2004, 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>ranked the song #130 on their list of The
    500 Greatest Songs of All Time.</p>
      <p>No other act has released the song as a single. The
    guitar-solo picking halfway through the song, though, was
    lifted by Deva, a film composer from South India, for the film 
    <i>Aasai</i>.</p>
      <p>Edwin McCain, Blur, Wet Wet Wet, and Ben Mills have recorded
    versions of "Maggie May"; Melissa Etheridge, The Pogues, The
    Dirty Three and Counting Crows have performed it in concert.
    The Spanish rock band M-Clan recorded a translated version of
    the song, called 
    <i>Maggie despierta</i>, on their 
    <i>Sin enchufe</i>(Unplugged) album. The Argentine skate punk
    band Massacre recorded version of the song on 
    <i>El Mamut</i>album 2008.</p>
      <p>Popular 70's band Top of the Poppers covered the song on its
    Top of the Pops, Volume 20 album, which reached No. 1 on the UK
    album charts in 1971.</p>
      <p>Canadian pianist and singer Burton Cummings has recorded a
    humorous variant on the song, titled "Gordon Lightfoot does
    Maggie May".</p>
      <p>The song is covered by Matthew Sweet &amp; Susanna Hoffs on
    their album "Under the Covers, Vol. 2"</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
