<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Car_Wash_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Car_Wash_(song)</songId>
   <title>Car Wash</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rose_Royce</artistId>
      <artistName>Rose Royce</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1977-01-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/b6/RoseRoyceCarWash.jpg/200px-RoseRoyceCarWash.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Rose-Royce+Car-Wash.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Car Wash: Original Motion Picture Soundtrack</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1976</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:20 (LP mix is 5:06)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MCA , 110 076</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Norman Whitfield</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Norman Whitfield</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Car Wash" is a 1976 number-one popular and soul music
    single album by Rose Royce for MCA Records, the group's debut
    single album and one of the most notable successes of the disco
    era. Written and produced by the band's main producer Norman
    Whitfield, "Car Wash", the theme of the 1976 film 
    <i>Car Wash</i>, was Rose Royce's most successful hit single.
    "Car Wash" also peaked at number three on the disco charts. The
    song was later covered in 2004 by Christina Aguilera and Missy
    Elliott, who released their version as the single for the 
    <i>Shark Tale</i>soundtrack.</p>
      <p>Norman Whitfield, a former producer for Motown Records, had
    been commissioned to record the soundtrack album for 
    <i>Car Wash</i>by director Michael Schultz. Although Whitfield
    did not want to assume the project, he did so because of both
    financial incentives and the chance to give Rose Royce, a
    disco/funk backing band who Whitfield signed to his own label
    in 1975, to get the exposure they needed to become mainstream.
    Unable to develop a theme song for the film, inspiration
    finally struck Whitfield while playing a game of basketball,
    and he allegedly wrote his first draft of "Car Wash" on a paper
    bag from a fried chicken eatery.</p>
      <p>The resulting song set the mood and tone for the
    blaxploitation comedy film it was commissioned for. Rose Royce
    lead singer Rose Norwalt(Gwen Dickey), with brief assistance
    from guitarist Kenji Brown, describes a fun and easy-going car
    washing business, where everything is "always cool/and the boss
    don't mind sometimes if you act a fool."</p>
      <p>
         <i>Car Wash's</i>soundtrack, a double album, was Rose Royce's
    debut LP, and the title track was their debut single. "Car
    Wash" sold two million copies, and was a number one success on
    both the Billboard popular and R&amp;B charts in the United
    States and a top ten success in the United Kingdom. The song
    held the number-one spot on the Billboard Hot 100 for one week,
    from January 22, 1977 to January 29, replacing "I Wish" by
    Stevie Wonder, and replaced by "Torn Between Two Lovers" by
    Mary MacGregor. The 
    <i>Car Wash</i>soundtrack album, entirely recorded by Rose
    Royce and Whitfield, spawned two more successful singles: "I
    Wanna Get Next to You" and "I'm Going Down" (later covered in
    1994 by Mary J. Blige).</p>
      <p>The original Rose Royce version of "Car Wash" is one of the
    most sampled songs in history, not for its main
    instrumentation, but for its introductory section. The song
    opens with a series of hand claps, which have been sampled many
    times for both hip hop and R&amp;B songs from the 1980s on. It
    was also re-released as a double A-side single with "Is It Love
    You're After?" in 1988 in the UK, peaking at #20.</p>
      <p>In 2004, pop singer Christina Aguilera and rapper/singer
    Missy Elliott recorded a cover version of "Car Wash", giving
    the disco song a more modern pop feel and adding rapped verses
    from Elliott. In an interview Aguilera said, "...we had to
    change the key to be a little bit higher for my range. So we
    couldn't take the exact samples, but we brought in all these
    live instruments to recreate kind of this old, old classic,
    soulful feel and sound...."</p>
      <p>"Car Wash" was the only single from the soundtrack to
    DreamWorks' computer animated film 
    <i>Shark Tale</i>. Their version was supported with a music
    video, featuring Aguilera and Elliott as animated fish similar
    to those in the film. Aguilera and Elliott's cover of "Car
    Wash" missed the U.S. Billboard Top 40, peaking at number
    sixty-three, while becoming a top five hit in the United
    Kingdom and became the 48th best selling single in the United
    Kingdom of 2004 with sales of over 100,000 copies, despite only
    being released in late November.</p>
      <p>In this context, the "car wash" the song refers to would be
    the place where Oscar (the main protagonist, voiced by Will
    Smith) works, where large sea animals who behave like cars are
    washed in the same manner.</p>
      <p>The music video to Christina's version was directed by Rich
    Newey.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
