<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Come_on-a_My_House 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Come_on-a_My_House</songId>
   <title>Come on-a My House</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rosemary_Clooney</artistId>
      <artistName>Rosemary Clooney</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1951-07-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/54/Come_on-a_My_House.jpg/200px-Come_on-a_My_House.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Rosemary-Clooney+Come-on-a-My-House.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Come On-A My House</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 6, 1951  (1951-06-06)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>78 rpm Vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1951</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Traditional Pop</genre>
      <genre>Vocal Jazz</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:02</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ross Bagdasarian</writer>
      <writer>William Saroyan</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Come on-a My House" is a song by Rosemary Clooney from her
    album 
    <i>Come On-A My House</i>, released on June 6, 1951. The song
    was written by Ross Bagdasarian and William Saroyan in summer
    of 1939 but did not become a hit until its release by Clooney.
    It was probably Saroyan's only effort at popular songwriting,
    and it was one of Bagdasarian's few well-known works that was
    not connected to his most famous creation, Alvin and the
    Chipmunks. In 2009, the song was heard as a commercial jingle
    for Macy's department stores.</p>
      <p>The song (written by two Armenian Americans) touches upon
    traditional Armenian customs of inviting over relatives and
    friends and providing them with a generously overflowing table
    of fruits, nuts, seeds, and other foods.</p>
      <p>The song was a major hit for Clooney in 1951; it was the
    first of a number of dialect songs she did. She recorded the
    song with Mitch Miller and his orchestra and harpsichordist
    Stan Freeman in the early part of 1951, and the song reached #1
    on the charts, staying in the top position for eight weeks.</p>
      <p>Although she performed "Come on-a My House" for many years,
    Clooney later confessed that she hated the song. She said she
    had been given a practice record of the song and told Miller
    that the song wasn't for her. Miller gave her an ultimatum -
    record the song or be fired. During a 1988 interview, Clooney
    said that whenever she listens to the recording she could hear
    the anger in her voice for being forced to sing it. Little did
    she know that the song would become one of her biggest
    hits.</p>
      <p>The song was covered by Ella Fitzgerald, as one side of a
    single whose other side was also a cover of a Clooney hit,
    "Mixed Emotions," on Decca Records (catalog number 27875).</p>
      <p>The song was later performed by Kay Starr, who added a few
    lines with funny, nearly surrealistic details and ended the
    song with an even more explicit offer. In 1952, Japanese singer
    Chiemi Eri covered the Kay Starr version. Della Reese also
    recorded the song, and it is her version that Madonna mimes to
    in the remake of 
    <i>Swept Away</i>. It was later used as the theme for the
    reality television series 
    <i>The Girls Next Door</i>, performed by the Nasty Tales and
    their orchestra. The Surf Punks remade the song in the late
    1980s. The composers performed the song themselves (Bagdasarian
    singing, Saroyan offering occasional narration) for Coral
    Records. It is sung briefly by Miss Miller (voiced by Dody
    Goodman) in the 1987 animated movie 
    <i>The Chipmunk Adventure</i>.</p>
      <p>Ross Bagdasarian performs the song on his album 
    <i>The Mixed-Up World of Ross Bagdasarian</i>and Alvin and the
    Chipmunks also sang this for their Thanksgiving episode- "A
    Chipmunk Celebration".</p>
      <p>In late 1951 MGM Records released a novelty response song,
    "Where's-a Your House?", which charted on the Cash Box Hot 50
    list. Sung by Robert Q. Lewis in dialect, the tune details the
    singer's frustrated attempts to follow up "Rosie's"
    invitation.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
