<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/This_Ole_House 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/This_Ole_House</songId>
   <title>This Ole House</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rosemary_Clooney</artistId>
      <artistName>Rosemary Clooney</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1954-11-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"This Ole House" (sometimes written "This Old House") is a
    popular song written by Stuart Hamblen, and published in
    1954.</p>
      <p>Hamblen was supposedly out on a hunting expedition when he
    and his fellow hunter, actor John Wayne, came across a
    tumbledown hut in the mountains, many miles from civilization.
    They went into the hut and there, lying amongst the rubbish and
    rubble of a crumbling building, was the body of a dead man.
    This inspired Hamblin to write "This Ole House", which Rosemary
    Clooney and later Shakin' Stevens, treated as a bouncy novelty
    number, rather than the epitaph for a mountain man that it was
    meant to be.</p>
      <p>The recorded version of "This Ole House" by Rosemary
    Clooney, featuring bass vocals by Thurl Ravenscroft, reached #1
    on the Billboard chart in 1954, as the flip side to her
    previous #1 song, "Hey There". Clooney's version also topped
    the UK Singles Chart, although there were other UK hit versions
    around by Billie Anthony, and Alma Cogan, both recorded in
    1954. The recording by Cogan was released by HMV as catalogue
    number 7M 269. The flip side was "Skokiaan".</p>
      <p>In March 1981, Shakin' Stevens took the song back to number
    one for three weeks in the United Kingdom. His version was
    re-released in 2005, after his appearance in the TV show 
    <i>Hit Me Baby One More Time</i>, and reached number 20 in the
    UK chart.</p>
      <p>The song was also covered by the Cathedral Quartet and Hovie
    Lister and the Statesmen as a Southern Gospel song with
    slightly modified lyrics, using the house as an analogy for an
    old body about to die and the soul about to go to heaven,
    usually tying the song in with "When the Saints Go Marching
    In".</p>
      <p>The song was most recently recorded by Bette Midler (in
    ballad form) on her 2003 tribute to Rosemary Clooney, "Bette
    Midler Sings the Rosemary Clooney Songbook", and included on
    her compilation "Jackpot: The Best Bette" in 2008.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
