<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It_Must_Have_Been_Love 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It_Must_Have_Been_Love</songId>
   <title>It Must Have Been Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roxette</artistId>
      <artistName>Roxette</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1990-06-16</week>
      <week>1990-06-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1987 , May 1, 1990 , September 1, 1993 (U.K. only)</released>
   <recorded>1987, , 1990 sections re-recorded</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:18</length>
   </lengths>
   <writers>
      <writer>Per Gessle</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"It Must Have Been Love" is a power ballad written by Per
    Gessle and performed by the Swedish pop duo Roxette. The ballad
    became the duo's 3rd #1 hit in the United States, and is one of
    their best-selling releases, leading the single to be certified
    gold in a number of countries.</p>
      <p>The song, included on the soundtrack to the hugely popular
    film 
    <i>Pretty Woman</i>, rivals "The Look", "Joyride" and "Listen
    to Your Heart" as the song most closely associated with them.
    In 2005, Per Gessle received an award from BMI after the song's
    four millionth radio play.</p>
      <p>"Christmas for the Broken Hearted", the song's original
    title, was first released in 1987 after EMI Germany asked
    Roxette to come up with an intelligent Christmas-single. It
    went on to become a Top 10 hit in Sweden but EMI Germany
    decided not to the release the track.</p>
      <p>This version of the song was not part of any Roxette album
    until the 1997 re-release of 
    <i>Pearls of Passion</i>, where it was included as a bonus
    track. The B-side to "Christmas for the Broken Hearted", "Turn
    to Me", also featured as a bonus track.</p>
      <p>During the run of chart-topping singles from 
    <i>Look Sharp!</i>Touchstone Pictures approached Roxette's
    record label, EMI, and the group about contributing a song to
    the soundtrack of the upcoming romantic comedy release 
    <i>Pretty Woman</i>, starring Richard Gere and Oscar nominee
    Julia Roberts. 
    <i>Pretty Woman</i>was released in March 1990 and went on to
    make more than $460 million worldwide.</p>
      <p>Gessle has claimed that "It Must Have Been Love", by then a
    two-year-old recording, was chosen because Roxette did not have
    time to compose and record a new song while touring Australia
    and New Zealand. Gessle and producer Clarence Öfwerman took the
    original 1987 recording, had Marie Fredriksson replace a single
    Christmas-referenced line in the song and added some
    instrumentation and background vocal overlays to enhance the
    sound. Gessle claimed the soundtrack producers initially turned
    down "It Must Have Been Love" but changed their minds after
    re-editing the film.</p>
      <p>Although "It Must Have Been Love" was part of the 
    <i>Pretty Woman</i>soundtrack, the song wasn't part of a
    Roxette album until 
    <i>Don't Bore Us, Get to the Chorus!</i>, their 1995 greatest
    hits release. The album wasn't released in the United States
    until September 26, 2000, with a different track listing.</p>
      <p>Though the lyrics refer to a lonely winter's day after the
    break-up of a relationship, "It Must Have Been Love" became an
    international hit in the summer of 1990. It was not the first
    single released from the 
    <i>Pretty Woman</i>soundtrack but "It Must Have Been Love"
    became the most successful, spending its first of two weeks at
    #1 on the Hot 100 in June and onto sales of 500,000 copies in
    the U.S. Billboard magazine listed "It Must Have Been Love" as
    the #2 Hot 100 single of the year behind Wilson Phillips' "Hold
    On". The single was released in the UK in June 1990 and peaked
    at #3, Roxette's best showing there, and stayed in the UK
    Singles Chart for 14 weeks. The song was re-released in
    September 1993 and peaked at #10. It was due to the success of
    this song that "Listen to Your Heart" and "Dressed for Success"
    were re-issued in the UK later that year. It later became
    Roxette's second of three #1 singles in Australia, spending two
    weeks at the top spot in July 1990, while it also peaked at #1
    in Norway, for 12 weeks, and in Switzerland. It also reached
    the Top 5 in Sweden, Austria and Germany, where the single
    spent 9 months in the Top 75, while it reached the Top 20 in
    Italy.</p>
      <p>In the CD liner notes for 
    <i>Don't Bore Us, Get to the Chorus!</i>, Fredriksson remarked,
    "Our third #1 in the U.S. ...not bad for a song that was lying
    around, gathering dust." The soundtrack went on to be certified
    three times platinum by the RIAA, with total Worldwide sales of
    nine million. While the song went onto receive gold
    certification in the Austria, Germany, United States, Sweden
    and New Zealand.</p>
      <p>The video was shot in a big bedroom, with Fredriksson
    singing and Gessle playing the guitar. It included scenes from
    the 
    <i>Pretty Woman</i>movie. There is also an original version of
    the video without the movie scenes. Original video is only
    available on the VHS titled The Videos. According to
    Fredriksson shooting the video was a surreal experience.</p>
      <p>... the video was a weird experience. The director wanted
    all movements in slow motion so I had to lip sync the vocals in
    double speed. My first lesson in how to sing an emotional
    ballad Mickey Mouse style. A strange way to make a living.</p>
      <p>-Marie Fredriksson</p>
      <p>A revised version of the song was recorded in a Los Angeles
    studio during Roxette's 1991 worldwide tour in support of the
    album 
    <i>Joyride</i>. This slower country music-esque version,
    featuring a steel guitar solo in place of the original's piano,
    was included in the 1992 album release from that tour, 
    <i>Tourism: Songs from Studios, Stages, Hotelrooms &amp; Other
    Strange Places</i>. On the 1996 album 
    <i>Baladas En Español</i>, Roxette recorded the song in
    Spanish; "No sé si es amor" ("I don't know if it's love"),
    reaching #6 in Spain.</p>
      <p>A re-issue of the 1990 version of the song entered the UK
    Top 10 in September 1993 after 
    <i>Pretty Woman</i>was first shown on UK terrestrial TV.</p>
      <p>In 2006, the Swedish pop singer Shirley Clamp recorded a
    Swedish language cover version of "It Must Have Been Love"
    called "När kärleken föds" ("When Love is Born") that was
    released as a single in April of that year and peaked at #6 at
    the Swedish singles chart. On 11 June 2006, "När kärleken föds"
    entered eighth place on Svensktoppen. "När kärleken föds" had
    no words related to Christmas or other seasons or holidays.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
