<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Look 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Look</songId>
   <title>The Look</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roxette</artistId>
      <artistName>Roxette</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1989-04-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/20/TheLook.jpg/200px-TheLook.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Roxette+The-Look.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Look Sharp!</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 12, 1989</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" maxi</format>
      <format>CD maxi</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1988</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:56</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>EMI</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Per Gessle</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Clarence Öfwerman</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Look", written by Per Gessle and performed by Roxette,
    was released as a single in early 1989 from the album 
    <i>Look Sharp!</i>. The song became Roxette's international
    "breakthrough" song, finally exposing the duo to music
    consumers outside of the duo's native Sweden and Europe after
    more than one attempt. It topped the U.S. singles chart in 1989
    becoming their first U.S. #1 success and scored #7 on the UK
    Singles Chart. The song also topped the charts in 24 other
    countries.</p>
      <p>While still unknown outside of Sweden, Roxette released
    their second album With the success of the first two singles
    from the album, they toured Sweden again. When "The Look" was
    about to be released in Sweden as the third single, an American
    exchange student named Dean Cushman returned from Sweden and
    urged radio station, KDWB in Minneapolis, to play "The Look".
    From there, "The Look" spread on cassette copies to other radio
    stations. With the song's radio success, EMI quickly released
    "The Look" Suddenly, Roxette had a #1 scoring single in the
    United States, and the record wasn't even released. When 
    <i>Look Sharp!</i>was finally released, it was able to debut on
    the U.S. album charts at #50, an unusual feat at the time for a
    newcomer artist, and later scored #23, eventually staying in
    the charts for 71 weeks.</p>
      <p>According to Gessle the first two verses lyrics were guide
    lyrics but were kept anyway.</p>
      <p>"Walking like a man, hitting like a hammer"... the first two
    verses are guide lyrics, words just scribbled down to have
    something to sing. Couldn't come up with anything better, so we
    kept them. Everybody gets lucky sometimes...</p>
      <p>Per Gessle</p>
      <p>All formats were released on 12 January 1989, (by
    EMI/Parlophone; 1363337). Also released on many formats,
    including 3" CD, 5" CD, and 12" vinyl. Included on most of
    those was The Look (Head-Drum Mix). The first edition of the
    vinyls was in red vinyl. A few exist in clear vinyl.</p>
      <p>"The Look '95" is a remixed version of Roxette's hit song
    and it was only released commercially in the UK in connection
    with the release of their greatest hits album 
    <i>Don't Bore Us, Get to the Chorus! - Roxette's Greatest
    Hits</i>.</p>
      <p>This version of the song does not appear on the album, but
    two of the versions from this single were eventually included
    on the European release of the single "She Doesn't Live Here
    Anymore".</p>
      <p>In 2009, "The Look" was used in a trailer and TV commercial
    for the game Grand Theft Auto: Episodes From Liberty City. Also
    it can heard on ingame radio station Vice City FM.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
