<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oh,_Pretty_Woman 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oh,_Pretty_Woman</songId>
   <title>Oh, Pretty Woman</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roy_Orbison</artistId>
      <artistName>Roy Orbison</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1964-09-26</week>
      <week>1964-10-03</week>
      <week>1964-10-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>August 1964</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Monument 851</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Roy Orbison</writer>
      <writer>Bill Dees</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Oh, Pretty Woman" is a song, released in 1964, which was a
    worldwide success for Roy Orbison. Recorded on the Monument
    Records label in Nashville, Tennessee, it was written by Roy
    Orbison and Bill Dees. The song spent three weeks at number one
    on the Hot 100. The best-known guitar performance was by Wayne
    Moss later of Barefoot Jerry. Although the official recording
    appeared in 1964, the Beatles recalled Orbison's having written
    and performed the song during a mid-1963 tour of the UK which
    included both acts.</p>
      <p>Orbison posthumously won the 1991 Grammy Award for Best Male
    Pop Vocal Performance for his live recording of the song on his
    HBO television special 
    <i>Roy Orbison and Friends, A Black and White Night</i>. In
    1999, the song was honored with a Grammy Hall of Fame Award and
    was named one of the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame's 500 Songs
    that Shaped Rock and Roll. In 2004, 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine ranked it #222 on their list of
    the "500 Greatest Songs of All Time."</p>
      <p>The lyrics tells the story of a man who sees a pretty woman
    walking by. He yearns for her and wonders if, as beautiful as
    she is, she might be lonely like he is. At the last minute, she
    turns back and joins him.</p>
      <p>The title was inspired by Orbison's wife Claudette
    interrupting a conversation to announce she was going out; when
    Orbison asked if she was okay for cash, his co-writer Bill Dees
    interjected "A pretty woman never needs any money."</p>
      <p>In 1989, the controversial rap group 2 Live Crew recorded a
    parody of the Orbison song, using the alternate title "Pretty
    Woman" for their album 
    <i>Clean As They Wanna Be</i>. The 2 Live Crew sampled the
    distinctive bassline from the Orbison song, but the romantic
    lyrics were replaced by talk about a hairy woman and her
    bald-headed friend and their appeal to the singer, as well as
    denunciation of a "two-timing woman."</p>
      <p>Orbison's publisher, Acuff-Rose Music sued 2 Live Crew on
    the basis that the fair use doctrine did not permit reuse of
    their copyrighted material for profit. The case, 
    <i>Campbell v. Acuff-Rose Music, Inc.</i>went all the way to
    the United States Supreme Court. The Supreme Court decided in 2
    Live Crew's favor, greatly expanding the doctrine of fair use
    and extending its protections to parodies created for profit.
    It is considered a seminal fair use decision.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by a number of artists:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
