<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Escape_(Rupert_Holmes_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Escape_(Rupert_Holmes_song)</songId>
   <title>Escape (The Piña Colada Song)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rupert_Holmes</artistId>
      <artistName>Rupert Holmes</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1979-12-22</week>
      <week>1979-12-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/21/Rupert_Holmes_Pina.jpg/200px-Rupert_Holmes_Pina.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Rupert-Holmes+Escape-The-Pina-Colada-Song.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Partners in Crime</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1979</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1979</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:34</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Infinity / Geffen</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Rupert Holmes</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Rupert Holmes</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Escape", later known as "Escape (The Piña Colada Song)",
    was the highest-charting hit for Rupert Holmes, released off
    his album 
    <i>Partners in Crime</i>. The song was also number one at the
    end of the 1970s and at the beginning of the 1980s. To this
    day, Holmes regards the song with a mixture of pride and
    chagrin; while it has made him wealthy and famous, as one of
    his friends described it, it is "the success that ruined his
    career", drawing too much attention from his more serious
    musical works.</p>
      <p>The song speaks, in three verses and three choruses, of a
    man who, disenchanted with his current relationship, reads the
    personals and spots an ad that catches his attention: the ad of
    a woman who is seeking a man who, among other things, must like
    piña coladas. Intrigued, he writes back and arranges to meet
    with the woman "at a bar called O'Malley's", only to find upon
    the meeting that his 
    <i>new</i>lover is his 
    <i>current</i>lover. The song ends on an upbeat note, showing
    that the two lovers realized they have more in common than they
    suspected, and that they do not have to look any further than
    each other for what they seek in a relationship.</p>
      <p>Contrary to urban legend, the inspiration for "Escape" did
    not come from a similar event happening to Holmes. Recorded for
    1979's 
    <i>Partners in Crime</i>, the song came from an unused track
    for which Holmes wrote temporary lyrics (that version, "The Law
    of The Jungle", was released as part of his 2005 
    <i>Cast of Characters</i>box set), and the lyrics were inspired
    by a want-ad he read while idly perusing the personals. As
    Holmes put it, "I thought, 
    <i>what would happen to me if I answered this ad?</i>I'd go and
    see if it was my own wife who was bored with me." The chorus
    originally started with "if you like Humphrey Bogart", which
    Holmes changed at the last minute, replacing the actor with the
    name of the first exotic cocktail he could think of.
    Ironically, he does not care for the drink; he once opined on
    the 
    <i>Uncle Floyd Show</i>that they tasted like Kaopectate.</p>
      <p>After its release as a single, the song became immediately
    popular, though initial sales were slow due to the song's
    actual title, "Escape" going unnoticed in the place of the
    oft-repeated cocktail. Holmes reluctantly agreed to rename the
    song "Escape (The Piña Colada Song)". The song shot up through
    the charts, becoming the last number-one Billboard Hot 100 hit
    of the 1970s. Although some sources list this song as the first
    number-one hit of the 1980s, this is not true; the first chart
    of that decade, dated on January 5, 1980, was topped by "Please
    Don't Go" by KC and the Sunshine Band. "Escape", which was #2
    that week, returned to #1 for an additional week on the January
    12 chart, thus having the distinction of being the only single
    to rise to the #1 position in different decades.</p>
      <p>"Escape" has made appearances in such movies as 
    <i>Shrek</i>, 
    <i>Bewitched</i>, 
    <i>Dirty Work</i>, 
    <i>The Sweetest Thing</i>, 
    <i>Detroit Rock City</i>, 
    <i>Tommy Boy</i>, 
    <i>American Splendor</i>, 
    <i>Mars Attacks!</i>, and 
    <i>Wanted</i>.</p>
      <p>Also on 
    <i>Mystery Science Theater 3000</i>, during one of the host
    segments of Show #421 (
    <i>Monster A Go-Go</i>), Joel Robinson and the robots discuss
    the deeper meaning surrounding the song and critique the
    couple: "They don't even know each other likes piña coladas?!
    What, would they always panic and order Manhattans or
    something?"</p>
      <p>The song was also the basis of a major episode storyline for
    the popular Australian television series 
    <i>Kath and Kim</i>.</p>
      <p>"Escape" was also heard playing on the radio during an
    episode of 
    <i>The Shield</i>, when the Strike Team are sitting in a car.
    It has also been used in advertising jingles on Cape Cod,
    typically using only the 
    <i>In the dunes on the Cape</i>line.</p>
      <p>"Escape" was also referenced in the song "this party sucks"
    by the pop punk band The Wonder Years (band)</p>
      <p>While Holmes has since had a successful career as a
    playwright and novelist, and fans feel affection for his other
    musical works, this song remains his most recognizable
    trademark. Holmes himself joked, "No matter what else I do, my
    tombstone will be a giant pineapple."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
