<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sleep_Walk_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sleep_Walk_(song)</songId>
   <title>Sleep Walk</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Santo_%26_Johnny</artistId>
      <artistName>Santo &amp; Johnny</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1959-09-21</week>
      <week>1959-09-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a1/Sleep_Walk.jpg/220px-Sleep_Walk.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Santo-Johnny+Sleep-Walk.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Santo &amp; Johnny</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1959</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Instrumental Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Canadian-American Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Santo Farina and Johnny Farina</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Santo &amp; Johnny</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Sleep Walk" is an instrumental steel guitar-based song
    recorded and released in 1959 by brothers Santo &amp; Johnny.
    The song was composed by Santo and Johnny Farina as well. (The
    original single credits three Farinas, including an "Ann
    Farina" for the composition. It is sometimes reported that
    their mother or sister helped, but this is apparently false.)
    It was recorded at Trinity Music in Manhattan. "Sleep Walk"
    entered 's Top 40 on August 17, 1959. It rose to the number-one
    position for two weeks in September (the 21st and the 28th) and
    remained in the Top 40 until November 9. "Sleep Walk" also
    reached number four on the R&amp;B chart and was the last
    instrumental to hit number one in the 1950s and earned Santo
    &amp; Johnny a gold record.</p>
      <p>One of the first covers was by Betsy Brye (stage name of
    Bette Anne Steele) in 1959. While Santo &amp; Johnny wrote
    lyrics for "Sleep Walk", they never recorded a lyrical version,
    but Betsy Brye's version included these lyrics.</p>
      <p>It has been also covered by Brian Setzer Orchestra, Al
    Kooper doing the guitar part on synthesizer, Paul Mauriat, The
    Shadows, The Ventures, Jake Shimabukuro, Larry Carlton,
    Deftones, Leo Kottke, Hapa, Chet Atkins, Danny Gatton, B. J.
    Cole, Micah P. Hinson, Amos Garrett, Steve Howe ("Quantum
    guitar" rec. 1996, Henri Rene, Jonathan Richman, Jeff Beck, Joe
    Satriani,</p>
      <p>Brian Setzer's recording received a Grammy Award for Best
    Pop Instrumental Performance of 1998.</p>
      <p>In America, Country Music Hall of Famer Jimmy Russell
    recorded his version of Sleepwalk in 2001.</p>
      <p>In Europe, French award-winning guitarist Jean-Pierre Danel
    had a Top 20 hit with his instrumental version of the song
    recorded in 2006.</p>
      <p>Modest Mouse, My Morning Jacket, The Raveonettes have all
    recorded adaptions of the song with lyrics.</p>
      <p>"Sleep Walk" has remained popular due to consistent radio
    airplay as well as its usage in commercials, television shows,
    and movies.</p>
      <p>The song appears prominently at the end of the 1987 film, 
    <i>La Bamba</i>, during Ritchie Valens' funeral and the
    subsequent scene of his brother, Bob, screaming Ritchie's name
    to the heavens. The song also appears at the beginning of the
    film in the initial dream sequence up to the point where the
    two planes collide over the playground. It is probably due to
    its usage in this film that some people associate the song with
    Valens, who died some months before it was written.</p>
      <p>The song was used in the 1992 Stephen King film, 
    <i>Sleepwalkers</i>. In the 1995 film, 
    <i>Twelve Monkeys</i>, the song plays over the car radio during
    a scene in which psychiatrist, Dr. Kathryn Railly, has been
    abducted by time traveler and mentally divergent, James Cole.
    The song was also used in Stacy Peralta's 2004 surf
    documentary, 
    <i>Riding Giants</i>.</p>
      <p>Recently, the song was played in the movie 
    <i>Charlie's Angels: Full Throttle</i>and in the television
    series 
    <i>Heroes</i>episode " 1961". It is played during a flashback
    to that time period.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
