<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Truly_Madly_Deeply 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Truly_Madly_Deeply</songId>
   <title>Truly Madly Deeply</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Savage_Garden</artistId>
      <artistName>Savage Garden</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1998-01-17</week>
      <week>1998-01-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Savage Garden</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 3, 1997</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1995-1996</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:38 (album version)</length>
      <length>4:35 (Night Radio Mix)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia (International) , Roadshow Music (Australia) , Sony Records (Japan)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Darren Hayes</writer>
      <writer>Daniel Jones</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Charles Fisher</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Truly Madly Deeply" is a 1995 song by Australian pop band
    Savage Garden, released as a single in 1997. Written by
    bandmates Darren Hayes and Daniel Jones, the song is a
    reworking of an older song of theirs called "Magical Kisses"
    and was the third single from their self-titled debut album.
    The song is considered to be the best song throughout the run
    of the duo.</p>
      <p>There were two videos made for "Truly Madly Deeply". One of
    them was filmed in the Sacré-Cœur area of Paris, said to be the
    most romantic city in the world. It was directed by Adolfo
    Doring.</p>
      <p>The Japanese release, available elsewhere on import, was
    actually a special, album-length disc comprising 14 rare
    tracks, featuring three versions of the title song, along with
    three bonus remixes, six rare B-sides and two acoustic live
    versions.</p>
      <p>There is two distinct versions of the song. One was released
    on the Australian album release, whereas the other version was
    on the US release. This version composed in 1996 features a
    drum-machine track instead of the more acoustic-sounding music
    in the Australian version. The US version also featured on
    their 2005 greatest hits, 
    <i>Truly Madly Compeletely</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1998 it was the main song from the soundtrack of the
    movie 
    <i>Music from Another Room</i>, starring Jude Law and Gretchen
    Mol.</p>
      <p>The song was a major and sustained success in the U.S.
    beginning in 1997. Entering the Billboard Hot 100 Singles chart
    at #26 on December 6, 1997, it peaked at #1 for two weeks in
    January 1998 and lingered for a full year on the chart. It hit
    #1 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Airplay chart and #2 on the Hot Adult
    Top 40 Tracks chart. It also went Top 10 on the Rhythmic Top 40
    chart.</p>
      <p>On the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Top 40 Mainstream chart the song hit number one
    for one week on January 31 before dropping to number two as
    Celine Dion assumed the top spot with the theme to the hit film
    
    <i>Titanic</i>, "My Heart Will Go On". Savage Garden's single
    held at #2 for ten weeks, before returning to the number one
    spot again the week of April 18.</p>
      <p>Savage Garden's "Truly Madly Deeply" set a record for the
    most weeks of any single in history on the U.S. Hot Adult
    Contemporary chart. In 1998 the song logged eleven weeks at
    number one on this chart, but its full chart span lasted 123
    weeks. That record would stand for just under two years, when
    another ballad spent its 124th week on that chart. That song
    was Savage Garden's "I Knew I Loved You", from the album 
    <i>Affirmation</i>.</p>
      <p>After leaving the main Adult Contemporary chart, the song
    entered the Hot Adult Contemporary Recurrents chart where it
    charted for another 202 weeks. The song was so popular that it
    re-entered 
    <i>Billboard's</i>Hot Singles Sales chart in March 2002
    and—four and a half years after its release—again became a U.S.
    Top 30 bestseller, remaining on that chart until late July
    2002. Savage Garden's original version logged its final week on
    the Hot Adult Contemporary Recurrents chart on June 17,
    2006.</p>
      <p>The song also reached #1 in their home country of Australia
    and in Canada. Savage Garden's single hit #2 in Norway, Sweden,
    Austria and Ireland and went Top Ten in France, Switzerland,
    the Netherlands, Belgium and the UK, where it peaked at #4.</p>
      <p>In 1998, the song was certified a Gold single in France, for
    sales of 200,000 copies.</p>
      <p>In May 2001 the Australasian Performing Right Association
    (APRA), as part of its 75th Anniversary celebrations, named
    "Truly Madly Deeply" as one of the Top 30 Australian songs of
    all time.</p>
      <p>In 2008, Savage Garden's single was listed at #30 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top 100.</i>[2]</p>
      <p>The song was covered in 1998 by Brazilian brother-sister
    singing duo Sandy &amp; Junior. The Portuguese-language
    version, "No Fundo Do Coração", was released as the third
    single from the teens' eighth album, 
    <i>Era Uma Vez (Ao Vivo)</i>. The album was certified Triple
    Platinum in Brazil in 1999 by the Brazilian Association of
    Discs Producers (ABPD) for sales of over 300,000 copies in
    Brazil alone. The album was their last for PolyGram Records
    before moving to Universal Music Group.</p>
      <p>German Eurotrance group Cascada covered "Truly Madly Deeply"
    on the album 
    <i>Everytime We Touch</i>and released it as the second single
    in the UK and Germany. Although the album version of the song
    is a ballad, there is also a trance version of the song more in
    keeping with their typical style, which is the main single
    version. Both versions are featured on the UK edition of the
    album. First released in the U.S. exclusively in the iTunes
    store on February 27, the U.S. physical release was March 13,
    2007.</p>
      <p>UK CD single Part 1</p>
      <p>UK CD single Part 2</p>
      <p>German 12" single</p>
      <p>German CD single</p>
      <p>U.S. 12" single</p>
      <p>Australian (2007)</p>
      <p>Other remixes</p>
      <p>The Cascada single entered the UK Singles Chart at number 17
    solely on downloads and peaked at number 4 the following week,
    after its physical release. In Ireland, it remained in the top
    4 for four weeks.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
