<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Temperature_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Temperature_(song)</songId>
   <title>Temperature</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sean_Paul</artistId>
      <artistName>Sean Paul</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2006-04-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/5c/Sean_Paul_Temperature.jpg/200px-Sean_Paul_Temperature.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Sean-Paul+Temperature.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Trinity</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 24, 2006</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2005</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dancehall</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:36</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic Records / VP Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>S. Henriques</writer>
      <writer>A. Marshall</writer>
      <writer>R. Fuller</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Rohan "Snowcone" Fuller</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Temperature" is a reggae–dancehall song written by Sean
    Paul for his third album 
    <i>The Trinity</i>(2005). The song reached #1 on the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100, Sean Paul's third U.S. #1 along with "Get
    Busy" and "Baby Boy" with Beyonce.</p>
      <p>"Temperature" was the third international single (second US
    single) from Sean Paul's 
    <i>The Trinity</i>album. The song was produced by Rohan
    "Snowcone" Fuller and received a positive reception from music
    critics. The song was released as the second U.S. single in the
    first quarter of 2006 and reached number one in the United
    States on the Billboard Hot 100 and became Paul's third number
    one hit single. It reached the top ten in Canada and France and
    the top twenty in the United Kingdom, peaking at #11 there. In
    Australia, "Temperature" debuted at number nineteen but quickly
    found its way to number five the following weeks.</p>
      <p>"Temperature" became Sean Paul's biggest hit single in the
    US. In Australia it became a smash hit, with Sean Paul making
    interview appearances on the Paul Celoni Radio Show, and shows
    alike. Even though it only spent one week at #1, as opposed to
    "Get Busy" and its three weeks on top, "Temperature" showed
    extreme longevity on The Billboard Hot 100 spending 17 weeks in
    the top 10. Until Nelly Furtado and Timbaland's
    "Promiscuous,"this was the longest run in the top ten for a
    single in 2006. On top of that it became Sean Paul's first
    single to sell an excess of one million digital downloads,
    earning platinum certification.</p>
      <p>The song uses the dancehall riddim "Applause". It was also
    used in the game 
    <i>Dance Dance Revolution SuperNOVA 2</i>. It can be heard in
    the 2007 film, 
    <i>Norbit</i>.</p>
      <p>Officially, there are two versions of the song. Only the use
    of the riddim makes both versions different.</p>
      <p>In 2008 the media reported a story regarding Stacey Gayle of
    New York City who experienced seizures as a result of hearing
    the song.</p>
      <p>In this video Sean Paul is seen dancing quite close with
    female dancers. The first dance sequence was with blowing
    leaves, centered in fall. Then as weather gets colder, he is in
    the snow with the thermometer frozen, centered in winter. The
    third sequence is in the rain, centered around spring. Finally
    he's at a tanning salon squirting sunscreen, centered around
    summer. There is evident sexual innuendo in the squirting of
    the lotion from the sunscreen bottles. At the end he raps and
    is in a club while performing to the song "Breakout."</p>
      <p>UK - CD: 1</p>
      <p>UK - CD: 2</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
