<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beautiful_Girls_(Sean_Kingston_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beautiful_Girls_(Sean_Kingston_song)</songId>
   <title>Beautiful Girls</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sean_Kingston</artistId>
      <artistName>Sean Kingston</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2007-08-11</week>
      <week>2007-08-18</week>
      <week>2007-08-25</week>
      <week>2007-09-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f6/Sean_Kingston_Beautiful_Girls.jpg/200px-Sean_Kingston_Beautiful_Girls.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Sean-Kingston+Beautiful-Girls.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Sean Kingston</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 26, 2007  (2007-03-26)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>ringle</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2007</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Reggae Fusion</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:02 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>3:43 (Radio Edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic , Geffen , Viacom , Koch</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ben E. King /Jordan/ Mike Stoller / J.R. Rotem / Jerry Leiber / Kisean Anderson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>J.R. Rotem</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Beautiful Girls" is a song by reggae-influenced musician
    Sean Kingston from his eponymous debut. The song samples Ben E.
    King's classic "Stand by Me" and uses digital pitch correction
    technology on the vocals. The song is about a boy who is
    suicidal over the failure of his relationship with a "beautiful
    girl".</p>
      <p>Rapper Lil Mama and actors Kenny Vibert and Lil' JJ are
    featured in the music video.</p>
      <p>Certain radio stations (mostly AC or hot AC stations and
    including Radio Disney) play the censored version of the song,
    which replaces the word "you had me suicidal, suicidal" with
    "you got me in denial, in denial." On MTV the word "suicidal"
    is completely removed with no replacement. On BET, Fuse and
    MuchMusic, as well as several top 40, urban and rhythmic top 40
    and AC stations, "suicidal" was left intact.</p>
      <p>Due to the lyrics containing references to suicide, the
    track has been removed from many radio playlists including
    FM104 in Dublin, where thousands of complaints were phoned in
    on a late night chat show 
    <i>The Adrian Kennedy Phoneshow</i>, and 
    <i>Wild 102</i>in Roseau, Minnesota. It was allegedly pulled
    from two FM although a spokesperson said the song is currently
    not on its playlist but could not confirm if it had been in the
    past. FM104 replaced "suicidal" with "in denial", a change Sean
    Kingston made for the radio station.</p>
      <p>UK CD single</p>
      <p>The song benefited from extensive airplay before its digital
    release, reaching as high as #17 on the Hot 100. On July 24,
    "Beautiful Girls" was accidentally leaked onto the U.S. iTunes
    Store, two days before the planned release date. The week after
    the song's digital release it hit number one on Billboard's Hot
    Digital Songs, debuting with 260,000 downloads in its first
    week (the second highest digital sales for a new song of 2007,
    only behind Rihanna's "Umbrella"). Kingston became the first
    artist born within the 1990s to top the Hot 100, beating rapper
    Soulja Boy Tell 'Em to it by six weeks. In the same week the
    song advanced from #23 to #1 on the Billboard Hot 100, tying it
    with Brandy and Monica's "The Boy Is Mine" for the biggest
    single-week upward movement to #1 on the Hot 100. It has also
    gone on to occupy the top spot on the U.S. Hot 100 Airplay and
    the Canadian Hot 100. It remained on top of the UK Singles
    Chart for four weeks before being knocked off by the Sugababes'
    first single from their 5th studio album 
    <i>Change</i>, "About You Now". The song ended 2007 as the
    year's 15th biggest-selling single in the UK. However, it made
    Sean Kingston a one-hit wonder as his next few singles
    underperformed in the UK Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>On the official ARIA charts in Australia it debuted at #1,
    fell to #2 when Delta Goodrem's comeback single took the top
    spot. "Beautiful Girls" returned the next week and remained for
    a month before being replaced by Timbaland's "The Way I
    Are".</p>
      <p>This song was #86 on 
    <i>MTV Asia</i>'s list of Top 100 Hits of 2007.</p>
      <p>A few months after "Beautiful Girls" was released in 2007, a
    new online video service called Votigo began a cover contest in
    which fans could submit covers of the song for a chance to get
    a call from Sean Kingston. After an online vote user Mallory
    Robbins won with an a cappella version of the song. Top honors
    also went to a rock cover of the song performed by the Ailan
    Christopher Project. Shortly afterward, recording artist JoJo
    released a cover response version of the track which was
    released on MySpace, however will not be featured on her
    upcoming album. Chris Moyles also released a parody cover,
    however it was about the song describing how bad it was in his
    opinion.</p>
      <p>The Plain White T's, whose song was knocked out of the
    charts by this one, did a cover version for Yahoo Music. Lead
    vocalist Tom Higgenson says that the group "started covering it
    as a joke almost. We started learning it because we were number
    one for a few weeks and then we got knocked out of the number
    one spot by Sean Kingston, by this song. It's kind of like an
    ode to Sean." To close out the song guitarist Mike Retondo
    breaks into the chorus of "Stand by Me", (which is also done in
    the cover version by Boyce Avenue a nod to the fact that that
    song's bassline is used in Beautiful Girls.</p>
      <p>Teddy Geiger covered the song on his 2007 tour, due to
    popularity a recorded version of the song will be featured as a
    bonus track on the iTunes version of his upcoming CD "The
    March".</p>
      <p>Jesse McCartney covered Beautiful Girls during his Right
    Where You Want Me tour.</p>
      <p>David Archuleta briefly sang the chorus of the song at the
    end of his May 6, 2008 performance on the U.S. TV show American
    Idol. He was singing Ben E. King's original Stand By Me
    song.</p>
      <p>Deer Tick (band) recorded a cover of Beautiful Girls, which
    can be found on Myspace.com.</p>
      <p>Casey Crescenzo of The Dear Hunter recorded a cover of this
    song and has occasionally performed it live.</p>
      <p>Boyband JLS choose a Mashup of the song and Stand by me as
    their bottom two performance on UK TV show The X Factor A year
    later on Series 6 of the show Lloyd Daniels sang the chorus and
    the last verse of the song in his November 30, 2008 performance
    also singing King's original Stand By Me.</p>
      <p>Bayside covers the song on Punk Goes Pop 2.</p>
      <p>BAMF! recorded a version entitled Bootyfull Girl.</p>
      <p>This song is also featured in the 2008 monster film 
    <i>Cloverfield</i>, and on The CW's 
    <i>Gossip Girl</i>. The "suicidal" version of the song, which
    ends differently from the single mix is also featured in the
    video game SingStar Hottest Hits.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
