<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It_Wasn%27t_Me 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It_Wasn%27t_Me</songId>
   <title>It Wasn't Me</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shaggy_(artist)</artistId>
      <artistName>Shaggy featuring Ricardo "RikRok" Ducent</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2001-02-03</week>
      <week>2001-02-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/b1/Shaggy-wasn%27t-me.jpg/200px-Shaggy-wasn%27t-me.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Shaggy-featuring-Ricardo-RikRok-Ducent+It-Wasn-t-Me.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Hot Shot</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 2000</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD maxi single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Reggae Fusion / Contemporary R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:47</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MCA Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Orville Burrell</writer>
      <writer>RikRok</writer>
      <writer>Shaun Pizzonia</writer>
      <writer>Braun Thompson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Shaun Pizzonia</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"It Wasn't Me" is a 2000 number one hit song by reggae
    artist Shaggy, featuring Ricardo "RikRok" Ducent. It achieved a
    huge success in many countries, topping the charts in the U.S.,
    France, UK, the Netherlands, Austria, Australia and
    Ireland.</p>
      <p>The song was originally never intended to be released as a
    single, MCA Records wanted "Dance and Shout" to be the first
    single released from the 
    <i>Hot Shot</i>album and didn't offer other tracks to DJs.
    Hawaiian DJ Pablo Sato downloaded the album from "a
    Napster-like MP3 site he won’t name" and discovered it "was the
    album’s standout cut." He played the song on the radio the next
    day. "The phone lines lit up right away. Within a couple of
    days, it was our number-one requested song."</p>
      <p>The lyrics depict one man (Rikrok) asking his friend
    (Shaggy) what to do after his girlfriend caught him with
    another woman. Shaggy's advice is to deny everything with the
    phrase "It wasn't me", despite all evidence to the
    contrary.</p>
      <p>Two versions of the song and video exist: the radio and
    television edit version replace the lyric 
    <i>"Picture this; we were both butt-naked banging on the
    bathroom floor"</i>with 
    <i>"Picture this; we were both caught making love on the
    bathroom floor."</i>
      </p>
      <p>The video starts out with Rikrok running to Shaggy's mansion
    to explain to him what just happened to him. Rikrok tells him
    that he cheated on his girlfriend and got caught. Shaggy tells
    him to tell her that "it wasn't me." The video then cuts into a
    flashback to earlier that day. Rikrok had been caught sleeping
    with another woman, and his girlfriend was outside the
    apartment in her convertible when two women pull up next to her
    on their motorcycles. The three women go into the building and
    Rikrok sneaks out the window, takes one of the motorcycles and
    leaves. The women come out and the girlfriend and one of the
    friends get in the convertible and the other women got on her
    motorcycle and chase after him. Shaggy, from his house, using
    his futuristic technology tracks down where Rikrok is going and
    prepares an escape for him. Rikrok then gets on a bridge over
    the highway when the friend rides on the bridge in front of
    him. He then hits the brakes to stop while she stops her
    motorcycle. Rikrok then hears a noise behind him and it's the
    other friends and the girlfriend driving the convertible on the
    other side of the bridge. On the highway below, an 18-wheeler
    drives by and Shaggy leaves him a text message telling him to
    look behind him. He notices the truck and jumps off the side of
    overhead and lands on the truck. He is then dropped off at
    Shaggy's mansion, showing the same scene from the start of the
    video.</p>
      <p>The song was Shaggy's first number-one hit in the U.S., and
    the follow-up, "Angel," also reached number one. The single
    also reached number one in the UK Singles Chart on March 4,
    2001, making the song a transatlantic chart topper. It also
    reached number one in Australia on April 1, 2001. It is also
    the 4th biggest selling single of the 21st century in the
    United Kingdom (the biggest selling single by a non-British
    artist). Prior to this the song reached number 31 on import
    sales in the UK before its release.</p>
      <p>Like many popular songs of the time, "It Wasn't Me" was
    subject to parody. It was parodied on an episode of 
    <i>Svengoolie</i>. It was also covered by Scrumpy and Western
    band the Wurzels.</p>
      <p>The song's lyrics inspired 
    <i>Slate</i>writer Josh Levin to coin the term the "Shaggy
    defense" to describe R. Kelly's defense at his child
    pornography trial stemming from the production of a sex tape:
    "I predict that in the decades to come, law schools will teach
    this as the "Shaggy defense." You allege that I was caught on
    camera, butt naked, banging on the log cabin floor? It wasn't
    me." Levin repeated the term on NPR.</p>
      <p>Import</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
