<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hips_Don%27t_Lie 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hips_Don%27t_Lie</songId>
   <title>Hips Don't Lie</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shakira</artistId>
      <artistName>Shakira featuring Wyclef Jean</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2006-06-17</week>
      <week>2006-06-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/c/c0/Shakira-HipsDon%27tLie.jpg/200px-Shakira-HipsDon%27tLie.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Shakira-featuring-Wyclef-Jean+Hips-Don-t-Lie.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Oral Fixation Vol. 2</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 2006 (North America)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Digital download</format>
      <format>12" maxi single</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Worldbeat</genre>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>Album Version (3:41)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Shakira</writer>
      <writer>Wyclef Jean</writer>
      <writer>Jerry 'Wonder' Duplessis</writer>
      <writer>Omar Alfano</writer>
      <writer>LaTravia Parker</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Shakira</producer>
      <producer>Wyclef Jean</producer>
      <producer>Jerry 'Wonder' Duplessis</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Hips Don't Lie" is a Latin pop song based in a salsa and
    Cumbia performed by Colombian singer Shakira and Haitian rapper
    Wyclef Jean. The song is a remake of Jean's 2004 song "Dance
    Like This" (which featured Claudette Ortiz and appeared on the
    soundtrack to 
    <i>Dirty Dancing: Havana Nights</i>) and takes some of its
    instrumentation from Jerry Rivera's "Amores Como El Nuestro"
    (which was also used for Lord Tariq and Peter Gunz's hit single
    "Déjà Vu (Uptown Baby)") and lyrics from Dominican composer
    Luis Dias' "Carnaval (Baila en la Calle)". Shakira wrote some
    parts of the new version, and co-produced the song. The song
    was released as the second single from Shakira's second English
    album 
    <i>Oral Fixation Vol. 2</i>in 2006. "Hips Don't Lie" became a
    global success, topping the charts in at least 55 countries. It
    became Shakira and Wyclef's first (and to date, only)
    number-one single in the U.S. The song became one of the
    world's best-selling singles of all time and one of the hottest
    songs of summer 2006. In the UK, this was Wyclef's third
    number-one hit (after The Fugees' "Killing Me Softly" and
    "Ready Or Not") and Shakira's first. In many other countries,
    it became Shakira's second number one, (following the massive
    success of "Whenever, Wherever") and her third number-one
    single in other countries such as Australia and Netherlands
    (after "Underneath Your Clothes"). An international remix was
    released indigitally and produced by Boston's DJ Niso
    International on April 21, 2006.</p>
      <p>There is a Spanish version of the song called "Será, Será
    (Las Caderas No Mienten)" which can be translated to "Could it
    Be, Could it Be (Hips Don't Lie)". It was released in Latin
    America, although some radios preferred to play the original
    version. This version has different verses and a different
    chorus, whilst the rap by Wyclef Jean is kept in English. The
    Fray has covered this song in Jo Whiley's live lounge.</p>
      <p>"Hips Don't Lie" was reportedly commissioned by Sony Music
    to revive sales of Shakira's flagging album 
    <i>Oral Fixation Vol. 2</i>, which had come out in late 2005 in
    time for the lucrative holiday-buying season. 
    <i>Vol. 2</i>was Shakira's second album of the year, directly
    following the Spanish-language 
    <i>Fijación Oral Vol. 1</i>by less than six months. (As part of
    a small trend in 2005, Shakira joined Sony label mates System
    of a Down in releasing two back-to-back albums of new material
    in a single calendar year.) Ironically, in the crucial U.S.
    market, 
    <i>Vol. 1</i>– for which Sony likely had lower expectations
    given the album's late-spring release and non-English content –
    actually sold better than 
    <i>Vol. 2</i>, Shakira's first English-language album since her
    breakthrough 
    <i>Laundry Service</i>four years earlier. Despite its release
    in a slower sales period of the year, 
    <i>Vol. 1</i>had bigger first-week sales than 
    <i>Vol. 2</i>(157,000 copies vs. 128,000), charted higher (#4 –
    a rare ranking for a Spanish album – vs. #5) and produced a
    genuine hit single in the #23 hit "La Tortura" with Alejandro
    Sanz, while 
    <i>Vol. 2'</i>s leadoff single "Don't Bother" stalled just
    outside the Top 40. 
    <i>Vol. 2</i>was too important a project for Epic, so around
    the start of 2006 they asked Wyclef Jean to remake his own song
    with Shakira and give the album a crucial radio hit – a tactic
    that proved a tremendous success: When 
    <i>Vol. 2</i>was re-released in March 2006 with "Hips Don't
    Lie" (plus an alternate version of "La Tortura"), the album
    shot up 92 spots on the Billboard 200, representing a one-week
    sales increase of 643%. As of November 2007, the album has sold
    close to 2 million copies in the United States, more than half
    of them the re-release containing "Hips Don't Lie."</p>
      <p>"Hips Don't Lie" debuted on the L.A.-based radio station
    KIIS-FM (on the 
    <i>Ryan Seacrest Morning Show</i>) on February 14, 2006.
    Shakira and Wyclef Jean performed the song on the following TV
    shows: 
    <i>American Idol</i>, 
    <i>The Ellen DeGeneres Show</i>, 
    <i>Live With Regis and Kelly</i>, 
    <i>The Today Show</i>, 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>, and the 
    <i>2007 Grammy Awards</i>. The song can be heard in the EA
    Sports video game MVP 06 NCAA Baseball, the film soundtrack to 
    <i>Ice Age: The Meltdown</i>, and on MySpace records.
    soundtrack on 27 Dresses.</p>
      <p>This is what Shakira says about the song "Hips Don't Lie" on
    her official website:</p>
      <p>
         <i>Wyclef from the Fugees is on the track with me and very soon
    it will be added to my album</i>Oral Fixation Vol. 2
    <i>. In reality, it wasn't anything I had planned - but during
    my vacation at the start of the year Wyclef and I bumped into
    each other. It was a happy accident.</i>"</p>
      <p>Controversially, Puerto Rican salsa singer Jerry Rivera was
    not informed that the opening trumpets of the song was used
    without his permission and accused her of plagiarism. Despite
    this, he decided to not press charges against her.</p>
      <p>Less than two weeks after its debut on KIIS, Z100 added the
    track, and less than a week after it was added to the playlist,
    it was the most requested song on the station as it hit #1 on
    the "Interactive 9@9". It stayed on top for about a month. In
    December 2006 it was announced that "Hips Don't Lie" was the #1
    song of the year. A first for both Shakira and Wyclef Jean.</p>
      <p>A Spanish version entitled "Será, Será (Las Caderas No
    Mienten)" was also released. This version is sung in Spanish,
    as well as the rap. Shakira also sang another version (produced
    by RedOne) called "Hips Don't Lie/Bamboo" at the closing
    ceremony of the 2006 FIFA World Cup in Berlin, Germany.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by British director Sophie
    Muller and filmed in Los Angeles, California, United States.
    While plotless, the video presents Shakira and Wyclef Jean
    enjoying themselves as they dance in an arena-like environment.
    The majority of the costumes and outfits featured in the video
    belong to the Carnaval de Barranquilla, some of which include
    the white dress Shakira dances in, and the colorful flags.
    Shakira was given dancing lessons for the music video by the
    Indian choreographer Farah Khan.</p>
      <p>"Hips Don't Lie" has proved successful on LAUNCHcast's
    top-hundred most-watched videos of the week, where it has spent
    an impressive four months at number one. Yahoo! had fans submit
    videos of themselves dancing to the song, which were edited
    into a "fans only" version which has also proved to be one of
    the most popular videos on LAUNCH. The video for "Hips Don't
    Lie" ran in the #1 spot on iTunes (along with the single) for
    several weeks. It was the most-watched video of 2006, and has
    drawn close to two million streamed performances. The video won
    the MTV Video Music Award for Best Choreography on August 31,
    2006 and the MTV Latin Award for Song Of The Year on October
    19, 2006. The video also placed #2 on VH1's "Top 40 Videos of
    2006".</p>
      <p>In February 2006, "Hips Don't Lie" debuted on the Hot 100 at
    #84. Four weeks later, it entered the U.S. 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100's top-forty on the chart and received
    the "greatest airplay gainer" title on the Hot 100 for three
    weeks in a row. The song achieved a peak position of #13 until
    it was released digitally on May 27, 2006. Shakira's record
    label Epic Records originally held back the release of the
    song's digital downloads to boost sales of 
    <i>Oral Fixation Vol. 2</i>. When Epic finally released it
    digitally the track hit #1, the single jumped from number nine
    to number one on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 for the week ending June 17, 2006,
    helped by the song's strong number-one status on the Hot 100
    Airplay chart and nearly 267,000 downloads in its first week
    (the accomplishment broke D4L's record with "Laffy Taffy" of
    179,000 paid downloads). On the iTunes download chart, the song
    bumped Nelly Furtado's "Promiscuous" to #2 less than 24 hours
    after it was digitally released. Within 3 weeks the single
    managed to move over 670,000 paid digital downloads. Since it
    has been digitally available in June 2006, the song has sold
    more than 2,000,000 downloads. "Hips Don't Lie" also set a
    record for the fastest selling record to reach the one million
    digital download mark. It sold its millionth digital download
    after 9 short weeks in the U.S., beating the previous record
    held by Daniel Powter's "Bad Day" which took 16 weeks. The song
    ended 2006 at #46 on the iTunes top 100, jumping up twenty-six
    spots from #72 on New Year's Eve. On January 1, 2007, AOL
    revealed a list of the Top 100 Songs and Top 100 Videos of
    2006, "Hips Don't Lie" was the #6 song and unsurprisingly the
    #1 video.</p>
      <p>According to Nielsen Broadcast Data Systems, "Hips Don't
    Lie" was the most-played pop song in a single week in American
    radio history. It was played 9,637 times in one week, breaking
    Gwen Stefani's previous record with 9,582 plays in a week for
    her #1 hit single "Hollaback Girl" in 2005. Shakira also became
    the first artist ever to top the Billboard's Hot 100 chart and
    the Latin Singles chart simultaneously. The single held the top
    spot in the Billboard Hot 100 for two weeks in a row, being
    dethroned on July 1 by "Do I Make You Proud" from Season 5
    winner Taylor Hicks.</p>
      <p>In the UK it spent a total of 5 weeks at number one. After
    its initial one-week reign at number one, it returned to the
    top in its 8th week preventing Christina Aguilera's "Ain't No
    Other Man", Rihanna's "Unfaithful", as well as Cascada's
    "Everytime We Touch" and Chamillionaire's "Ridin'" from going
    to #1 until it was replaced by Beyoncé Knowles' "Déjà Vu".
    "Hips Don't Lie" broke the record for the most weeks for a song
    in a second run, staying four weeks during its second reign at
    number-one. The song remained in the top 10 for 16 weeks, and
    then stayed within the top 75 for an additional 38 weeks. "Hips
    Don't Lie" is currently the 11th best selling single by a
    female artist in the 21st century in the UK, and also the 10th
    best selling collaboration. It is also the 46th best-selling
    single of the 2000 decade in UK.</p>
      <p>In Ireland, the single remained at the number 1 spot for a
    total of nine weeks throughout the summer.</p>
      <p>"Hips Don't Lie" was the most successful song of 2006
    worldwide and it is one of a few songs in history to reach #1
    in almost every charting country and territory around the
    world. It reached number one on the USA Hot 100, Pop 100 and
    Hot Latin Tracks, in Australia, Belgium, Bolivia, Canada (on
    the Digital Chart), Czech Republic, Europe, France, Germany,
    Greece, Guatemala, Hong Kong, Hungary, India, Ireland, Israel,
    Italy, Latin America, Lebanon, Netherlands, New Zealand,
    Romania, Serbia, Singapore, Slovakia, Slovenia, Switzerland,
    Turkey, Ukraine, , and other countries to date; the only
    countries where the song didn't reach the top position, but
    reached the top ten are Austria, Canada (on the Canadian
    Airplay Chart), China, Finland, Norway and Russia peaking at
    number two and in Denmark peaking at number six. In Taiwan, the
    song peaked at number eleven, while it reached the top position
    on the Japan International Singles. The only nation worldwide
    where the song didn't reach a Top 20 position was in Sweden,
    where it peaked at number forty-five due to its late October
    release on the charts.</p>
      <p>"Hips Don't Lie" was the number-two year-end song in the
    Netherlands; it also finished number three in Germany and the
    UK, while in Peru it was number four and in USA it was number
    five. On July 9, 2006 Shakira performed Hips don't Lie at the
    World Cup Final in Berlin, Germany to a worldwide audience of
    one billion people.</p>
      <p>CD single:</p>
      <p>Maxi CD single:</p>
      <p>Japanese release:</p>
      <p>Ringle:</p>
      <p>(This CD comes with a code for the free downloadable
    ringtone)</p>
      <p>The master ringtone of "Hips Don't Lie" (English, Spanish
    and Bamboo version) has sold nearly 100,000 units in
    Mexico.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
