<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Da_Doo_Ron_Ron 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Da_Doo_Ron_Ron</songId>
   <title>Da Doo Ron Ron</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shaun_Cassidy</artistId>
      <artistName>Shaun Cassidy</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1977-07-16</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1963</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1962-1963</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Doo Wop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:18</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Philles Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Phil Spector</writer>
      <writer>Jeff Barry</writer>
      <writer>Ellie Greenwich</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Phil Spector</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Da Doo Ron Ron" is a 1963 hit single by The Crystals
    produced by Phil Spector in his Wall of Sound style. The song
    was written by Jeff Barry, Ellie Greenwich and Spector; on June
    8, it reached number three on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100. It also reached number five in the UK.
    According to Darlene Love (another of Spector's recording
    artists) the track was originally recorded by The Blossoms,
    with Love herself on lead vocal. Prior to release, Spector
    erased Love's lead and replaced it with a vocal by the
    Crystals' Dolores "LaLa" Brooks, although he kept the Blossoms'
    backing vocals in place.</p>
      <p>Bette Midler recorded a cover of the song for her album 
    <i>Bette Midler</i>(1973). The song is performed as a medley
    with "Uptown" and "Don't Say Nothin' Bad (About My Baby)".</p>
      <p>Bootlegged studio recordings of the song are found by such
    artists as Bob Dylan, The Rolling Stones, and The Beach Boys (
    <i>Keepin' The Summer Alive</i>era). It became a #1 Billboard
    hit in 1977, launching the career of teen idol Shaun Cassidy.
    (The words were changed slightly to keep it a boy-girl song.)
    All-girl rock band The Donnas recorded a version of the song as
    a single, which was later placed on the 1998 re-release of
    their 1997 self-titled cd. Other artists who have covered this
    song include The Carpenters, Jack Nitzsche, Ian Matthews, The
    Raindrops, Brian Poole and the Tremeloes and The Searchers.</p>
      <p>In 2004, this song was ranked #114 on Rolling Stone's list
    of The 500 Greatest Songs of All Time.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
