<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/9_to_5_(Sheena_Easton_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/9_to_5_(Sheena_Easton_song)</songId>
   <title>Morning Train (Nine to Five)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheena_Easton</artistId>
      <artistName>Sheena Easton</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1981-05-02</week>
      <week>1981-05-09</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/20/9_to_5_Morning_Train.jpg/200px-9_to_5_Morning_Train.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Sheena-Easton+Morning-Train-Nine-to-Five.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Take My Time</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>16 May 1980 (UK) , February 1981 (USA)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1980</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>EMI</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Florrie Palmer</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Christopher Neil</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"9 to 5" is the title of a popular song recorded by Sheena
    Easton in 1980, becoming her biggest hit. It peaked at number
    three in the United Kingdom in August 1980 and was released in
    the United States in February 1981 (retitled Morning Train to
    avoid confusion with a similarly named song), where it reached
    number one.</p>
      <p>Easton had released one single prior to "9 to 5": "Modern
    Girl". This had failed to chart highly, but after exposure on
    the BBC documentary, , both "9 to 5" and "Modern Girl" were
    propelled into the top ten at the same time, making her the
    first female artist to achieve this feat. "9 to 5" became a top
    three hit and was one of the best-selling singles of the
    year.</p>
      <p>Early in 1981, EMI Records decided to launch Easton in the
    US and released "9 to 5" as her debut single. The title of the
    song was changed to "Morning Train (Nine to Five)" to avoid
    confusion with the Dolly Parton song of the same name. Easton's
    song went to #1 on both the U.S. pop and adult contemporary
    charts; it remained at the top for two weeks on Billboard's pop
    chart.</p>
      <p>The song is about a woman who waits at home all day for her
    man to come home from work. The music video was filmed on the
    Bluebell Railway, a heritage line running between East and West
    Sussex in England. The video stars London and South Western
    Railway No. 488, a preserved LSWR 0415 Class locomotive.</p>
      <p>The tune was featured in the 2004 movie 
    <i>EuroTrip</i>as the Manchester United Supporters Club theme
    and was also played as part of a montage in two episodes of 
    <i>Seinfeld</i>: "The Bizarro Jerry" episode in which Kramer
    finds himself working 9 to 5 at Brand/Leland, and "The Butter
    Shave" episode in which George fakes a handicap at Play Now. Of
    note, David Mandel has writing credits on EuroTrip and the two
    Seinfeld episodes. Alec Berg holds writing credits on EuroTrip
    and "The Butter Shave."</p>
      <p>The song also features in a sketch in 
    <i>Not The Nine O'Clock News</i>, in which Pamela Stephenson
    sings it in relation to her "husband", Rowan Atkinson.
    Atkinson, having come home from work, corrects Stephenson's
    lyrics ("I don't take the train, I've taken the bus for fifteen
    years!", Stephenson obligingly changes the lyrics), before
    revealing that "he spends all day with a whore" (again sung by
    Stephenson) and attempting to kill her. The sketch ends with
    Stephenson singing "and then he tries to strangle me".</p>
      <p>In an episode of 
    <i>South Park</i>("Kenny Dies"), Eric Cartman briefly sings the
    song as he happens upon a truck that went off the side of a
    road.</p>
      <p>In an episode of the 1997 sitcom 
    <i>Soul Man</i>, Anthony Clark's character begins to play the
    song on a church organ.</p>
      <p>On the season 26 finale episode of 
    <i>Saturday Night Live</i>(host: Christopher Walken; musical
    guest: Weezer), in a "Mango" sketch, Mango (Chris Kattan) sings
    "Morning Train" as he's working out in his dressing room.</p>
      <p>In the 
    <i>Drawn Together</i>episode "Xandir and Tim, Sitting in a
    Tree", Jimmy Kimmel sings the song during a story in which
    Spanky Ham has left the Drawn Together house and taken a 9 to 5
    job as a hostage negotiator.</p>
      <p>The song was also featured in a 2004 television commercial
    for Connex Melbourne where a trainload of passengers take turns
    in singing a line from the song while the train pulls up at
    Burnley railway station where a woman boards the train. One of
    the passengers says "Sheena!" and the woman is then revealed to
    be Easton who responds with a scream; the ad concludes with all
    the passengers singing the chorus of the song as the train is
    shown leaving the station.</p>
      <p>Swedish-born Norwegian singer Elisabeth Andreasson covered
    the song in Swedish, as "Han pendlar varje dag" (which means
    "He commutes every day") with the new lyrics by Olle Bergman,
    on her 1981 album "Angel of the Morning". This version also
    stayed at Svensktoppen for 9 weeks during the period 21
    February-18 April 1982, with a 4th place as best result there
    .</p>
      <p>Sylvie Vartan remade "Morning Train" for the French market
    as "L’amour c'est comme une cigarette" ("Love is like a
    cigarette"): the lyrics were written by Michel Mallory who
    reworked a number of English language hits for Vartan. The
    concept of Vartan's version was echoed in the Dutch remake by
    Benny Neyman: "Liefde is als een sigaret", which reached #49 in
    the Netherlands in 1982.</p>
      <p>It was revealed in the documentary John Peel's Record Box
    that British radio DJ John Peel loved the record so much that
    he kept two copies of it in a small wooden box of his 142
    favourite singles.</p>
      <p>In the 7th episode of the mini-series Generation Kill (Bomb
    in the Garden), Corporal Josh Ray Person sings this song while
    waiting to move into combat.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
