<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johnny_Angel_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johnny_Angel_(song)</songId>
   <title>Johnny Angel</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shelley_Fabares</artistId>
      <artistName>Shelley Fabares</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1962-04-07</week>
      <week>1962-04-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Johnny Angel" is a song written by Lyn Duddy and Lee
    Pockriss and recorded by Shelley Fabares. It hit number one on
    the Billboard Hot 100 on April 7, 1962, during a 15-week run on
    the chart. The song is an expression of a teenage girl's
    romantic longing for a boy who doesn't know she exists, to the
    point where she declines other boys' propositions for dates
    because she'd rather concentrate on the boy she loves. The song
    premiered on an episode of Fabares' sitcom, 
    <i>The Donna Reed Show</i>, and was released on Columbia
    Pictures' Colpix Records label. The song also has a sequel song
    entitled "Johnny Loves Me" (which tells the story of how the
    girl won Johnny's heart). The song had previously been recorded
    by Georgia Lee on the Decca label.</p>
      <p>Darlene Love and her group, the Blossoms, sang backup vocals
    on the track. Fabares is quoted in 
    <i>The Billboard Book of Number One Singles</i>by Fred Bronson
    as saying she was intimidated by Love's group and their
    "beautiful" voices and was terrified at the prospect of
    becoming a recording artist, as she did not consider herself a
    singer.</p>
      <p>Although Fabares' career as a singer came to an end (though
    her career as an actress stayed strong for three decades)
    within a few years of "Johnny Angel" after she was unable to
    come up with another Top 20 hit, the song has become an oldies
    radio airplay favorite. The Carpenters covered "Johnny Angel"
    in 1973 as part of a medley of oldies on side two of their
    album 
    <i>Now and Then</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
