<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/When_I%27m_with_You 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/When_I%27m_with_You</songId>
   <title>When I'm with You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheriff_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Sheriff</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1989-02-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Sheriff</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1983 , 1989</released>
   <formats>
      <format>45 record</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Arena Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Capitol</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Arnold Lanni</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Stacy Haydon</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"When I'm with You" is a power ballad by Canadian arena rock
    band Sheriff. It hit number one in the United States in 1989,
    four years after the band separated.</p>
      <p>After the success of When I'm With You, Freddy Curci (Lead
    Vocalist) and Steve DeMarchi (Lead Guitarist) tried to put
    Sheriff back together, but the other band members would not
    cooperate and would not release permission for the use of the
    band name. This caused Curci and DeMarchi to form the band
    ALIAS.</p>
      <p>The following year, in 1990, ALIAS released a self-titled
    debut album. It contained the very successful power ballad
    "More Than Words Can Say", "Haunted Heart", "Waiting for Love"
    and "Perfect World".</p>
      <p>Freddy Curci is listed in the Guinness Book of Records for
    holding the longest note in a pop song, timed and submitted by
    a Houston university, at the ending line of "When I'm with
    You."</p>
      <p>Sheriff's keyboardist Arnold Lanni wrote the song after
    meeting Valeri Brown and falling in love with her. 'I sat down,
    put my coffee on the piano, tinkled some ivories, and four
    minutes later 80 percent of the song was written. On
    Valentine's Day I played the song for Valerie and said, "I
    don't have anything, this is all I can give you right now. It's
    yours." Valeri loved the song; two years later she married
    me.'</p>
      <p>Lanni also played the song to his bandmembers in Sheriff.
    "The band really liked it, so we started playing it live. That
    was one of the last songs we recorded when we did the record.
    The producer said, 'Is there anything else?' I said, 'There's
    this song we play, it's kind of a wimpy song.' So we played it
    for him and he said 'Yeah, that's kind of nice.'"</p>
      <p>"When I’m With You" is also the title of an unrelated song
    from the 30’s and 40's sung by Shirley Temple and Alice
    Faye.</p>
      <p>"When I'm with You" was originally released as the third
    single off Sheriff's debut album. It entered the Hot 100 on May
    14, 1983, and peaked at number sixty-one four weeks later.
    Disappointed by the lack of success, the band broke up.</p>
      <p>In 1988, a disc jockey in Las Vegas began playing the song,
    and other stations followed. This encouraged Capitol Records to
    re-release the song as a single. On February 4, 1989, "When I'm
    with You" hit number one in the United States.</p>
      <p>By that time Lanni and bassist Wolf Hassell had formed a duo
    named Frozen Ghost, and declined to re-form the group.
    Sheriff's lead vocalist Freddy Curci and guitarist Steve
    DeMarchi subsequently formed the band Alias and reached the top
    of the charts again the following year with the similar
    number-two hit "More Than Words Can Say".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
