<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Sounds_of_Silence 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Sounds_of_Silence</songId>
   <title>The Sounds of Silence</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simon_%26_Garfunkel</artistId>
      <artistName>Simon &amp; Garfunkel</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1966-01-01</week>
      <week>1966-01-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/4b/Soundofsilence.jpg/200px-Soundofsilence.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Simon-Garfunkel+The-Sounds-of-Silence.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Sounds of Silence</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 1965</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>March 10, 1964 (main track); June 15, 1965 (overdub)</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Folk Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:05</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Paul Simon</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Tom Wilson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Sounds of Silence" is the song that propelled the 1960s
    folk music duo Simon and Garfunkel to popularity. It was
    written in February 1964 by Paul Simon in the aftermath of the
    November 22, 1963 assassination of U.S. President John F.
    Kennedy.</p>
      <p>The song features Simon on acoustic guitar and both Simon
    and Garfunkel singing. It was originally recorded as an
    acoustic piece for their first album 
    <i>Wednesday Morning, 3 A.M.</i>but on the initiative of the
    record company was later overdubbed with electric instruments
    and rereleased as a single in September 1965. The single
    reached number one on New Year's Day 1966 and was included in
    the 1966 album 
    <i>Sounds of Silence</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was originally called "The 
    <i>Sounds</i>of Silence" and is titled that way on the early
    albums in which it appeared and on the single. In later
    compilations it was retitled "The Sound of Silence". Both the
    singular and the plural form of the word appear in the lyrics.
    In his book 
    <i>Lyrics 1964–2008</i>Simon has the title in the singular.</p>
      <p>Simon began working on the song sometime after the Kennedy
    assassination. He had made progress on the music but had yet to
    get down the lyrics. On 19 February 1964 the lyrics apparently
    coalesced, and Simon showed the new composition to Garfunkel
    the same day. Shortly afterward, the duo began to perform it at
    folk clubs in New York. They recorded it for the first time on
    March 10, and included the track on their debut album, 
    <i>Wednesday Morning, 3 A.M.</i>, released that October. The
    album flopped upon its release, and the duo split up, with
    Simon going to England for much of 1965. There he often
    performed the song solo in folk clubs, and recorded it for a
    second time on his solo LP in May 1965, 
    <i>The Paul Simon Songbook</i>.</p>
      <p>In the meantime, Simon and Garfunkel's producer at Columbia
    Records in New York, Tom Wilson, had learned that the song had
    begun to receive airplay on radio stations in Boston,
    Massachusetts and around Gainesville and Cocoa Beach,
    Florida.</p>
      <p>On June 15, 1965, immediately after the recording session of
    Bob Dylan's "Like a Rolling Stone," Wilson took the original
    track of Simon &amp; Garfunkel, and overdubbed the recording
    with electric guitar (played by Al Gorgoni), electric bass (Bob
    Bushnell), and drums (Bobby Gregg), and released it as a single
    without even consulting Simon or Garfunkel. For the B-Side
    Wilson used an unreleased track he cut with the duo a few
    months earlier on which they had tried out a more
    "contemporary" sound. "Sounds of Silence"/"We've Got a Groovey
    Thing Going" entered the U.S. pop charts in September 1965 and
    slowly began its ascent.</p>
      <p>Simon learned that it had entered the charts minutes before
    he went on stage to perform at a club in Copenhagen, Denmark,
    and in the later fall of 1965 he returned to the United States.
    By the end of 1965 and the first few weeks of 1966, the song
    reached number one on the U.S. charts. Simon and Garfunkel then
    reunited as a musical act, and included the song as the title
    track of their next album, 
    <i>Sounds of Silence</i>, hastily recorded in December 1965 and
    released in January 1966 to capitalize on their success. The
    song propelled them to stardom and, together with two other
    top-five (in the U.S.) hits in the summer of 1966, "I Am a
    Rock" and "Homeward Bound," ensured the duo's fame. In 1999,
    BMI named "The Sounds of Silence" as the 18th-most performed
    song of the 20th century. In 2004 it was ranked #156 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>'s list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time, one of the duo's three songs on the list.</p>
      <p>The original acoustic stereo mix of the song had the duo's
    vocals on separate channels, spotlighting the delicate
    harmonies. When the 'rock' version was mixed to stereo, Wilson
    mixed the vocals in the middle, which is not as clear sounding
    as the original acoustic version.</p>
      <p>On the duo's 1968 album 
    <i>Bookends</i>, the track "Save the Life of My Child" features
    a distorted sample of Art Garfunkel's "
    <i>Hello darkness my old friend, I've come to talk with
    you</i>" line from the original recording of "The Sounds Of
    Silence"). At 2:16 in the song somebody says "echo me"</p>
      <p>In 2009, the song was released (along with "I Am a Rock") as
    a downloadable track for rhythm video game Rock Band 2</p>
      <p>"The Sounds of Silence" was released on Columbia Records as
    45 rpm catalog number #4-43396. The single has several
    variations:</p>
      <p>The song was used three times in the film 
    <i>The Graduate</i>, played during the opening credits and the
    closing footage, and in the film 
    <i>Bobby</i>, where it is played during Robert Kennedy's
    victory speech at the Ambassador Hotel, just before his
    assassination. It can also be heard in the last episodes of the
    Japanese dorama 
    <i>Taiyo to Umi no Kyoshitsu</i>. It can also be heard in the
    comedy film 
    <i>Old School</i>when Will Ferrell gets shot with a
    tranquilizer dart and falls into the pool going into a dream
    daze. Additionally, the song is played in the film 
    <i>Kingpin</i>, following sexual activity between protagonist
    Roy Munson and his landlady. In the film 
    <i>More American Graffiti</i>, the 1966 recording is heard
    playing after a rather large bar fight. In 2009's 
    <i>Watchmen</i>the song is featured on the soundtrack for the
    film and used during The Comedian's funeral.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
