<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holding_Back_the_Years 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holding_Back_the_Years</songId>
   <title>Holding Back the Years</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simply_Red</artistId>
      <artistName>Simply Red</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-07-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/3b/Simply_Red_-_Holding_Back_the_Years.jpg/200px-Simply_Red_-_Holding_Back_the_Years.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Simply-Red+Holding-Back-the-Years.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Picture Book</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1985 (original release) , 1986 (re-release)</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop / Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:27</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>WEA Records , Elektra Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mick Hucknall</writer>
      <writer>Neil Moss</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Holding Back the Years" is the 7th track of Simply Red's
    debut studio album 
    <i>Picture Book</i>. The song was a smash success for the group
    and quickly rose to the top of charts across the world. It
    remains their most successful single, reaching number one on
    the Billboard Hot 100 for the week ending July 12, 1986. It is
    one of two Simply Red songs (the other being their cover of "If
    You Don't Know Me by Now") to reach number one. "Holding Back
    the Years" reached #2 in the UK and was a worldwide hit. It had
    initially been released in the UK the year before, reaching
    #51.</p>
      <p>Frontman of the group, Mick Hucknall, wrote the song when he
    was seventeen, while living at his father's house. The chorus
    did not come to him until many years later. His mother left the
    family when he was three; the upheaval caused by this event
    inspired him to write the song.</p>
      <p>He recorded a version of the song with his first group the
    Frantic Elevators in 1982 but the real success came when the
    Simply Red version was released in 1985. In 2005, a brand-new
    stripped down acoustic version of the song was released on the
    album 
    <i>Simplified</i>, and this version received heavy airplay on
    smooth jazz radio stations.</p>
      <p>The video for this song was filmed in the English coastal
    town of Whitby and the famous scene where Hucknall watches the
    coastal view from his window can be seen on the cover of the
    single, in its music video and, for a brief time, in the music
    video of "If You Don't Know Me by Now". The other band members
    play the role of the local cricket team who see Hucknall off on
    his journey.</p>
      <p>
         <i>EastEnders</i>&amp; 
    <i>Shameless</i>actress Maggie O'Neill made her acting debut as
    the schoolteacher in the video, where she is seen engaging in
    sexual foreplay in a church graveyard. Understandably, this
    causes great consternation to her pupils who witness their
    teacher's liaison whilst innocently playing.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
