<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Ballad_of_Davy_Crockett 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Ballad_of_Davy_Crockett</songId>
   <title>The Ballad of Davy Crockett " Bill Hayes</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>"Sincerely" McGuire Sisters</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1955-03-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Ballad of Davy Crockett" is a song with music by George
    Bruns and lyrics by Tom W. Blackburn.</p>
      <p>The first recording of the song was made by Bill Hayes,
    quickly followed by versions by Fess Parker and Tennessee Ernie
    Ford (recorded February 7, 1955), all in 1955. All three
    versions made the Billboard charts: Hayes' version made #1 on
    the weekly chart (from March 26 through April 23, 1955) and #7
    for the year, Parker's reached #6 on the weekly charts and #31
    for the year, while Ford's peaked at #4 on the weekly country
    chart and #5 on the weekly pop chart and charted at #37 for the
    year. The song also reached #1 on the Cash Box charts, from
    March 26 through May 14, 1955. A contemporary version also
    exists of the famous Western singing group the Sons of the
    Pioneers. Over ten million copies of the song were sold.</p>
      <p>The song was introduced on the television miniseries 
    <i>Davy Crockett</i>, first telecast on December 15, 1954, on
    ABC's 
    <i>Disneyland</i>. Fess Parker played the role of Davy Crockett
    and continued in four other episodes made by Walt Disney
    Studios. Buddy Ebsen co-starred as Georgie Russell, and Jeff
    York played legendary boatman Mike Fink.</p>
      <p>To publicise the 1955 film 
    <i>Davy Crockett, King of the Wild Frontier</i>(released in
    Britain in 1956), Walt Disney Productions launched a massive
    marketing campaign in the UK in order to make the country's
    youth "Crockett conscious." There was already a "Crockett
    craze" in the U.S., where the episodes had become wildly
    popular. Crockett merchandise was produced 
    <i>en masse</i>, the most iconic item being the imitation
    coonskin cap. The craze became immensely popular amongst
    schoolchildren, and the ballad made its way across the
    Atlantic.</p>
      <p>The Crockett phenomenon is referenced in books of the time
    such as 
    <i>Back in the Jug Agane</i>, one of the Molesworth series by
    Geoffrey Willans and Ronald Searle.</p>
      <p>The craze was referenced in the film 
    <i>Back to the Future</i>, which is set predominantly in 1955.
    In the film, the Fess Parker version of the song is heard on a
    jukebox and, in a later scene, one of Lorraine Baines' brothers
    appears wearing a coonskin cap. The 2009 film 
    <i>Fantastic Mr. Fox</i>opens with the titular character
    playing the song on his belt radio.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
