<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Singing_the_Blues 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Singing_the_Blues</songId>
   <title>Singing the Blues " Guy Mitchell</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>"Singing the Blues" Guy Mitchell</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1956-12-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>, "Singing the Blues" is a popular song. It was written by
    Melvin Endsley and was published in 1956. Note that it is not
    related to the song "Singin' the Blues," written by Sam Lewis,
    Joe Young, Con Conrad and J. Russel Robinson and recorded by
    Frank Trumbauer and Bix Beiderbecke in 1927.</p>
      <p>The best-known recording of Endsley's song was released in
    October 1956 by Guy Mitchell, and spent nine weeks at #1 on the
    U.S. Billboard chart from December 8, 1956 - February 2, 1957.
    Mitchell's version was also number 1 in the U.K. for three
    (non-consecutive) weeks in early 1957.</p>
      <p>Two other charting versions of the song were released amost
    simultaneously with Mitchell's, one by U.K. cover specialist
    Tommy Steele &amp; The Steelmen, the other by U.S. country
    singer Marty Robbins.</p>
      <p>Tommy Steele's version of "Singing The Blues" made #1 in the
    UK Singles Chart for one week on 11 January 1957, sandwiched by
    two of the weeks that Guy Mitchell's version of the same song
    topped the charts. Steele's recording of the song was not a
    chart success in the US.</p>
      <p>The Marty Robbins version made it to number one on the U.S.
    C&amp;W Best Seller charts for thirteen weeks in 1956/57, and
    peaked at number seventeen on the U.S. pop charts .</p>
      <p>The song is often revived, and on three occasions new
    recordings of "Singing The Blues" have become U.K. Top 40 hits.
    These latter-day hit versions were by Dave Edmunds (1980);
    Daniel O'Donnell (1994); and Cliff Richard &amp; The Shadows
    (2009).</p>
      <p>Other notable cover versions include a 1960 recording by
    Bill Haley &amp; His Comets, a 1963 version by Dean Martin, and
    a 1971 version by Black Oak Arkansas. The tune was also sung by
    Vivian Vance and William Frawley (Ethel and Fred of 
    <i>I Love Lucy</i>fame) for a Ford Motor Company television
    commercial promoting the Edsel.</p>
      <p>A cover version was released by Marie Osmond on her 1975
    album 
    <i>In My Little Corner of the World.</i>(MGM SE4944)</p>
      <p>"Singing the Blues" was performed live by Paul McCartney on
    the MTV show 
    <i>Unplugged</i>in 1991 and included on the subsequent
    soundtrack, 
    <i>Unplugged (The Official Bootleg)</i>.</p>
      <p>A cover version was released by the Kentucky Headhunters on
    their 1997 album 
    <i>Stompin' Grounds</i>.</p>
      <p>A "Singing The Blues" cover version was released by Gene
    Summers on his 1981 French album 
    <i>Gene Summers In Nashville</i>(Big Beat Records BBR-0011)</p>
      <p>The first line of this song is famously the last line of
    London Calling by the Clash, cut short and echoed in the final
    mix of the song (I never felt so much a-like, a-like,
    a-like...).</p>
      <p>This song has also famously been used by Sheffield Wednesday
    fans since the 'Boxing Day Massacre', on December 26, 1979,
    where the Owls beat their fierce rivals, Sheffield United, 4-0.
    One of the Wednesday scorers on that day,Terry Curran, even
    recorded a version of the song and it is still used at
    Hillsborough to this day.</p>
      <p>A version appears on the Crimson Moon CD by Bert Jansch.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by Cliff Richard and the Shadows
    and released as a single by Cliff Richard and the Shadows on
    14th September 2009.</p>
      <p>Birmingham City-supporting radio presenters Tom Ross and Ian
    Danter released a version to celebrate Birmingham's promotion
    to the Premier League.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
