<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Everyday_People_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Everyday_People_(song)</songId>
   <title>Everyday People</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sly_%26_the_Family_Stone</artistId>
      <artistName>Sly &amp; the Family Stone</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1969-02-15</week>
      <week>1969-02-22</week>
      <week>1969-03-01</week>
      <week>1969-03-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/05/Epic-sly-everyday-people.jpg/200px-Epic-sly-everyday-people.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Sly-the-Family-Stone+Everyday-People.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Stand!</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 1968</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1968</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Psychedelic Soul / Funk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:22</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic , 5-10407</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Sly Stone</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Sly Stone</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Everyday People" is a 1968 song by Sly &amp; the Family
    Stone. It was the first single by the band to go to number one
    on the Soul singles chart and the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 chart.
    It held that position, on the Hot 100, for four weeks from
    February 15, 1969, until March 14, 1969, and is remembered as a
    popular song of the 1960s. Like nearly all of Sly &amp; the
    Family Stone's songs, Sly Stone was credited as the sole
    songwriter.</p>
      <p>The song is one of Sly Stone's pleas for peace and equality
    between differing races and social groups, a major theme and
    focus for the band. The Family Stone featured caucasians Greg
    Errico and Jerry Martini in its lineup, as well as females Rose
    Stone and Cynthia Robinson; making it the first major
    integrated band in rock history. Sly &amp; the Family Stone's
    message was about peace and equality through music, and this
    song reflects the same.</p>
      <p>Unlike the band's more typically funky and psychedelic
    records, "Everyday People" is a mid-tempo number with a more
    mainstream pop feel. Sly, singing the main verses for the song,
    explains that he is "no better / and neither are you / we are
    the same / whatever we do."</p>
      <p>Sly's sister Rose Stone sings bridging sections that mock
    the futility of people hating each other for being tall, short,
    fat, skinny, white, black, or anything else. The bridges of the
    song contain the line "different strokes for different folks,"
    which became a popular catchphrase in 1969.</p>
      <p>For the chorus, all of the singing members of the band (Sly,
    Rosie, Larry Graham, and Sly's brother Freddie Stone) proclaim
    that "I am everyday people," meaning that each of them (and
    each listener as well) should consider himself or herself as
    parts of one whole, not of smaller, specialized factions.</p>
      <p>Bassist Larry Graham contends that the track featured the
    first instance of the "slap bass" technique, which would become
    a staple of funk and other genres. The technique involves
    striking a string with the thumb of the right hand (or left
    hand, for a left-handed player) so that the string collides
    with the frets, producing a metallic "clunk" at the beginning
    of the note. Later slap bass songs – for example, Graham's
    performance on "Thank You (Falettinme Be Mice Elf Again)" –
    expanded on the technique, incorporating a complementary "pull"
    or "pop" component.</p>
      <p>"Everyday People" was included on the band's classic album 
    <i>Stand!</i>(1969), which sold over three million copies. It
    is one of the most covered songs in the band's repertoire, with
    versions by Aretha Franklin, The Staple Singers, Joan Jett (a
    modest hit in the year of 1983), The Supremes &amp; The Four
    Tops, Peggy Lee, Belle &amp; Sebastian, and Pearl Jam, among
    many others. Hip-hop group Arrested Development used the song
    as the basis of their 1992 hit, "People Everyday," which
    reached #2 on the UK Singles Chart and #8 on the Hot 100. Dolly
    Parton's previously unreleased 1980 cover of the song was
    included as a bonus track on the 2009 reissue of her 
    <i>9 to 5 and Odd Jobs</i>album. it was also prominently
    featured in a series of television commercials for Toyota
    automobiles in the late 1990s and most recently for Smarties
    candy in 2008. Rolling Stone ranked "Everyday People" as #145
    on their list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All Time.</p>
      <p>On the 2005 Sly &amp; the Family Stone tribute album 
    <i>Different Strokes by Different Folks</i>, Maroon 5 performs
    a cover of "Everyday People", accompanied by samples from the
    original.</p>
      <p>"Everyday People" is prominently featured in the opening
    sequence of the 2008 romantic comedy film 
    <i>Definitely, Maybe</i>. The lead character, Will Hayes
    (played by Ryan Reynolds), calls it his "perfect song" for that
    particular day. It can also be heard in the film 
    <i>Purple Haze</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
