<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Family_Affair_(Sly_%26_the_Family_Stone_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Family_Affair_(Sly_%26_the_Family_Stone_song)</songId>
   <title>Family Affair</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sly_%26_the_Family_Stone</artistId>
      <artistName>Sly &amp; the Family Stone</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1971-12-04</week>
      <week>1971-12-11</week>
      <week>1971-12-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/53/Sly-family-affair-single2.jpg/200px-Sly-family-affair-single2.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Sly-the-Family-Stone+Family-Affair.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>There's a Riot Goin' On</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 1971</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1971</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:06</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic , 5-10805</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Sly Stone</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Sly Stone</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Family Affair" is a 1971 number-one hit single recorded by
    Sly &amp; the Family Stone for the Epic Records label. Their
    first new material since the double a-sided single "Thank You
    (Falettinme Be Mice Elf Agin)"/ "Everybody is a Star" nearly
    two years prior, "Family Affair" became the fourth and final
    number-one pop hit for the band. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine later ranked the song #138 on
    their list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All Time.</p>
      <p>Released on November 6, 1971, "Family Affair" was markedly
    different from the earlier Sly &amp; the Family Stone hits.
    "Family Affair" is a somber, Wurlitzer electric piano based
    record with a rhythm box (or drum machine) providing the
    rhythm, making it the first number-one hit to feature a
    programmed rhythm track. Sly Stone and his sister Rose sing
    lead on the song. The lyrics reflect the good and bad aspects
    of being family, with Sly delivering his part in a low
    funk-styled tone instead of his earlier gospel-based shout.</p>
      <p>"Family Affair" was the most successful hit of Sly &amp; the
    Family Stone's career, peaking at number-one on the Billboard
    Hot 100 for three weeks, while achieving the same on the
    Billboard R&amp;B Singles chart for five weeks.. The band's
    long-awaited fifth album, 
    <i>There's a Riot Goin' On</i>, debuted at number one on the
    Billboard album charts during the same period. 
    <i>There's a Riot Goin' On</i>was typified by a deep, dark
    style of funk, evident in "Family Affair", that earned the
    album a place as one of the most influential albums of all
    time.</p>
      <p>Partially recorded in a Winnebago, Sly Stone did not utilize
    the Family Stone for this recording, with the exception of his
    sister Rose. His friends Billy Preston and Bobby Womack played
    the keyboard and guitar lines, respectively, for the song, with
    Sly playing the bass and programming the rhythm box.</p>
      <p>According to the biography 
    <i>Sly and the Family Stone: An Oral History</i>, Sly Stone
    felt that this song wasn't strong enough to be released as a
    single. His manager and Epic Records had to convince him
    otherwise.</p>
      <p>"Family Affair" has been heavily covered, with versions by
    Tyrone Davis, The Brothers Johnson, MFSB, Iggy Pop, Bunny
    Wailer, and many more. The song's drum machine-created rhythm
    was duplicated in several early to mid-1970s recordings, in
    particular The Temptations' "Let Your Hair Down" (1973), and
    Stevie Wonder's "You Haven't Done Nothin'" (1974).</p>
      <p>A retooled cover was done in 1993 by Shabba Ranks featuring
    Patra and Terri &amp; Monica as a single for the 
    <i>Addams Family Values</i>soundtrack. This version charted on
    the Billboard pop chart at number 84, number 16 on the R&amp;B
    chart, and number-six on the Hot Rap Tracks chart. Madonna
    featured this song as an intro to "Keep It Together" on her
    Blond Ambition Tour in 1990. Prince samples the song on his
    track 'Y Should Eye Do That When Eye Can Do This?'</p>
      <p>In 2005, John Legend, Joss Stone, and Van Hunt recorded a
    cover featuring elements of the original recording for 
    <i>Different Strokes by Different Folks</i>, a Sly &amp; the
    Family Stone tribute/remix album. This version of "Family
    Affair" won the 2007 Grammy Award for Best R&amp;B Performance
    by a Duo or Group with Vocals.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
