<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thank_You_(Falettinme_Be_Mice_Elf_Agin) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thank_You_(Falettinme_Be_Mice_Elf_Agin)</songId>
   <title>Thank You (Falettinme Be Mice Elf Agin)" / "Everybody Is a Star</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sly_%26_the_Family_Stone</artistId>
      <artistName>Sly &amp; the Family Stone</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1970-02-14</week>
      <week>1970-02-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/3/30/Sly-fam-thankyou-star.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Sly-the-Family-Stone+Thank-You-Falettinme-Be-Mice-Elf-Agin-Everybody-Is-a-Star.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Greatest Hits</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 1969</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1969</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:48</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic , 5-10555</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Sly Stone</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Sly Stone</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Thank You (Falettinme Be Mice Elf Agin)", released in
    December 1969, is a 1970 hit single recorded by Sly &amp; the
    Family Stone, recognized as one of the greatest and most
    influential funk songs of all time. The song, double a-sided
    with "Everybody is a Star", reached number one on the soul
    single charts for five weeks, and reached number one on the
    Billboard Hot 100 in February 1970. "Thank You" was intended to
    be included on an in-progress album with "Star" and "Hot Fun in
    the Summertime"; the LP was never completed, and the three
    tracks were instead included on the band's 1970 
    <i>Greatest Hits</i>LP. "Thank You" and "Star", the final
    Family Stone recordings issued in the 1960s, marked the
    beginning of a twenty-month gap of releases from the band,
    which would finally end with the release of "Family Affair" in
    1971.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Rolling Stone</i>ranked the song #402 on their list of the
    "500 Greatest Songs of All Time".</p>
      <p>The title is a unique way of writing what would otherwise be
    "thank you for letting me be myself again." The lyrics can be
    interpreted as a summation of both the career of Sly &amp; the
    Family Stone to date, as well as a portrait of the era at the
    transition from the 1960s into the 1970s. The third verse
    contains specific references to the group's previous hit songs,
    "Dance To The Music" "Everyday People", "Sing a Simple Song",
    and "You Can Make It If You Try." The song features co-lead
    vocals from Sly Stone, Rose Stone, Freddie Stone, and Larry
    Graham.</p>
      <p>Bassist Larry Graham, prominently uses the then-new
    technique of slap bass on this recording.</p>
      <p>The first act to cover "Thank You (Falettinme Be Mice Elf
    Agin)" was Sly &amp; the Family Stone itself. The cover,
    recorded in 1971 for 
    <i>There's a Riot Going On</i>, completely transformed the song
    into a seven-minute track titled "Thank You For Talkin' to Me
    Africa". Although the lyrics, vocalists, and musicians are all
    the same, the record itself is as different from the original
    "Thank You" as that record had been from the earlier Family
    Stone records. The song's lyrics are delivered in a depressed
    tone with heavily reverberated vocals, over a slow,
    stripped-down deep funk backing track.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by many other acts, including The
    Jackson 5, Widespread Panic, Robert Randolph and the Family
    Band, Victor Wooten, Dave Matthews &amp; Friends, the Dave
    Matthews Band, Magazine, Merl Saunders &amp; the Rainforest
    Band. UK hip hop act Big Brovaz covered the song for use in the
    Warner Bros. film 
    <i>Scooby-Doo 2: Monsters Unleashed</i>. They also sampled the
    song to create the theme song for the movie, "We Wanna Thank
    You (The Things You Do)". Gladys Knight and the Pips and
    several others have also covered the song. Freddie Stone's
    guitar riff from the bridging sections of the song is
    immediately recognizable to modern audiences as the backbone of
    Janet Jackson's 1989 hit single "Rhythm Nation". Van Morrison
    does an expanded version of the song in a medley with "See Me
    Through" and "Soldier of Fortune" on his album 
    <i>A Night in San Francisco</i>. Rapper Vanilla Ice also
    sampled "Thank You" as part of the soundtrack to his film, 
    <i>Cool as Ice</i>.</p>
      <p>The song recently appeared in 2007 during the closing
    credits of "Shrek the Third", as performed by Donkey (Eddie
    Murphy) and Puss in Boots (Antonio Banderas).</p>
      <p>The Rolling Stones have rehearsed the song in May 2007 in
    Vilvoorde, Belgium before their A Bigger Bang Eur07 Tour, but
    the song has not been performed in concert.</p>
      <p>Soundgarden performed this song numerous times on their 1989
    tour as well as during their John Peel session that year.</p>
      <p>Dave Matthews Band has performed the song numerous times on
    their 2008 summer tour. It was often featured as the final song
    of the encore. It was released on Live Trax Vol. 13, from St.
    Louis, Missouri, and also on Live at Mile High Music Festival,
    from their set in Commerce City, Colorado. It was the last song
    LeRoi Moore performed as a member of Dave Matthews Band. That
    performance of the song is featured on 
    <i>Live Trax Vol. 14</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2009, the song became a staple on the North American leg
    of U2's 360 Tour in support of their album "No Line On The
    Horizon."</p>
      <p>, Sly Stone plays bass guitar on the "Thank You For Talkin
    To Me, Africa" version from 
    <i>There's a Riot Goin' On</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
