<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_I_Want_for_Christmas_Is_My_Two_Front_Teeth 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_I_Want_for_Christmas_Is_My_Two_Front_Teeth</songId>
   <title>All I Want for Christmas (Is My Two Front Teeth)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spike_Jones</artistId>
      <artistName>Spike Jones</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1949-01-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"All I Want for Christmas Is My Two Front Teeth" is a
    novelty Christmas song written in 1944 by Donald Yetter Gardner
    (b. 20 August 1913, Portland, Pennsylvania – d. 15 September
    2004, Brockton, Massachusetts) while teaching music at public
    schools in Smithtown, New York. He asked his second grade class
    what they wanted for Christmas, and noticed that almost all of
    the students had at least one front tooth missing as they
    answered in a lisp. Gardner wrote the song in 30 minutes. In a
    1995 interview, Gardner said, "I was amazed at the way that
    silly little song was picked up by the whole country." The song
    was published in 1948 after an employee of Witmark music
    company heard Gardner sing it at a music teachers
    conference.</p>
      <p>The song was originally recorded by Spike Jones &amp; His
    City Slickers on December 6, 1948, with lead vocal by George
    Rock. That version reached the top of pop charts in 1949. The
    song has also been recorded by numerous other singers and
    performers, including George Strait, Danny Kaye with The
    Andrews Sisters, The Platters, The Kelly Family, Nat King Cole
    (reportedly Gardner's favorite version), The Chipmunks, the
    Hampton String Quartet and the cast of 
    <i>Sesame Street</i>.</p>
      <p>Drag performer and singer RuPaul parodied the song on her
    Christmas album 
    <i>Ho, Ho, Ho</i>. In RuPaul's version, which is an up-tempo
    electronica/disco style, she lists the various plastic surgery
    procedures she wants for Christmas, so she can, as she sings,
    "Look real purdy!".</p>
      <p>Country music parodist Cledus T. Judd parodied the song on
    his 2002 Christmas album 
    <i>Cledus Navidad</i>. Titled "All I Want For Christmas Is Two
    Gold Front Teef", Judd's parody is performed in rap.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
