<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ballad_of_the_Green_Berets 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ballad_of_the_Green_Berets</songId>
   <title>Ballad of the Green Berets</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barry_Sadler</artistId>
      <artistName>SSgt Barry Sadler</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1966-03-05</week>
      <week>1966-03-12</week>
      <week>1966-03-19</week>
      <week>1966-03-26</week>
      <week>1966-04-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/b/bc/Ballad_of_the_Green_Berets.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/SSgt-Barry-Sadler+Ballad-of-the-Green-Berets.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Ballads of the Green Berets</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1966</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Ballad</genre>
      <genre>Patriotic</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:27</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA Victor</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Robin Moore</writer>
      <writer>Staff Sgt. Barry Sadler</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Ballad Of The Green Berets" is a patriotic song in the
    ballad style about the Green Berets, an elite special force in
    the U.S. Army. It is one of the very few songs of the 1960s to
    cast the military in a positive light and yet it became a major
    hit, reaching number one on the Billboard Charts for five weeks
    in 1966. It was also a multi-market smash, reaching #1 on
    Billboard's Easy Listening chart, and #2 on Billboard's Country
    survey.</p>
      <p>The song was written by Robin Moore and Staff Sgt. Barry
    Sadler, while the latter was recuperating from a leg wound
    suffered as a medic in the Vietnam War. Moore also wrote a
    non-fiction book, 
    <i>The Green Berets</i>, about the force.</p>
      <p>The recording of the song was the number one hit in the
    United States for five weeks in 1966 and was the number
    twenty-one song of 1960s, despite the later unpopularity of the
    Vietnam War. Refer to United States Army Special Forces in
    popular culture</p>
      <p>It has sold over nine million singles and albums. It was the
    top single of a year in which the British Invasion, led by the
    Beatles and the Rolling Stones, dominated the U.S. charts.</p>
      <p>It is currently used as one of the four primary marching
    tunes of the Fightin' Texas Aggie Band.</p>
      <p>The song is heard in a choral rendition by Ken Darby in the
    1968 John Wayne film 
    <i>The Green Berets</i>, which was based on Moore's book. The
    score of the movie was never released as an album until 
    <i>Film Score Monthly</i>released it in 2005. A film tie-in
    featuring artwork from the film and a cover version by Ennio
    Morricone was released in Europe, though the other tracks on
    the album were soundtracks from 
    <i>A Fistful of Dollars</i>and 
    <i>For a Few Dollars More</i>.</p>
      <p>The song appears in the films 
    <i>More American Graffiti</i>and 
    <i>Canadian Bacon</i>. It can be heard in the gun show scene
    from the 2002 film 
    <i>Showtime</i>, and in the film 
    <i>Jesus' Son</i>, in a scene that features a hitch-hiking Jack
    Black.</p>
      <p>There are many cover versions of the song including in
    different languages rewritten to reference local units, these
    include</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
