<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/We_Built_This_City 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/We_Built_This_City</songId>
   <title>We Built This City</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jefferson_Starship#Starship</artistId>
      <artistName>Starship</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1985-11-16</week>
      <week>1985-11-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/4d/WeBuiltThisCity.jpg/200px-WeBuiltThisCity.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Starship+We-Built-This-City.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Knee Deep in the Hoopla</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 30, 1985</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1984-1985</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock Pop Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:56</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Grunt/RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bernie Taupin</writer>
      <writer>Martin Page</writer>
      <writer>Dennis Lambert</writer>
      <writer>Peter Wolf</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Peter Wolf</producer>
      <producer>Jeremy Smith</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"We Built This City" is a song written by Bernie Taupin,
    Martin Page, Dennis Lambert, and Peter Wolf, and originally
    recorded by the group Starship and released as its debut single
    on August 30, 1985. The lyrics were written by Bernie Taupin,
    best known for his longtime collaboration with Elton John. The
    song features Mickey Thomas and Grace Slick on lead vocals, and
    the single version reached number one on the U.S. Hot 100 on
    November 16, 1985, and also number one on the U.S. Top Rock
    Tracks chart and number twelve in the United Kingdom. The song
    was engineered by Grammy-winning producer Bill Bottrell and
    arranged by Bottrell and Jasun Martz.</p>
      <p>In April 2004, the song was listed as "the #1 Worst Song
    Ever" by magazine.</p>
      <p>According to Slick, the song was written about early-1970s
    Los Angeles. The radio station in a late interlude references
    "The City By the Bay", "The City That Rocks" and "The City That
    Never Sleeps", meaning San Francisco, Cleveland, and New York
    City, respectively.</p>
      <p>MTV executive and former D.J. Les Garland provided the D.J.
    voice-over during the song's bridge.</p>
      <p>The song was also released without the traffic report and
    D.J. interaction during the song's bridge (the B-side of the
    promotional 45-rpm record). Local stations were encouraged to
    make local versions. New York City, for example, included a
    traffic report describing conditions on the George Washington
    Bridge and LG73 in Vancouver, British Columbia included a
    traffic report overlooking the Lion's Gate Bridge.</p>
      <p>Janice Cruz, later from the Brooklyn-based indie rock trio
    Dark Room NYC, appears in the first verse of the video.</p>
      <p>The song references radio pioneer Guglielmo Marconi playing
    the "mamba". While "mamba" has no musical connotations, there
    is a dance known as the mambo.</p>
      <p>The ranking of the song as the worst song ever was in
    conjunction with a VH1 Special of 
    <i>The 50 Most Awesomely Bad Songs...Ever</i>. In order to
    qualify for the distinction, the songs on the list had to be a
    popular hit at some point, thus disqualifying many songs that
    would by general consensus be considered much worse. 
    <i>Blender</i>editor Craig Marks said of the song, "It purports
    to be anti-commercial but reeks of '80s corporate-rock
    commercialism. It's a real reflection of what practically
    killed rock music in the '80s."</p>
      <p>
         <i>Blender</i>magazine contributor Russ Heller later set a
    record for listening to "We Built This City" continuously for
    24 hours. He was encased in a Plexiglas booth—without
    earplugs—beginning Friday, October 13, 2006 at 8:00 a.m. at a
    Best Buy store in New York City.</p>
      <p>Australian punk band Frenzal Rhomb covered "We Built This
    City" on their 2004 album 
    <i>For the Term of Their Unnatural Lives</i>.</p>
      <p>It was later covered by LMP on its album 
    <i>A Century of Song</i>, and by the hip hop group The
    Diplomats. The British band Half Man Half Biscuit recorded a
    song called "We Built This Village on a Trad Arr Tune". In the
    Swedish Idol 2008, Johan Palm and Robin Ericsson did a cover of
    this song.</p>
      <p>Bristol native Kid Carpet often breaks into a parody of the
    song during his live shows, using the lyrics "We built this
    city on slavery" in reference to the History of Bristol.</p>
      <p>American punk band A Wilhelm Scream wrote a song called We
    Built This City on Debts and Booze.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
