<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whatever_You_Like_(T.I._song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whatever_You_Like_(T.I._song)</songId>
   <title>Whatever You Like</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/T.I.</artistId>
      <artistName>T.I.</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2008-09-06</week>
      <week>2008-09-13</week>
      <week>2008-09-20</week>
      <week>2008-10-04</week>
      <week>2008-10-11</week>
      <week>2008-11-01</week>
      <week>2008-11-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/b2/T.I._Whatever_You_Like_Paper_Trail_Single.jpg/200px-T.I._Whatever_You_Like_Paper_Trail_Single.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/T-I+Whatever-You-Like.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Paper Trail</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 29, 2008  (2008-07-29) (digital download)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Music download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2008</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Electrohop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:09 (album version)</length>
      <length>3:40 (radio edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Grand Hustle , Atlantic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Clifford Harris</writer>
      <writer>James Scheffer</writer>
      <writer>David Siegel</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jim Jonsin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Whatever You Like" is a song by American recording artist
    T.I., released as the first single from his sixth studio album,
    
    <i>Paper Trail</i>. The song was written by T.I., James
    Scheffer and David Siegel and produced by Jim Jonsin. "Whatever
    You Like" served as the third single from 
    <i>Paper Trail</i>in the UK with a release date of 1 June 2009
    . It was named the 16th most successful song from 2000 to 2009,
    on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade.</p>
      <p>This song is T.I.'s most successful single to date, having
    been on top of the charts for seven nonconsecutive weeks, and
    in the top 3 of the charts for over 3 total months (12 weeks).
    It has also been certified 4x platinum by the RIAA.</p>
      <p>"Whatever You Like" was written by T.I., James Scheffer and
    David Siegel. The song was produced by Jim Jonsin, who produced
    Lil Wayne's single, "Lollipop". The production team worked on
    the track when T.I. was in the studio recording his album.</p>
      <p>The instrumentals for "Whatever You Like" are based on a
    beat of lead synthesizers and drum pattern. The song runs for
    4:09 and speaks about a man who can buy a woman whatever she
    asks for, as well encourages the woman to ask for anything she
    wants. It is a slow rap song and the chorus contains breathy
    soft, singing vocals. The song also contains a sample from
    "Redemption", the opening and closing theme song from the film 
    <i>Rocky II</i>.</p>
      <p>A second version of "Whatever You Like" was released in
    order to be suitable for radio stations. The original version
    of the track features T.I saying "Late night sex so wet, it's
    so tight", while the radio version replaces these lyrics with
    the line "Baby I can treat you so special, so nice" and
    replacing the line "Thing gets so wet/ it hits so right" with
    "Girl, you smell so fresh, and look so nice". The music video
    also uses the edited lyrics. Other changes include replacing
    the line "Tell 'em other broke niggas be quiet" with "Tell 'em
    other broke jokers be quiet" and muting the word "brain" in the
    line "Brain so good/ could've sworn you went to college" due to
    a slang definition of the word referring to oral sex.</p>
      <p>The music video was filmed in Malibu, Los Angeles,
    California, and was directed by Dave Meyers. Reagan
    Gomez-Preston plays T.I.'s love interest. Cameos include Jackie
    Long, Lil Duval, Jim Jonsin, and T.I.'s girlfriend Tameka
    Cottle.</p>
      <p>The video starts with a girl working at a fast food
    restaurant. When T.I. comes into the restaurant, after ordering
    hot wings, he hands the girl a folded up paper with his number
    on it. She then calls him and T.I. invites her to his house.
    The video then shows her living the high life, with T.I.
    treating her to private jet rides, fancy dinners, and buying
    her many expensive gifts, such as a new car. The video also
    show clips of her living her normal life with her boyfriend.
    Right before the end of the video, it shows the release date of
    T.I.'s new album 
    <i>Paper Trail</i>while T.I. is on the red carpet with his
    girl. At the end it is revealed it is all merely a fantasy
    sequence the girl was having, and T.I. had only handed the girl
    a hundred dollar bill, not his number.</p>
      <p>Reviews for "Whatever You Like" were generally favorable.
    Jared W. Dillon of Sputnikmusic called the song a "more
    sophisticated take" on Lil Wayne's "Lollipop". Ian Cohen of
    Pitchfork Media noted that the song contained virtually no
    rapping while praising the synth-driven beat. 
    <i>Blender</i>magazine ranked the song number 14 their Top 144
    Songs of 2008 and number 18 on MTV's Commercially Released
    Hip-Hop Singles.</p>
      <p>"Whatever You Like" debuted at number 99 on the Hot 100. In
    its third week, it achieved the third biggest leap to number
    one in 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 chart history when it jumped 70
    positions, from number 71 to the top of the chart, breaking the
    record previously held by Maroon 5's "Makes Me Wonder", which
    jumped 64 to number one. It became T.I.'s first solo Hot 100
    number one of his career and his second overall following the
    Justin Timberlake song "My Love" where T.I. was a featured
    artist. The song's jump can be partially attributed to huge
    first week digital sales of 205,000, debuting at number one on 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Hot Digital Songs chart. The song held the
    number one position on the Hot 100 for three consecutive weeks,
    before being replaced by Pink's "So What." The following week
    the song knocked off "So What" to return to number one on the
    Hot 100, marking its fourth week overall at the top of the
    chart. It remained there for another week, marking its 5th week
    overall. The next week T.I. replaced himself at number one with
    the follow up single "Live Your Life" which hasn't been done
    since Usher in 2004 with the first and second singles off his
    album (Yeah! and Burn). After spending two weeks at number two
    on the Hot 100, "Whatever You Like" again topped the chart by
    knocking off "Womanizer" by Britney Spears, marking its 6th
    non-consecutive week at number one on the Hot 100. This was the
    first time a song returned to number one on the chart after the
    artist's follow up single had already spent time at number one
    ("Live Your Life" having already spent a week at number one).
    It is also only the third song to ever have three separate runs
    at number one on the Hot 100, following Chic's "Le Freak" in
    1979 and Leona Lewis' "Bleeding Love" earlier in 2008. The song
    retained the number one position the following week, bringing
    its total to seven non-consecutive weeks at number one.</p>
      <p>On the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs chart, "Whatever You Like"
    has peaked at number one, giving T.I. his thirteenth top ten on
    the chart, and second number one song. It has also reached
    number three on the Pop 100, giving T.I. his biggest solo pop
    hit. The song has become T.I.'s biggest radio hit as well,
    reaching number one on the Hot 100 Airplay chart, and number
    four so far on Mainstream Top 40. Overall it has topped over
    nine different 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts.</p>
      <p>Internationally, "Whatever You Like" debuted at number
    twenty-two on the Canadian Hot 100 and has thus far risen to
    number twelve. It made a strong debut on the Irish Singles
    Chart at number nineteen. In Australia, on the ARIA Singles
    Chart, it has so far peaked at number 15 and on the digital
    track chart at number 15. In New Zealand, the song made a
    massive jump from number 32 to number eight on the official
    RIANZ Chart. The following week it became his first number one
    in New Zealand and are certified by Platinum in that country.
    It also debuted at number sixty on the UK Singles Chart and
    peaked at number forty-seven due to strong download sales. It
    will be re-released as a full CD single release on 1 June 2009
    and has been added to the B-list at BBC Radio 1 .</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
