<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Music!_Music!_Music! 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Music!_Music!_Music!</songId>
   <title>Music! Music! Music!</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teresa_Brewer</artistId>
      <artistName>Teresa Brewer</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1950-03-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Music! Music! Music!" is a popular song written by Stephen
    Weiss and Bernie Baum and published in 1949.</p>
      <p>The biggest-selling version of the song was recorded by
    Teresa Brewer on December 20, 1949 and released by London
    Records as catalog number 604. It became a number 1 hit and a
    million-seller in 1950. A version recorded by British singer
    Petula Clark was popular in Australia the same year. An
    instrumental version was recorded by Bill Haley &amp; His
    Comets in 1959 and released as a single in 1960; it was the
    band's final release for Decca Records and was only a minor
    hit. The R&amp;B group The Sensations released an updated
    rendition in 1961., Melanie also covered the song on her 1976
    album 
    <i>Photograph</i>.</p>
      <p>Teresa Brewer recorded several renditions of the song during
    her career. The Coral label made a recording for their catalog,
    which had a larger orchestral arrangement and stronger beat.
    When she moved to the Philips label in 1962 they made a new
    recording in Nashville. In 1973 on the Amsterdam label a
    rendition with a strong rock and roll beat was produced. When
    she was with the RCA label in 1974-75, Brewer recorded an new
    version. In 1976 on the Signature label, Brewer recorded a
    disco version. Only the original London release was a chart
    hit. She sang this song on the muppet show as well as many
    others. She also sang Tomorrow, the hit song from one the
    Broadway play, Annie.</p>
      <p>The song was also covered by The Happenings in the late
    60's</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
