<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seasons_in_the_Sun 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seasons_in_the_Sun</songId>
   <title>Seasons in the Sun</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terry_Jacks</artistId>
      <artistName>Terry Jacks</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1974-03-02</week>
      <week>1974-03-09</week>
      <week>1974-03-16</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>5</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1961</released>
   <recorded>22 February 1961</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Chanson</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Philips</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jacques Brel</writer>
      <writer>Rod McKuen (English lyrics "Seasons in the Sun")</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>5</i>
      </p>
      <p>Kingston Trio 1963, Coachmen, The Fortunes, Pearls Before
    Swine, Cat Stevens, Westlife, Spell</p>
      <p>"Seasons in the Sun" is an English-language adaptation of
    the song "Le Moribond" by Belgian singer-songwriter Jacques
    Brel. It became a worldwide hit in 1974 for Terry Jacks and
    became a Christmas Number 1 in 1999 for Westlife.</p>
      <p>The song is a dying protagonist's farewell to relatives and
    friends.</p>
      <p>The original French-language song included sarcasm and
    references to his wife's infidelity - but these are often
    missing from the English-language adaptation. Jacks's recording
    was released in Canada and the United States early in the year,
    and rose to number one in America by March 2. Earlier
    recordings had been released by The Kingston Trio, the British
    band The Fortunes in 1968 and by Pearls Before Swine in
    1970/71.</p>
      <p>The song was recorded in Vancouver, B.C. by Jacks and his
    wife at the time, Susan Jacks (the Poppy Family), shortly
    before their marriage ended. When the Beach Boys decided not to
    finish recording it, Terry and Susan made the decision to
    record it themselves and release it under Terry's name. The
    distinctive twangy guitar riff has frequently been attributed
    to Link Wray, however Wray himself always denied playing on the
    recording. Jacks released it on his own label and it soon
    topped the record charts in the U.S. (where it was released on
    Bell Records), Canada and the UK and sold over six million
    copies worldwide.</p>
      <p>Jacks' version was released in the United States in December
    1973, and made the Billboard Hot 100 a month later. On March 2,
    1974, the song began a three-week run at No. 1 atop the Hot
    100, and remained in the top 40 until almost Memorial Day
    weekend. Although he released several other singles that were
    successful in Canada, "Seasons in the Sun" would become Jacks'
    only major solo hit in the United States.</p>
      <p>This is an English translation of the original final verse
    by Jacques Brel:</p>
      <p>Terry Jacks omits the original third and fourth verses and
    adds this verse, which could refer to either a daughter or a
    young girlfriend:</p>
      <p>Apart from the versions noted above, there have been
    numerous cover versions of the song. Generally, these use the
    same translation as the Terry Jacks version, and thus inherit
    that version's less harsh interpretation of the song's
    storyline.</p>
      <p>Swedish dansband Vikingarna covered the song in Swedish in
    1974, as "Sommar varje dag". The song has also been covered by
    Spell, The Beach Boys, Bad Religion, Too Much Joy, Black Box
    Recorder, Nirvana, Indochine, Pearls Before Swine, Alcazar, Me
    First and the Gimme Gimmes, Westlife, Second Run, Television
    Personalities and Gob featuring Blink 182. In 2006, fictional
    boyband BoyTown recorded the song for the film of the same
    title. It featured at the end of the film, with all five
    members singing it to their loved ones through a dream-like
    cloud motif.</p>
      <p>The Kingston Trio version omits the third and fourth verses
    of the original version and adds this verse:</p>
      <p>, The Westlife version has been their fourth limited edition
    single from their self-titled debut album 
    <i>Westlife</i>and included on A-side together with "I Have A
    Dream" which became their first remake #1 on Christmas 1999 and
    continued reigning up to first week of year 2000.</p>
      <p>The cover Nirvana did featured complete mix-up of the
    members, with Kurt Cobain on drums and vocals, Dave Grohl on
    bass and Krist Novoselic on guitar.</p>
      <p>Another cover version, by Bobby Wright (son of Johnnie
    Wright and Kitty Wells), reached the Top 40 of the 
    <i>Billboard magazine</i>Hot Country Singles chart in 1974.</p>
      <p>The earliest single recording may well have been the
    Manchester based Coachmen's version recorded At EMI's Abbey
    Road Studios in July 1966 and released on Columbia DB8057 in
    November 1966.</p>
      <p>The song was used by Shabba Ranks and Crystal in their big
    reggae hit "Twice My Age", with the words in the chorus (sung
    by Crystal) changed to:</p>
      <p>Contrary to some reports and assumptions, American born
    singer Scott Walker did not cover the song, despite being a
    prolific singer of translated Jacques Brel songs in his early
    solo career.</p>
      <p>Spanish versions (entitled '
    <i>Epocas de Sol</i>, 
    <i>Estaciones en el Sol</i>or 
    <i>Etapas de mi Vida</i>) Many versions were released by Grupo
    Montéz de Durango, Lalo Rodarte, Grupo Topazz, Jorge Duarte,
    and Ana y Jaime,amongst others.</p>
      <p>There is a German version called 
    <i>Adieu Emile</i>by Klaus Hoffmann published in 1975. The
    translated lyrics are very close to the French ones but the
    melody is slightly altered and the whole song has a 3/4
    beat.</p>
      <p>Italian singer/songwriter Roberto Vecchioni recorded an
    Italian version called "Stagioni nel sole" for his 2005
    acoustic, jazz-influenced live album 
    <i>Il Contastorie</i>. The title of his version is a literal
    translation of "Seasons in the Sun", but both the lyrics
    (rewritten by Vecchioni himself) and the musical structure of
    Vecchioni's version are much closer to Jacques Brel's original
    (including a vague allusion to the protagonist's wife being
    unfaithful) than to the Jacks/McKuen version. The accompaniment
    of this rendition, played on acoustic guitar, piano and double
    bass (with no drums) is march-like, similar to Brel's, and
    pointedly un-romantic.</p>
      <p>The band Beirut have covered "Le Moribond" live on a number
    of occasions. A version performed for KEXP was recorded along
    with "My Family's Role in the World Revolution" for the third
    track on the Elephant Gun EP. Beirut perform a cover that is
    quite faithful to the original Jacques Brel version,
    maintaining the French lyrics and the marching up-beat
    tempo.</p>
      <p>The Finnish schlager singer Arto Sotavalta have recorded a
    Finnish version of the song called Päivät kuin unta (Eng. Days
    like dreams). The Finnish translation is very similar to the
    English text.</p>
      <p>The Vietnamese version, called "Nhung ngay nang dep"
    (Beautiful sunny days) was translated by musician Pham Duy. The
    translated lyrics are quite similar to the English one. A
    number of overseas Vietnamese singers have covered this
    version.</p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Brian McFadden •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Simon Cowell •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Louis Walsh •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Ronan Keating •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Steve Mac •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Wayne Hector</span>, 
    <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Cecelia Ahern •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Jodi Albert •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Kevin McDaid •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap;">Kerry Katona</span>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
