<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_Lovin%27 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_Lovin%27</songId>
   <title>Good Lovin'</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Rascals</artistId>
      <artistName>The Young Rascals</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1966-04-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>February 21, 1966</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>February 1, 1966</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rhythm And Blues</genre>
      <genre>Blue Eyed Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:31</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Rudy Clark</writer>
      <writer>Arthur Resnick</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>The Rascals with Arif Mardin</producer>
      <producer>Tom Dowd</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Good Lovin'" is a song written by Rudy Clark and Arthur
    Resnick that was a number one hit single for The Young Rascals
    in 1966.</p>
      <p>The song was first recorded in 1965 by R&amp;B/novelty
    artists The Olympics, but was only moderately successful at
    best, reaching number 81 on the Billboard Pop Singles chart.
    The tale is told that Rascal Felix Cavaliere heard it on a New
    York City radio station and the group added it to their concert
    repertoire. Co-producer Tom Dowd captured this live feel on the
    recording, even though the group did not think the performance
    held together well.</p>
      <p>Divining a mixture of garage rock and white soul, the
    Rascals' "Good Lovin'" jumped out of radios with a "One - Two -
    Three -" count-in, high-energy instrumentation, and insistent
    call-and-response vocals from Cavaliere and the band:</p>
      <p>These were followed by an organ break from Cavaliere, and a
    full stop false ending that was suddenly popular at the time
    (cf. "Rain" and "Monday, Monday") — all in two and a half
    minutes. "Good Lovin'" rose to the top of the Billboard Pop
    Singles chart in the spring of 1966 and represented The Young
    Rascals' first real hit. It was also the first of three #1 hits
    for the group.</p>
      <p>"Good Lovin'" is one of The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame's 500
    Songs that Shaped Rock and Roll, and was ranked number 325 on
    Rolling Stone's 500 Greatest Songs of All Time list. Writer
    Dave Marsh placed it at number 108 in his 1989 book 
    <i>The Heart of Rock and Soul: The 1001 Greatest Singles Ever
    Made</i>, saying it is "the greatest example ever of a remake
    surpassing the quality of an original without changing a thing
    about the arrangement," and that "'Good Lovin' all by itself is
    enough to dispel the idiotic notion that rock and roll is
    nothing more than white boys stealing from blacks."</p>
      <p>The song has since been performed and recorded by a number
    of artists, including Tommy James and the Shondells (1966),
    Herbie Mann (1966), The Who (1965), and Bobby McFerrin (several
    versions). The Grateful Dead made it a workhorse of their
    concert rotation, sung in their early years by Ron "Pigpen"
    McKernan and then later sung by Bob Weir. The Weir rendition
    was recorded for the group's 1978 
    <i>Shakedown Street</i>album and came in for a good amount of
    criticism: 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>said it "feature[d] aimless ensemble work
    and vocals that Bob Weir should never have attempted." "Good
    Lovin'" was the title song of a 2008 album by Australian singer
    David Campbell.</p>
      <p>The Rascals' "Good Lovin'" was also featured in the 1986
    third season "Atomic Shakespeare"/
    <i>Taming of the Shrew</i>episode of , with Bruce Willis
    singing the Cavaliere vocal, as well as the 1987 first season 
    <i>Wiseguy</i>episode "No One Gets Out of Here Alive".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
