<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue_Moon_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue_Moon_(song)</songId>
   <title>Blue Moon</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Marcels</artistId>
      <artistName>The Marcels</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1961-04-03</week>
      <week>1961-04-10</week>
      <week>1961-04-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Elvis Presley</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 31, 1956</released>
   <recorded>Jul 5, 1954-Jan 30, 1956</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock N' Roll</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:31</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Richard Rodgers</writer>
      <writer>Lorenz Hart</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Blue Moon" is a classic popular song. It was written by
    Richard Rodgers and Lorenz Hart in 1934, and has become a
    standard ballad.</p>
      <p>The lyrics presumably refer to an English idiomatic
    expression: "once in a blue moon" means very rarely. (The
    origin of the expression is unclear; see article blue moon.)
    The narrator of the song is relating a stroke of luck so
    unlikely that it must have taken place under a blue moon. The
    title relies on a play on words, since Blue is also the colour
    of melancholy, and indeed the narrator is sad and lonely until
    he (or she) finds love.</p>
      <p>Richard Rodgers and Lorenz Hart were contracted to
    Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer in May 1933. They were soon commissioned to
    write the songs for 
    <i>Hollywood Party</i>, a film that was to star many of the
    studio's top artists. Richard Rodgers later recalled "One of
    our ideas was to include a scene in which Jean Harlow is shown
    as an innocent young girl saying - or rather singing - her
    prayers. How the sequence fitted into the movie I haven't the
    foggiest notion, but the purpose was to express Harlow's
    overwhelming ambition to become a movie star ('Oh Lord, if
    you're not busy up there,/I ask for help with a prayer/So
    please don't give me the air...')." The song was not even
    recorded and MGM Song #225 "Prayer (Oh Lord, make me a movie
    star)" dated June 14, 1933, was registered for copyright as an
    unpublished work on July 10, 1933.</p>
      <p>Lorenz Hart wrote new lyrics for the tune to create a title
    song for the 1934 film 
    <i>Manhattan Melodrama</i>: "Act One:/You gulp your coffee and
    run;/Into the subway you crowd./Don’t breathe, it isn’t
    allowed". The song, which was also titled 
    <i>It's Just That Kind Of Play</i>, was cut from the film
    before release, and registered for copyright as an unpublished
    work on March 30, 1934. The studio then asked for a nightclub
    number for the film. Rodgers still liked the melody so Hart
    wrote a third lyric: 
    <i>The Bad In Every Man</i>, (Oh, Lord …/I could be good to a
    lover,/But then I always discover/The bad in ev’ry man), which
    was sung by Shirley Ross made up in blackface. The song, which
    was also released as sheet music, was not a hit.</p>
      <p>After the film was released by MGM, Jack Robbins — the head
    of the studio's publishing company—decided that the tune was
    suited to commercial release but needed more romantic lyrics
    and a punchier title. Hart was initially reluctant to write yet
    another lyric but he was persuaded. The result was "Blue
    moon/you saw me standing alone/without a dream in my
    heart/without a love of my own".</p>
      <p>In actual fact, there is another verse that comes before the
    usual start of the song. Both Eric Clapton &amp; Rod Stewart
    used it in their recent versions of the song. The last line of
    this extra verse is "Life was a bitter cup for the saddest of
    all men."</p>
      <p>Robbins licensed the song to 
    <i>Hollywood Hotel</i>, a radio program that used it as the
    theme. On January 15, 1935, Connee Boswell recorded it for
    Brunswick Records. It subsequently was featured in at least
    seven more MGM films including the Marx Brothers' 
    <i>At the Circus</i>and 
    <i>Viva Las Vegas</i>. Part of the song was in the musical 
    <i>Grease</i>.</p>
      <p>Since 1934, the song has been recorded by many performers. A
    partial list follows:</p>
      <p>Mel Tormé's version was the only one that actually reached
    the Billboard magazine charts; it was released by Capitol
    Records as catalog number 15428. It first reached the Billboard
    magazine Best Seller chart on April 8, 1949 and lasted 5 weeks
    on the chart, peaking at #20. The record was a two-sided hit,
    as the flip side "Again" also charted.</p>
      <p>The first crossover recording to rock and roll came from
    Elvis Presley, but the version that really stirred things up
    came from The Marcels, a doo-wop group. In 1961 the Marcels had
    3 songs to record and needed one more. Producer Stu Phillips
    did not like any of the other songs except one that had the
    same changes as Heart and Soul and Blue Moon. He asked them if
    they knew either, and one knew Blue Moon and taught it to the
    others, though with the bridge or release (middle section - "I
    heard somebody whisper...") wrong. The famous introduction to
    the song ("bomp-baba-bomp" and "dip-da-dip") was an excerpt of
    an original song that the group had in its act. The record
    reached #1 on the Billboard Pop chart for three weeks and #1 on
    the R&amp;B charts. The Marcels version of "Blue Moon" sold a
    million copies, and is featured in 
    <i>The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame's 500 Songs that Shaped Rock
    and Roll</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1967, Eric Clapton used a portion of the song in his
    guitar solo from Cream's hit "Sunshine of Your Love." Bob Dylan
    covered the song on his 
    <i>Self Portrait</i>album in 1970. In 1978, an arrangement by
    Jeff Funk was used in the film 
    <i>Grease</i>. This has been followed by a country version from
    The Mavericks. More recently, it has been recorded by Rod
    Stewart. Elkie Brooks. Cybill Shepherd sang "Blue Moon" on an
    episode of 
    <i>Moonlighting</i>(the detective agency in that show was
    called "Blue Moon Investigations".)</p>
      <p>In Jim Jarmusch's 1989 film "Mystery Train", the three
    distinct stories that make up the narrative are linked by a
    portion of Elvis Presley's version of "Blue Moon" (as heard on
    a radio broadcast) and a subsequent offscreen gunshot, which
    are heard once during each story, revealing that the three
    stories occur simultaneously in real time.</p>
      <p>A version suitable for performance by chamber choir arranged
    by David Blackwell is in the collection "In the Mood" published
    by Oxford University Press.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
