<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lion_Sleeps_Tonight 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lion_Sleeps_Tonight</songId>
   <title>The Lion Sleeps Tonight</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tokens</artistId>
      <artistName>The Tokens</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1962-01-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1961</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Doo Wop</genre>
      <genre>World Music</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:38</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Solomon Linda</writer>
      <writer>Hugo Peretti</writer>
      <writer>Luigi Creatore</writer>
      <writer>George David Weiss</writer>
      <writer>Albert Stanton</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Lion Sleeps Tonight" is an acclaimed song recorded by
    The Tokens and written as 
    <i>Mbube</i>by Solomon Linda.</p>
      <p>"Mbube" (Zulu for "lion") was first recorded by its writer,
    Solomon Linda, and his group, the Evening Birds, in 1939. Gallo
    Record Company paid Linda a single fee for the recording and no
    royalties. "Mbube" became a hit throughout South Africa and
    sold about 100,000 copies during the 1940s. The song became so
    popular that Mbube lent its name to a style of African a
    cappella music, though the style has since been mostly replaced
    by isicathamiya (a softer version).</p>
      <p>Alan Lomax brought the song to the attention of Pete Seeger
    of the folk group The Weavers. It was on one of several records
    Lomax lent to Seeger. In November 1951 after having performed
    the song for at least a year in their concerts the Weavers
    recorded their version entitled "Wimoweh", a mishearing of the
    original song's chorus of 'uyimbube' (meaning "you're a lion").
    Pete Seeger had made some of his own additions to the melody.
    The song was credited exclusively to Paul Campbell, a
    fictitious entity used by Howard Richmond to copyright material
    in the public domain.</p>
      <p>Pete Seeger explains in one recording, "it refers to an old
    legend down there, [about] their last king [of the Zulus], who
    was known as Shaka The Lion. Legend says, Shaka The Lion didn't
    die when Europeans took over our country; he simply went to
    sleep, and he'll wake up some day." (See "Senzenina / Wimoweh"
    on Seeger's 
    <i>With Voices Together We Sing (Live)</i>.) 
    <i>cf. sleeping hero</i>
      </p>
      <p>It was published by Folkways, a subsidiary of Richmond/TRO.
    The Weavers 1952 version, arranged by Gordon Jenkins, became a
    top-twenty hit in the U.S., and their live 1957 recording
    turned it into a folk music staple. This version was covered in
    1959 by The Kingston Trio.</p>
      <p>New lyrics to the song were written by George David Weiss,
    Luigi Creatore, and Hugo Peretti, based very loosely upon the
    meaning of the original song. The Tokens' 1961 cover of this
    version rose to number one on the Billboard Hot 100 and still
    receives fairly frequent replay on many American Oldies radio
    stations. In the UK, an up-tempo, yodel-dominated rendering was
    a top-ten hit for Karl Denver and his Trio. In 1971 Robert John
    also recorded this version, and it reached #3 on the Billboard
    Hot 100 in 1972. Since then, "Wimoweh" / "The Lion Sleeps
    Tonight" has remained popular and frequently covered.</p>
      <p>Pete Seeger later said in the book 
    <i>A Lion's Trail,</i>"The big mistake I made was not making
    sure that my publisher signed a regular songwriters’ contract
    with Linda. My publisher simply sent Linda some money and
    copyrighted The Weavers’ arrangement here and sent The Weavers
    some money."</p>
      <p>Seeger's publisher was The Richmond Organization (TRO),
    which also goes by a number of other names, including Ludlow,
    Cromwell, Essex, Hollis, Melody Trails, and Folkways Music
    Publishers. Since Solomon Linda's 1939 "Mbube" was apparently
    not under copyright protection, TRO founder Howard Richmond had
    himself claimed authorship to "Wimoweh" using a pseudonym, in
    this case "Paul Campbell". This was not illegal but was
    customary in the music business, the purpose of the pseudonym
    possibly being to avoid embarrassment, so that it wouldn't look
    like, for example, that Howie Richmond had claimed authorship
    for an old song like "Greensleeves" (a song he claimed author's
    royalties for under the name Jessie Cavanaugh). The songwriter
    and publisher's share of the royalties are customarily split
    50-50, with the performers, song pluggers', and agents' shares
    usually come out of the composer's half. By claiming author's
    rights, TRO thus secured for itself a portion of the
    songwriters' royalties as well as all of the publishers' share
    of the song's earnings.</p>
      <p>"Originally they were going to send the royalties to Gallo
    [a huge South African music publisher] ," Seeger recalled. "I
    said, 'Don't do that, because Linda won't get a penny.'"</p>
      <p>Anti-apartheid activists put Seeger in touch with a
    Johannesburg lawyer, who set forth into the forbidden townships
    to find Solomon Linda. Once contact was established, Seeger
    sent the Zulu a $1,000 check and instructed his publisher to do
    the same with all future payments. He was still bragging about
    it fifty years later. "I never got author's royalties on
    'Wimoweh'," Seeger said. "Right from '51 or '52, I understood
    that the money was going to Linda. I assumed they were keeping
    the publisher's fifty percent and sending the rest."</p>
      <p>Unfortunately, Solomon's family maintains that the money
    only arrived years later, and even then, it was nothing like
    the full writer's share Seeger was hoping to bestow.</p>
      <p>In 2000, South African journalist Rian Malan wrote a feature
    article for 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine, highlighting Linda's story and
    estimating that the song had earned U.S. $15 million for its
    use in the movie 
    <i>The Lion King</i>alone; this prompted the South African
    documentary 
    <i>A Lion's Trail</i>by François Verster that documented the
    song's history. Screened by PBS, in September 2006, the
    documentary won an Emmy Award.</p>
      <p>In July 2004, the song became the subject of a lawsuit
    between the family of its writer Solomon Linda, represented by
    Dr. Owen Dean of Spoor &amp; Fisher and Disney. The suit
    claimed that Disney owed $1.6 million in royalties for the use
    of "The Lion Sleeps Tonight" in the film and stage production
    of 
    <i>The Lion King</i>. Meanwhile, TRO/Folkways, publisher of The
    Weavers' "Wimoweh", began to pay $3,000 annually to Linda's
    heirs.</p>
      <p>In February 2006, Linda's heirs reached a legal settlement
    for an undisclosed amount with Abilene Music, who held the
    worldwide rights and had licensed the song to Disney. This
    settlement has applied to worldwide rights, not just South
    Africa, since 1987.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
