<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Papa_Was_a_Rollin%27_Stone 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Papa_Was_a_Rollin%27_Stone</songId>
   <title>Papa Was a Rollin' Stone</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Temptations</artistId>
      <artistName>The Temptations</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1972-12-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/50/Papa-rolling-stone-tempts.jpg/200px-Papa-rolling-stone-tempts.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Temptations+Papa-Was-a-Rollin-Stone.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>All Directions</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 28, 1972</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Hitsville USA (Studio A); May 15, June 14, June 22, &amp; June 28, 1972</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
      <genre>Psychedelic Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>6:54 (single edit)</length>
      <length>11:47 (album mix)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Motown , G 7121</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Norman Whitfield</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Papa Was a Rollin' Stone" is a soul song, written by Motown
    songwriters Norman Whitfield and Barrett Strong as a single for
    Motown act The Undisputed Truth in 1971. This version of "Papa"
    was released as a single in early 1972, and peaked at number
    sixty-three on the pop charts and number twenty-four on the
    R&amp;B charts.</p>
      <p>Later in 1972, Whitfield, who also produced the song, took
    "Papa Was a Rollin' Stone" and remade it as a twelve-minute
    record for The Temptations, which was a number-one hit on the
    Billboard Hot 100 and won three Grammy Awards in 1973. While
    the original Undisputed Truth version of the song has been
    largely forgotten, The Temptations' version of the song has
    been an enduring and influential soul classic. It was ranked
    #168 on Rolling Stone's list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time, one of the group's three songs on the list. In
    retrospect, The Temptations' Otis Williams considers "Papa" to
    be the last real classic the group recorded.</p>
      <p>Beginning with an extended instrumental introduction, each
    of the song's three verses is separated by extended musical
    passages, in which Whitfield brings various instrumental
    textures in and out of the mix. A solo plucked bass guitar
    part, backed by hi-hat cymbals drumming, establishes the
    musical theme, a simple three-note figure; the bass is
    gradually joined by other instruments, including a blues
    guitar, wah-wah guitar, Wurlitzer Electric Piano notes,
    handclaps, horns, and strings; all are tied together by the
    ever-present bass guitar line and repeating hi-hat rhythm. A
    very unusual thing about this song is that it uses only one
    chord throughout the entire song -- B-flat minor.</p>
      <p>Vocal duties are performed in a true ensemble style:
    Temptations singers Dennis Edwards, Melvin Franklin, Richard
    Street, Otis Williams and Damon Harris alternate vocal lines,
    taking the role of siblings questioning their mother about
    their now-deceased father; their increasingly-pointed
    questions, and the mother's repeated response ("Papa was a
    rollin' stone/wherever he laid his hat was his home/and when he
    died, all he left us was alone") paint a somber picture for the
    children who have never seen their father and have "never heard
    nothing but bad things about him."</p>
      <p>Friction arose during the recording of "Papa Was a Rollin'
    Stone" for a number of reasons. The Temptations didn't like the
    fact that Whitfield's instrumentation had been getting more
    emphasis than their vocals on their songs at the time, and that
    they had to press Whitfield to get him to produce ballads for
    the group. In addition, Dennis Edwards was angered by the
    song's first verse: "It was the 3rd of September/That day I'll
    always remember/'cause that was the day/that my daddy died".
    Edwards' father had died on that date, and although the song
    wasn't originally written for the Temptations, Edwards was
    convinced that Whitfield assigning him the line was
    intentional. Although Whitfield denied the accusation, he used
    it to his advantage: he made Edwards record the disputed line
    over and over again until Whitfield finally got the angered,
    bitter grumble he desired out of the usually fiery-toned
    Edwards (it was, however, one of the reasons Whitfield was
    eventually fired as the group's producer).</p>
      <p>The Temptations' version of "Papa Was a Rollin' Stone" set a
    precedent for extra-length "cinematic soul" song mixes, and
    future songs like Donna Summer's fourteen-minute "Love to Love
    You Baby" and the instrumentals of MFSB expanded upon the
    concept in the mid-1970s.</p>
      <p>A seven-minute edited version of "Papa Was a Rollin' Stone"
    was released as a single in September 1972. For this mono mix,
    congas were added to bolster the song's sparse percussion; this
    version appeared on the 1973 
    <i>Anthology</i>triple LP. The Temptations' box set 
    <i>Emperors of Soul</i>has the edited version in stereo, but
    without the congas. The b-side was the instrumental backing by
    The Funk Brothers without the Temptations' vocals (except for a
    single "Unngh!" at the end of the second verse). "Papa" rose to
    number one on the U.S. pop charts and number five on the U.S.
    R&amp;B charts, becoming the Temptations' final pop number-one
    hit. The song, the anchor of the 1972 Temptations album 
    <i>All Directions</i>, won three 1973 Grammys: its a-side won
    for Best R&amp;B Vocal Performance by a Group; its b-side won
    for Best R&amp;B Instrumental (awarded to Whitfield and
    arranger/conductor Paul Riser); and Whitfield and Barret Strong
    won for Best R&amp;B Song as the song's composers.</p>
      <p>A number of notable covers of "Papa Was a Rollin' Stone"
    have been recorded. A 1993 version by George Michael was
    released on the EP 
    <i>Five Live</i>. The group Was (Not Was) covered the song on
    their album 
    <i>Are You Okay?</i>(1990), and their version reached number
    twelve in the UK. Bill "Wolf" Wolfer created an electronic
    cover of the number for his 1982 debut album, 
    <i>Wolf</i>; Michael Jackson provided backing vocals.</p>
      <p>David Lindley and his band El Rayo-X covered the song on
    their 1988 album 
    <i>Very Greasy</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was covered by David Hernandez on American Idol
    (season 7) during the Top 10 males week and by Allison Iraheta
    on American Idol (season 8) during Motown week.</p>
      <p>Rockapella performed the song on their concert album 
    <i>Live in Japan</i>(2004); it is a staple at their live shows.
    George Baldi III, the current bass for Rockapella, sings
    lead.</p>
      <p>The Pioneers made a rocksteady cover of this song on a
    single produced by Joe Gibbs.</p>
      <p>Lee Ritenour recorded a version on the album 
    <i>Overtime</i>in 2005.</p>
      <p>Craig David Recorded a Version on His 2010 Cover Album
    "Signed Sealed Delivered"</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
