<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_You_Need_Is_Love 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_You_Need_Is_Love</songId>
   <title>All You Need Is Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1967-08-19</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>7 July 1967</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>25 June 1967 , Abbey Road Studios</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Baroque Pop</genre>
      <genre>Big Band</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:57</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Parlophone</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"All You Need Is Love" is a song written by John Lennon and
    credited to Lennon/McCartney. It was first performed by The
    Beatles on 
    <i>Our World</i>, the first live global television link.
    Watched by 400 million in 26 countries, the programme was
    broadcast via satellite on 25 June 1967. The BBC had
    commissioned the Beatles to write a song for the UK's
    contribution. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine ranked it at #362 in their 500
    greatest songs of all time.</p>
      <p>The Beatles were asked to come up with a song containing a
    simple message to be understood by all nationalities. "It was
    an inspired song and they really wanted to give the world a
    message," said Brian Epstein. "The nice thing about it is that
    it cannot be misinterpreted. It is a clear message saying that
    love is everything." According to journalist Jade Wright,
    "Lennon was fascinated by the power of slogans to unite people
    and never afraid to create art out of propaganda. When asked in
    1971 whether songs like Give Peace a Chance and Power to the
    People were propaganda songs, he answered: 'Sure. So was All
    You Need Is Love. I'm a revolutionary artist. My art is
    dedicated to change.'"</p>
      <p>The day before the 
    <i>Our World</i>broadcast, the Beatles decided that the song
    should be their next single. Released in the UK on 7 July, it
    went straight to number one and remained there for three weeks.
    It was similarly successful in the US after its release on 17
    July, reaching number one for a week. It was also included on
    the American LP version of 
    <i>Magical Mystery Tour</i>in November).</p>
      <p>The interviews on 
    <i>The Beatles Anthology</i>documentary series reveal that Paul
    McCartney and George Harrison were unsure whether the song was
    written for 
    <i>Our World</i>. However, George Martin and Ringo Starr assert
    it was. When asked, McCartney replied:</p>
      <p>"I don't think it was written specially for it. But it was
    one of the songs we had. [...] It was certainly tailored to it
    once we had it. But I've got a feeling it was just one of
    John's songs that was coming there. We went down to Olympic
    Studios in Barnes and recorded it and then it became the song
    they said, 'Ah. This is the one we should use.' I don't
    actually think it was written for it."</p>
      <p>For the broadcast, the Beatles were (except for Starr)
    seated on stools, accompanied by a small studio orchestra. They
    were surrounded by friends and acquaintances seated on the
    floor, who sang with the refrain during the fade-out, including
    Mick Jagger, Marianne Faithfull, Keith Richards, Keith Moon,
    Eric Clapton, Pattie Harrison, Jane Asher, Mike McCartney,
    Graham Nash, Gary Leeds and Hunter Davies.</p>
      <p>The performance was not completely live: The Beatles, the
    orchestra, and guests were overdubbing onto a pre-recorded
    rhythm track mainly consisting of piano, harpsichord, drums,
    and backing vocals. The full 
    <i>Our World</i>segment opens with the band and company
    listening to the raw backing track, as commentator Steve Race
    explained the process in voiceover. The live overdubs seem to
    include not only lead vocals, orchestra, and the improvised
    call-and-response, but also bass guitar, Harrison's guitar
    solo, and a second drum track — which seems to go out of time
    with the original track during the first few bars. At the
    beginning of the song, under "La Marseillaise," a tambourine is
    shaken, but this was mixed out and replaced with a drum roll
    before the single was released.</p>
      <p>Lennon, affecting indifference, was said to be nervous about
    the broadcast, given the potential size of the international TV
    audience. Dissatisfied with his singing, he re-recorded the
    solo verses for use on the single. Starr also overdubbed drums
    before the single was released, fixing the aforementioned
    timing problems and adding the drum roll.</p>
      <p>The programme was broadcast in ‘black-and-white’ (colour
    television had yet to commence broadcasting in Britain and most
    of the world). The Beatles' footage was colourised, based on
    photographs of the event, for 
    <i>The Beatles Anthology</i>documentary.</p>
      <p>Because of the worldwide broadcast, the song was given an
    international feel, opening with the French National anthem "La
    Marseillaise" omitting the first note, and including excerpts
    of other pieces during the long fade-out, including "two-part
    Invention #8 in F" by Johann Sebastian Bach (transposed to G
    and played on 2 piccolo trumpets), "Greensleeves" (played by
    the strings), Glenn Miller's "In the Mood" (played on a
    saxophone), one of the Beatles' seminal hits (particularly in
    Great Britain and the United States), "She Loves You" (ad
    libbed by Lennon and McCartney), and Jeremiah Clarke's "Prince
    of Denmark's March" lilting off at the end. Many sources,
    including Beatles' producer George Martin, have misremembered
    or misidentified the Bach quote as being from the "Brandenburg
    Concerto No. 2". Lennon can also be heard scatting what sounds
    like the title of "Yesterday", though others maintain he is
    saying "Yes, you can." (Interestingly, the vocal chart for this
    song on The Beatles: Rock Band lists the lyric as
    "yesterday")</p>
      <p>The structure of the song is complex. The main body (the
    verse) is in a 7/4 time signature with two measures of 7/4, one
    of 8/4, then back to 7/4 with the intro background vocals
    repeatedly singing "Love, love, love", over the top of which
    enter Lennon's lyrics:</p>
      <p>By contrast, the chorus is simple: "All you need is love",
    in 4/4 time repeated against the horn response but, each chorus
    has only seven measures as opposed to the usual eight, and the
    seventh is 6/4, then back to the verse in 7/4.</p>
      <p>"All You Need Is Love" remains one of only two songs (along
    with Pink Floyd's "Money" from 1973) written in 7/4 time to
    reach the top 20 in the United States.</p>
      <p>In the film 
    <i>Yellow Submarine</i>(1968), the second verse as well as the
    instrumental are deleted. Also, the last choruses are switched,
    the "all together now", and "everybody" coming first before the
    last group of choruses.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
