<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Easier_Said_Than_Done 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Easier_Said_Than_Done</songId>
   <title>Easier Said Than Done</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Essex</artistId>
      <artistName>The Essex</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1963-07-06</week>
      <week>1963-07-13</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Easier Said Than Done</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 1963</released>
   <formats>
      <format>vinyl single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Girl Group</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:08</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Roulette</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>William Linton</writer>
      <writer>Larry Huff</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Easier Said Than Done" is a popular song sung by The Essex
    that was a number-one song in the United States during the year
    1963. It topped the Billboard Hot 100 singles chart on
    July 6, 1963 and remained there for two weeks. The song
    was written by William Linton and Larry Huff.</p>
      <p>The Essex were active-duty members of the United States
    Marine Corps at the time, as was Linton, who wrote the song at
    the request of Essex member Walter Vickers. The song's rhythm
    was inspired by the sound of the teletype machines in the
    communications office of their Marine post. The group was not
    thrilled with the song, but recorded it for use as the b-side
    of their debut single, "Are You Going My Way". The recording
    was unusually short, and editing was used to repeat part of the
    recording; even so, the song was only a little over two
    minutes. The single was released in May 1963, but "Easier Said
    Than Done" quickly emerged as the more popular side. The song
    became a major hit with broad appeal, reaching number one on
    both the pop and rhythm and blues charts. . The song became the
    title track of the group's first album, which reached #113 on
    the Billboard album chart, becoming their only charting
    album.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
