<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Want_You,_I_Need_You,_I_Love_You 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Want_You,_I_Need_You,_I_Love_You</songId>
   <title>I Want You, I Need You, I Love You "/ "My Baby Left Me" Elvis Presley</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>"The Wayward Wind" Gogi Grant</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1956-07-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>May 12, 1956  (1956-05-12)</released>
   <recorded>Nashville on April 14, 1956  (1956-04-14)</recorded>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:37</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA Victor</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Maurice Mysels and Ira Kosloff</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Steve Sholes</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Want You, I Need You, I Love You" is a popular song
    written by Maurice Mysels and Ira Kosloff. It is perhaps best
    known for being Elvis Presley's second RCA single release. It
    was released in May, 1956 becoming Presley's second #1 single
    on the Country charts, and peaking at #3 on the Pop charts.</p>
      <p>In April 1956, 
    <i>Variety Magazine</i>reported that Presley's first RCA Victor
    single, 
    <i>Heartbreak Hotel</i>, had sold one million copies. RCA
    producer Steve Sholes was looking for a strong single to be the
    follow up, aware that there was not a lot of good material
    available. Due to Presley's busy touring schedule, Sholes
    needed to get him into the studio as soon as possible. Presley
    and his band chartered a small prop plane to Nashville for one
    day of recording between shows.</p>
      <p>En route from Amarillo, the plane developed engine trouble
    and fell through the sky several times. Upon arrival in
    Nashville on the morning of April 14, all four were shaken up.
    Presley arrived at RCA Studios with no ideas for the recording
    session and therefore had no choice but to take Sholes'
    suggestions, one of which was "I Want You, I Need You, I Love
    You".</p>
      <p>Being used to later working hours, coupled with his
    traumatic experience during his overnight flight, the recording
    session did not go well. Take after take was ruined for one
    reason or another and the band was not relaxed. Presley,
    usually a very quick study with a song, couldn't get the lyrics
    right. After 17 takes in three hours, Sholes decided Presley
    and the band weren't up for recording and sent them home.</p>
      <p>After the session, Sholes listened to the takes again. He
    wasn't happy with the results of what he considered to be an
    unprofessional and wasted session. It had cost $1,000 to fly
    Presley and his band in on a private flight, and Sholes wasted
    no time in letting Presley's manager, Colonel Tom Parker, know
    that he was unsatisfied with the work and required material
    urgently for a second album. He knew that with Presley's busy
    touring schedule it could be months before RCA Victor got him
    back into the studio.</p>
      <p>Performing what was a very rare and generally unsuccessful
    procedure for the 1950s, Sholes took parts of two takes he
    liked (takes 14 and 17) and cut and spliced them together to
    come up with a take worthy of release. His cuts were so
    seamless, nobody at RCA Victor could tell it wasn't from a
    single take.</p>
      <p>"I Want You, I Need You, I Love You" was backed with "My
    Baby Left Me" and was released on May 4, 1956. Pre-orders of
    over 300,000 were the biggest ever in the history of the label.
    <span class="Z3988"
               title="ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;rft.genre=book&amp;rft.btitle=&amp;rfr_id=info:sid/en.wikipedia.org:I_Want_You,_I_Need_You,_I_Love_You">

 
</span>At the time of its release, Presley had three songs in the
Top 20: "Heartbreak Hotel/I Was the One," "My Baby Left Me", and "I
Want You, I Need You, I Love You".
    <span class="Z3988"
               title="ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;rft.genre=book&amp;rft.btitle=&amp;rfr_id=info:sid/en.wikipedia.org:I_Want_You,_I_Need_You,_I_Love_You">

 
</span>On June 5, 1956 Presley performed the song on 
    <i>The Milton Berle Show</i>, as well as a raw version of
    "Hound Dog" that resulted in a negative reaction from both the
    media, and public watchdogs.</p>
      <p>Despite this negative publicity, the single was generally
    well received, peaking at #3 on the Pop chart and reaching #1
    on the Country chart. The song earned Presley his second Gold
    record, with sales in excess of 1.3 million.</p>
      <p>A small footnote in Presley history considering his previous
    single "Heartbreak Hotel" reigned the charts for eight weeks
    and his next two singles, the mega-selling double-sided hit
    "Don't Be Cruel"/"Hound Dog" and "Love Me Tender", would rule
    the charts for a combined 16 weeks.</p>
      <p>This song was the inspiration for the Meat Loaf single "Two
    Out of Three Ain't Bad". The song remains popular, as it is
    used for the themes of many organizations. The song
    particularly uses the lyrics: “I want you, I need you/But there
    ain't no way I'm ever gonna love you”.
    <span class="Z3988"
               title="ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Abook&amp;rft.genre=book&amp;rft.btitle=&amp;rfr_id=info:sid/en.wikipedia.org:I_Want_You,_I_Need_You,_I_Love_You">

 
</span>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
