<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Summer_in_the_City 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Summer_in_the_City</songId>
   <title>Summer in the City</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lovin%27_Spoonful</artistId>
      <artistName>The Lovin' Spoonful</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1966-08-13</week>
      <week>1966-08-20</week>
      <week>1966-08-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/33/Summer_in_the_City.jpg/200px-Summer_in_the_City.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Lovin-Spoonful+Summer-in-the-City.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Hums of the Lovin' Spoonful</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1966</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" 45rpm</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:41</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Kama Sutra</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mark Sebastian</writer>
      <writer>Steve Boone</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Paul Leka</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Summer in the City" is a 1966 hit single by The Lovin'
    Spoonful, written by Mark Sebastian (brother of John Sebastian)
    and Steve Boone. It came from their album, 
    <i>Hums of the Lovin' Spoonful</i>. It reached number one on
    the Billboard Hot 100 on August 13. The song featured a series
    of car horns, during the instrumental bridge, starting with a
    Volkswagen Beetle horn, and ending up with a jackhammer sound,
    in order to give the impressions of the sounds of the summer in
    the city. The song is ranked number 393 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s list of The 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time.</p>
      <p>The signature keyboard part is played on a Hohner Pianet,
    and the organ is a Vox Continental.</p>
      <p>When at Blair Academy, Mark Sebastian submitted the lyrics
    as a poem for the literary magazine. That poem, entitled
    "Summer In the City," had the refrain "but at night it's a
    different world, go out and find a girl, come on, come on and
    dance all night, despite the heat it'll be alright, and babe
    don't you know it's a pity, the days can't be like the night,
    in the summer in the city." His older brother John changed the
    slower verses to a more upbeat model, keeping the title and the
    refrain. Mark's part remains as he wrote it, words and music.
    Bassist Steve Boone added the instrumental coda in the
    middle.</p>
      <p>The song was featured on 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>episode "Papa's Got a Brand New Badge", 
    <i>Only Fools and Horses</i>episode "Miami Twice", in the
    opening scenes of the Bruce Willis action film 
    <i>Die Hard: With a Vengeance</i>, in a 2006 Gatorade
    commercial, the 1994 PBS documentary 
    <i>Baseball: A Film by Ken Burns</i>, in the 1989 movie 
    <i>The Karate Kid, Part III</i>, in an advert for the UK
    retailer Marks &amp; Spencer and in a commercial for Dutch
    brewer Grolsch. The song was used in the Debenhams advert
    "Actor". The song was also featured on the television show 
    <i>Family Ties</i>, when Steven Keaton (Michael Gross) sings
    the first few lyrics while narrating a home movie.</p>
      <p>On a VH1 Classic episode of 
    <i>Classic Albums</i>featuring 
    <i>Disraeli Gears</i>by Cream, it was asserted that the
    predominant guitar riff of the song "Tales of Brave Ulysses"
    from 
    <i>Disraeli Gears</i>was inspired by the keyboard riff of
    "Summer in the City."</p>
      <p>The song was featured in German art-director Wim Wenders'
    first film, 1970's 
    <i>Summer in the City</i>. Comedians Horatio Sanz and Fred
    Armisen sang the song on the 2004 season finale of 
    <i>Saturday Night Live</i>during a sketch that contained
    different cast members singing songs that had a summer theme.
    "Summer in the City" was used as background music on American
    Idol Season 8 during tryouts in Phoenix, Arizona.</p>
      <p>Cover versions of the song include BB King in 1972, Quincy
    Jones in 1973, Canadian Rockers "The Stampeders" on their 1975
    Album "Steamin", Tim Curry in 1982, Joe Cocker in 1993, and The
    Stranglers on their 1997 album 
    <i>Written in Red</i>. In 2000, Joe Jackson released a live
    album titled 
    <i>Summer in the City: Live in New York</i>, which opens with a
    cover of the song. The band Eat released a cover of the song in
    1989. Country music artist Larry Stewart recorded it on his
    1999 album 
    <i>Learning to Breathe</i>. The Butthole Surfers covered the
    song on "Music for Our Mother Ocean (MOM)" Series No. 3
    released in 1999. Styx covered the song on their "Big Bang
    Theory" released in 2005. It was also sampled by Dan Le Sac Vs
    Scroobius Pip in 2006 for their song "First Time We Met Musik".
    A modified version of the chorus was used in the third single
    Thru Ya City from Art Official Intelligence: Mosaic Thump by De
    La Soul, Feat. D.V. Alias Khrist. In 2008, Barry Hay (The
    leadsinger of Golden Earring) covered this song together with
    the Metropole Orchestra.</p>
      <p>The Quincy Jones cover of "Summer in the City" has been
    sampled by Massive Attack in the song "Exchange" from their
    acclaimed album 
    <i>Mezzanine</i>, Nightmares on Wax in his song "Night's
    Introlude" on the album 
    <i>Smokers Delight</i>, and also by The Pharcyde on their
    seminal hit "Passin' Me By" from the album 
    <i>Bizarre Ride II the Pharcyde</i>. It has also been sampled
    by Black Moon on their 1994 song "Reality" and also sampled by
    Joe on the remix to his 2001 hit "Stutter". Another cover, by
    the Gutter Brothers appeared on the soundtrack to the 
    <i>Only Fools and Horses</i>film "Miami Twice". The song has
    also been covered by UK jazz-dance act, Incognito on the 2006
    album 
    <i>Bees + Things + Flowers.</i>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
