<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Just_My_Imagination_(Running_Away_with_Me) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Just_My_Imagination_(Running_Away_with_Me)</songId>
   <title>Just My Imagination (Running Away with Me)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Temptations</artistId>
      <artistName>The Temptations</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1971-04-03</week>
      <week>1971-04-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/7/77/Just-my-imagination-tempts-45.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Temptations+Just-My-Imagination-Running-Away-with-Me.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Sky's the Limit</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 14, 1971</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Hitsville USA (Studio A); November 24, 1970 and December 3, 1970</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:54</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Gordy , G 7105</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Norman Whitfield</writer>
      <writer>Barrett Strong</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Norman Whitfield</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Some Girls</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Just My Imagination (Running Away with Me)" is a song by
    American soul group The Temptations. Released on the Gordy
    (Motown) label, and produced by Norman Whitfield, it features
    on the group's 1971 album, 
    <i>Sky's the Limit</i>. When released as a single, "Just My
    Imagination" became the third Temptations song to reach number
    one on the US Hot 100. The single held the number one position
    on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Pop Singles Chart for two weeks in 1971, from
    March 27 to April 10. "Just My Imagination" also held the
    number-one spot on the R&amp;B Singles chart for three weeks,
    from February 27 to March 20.</p>
      <p>Today, "Just My Imagination" is considered one of the
    Temptations' signature songs, and is notable for recalling the
    sound of the group's 1960s recordings. It is also the final
    Temptations single to feature founding members Eddie Kendricks
    and Paul Williams. During the process of recording and
    releasing the single, Kendricks left the group to begin a solo
    career, while the ailing Williams was forced to retire from the
    act for health reasons. In 2004, 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine listed "Just My Imagination" as
    number 389 on its list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time.</p>
      <p>A full orchestral arrangement with strings and French horns
    adorning a bluesy rhythm track and guitar line provides the
    instrumentals. Music critic Stephen Thomas Erlewine of allmusic
    interprets the song as describing the bittersweet story of a
    man who fantasizes about the woman he loves and imagines a
    relationship with her. The narrator is canny enough to realize
    that his daydreams are fiction and not fact, but nevertheless
    resigns himself to his fantasies. For Erlewine, "the
    Temptations' performance has a dream-like quality, quietly
    drifting through the singer's hopes and desires."</p>
      <p>The song's first two verses establish the song's theme and
    explore the narrator's daydreams. In his mind, the narrator and
    his unrequited love are lovers, prepared to be married, "raise
    a family", and build "a cozy little home / out in the country /
    (with) the two children, maybe three". Then, in the bridge, the
    narrator prays to God that he will never lose the lady's love
    to another, or he will "surely die". The song's final line,
    however, reveals that he possesses her love only within the
    confines of his own imagination: "But in reality / she doesn't
    even know me."</p>
      <p>During the late 1960s and early 1970s, producer/composer
    Norman Whitfield and lyricist Barrett Strong crafted a string
    of "psychedelic soul" tracks for the Temptations. By 1970, the
    Temptations had released psychadecially-influenced hits such as
    "Runaway Child, Running Wild", "Psychedelic Shack", "Ball of
    Confusion (That's What the World Is Today)", and the Grammy
    Award-winning "Cloud Nine". In a 1991 interview, Eddie
    Kendricks recalled that many of the Temptations' fans were
    "screaming bloody murder" after the group delved into
    psychedelia, and demanded a return to their original soul
    sound.</p>
      <p>"Just My Imagination" was the result of one of the few times
    that Whitfield relented and produced a ballad as a single for
    the group. Whitfield and Strong wrote the song in 1969, but
    with the Temptations' psychedelic soul singles consistently
    keeping them in the US Top 20, Whitfield and Strong decided to
    shelve the composition and wait for the right time to record
    it. In late 1970, the Temptations' single "Ungena Za Ulimwengu
    (Unite the World)", a psychedelic soul song about world peace,
    failed to reach the Top 30, and Whitfield decided to record and
    release "Just My Imagination" as the next single. He approached
    Barrett Strong, and asked him to pull out "that song we were
    messing around with a year ago...because I'm going to record it
    today." Except their late 1960s duets with Diana Ross &amp; the
    Supremes, the Temptations had not released a single that was
    not based in psychedelia since "Please Return Your Love to Me"
    from 
    <i>The Temptations Wish It Would Rain</i>in 1968.</p>
      <p>Norman Whitfield began the recording of "Just My
    Imagination" by preparing the song's instrumental track.
    Whitfield arranged and recorded the non-orchestral elements of
    the instrumental with Motown's studio band, The Funk Brothers,
    who for this recording included Eddie "Chank" Willis on guitar,
    Jack Ashford on marimba, Jack Brokensha on timpani, Andrew
    Smith on drums, and Bob Babbitt on bass. Jerry Long, an
    arranger who had previous experience with scoring films in
    Paris, worked on the orchestral arrangement and conducted
    several members of the Detroit Symphony Orchestra in performing
    the horns and strings for the recording. The Temptations had
    heard the Funk Brothers' tracks and loved them, but were
    "totally knocked out", according to Otis Williams, when they
    heard "the finished record with all the strings."</p>
      <p>The Temptations added their vocals at Motown's Hitsville USA
    headquarters. While all five Temptations usually sang lead on
    singles during the psychedelic soul era, "Just My Imagination"
    is primarily a showcase for Eddie Kendricks, who sang lead on
    Temptations hits such as "Get Ready", "The Way You Do the
    Things You Do", and "You're My Everything". The Temptations
    remained at Hitsville overnight recording "Just My
    Imagination", and while the other four members went home at six
    o'clock in the morning, Kendricks remained in the studio,
    spending several additional hours recording takes for his lead
    vocal.</p>
      <p>The song was recorded in the midst of a bitter feud between
    Eddie Kendricks and the Temptations' de facto leader, Otis
    Williams. Dissatisfied and frustrated with Williams'
    leadership, Kendricks began to withdraw from the group, and
    picked several fights with either Williams or his best friend,
    bass singer Melvin Franklin. Kendricks told his friend,
    ex-Temptation David Ruffin, of his problems in the group, and
    Ruffin convinced Kendricks that he should begin a solo career.
    After a final altercation during a November 1970 Copacabana
    engagement, both Kendricks and Williams agreed that it would be
    best for Kendricks to leave the group. By the time "Just My
    Imagination" was recorded, Williams and Kendricks were no
    longer on friendly speaking terms. Nevertheless, Otis Williams
    was impressed by Kendricks' performance on the recording, and
    in his 1988 
    <i>Temptations</i>biography referred to "Just My Imagination"
    as "Eddie's finest moment."</p>
      <p>Paul Williams, the Temptations' original lead singer and
    Kendricks' lifelong best friend, sings the lead vocal during
    the first verse of "Just My Imagination's" bridge ("Every
    night, on my knees, I pray..."). For the last three years,
    Williams had suffered from health problems caused by both
    alcoholism and sickle-cell disease. By the time of "Just My
    Imagination's" recording, Paul Williams' contributions to the
    Temptations' recordings had been reduced, and the group had
    Otis Williams' old associate Richard Street lined up as Paul
    Williams' replacement.</p>
      <p>Motown released "Just My Imagination" as a single on their
    Gordy label on January 14, 1971, with the up-tempo psychedelic
    soul song "You Make Your Own Heaven and Hell Right Here on
    Earth", from the 1970 
    <i>Psychedelic Shack</i>LP, as the b-side. The Temptations
    performed "Just My Imagination" and "Get Ready" for their final
    appearance on 
    <i>The Ed Sullivan Show</i>, broadcast live on January 31.
    On-screen, Kendricks stood several feet away from the other
    Temptations, and made little eye contact with them; Otis
    Williams later remarked that one could see the group was no
    longer a complete unit:</p>
      <p>But there was such a bittersweet feeling. Eddie had really
    changed. Paul was on his last legs. Watch the clip of us doing
    the song on 
    <i>Ed Sullivan</i>we're not together. Eddie is off by himself.
    There was no more group. Sure enough, when we played the Copa
    that week, Eddie left between shows. He didn't come back.</p>
      <p>On February 7, 1971, "Just My Imagination" entered the U.S. 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 chart at the 71st spot and later number
    one on both the Hot 100 and the U.S. Billboard R&amp;B Singles
    charts. It also became the group's first entry on the adult
    contemporary chart, reaching #33; the group would not return to
    that chart until 1984.</p>
      <p>The single was included along with "Unite the World" on the
    Temptations' ninth regular studio album, 
    <i>Sky's the Limit</i>, which included the final Temptations
    recordings to feature Eddie Kendricks. He began working on his
    solo album 
    <i>All By Myself</i>shortly before officially leaving the
    group.</p>
      <p>The intended follow-up to "Just My Imagination" was "Smiling
    Faces Sometimes", on which Kendricks sang lead. After his
    departure, the group re-recorded "It's Summer", the b-side to
    "Ball of Confusion", as a last-minute replacement single, and
    Norman Whitfield had "Smiling Faces Sometimes" recorded as a
    hit for The Undisputed Truth. The Temptations and Norman
    Whitfield returned to psychedelic soul for their next album, 
    <i>Solid Rock</i>, whose second single, "Superstar (Remember
    How You Got Where You Are)", was written by Whitfield and
    Barrett Strong as a criticism of both Kendricks and David
    Ruffin.</p>
      <p>A number of artists have since covered "Just My
    Imagination", often in different styles from the original.
    Among the most notable covers is a version by The Rolling
    Stones, featured on their 1978 album 
    <i>Some Girls</i>, the 1982 live album 
    <i>Still Life</i>, and the 2008 live album 
    <i>Shine a Light</i>. Unlike the Temptations' original, the
    Rolling Stones cover has a higher tempo, prominent electric
    guitars, and replaces the subdued tone of the original with a
    rougher feel. Other notable covers include a smooth-jazz
    version by Larry Carlton, an acoustic cover by Ted Hawkins, a
    mid-tempo pop interpretation by Bette Midler,, instrumental
    versions by both Booker T &amp; the MG's and Donald Byrd, who
    included his funk-influenced cover of "Just My Imagination" on
    his successful 1975 album 
    <i>Places and Spaces</i>and Rose Royce's version from their
    1986 album Fresh Cut.</p>
      <p>Working from the original Motown session tapes, hip hop
    producer Easy Mo Bee produced a remix of "Just My Imagination"
    that adds modernized keyboard lines, bass, and programmed drums
    to the original mix. This remix was included on the 2005
    compilation 
    <i>Motown Remixed</i>, along with several other reworked Motown
    hits. Pete Yorn covered the song for the 2005 movie 
    <i>Just Like Heaven</i>, and Gwyneth Paltrow and Babyface
    performed a cover version for 
    <i>Duets</i>. Boyz II Men covered Just My Imagination on their
    2007 album 
    <i>Motown: A Journey Through Hitsville USA</i>. Their version
    reached 83 on the R&amp;B chart in 2008. In June 2008, Dianne
    Reeves covered the song for the JVC Jazz Festival at Carnegie
    Hall in New York City; Jon Pareles of 
    <i>The New York Times</i>considered her version to be
    "easy-swaying".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
