<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Sharona 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Sharona</songId>
   <title>My Sharona</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Knack</artistId>
      <artistName>The Knack</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1979-08-25</week>
      <week>1979-09-01</week>
      <week>1979-09-08</week>
      <week>1979-09-15</week>
      <week>1979-09-22</week>
      <week>1979-09-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/53/MySharonaCover.jpg/200px-MySharonaCover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Knack+My-Sharona.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Get the Knack</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>June 1979  (1979-06)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>April 1979</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
      <genre>Power Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:58 (single edit) 4:52 (album version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Doug Fieger</writer>
      <writer>Berton Averre</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mike Chapman</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"My Sharona" is the debut single by The Knack, released in
    1979 from their album 
    <i>Get the Knack</i>. It reached #1 on the Billboard Hot 100
    singles chart where it remained for six weeks and was #1 on
    Billboard's Top Pop Singles of 1979 year-end chart. It was
    certified gold (one million units sold) by the Recording
    Industry Association of America.</p>
      <p>Lead singer/guitarist Doug Fieger was 25 when he met Sharona
    Alperin, who was 17 at the time. She inspired a two-month-long
    run of songwriting, as well as becoming Fieger's girlfriend for
    the next four years. "It was like getting hit in the head with
    a baseball bat; I fell in love with her instantly. And when
    that happened, it sparked something and I started writing a lot
    of songs feverishly in a short amount of time." Whenever Fieger
    thought about Alperin, he would think of Berton Averre's guitar
    riff. The two worked out the structure and melody from
    there.</p>
      <p>Sharona herself appears on the picture sleeve for the
    single, and became a major booster of the band bringing many
    girls to their early shows. Sharona Alperin is now a real
    estate agent in Los Angeles, California. The easily
    recognizable riff of "My Sharona" was written by the band's
    guitarist, Berton Averre, long before he ever joined The
    Knack.</p>
      <p>The song's bright, driving bassline, played mainly in G
    octaves, appears in the playlist of many aspiring bass players,
    often cited as a superb technical example of its genre. In
    1994, "My Sharona" re-entered the Billboard Hot 100 chart
    (peaking at #91) when it was released as a single from the 
    <i>Reality Bites</i>soundtrack album.</p>
      <p>The song was used in a Saturday Night Live parody of
    then-U.S. Attorney General Janet Reno in a sketch starring Will
    Ferrell.</p>
      <p>The original song gained some attention in 2005 when it
    appeared on the playlist of U.S. President George W. Bush's
    iPod.</p>
      <p>The song was ranked at #75 on the 
    <i>Billboard Hot 100 All-Time Top Songs</i>in 2008.</p>
      <p>A cover version song is also featured as downloadable
    content the music video game series Rock Band. The original
    version of the song, along with its music video, is feature on
    Lips: Party Classics on Xbox 360.</p>
      <p>With both the notoriety gained from being an international
    hit, and its distinctive rock guitar riff, "My Sharona" has
    been the subject of numerous parodies, tributes, and sampling,
    including:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
