<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indian_Reservation_(The_Lament_of_the_Cherokee_Reservation_Indian) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indian_Reservation_(The_Lament_of_the_Cherokee_Reservation_Indian)</songId>
   <title>Indian Reservation (The Lament of the Cherokee Reservation Indian)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Revere_%26_the_Raiders</artistId>
      <artistName>The Raiders</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1971-07-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Indian Reservation (The Lament of the Cherokee Reservation
    Indian)" is a song written by John D. Loudermilk. It was first
    recorded in 1959 by Marvin Rainwater and released as "The Pale
    Faced Indian". Rainwater's MGM release stayed unnoticed. The
    first hit version was a 1970 cover by Don Fardon, a former
    member of The Sorrows, that reached #20 on the U.S. Billboard
    Hot 100 chart and #3 on the UK Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>In 1971 the Raiders recorded the song. It was released on
    the Columbia Records label and became #1 on the U.S. chart on
    July 24. The RIAA gold certification followed on 30 June 1971,
    for selling over a million copies. The UK punk band, 999,
    released a cover version on 14 November 1981 on the Albion Ion
    label, and it reached #51 in the UK chart. The song was later
    further covered by the Orlando Riva Sound.</p>
      <p>A 1994 country song by Tim McGraw, "Indian Outlaw", ends
    with part of the main "Cherokee people" chorus from "Indian
    Reservation". The live version also uses the full chorus near
    the end of the song.</p>
      <p>The song refers to the forcible removal and relocation of
    Cherokee people from southeastern states of the United States
    to territories west of the Mississippi River. This removal in
    the 1830s is often referred to as the "Trail of Tears". It
    followed the Indian Removal Act of 1830. This action was part
    of a larger United States policy of Indian removal.</p>
      <p>The music is in a minor key, with sustained minor chords
    ending each phrase in the primary melody, while the electronic
    organ holds the melody line through a slow musical turn
    (turning of related notes) which ends each phrase, and
    emphasizes the ominous minor chords. Underneath the slow, paced
    melody, is a rhythmic, low "drum beat" in double-time,
    constantly, relentlessly pushing to follow along, but the
    melody continues its slow, deliberate pace above the drum
    beat.</p>
      <p>Below are partial lyrics from the Raiders' version:</p>
      <p>The lyrics vary somewhat among the recorded versions.
    Rainwater's version omits the "Cherokee people!" chorus but
    includes instead a series of "Hiya hiya ho!" chants. Fardon's
    version is similar to the Raiders' through the first verse and
    chorus, but differs in the second verse, which includes the
    lines "Altho' they changed our ways of old/They'll never change
    our heart and soul", also found in Rainwater's version.
    Rainwater includes some of the elements found in the other
    versions in a different order, and his first verse has words
    not found in the others, such as "They put our papoose in a
    crib/and took the buck skin from our rib".</p>
      <p>At the end, where the Raiders sing "...Cherokee nation will
    return", Fardon says "Cherokee Indian...", while Rainwater
    omits the line and ends with "beads...nowadays made in
    Japan."</p>
      <p>, ,</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
