<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Come_Together 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Come_Together</songId>
   <title>Come Together" / "Something</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1969-11-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/39/Something_single.jpg/200px-Something_single.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Beatles+Come-Together-Something.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Abbey Road</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>6 October 1969</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Abbey Road Studios , 21 July 1969</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Blues Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:18</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Apple Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Come Together" is a song by The Beatles written primarily
    by John Lennon and credited to Lennon/McCartney. The song is
    the opening track on The Beatles' September 1969 album 
    <i>Abbey Road</i>. One month later it was released as a double
    A-sided single with "Something", their twenty-first single in
    the United Kingdom and twenty-sixth in the United States. The
    song reached the top of the charts in the US, and peaked at
    number four in the UK.</p>
      <p>The song's history began with Lennon writing a song for
    Timothy Leary's failed gubernatorial campaign in California,
    United States against Ronald Reagan, which promptly ended when
    Leary was sent to prison for possession of marijuana.</p>
      <p>Lennon played rhythm guitar and sang the vocal; Paul
    McCartney played bass; Ringo Starr played drums; and George
    Harrison played lead guitar. It was produced by George Martin
    and recorded at the end of July 1969 at Abbey Road Studios. In
    the intro, Lennon says "shoot me" which is accompanied by
    McCartney's heavy bass riff. The famous Beatles "walrus" from
    "I Am the Walrus" and "Glass Onion" returns in the line "he got
    walrus gumboot", followed by "he got Ono sideboard". Bluesman
    Muddy Waters is also mentioned in the song.</p>
      <p>Although McCartney composed the electric piano part, Lennon
    looked over his shoulder to learn it so he could perform it
    himself on the recording. Music critic Ian MacDonald reports
    that McCartney sang a backing vocal, but Geoff Emerick said
    that Lennon did all the vocals himself, and when a frustrated
    McCartney asked Lennon, "What do you want me to do on this
    track, John?", Lennon replied, "Don't worry, I'll do the
    [vocal] overdubs on this."</p>
      <p>"Come Together" was released as a double A-side with
    "Something" and as the opening track of 
    <i>Abbey Road</i>. The single was released on 6 October 1969 in
    the United States and 31 October 1969 in the United
    Kingdom.</p>
      <p>For a time, the song was banned by the BBC, as they believed
    the song's reference to "shoot[ing] Coca-Cola" could be
    construed as either a cocaine reference or an advertisement of
    a soft drink.</p>
      <p>Rolling Stone ranked "Come Together" at #202 on their list
    of the 500 Greatest Songs of All Time.</p>
      <p>On the compilation album 
    <i>Love</i>, "Come Together" is the 19th track. Sections of
    "Dear Prudence" and "Cry Baby Cry" fade in at the end of the
    track.</p>
      <p>"Come Together" was the only Beatles tune Lennon sang during
    his 1972 Madison Square Garden concert; that version of the
    song appears on the concert album 
    <i>Live in New York City</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1973, "Come Together" was the subject of a lawsuit
    brought against Lennon by Big Seven Music Corp. (owned by
    Morris Levy) who was the publisher of Chuck Berry's "You Can't
    Catch Me". This was because it sounded similar musically to
    Berry's original and shared some lyrics (Lennon sang "Here come
    ol' flattop, he come groovin' up slowly" and Berry's had sung
    "Here come a flattop, he was movin' up with me"). Before
    recording, Lennon and McCartney deliberately slowed the song
    down and added a heavy bass riff in order to make the song more
    original. After settling out of court, Lennon promised to
    record three other songs owned by Levy. "You Can't Catch Me"
    and "Ya Ya" were released on Lennon's 1975 album 
    <i>Rock 'n' Roll</i>, but the third, "Angel Baby", remained
    unreleased until after Lennon's death. Levy again sued Lennon
    for breach of contract, and was eventually awarded $6,795.</p>
      <p>John Lennon and his band played this song during his famous,
    "Live in New York City" concert. The concert was recorded at
    Madison Square Garden on August 30, 1972--Lennon's last
    full-length concert performance--the show was finally made
    available in 1986.</p>
      <p>American hard rock band Aerosmith performed one of the first
    and most successful cover versions of "Come Together". It was
    recorded in 1978 and appeared in the movie and on the
    soundtrack to the film 
    <i>Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band</i>, in which the band
    also appeared. The single was an immediate success, reaching
    #23 on the Billboard Hot 100, following on the heels of a
    string of Top 40 hits for the band in the mid-1970s. However it
    would be the last Top 40 hit for the band for nearly a
    decade.</p>
      <p>A rare live demo of the song was also released months later
    on Aerosmith's live album 
    <i>Live! Bootleg</i>. The song was also featured on 
    <i>Aerosmith's Greatest Hits</i>, the band's single-disc
    compilation released in 1980. The song has also surfaced on a
    number of Aerosmith compilations and live albums since then, as
    well as on the soundtrack for the film 
    <i>Armageddon</i>.</p>
      <p>The Aerosmith version is still frequently heard on
    mainstream and album rock radio stations. Aerosmith still
    occasionally performs "Come Together" in concert.</p>
      <p>Since 2006, New Zealand telecommunications company Telecom
    used a cover of this song for its "Come Together" campaign.</p>
      <p>The song has since become one of the most covered songs of
    all time:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
