<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Save_the_Last_Dance_for_Me 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Save_the_Last_Dance_for_Me</songId>
   <title>Save the Last Dance for Me</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Drifters</artistId>
      <artistName>The Drifters</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1960-10-17</week>
      <week>1960-10-31</week>
      <week>1960-11-07</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1960</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" (45 rpm)</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Atlantic Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Doc Pomus</writer>
      <writer>Mort Shuman</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jerry Leiber</producer>
      <producer>Mike Stoller</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Save the Last Dance for Me" is the title of a popular song
    written by Doc Pomus and Mort Shuman, first recorded in 1960 by
    Ben E. King with The Drifters.</p>
      <p>The Drifters' version of the song spent three
    non-consecutive weeks at number one on the U.S. pop chart, in
    addition to logging one week atop the U.S. R&amp;B chart. In
    the UK, the Drifters' recording reached number two in December
    1960. This single was produced by Jerry Leiber and Mike
    Stoller, two noted American music producers who at the time had
    an apprentice relationship with a then-unknown Phil Spector.
    Although he was working with Lieber and Stoller at the time, it
    is unknown whether Spector assisted with the production of this
    record; however, many Spector fans have noticed similarities
    between this record and other music he would eventually produce
    on his own.</p>
      <p>In the song, the narrator tells his lover she is free to
    mingle and socialize throughout the evening, but to make sure
    to save him one dance at the end of the night. The song is
    likely based on the personal experience of songwriter Pomus,
    who had polio and used crutches to get around and could not
    dance. His wife, however, was a Broadway actress and dancer.
    The song gives his perspective of plaintively telling his wife
    to have fun dancing, but reminds her who will be taking her
    home and "in whose arms you're gonna be." The personnel for the
    Drifters' recording were: Bucky Pizzarelli, Allan Hanlon
    (guitar), Lloyd Trotman (bass), Gary Chester (drums).</p>
      <p>"Save the Last Dance for Me" was the second, and last,
    single to be released from 
    <i>It's Time</i>, Michael Bublé's second album. This version of
    the song first made the American music charts as a dance
    recording that was listed as being remixed by "Ralphi Rosario
    and Eddie Baez". The remixes peaked at #22 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>dance chart in September 2005. In early 2006,
    the album version of the song was released to radio, and it
    peaked at number five on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>adult contemporary chart as well as reaching
    number 99 on the Hot 100 chart. Bublé sings the song at the end
    of the 2005 film 
    <i>The Wedding Date</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
