<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mo_Money_Mo_Problems 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mo_Money_Mo_Problems</songId>
   <title>Mo Money Mo Problems</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>The Notorious B.I.G. featuring Puff Daddy and Mase</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1997-08-30</week>
      <week>1997-09-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/9/9d/Biggiemomoneymoproblems.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Notorious-B-I-G-featuring-Puff-Daddy-and-Mase+Mo-Money-Mo-Problems.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Life After Death</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 15, 1997</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
      <format>12" vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1996</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>East Coast Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:17</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Bad Boy Records / Arista Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bernard Edwards</writer>
      <writer>Mason Betha</writer>
      <writer>Nile Rodgers</writer>
      <writer>Steven Jordan</writer>
      <writer>Sean Combs</writer>
      <writer>Christopher Wallace</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Stevie J</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Mo Money Mo Problems" is a single by Notorious B.I.G., the
    second single from his album 
    <i>Life After Death</i>. Released posthumously, the single
    topped the Hot 100 for two weeks in 1997, replacing "I'll Be
    Missing You" from the chart, Puff Daddy's song about Notorious
    B.I.G's death. The song is Notorious B.I.G.'s second posthumous
    number one single, and was nominated for the 1998 Grammy Award
    for Best Rap Performance by a Duo or Group.</p>
      <p>The song features guest vocals from Ma$e and Sean "Puff
    Daddy" Combs. The instrumental contains a sample of the Diana
    Ross song "I'm Coming Out". The refrain of the song was sung by
    Kelly Price. Based on Airplay and chart success the song is
    considered one of the most popular singles in Hip Hop History.
    It remains a radio favorite to this day.</p>
      <p>"Mo Money Mo Problems" was able to top the Billboard Hot 100
    for two weeks giving Biggie his second number 1 hit in the US.
    The song hit number 1 after he had died. It was preceded by
    "I'll Be Missing You" by Puff Daddy featuring 112 &amp; Faith
    Evans and was succeeded by "Honey" by Mariah Carey. The single
    reached #6 in the UK charts.</p>
      <p>The video directed by Hype Williams featured Mase and Combs
    in futuristic locations, including a tunnel lined with
    fluorescent lamps and a stark white chamber with pressurized
    air blowing out of the floor, allowing the two to float in
    midair. This video is also famous for the red shiny jackets
    that are worn by Combs and Mase. The "air chamber" also had a
    video screen showing, at first, images of Kelly Price
    lip-synching to the sample of Diana Ross' voice and singing the
    song's chorus. During the final verse, which the Notorious
    B.I.G. performed, Mase and Puffy looked on as the video screen
    showed archival footage of B.I.G. performing, it ran at a speed
    so that the footage seemed to sync with B.I.G.'s vocals; since
    the rapper had died just prior to the release of 
    <i>Life After Death</i>, and well before the filming of the
    video, this was the only way to have him appear in the video.
    Song produced by Steven "Stevie J." Jordan and Sean Combs. The
    video also has a short story, which is about how Combs was
    competing in a golf tournament and gained help from the spirit
    of The Notorious B.I.G, who helps him win the tournament. This
    was a reaction to the newly popular success of Tiger Woods.</p>
      <p>MuchMoreMusic ranked "Mo Money Mo Problems" #31 on 
    <i>Listed'</i>s "40 Most Memorable Videos Pt. 1 &amp; 2" for
    its flashy wardrobe, and use of syncing old footage with the
    lyrics. VH1 ranked the song #63 as one of the "100 Greatest
    Songs of the 90s".</p>
      <p>John Randle, Minnesota Vikings defensive tackle, is featured
    in an NFL promotional commercial, singing this song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
