<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27m_a_Believer 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27m_a_Believer</songId>
   <title>I'm a Believer</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Monkees</artistId>
      <artistName>The Monkees</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1967-01-07</week>
      <week>1967-01-14</week>
      <week>1967-01-21</week>
      <week>1967-01-28</week>
      <week>1967-02-04</week>
      <week>1967-02-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/4d/Us45m1002c1.jpg/200px-Us45m1002c1.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Monkees+I-m-a-Believer.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>More of The Monkees</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 21, 1966</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:41</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Neil Diamond</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jeff Barry</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I'm a Believer" is a song composed by Neil Diamond and
    recorded by the The Monkees in 1966 with the lead vocals by
    Micky Dolenz. The single, produced by Jeff Barry, hit the
    number one spot on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 chart on December
    31, 1966 and remained there for seven weeks, becoming the
    biggest-selling record for all of 1967, and one of the biggest
    of all time. Because of advance orders, over 1,051,280, it went
    gold within two days of release.</p>
      <p>The song became Billboard's top single of the year and kept
    the novelty smash, "Snoopy Vs. The Red Baron" by The Royal
    Guardsmen, at number two for four weeks. Neil Diamond also
    suggested it to The Fifth Estate who recorded it as a 1967
    album cut in follow up to their smash hit "Ding Dong! The Witch
    Is Dead". Neil Diamond had already recorded this song before it
    was covered by The Monkees, and it still sometimes appears in
    his live concerts. A revised recording by Neil Diamond,
    featuring additional lyrics, appears on the album 
    <i>September Morn</i>, whilst his original recording can be
    found on several albums, including his greatest hits album, 
    <i>The Essential Neil Diamond</i>.</p>
      <p>A cover by British singer-songwriter Robert Wyatt was an
    unlikely hit in the UK in 1974. In 1995, British comedian Vic
    Reeves teamed up with then-popular band EMF for a version which
    reached #3 on the UK singles chart.</p>
      <p>This song was also covered by Smash Mouth and Eddie Murphy
    in 2001, as part of the soundtrack to the movie 
    <i>Shrek</i>(the band also released the song on its self-titled
    album). Eddie Murphy, portraying the character "Donkey", also
    performed a rendition of the song in the film. The song was
    chosen for its opening line, "I thought love was only true in
    fairy tales," which matched the fairy tale motif of the film.
    Subsequently, the song was played as exit music for the
    Broadway musical adaptation of the film, for comic effect. A
    year into the show's run, it was inserted into its finale. A
    nod to the version by Reeves &amp; Mortimer with EMF is
    included in 
    <i>Shrek</i>; though the "Oi!" does not appear in any album
    version of Smash Mouth's cover, it is inserted into the song
    when it is played in the film's finale, shouted by Snow White's
    Seven Dwarfs.</p>
      <p>In 2008, this song ranked #1 on Dallas station KLUV 98.7FM's
    Top 500 Memorial Day Countdown, as voted on by the listeners.
    The song is listed at #48 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top 100.</i>[1]</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
