<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Last_Train_to_Clarksville 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Last_Train_to_Clarksville</songId>
   <title>Last Train to Clarksville</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Monkees</artistId>
      <artistName>The Monkees</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1966-11-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Last Train to Clarksville" is the debut and number-one
    single by The Monkees, included on the group's 1966 self-titled
    album, that was released one month later.</p>
      <p>Recorded at RCA Records Studio A, Hollywood, on July 25,
    1966, "Last Train to Clarksville" peaked at number one on the
    Billboard Hot 100 chart in the United States.</p>
      <p>According to the song's authors, Tommy Boyce and Bobby Hart,
    the song is their protest of the Vietnam War and tells the
    story of a young man who has been drafted. He is waiting for
    the train that will take him to an army base, and he knows he
    may die in Vietnam. At the end of the song he states, "I don't
    know if I'm ever coming home." Like many hit Monkees songs of
    the era ("Cuddly Toy," "Pleasant Valley Sunday"), the song
    pairs a fast, chipper melody with darker lyrics. Micky Dolenz
    performs the lead vocals, with Boyce playing acoustic
    guitar.</p>
      <p>The song has been compared to The Beatles' "Paperback
    Writer", both in the style of "jangly" guitar and the chord
    structure. It also resembles the guitar riff in "Blue's Theme",
    by Davie Allan and the Arrows, from the Peter Fonda biker movie
    
    <i>The Wild Angels</i>. The opening/recurring guitar riff on
    the song "Find Your Way Back", written by Craig Chaquico and
    performed by Jefferson Starship on their 1980 album Modern
    Times, is almost identical to the one on "Last Train" in note
    structure, but very dissimilar in tempo and meter.</p>
      <p>Though the Clarksville in the song's title appears to refer
    to the city of Clarksville, Tennessee—and by implication to
    nearby Fort Campbell, Kentucky, which is home to the 101st
    Airborne Division—Hart who did not create the theme for the
    song states that this is a coincidence and that the choice of
    the name "Clarksville" was settled on for the way it sounded,
    after similar names like Clarkdale had been rejected. There are
    a few other "Clarksvilles" in the U.S., near military training
    centers, where the song could be set, which helped to make the
    song a favorite for many people during the Vietnam War. Phillip
    E. Meyers, who conceived the theme for the song, said that it
    is specifically intended to imply Fort Campbell and any
    military center near the other Clarksvilles. The song is not
    intended to be a protest, but a sensitive focus upon the
    sacrifices that the US soldiers and their families were making
    to serve in Vietnam. The reason they were taking the last train
    was because they wanted to spend all of their last hours with
    their families before possibly dying in Vietnam. The song was
    used in an Army produced film shown to new inductees, as early
    as November, 1967, and at least in the big induction center at
    Ft. Jackson, South Carolina. It played as the film showed new
    recruits getting off the train at Ft. Jackson, and would get a
    big laugh from the men watching the film.</p>
      <p>Ed Bruce covered the song in 1967.</p>
      <p>The Plastics covered this song (in their electropop style)
    on their debut album 
    <i>Welcome Plastics</i>.</p>
      <p>Cassandra Wilson recorded a jazz cover of the song on her
    1995 album 
    <i>New Moon Daughter</i>.</p>
      <p>On January 15, 2008, a cover of the song was made available
    as downloadable content for the music video game series 
    <i>Rock Band</i>. The January 2009 issue of 
    <i>PlayStation: The Official Magazine</i>lists The Monkees'
    "Last Train to Clarksville" as fourth on its list of 
    <i>Rock Band</i>’s "Five Most Unexpectedly Rockin' Downloadable
    Songs."</p>
      <p>The Standells did a cover version in 1966 on their album The
    Hot Ones.</p>
      <p>George Benson has done an instrumental version in his jazzy
    style.</p>
      <p>It was also covered by the Four Tops on their album Reach
    Out.</p>
      <p>Riblja Čorba released a cover titled "Zadnji voz za Čačak"
    (trans. "Last Train to Čačak") on their 1987 album 
    <i>Ujed za dušu</i>.</p>
      <p>The Cory Daniel Band play a country-rock version of the song
    at most of their concerts.</p>
      <p>R.E.M. performed this song live in their early years.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
