<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yesterday_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yesterday_(song)</songId>
   <title>Yesterday</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1965-10-09</week>
      <week>1965-10-16</week>
      <week>1965-10-23</week>
      <week>1965-10-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e5/Beatles-singles-yesterday.jpg/200px-Beatles-singles-yesterday.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Beatles+Yesterday.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Help!</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>13 September 1965</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>14 June 1965 , Abbey Road Studios</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Baroque Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:03</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Yesterday" is a song originally recorded by The Beatles for
    their 1965 album 
    <i>Help!</i>. According to the 
    <i>Guinness Book of Records</i>, "Yesterday" has the most cover
    versions of any song ever written. The song remains popular
    today with more than 3,000 recorded cover versions, the first
    hitting the United Kingdom top 10 three months after the
    release of 
    <i>Help!</i>. Broadcast Music Incorporated (BMI) asserts that
    it was performed over seven million times in the 20th century
    alone. The song was not released as a single in the UK at the
    time of the US release, and thus never gained number 1 single
    status in that country. However, "Yesterday" was voted the best
    song of the 20th century in a 1999 BBC Radio 2 poll of music
    experts and listeners. In 2000, "Yesterday" was voted the #1
    Pop song of all time by MTV and Rolling Stone Magazine.</p>
      <p>"Yesterday" takes the form of a melancholic acoustic guitar
    ballad about a breakup. It was the first official recording by
    The Beatles that relied upon a performance by a single member
    of the band, namely, Paul McCartney. He was accompanied solely
    by a string quartet. The final recording differed so greatly
    from other works by The Beatles that the other three members of
    the band vetoed the release of the song as a single in the
    United Kingdom (however, in 1976 it was eventually issued as a
    single there). Although credited to "Lennon/McCartney", the
    song was written solely by McCartney. In 2002, McCartney asked
    Yoko Ono if she would consider reversing the songwriting
    credits on the song to read "McCartney/Lennon". Ono
    refused.</p>
      <p>According to biographers of McCartney and The Beatles,
    McCartney composed the entire melody in a dream one night in
    his room at the Wimpole Street home of his then girlfriend Jane
    Asher and her family. Upon waking, he hurried to a piano and
    played the tune to avoid forgetting it.</p>
      <p>McCartney's initial concern was that he had subconsciously
    plagiarised someone else's work (known as cryptomnesia). As he
    put it, "For about a month I went round to people in the music
    business and asked them whether they had ever heard it before.
    Eventually it became like handing something in to the police. I
    thought if no-one claimed it after a few weeks then I could
    have it."</p>
      <p>Upon being convinced that he had not robbed anyone of his
    melody, McCartney began writing lyrics to suit it. As Lennon
    and McCartney were known to do at the time, a substitute
    working lyric, entitled "Scrambled Eggs", was used for the song
    until something more suitable was written. In his biography, 
    <i>Paul McCartney: Many Years from Now</i>, McCartney recalled:
    "So first of all I checked this melody out, and people said to
    me, 'No, it's lovely, and I'm sure it's all yours.' It took me
    a little while to allow myself to claim it, but then like a
    prospector I finally staked my claim; stuck a little sign on it
    and said, 'Okay, it's mine!' It had no words. I used to call it
    'Scrambled Eggs'."</p>
      <p>During the shooting of 
    <i>Help!</i>, a piano was placed on one of the stages where
    filming was being conducted and McCartney would take advantage
    of this opportunity to tinker with the song. Richard Lester,
    the director, was eventually greatly annoyed by this and lost
    his temper, telling McCartney to finish writing the song or he
    would have the piano removed. The patience of the other Beatles
    was also tested by McCartney's work in progress, George
    Harrison summing this up when he said: "Blimey, he's always
    talking about that song . You'd think he was Beethoven or
    somebody!"</p>
      <p>McCartney originally claimed he had written "Yesterday"
    during The Beatles' tour of France in 1964; however, the song
    was not released until the summer of 1965. During the
    intervening time, The Beatles released two albums, 
    <i>Beatles for Sale</i>and 
    <i>A Hard Day's Night</i>, both of which could have included
    "Yesterday". Although McCartney has never elaborated his
    claims, a delay may have been due to a disagreement between
    McCartney and George Martin regarding the song's arrangement,
    or the opinion of the other Beatles who felt it didn't suit
    their image.</p>
      <p>Lennon later indicated that the song had been around for a
    while before:</p>
      <p>McCartney said the breakthrough with the lyrics came during
    a trip to Portugal in May 1965:</p>
      <p>On 27 May 1965, McCartney and Asher flew to Lisbon for a
    holiday in Albufeira, Algarve, and he borrowed an acoustic
    guitar from Bruce Welch, in whose house they were staying, and
    completed the work on "Yesterday".</p>
      <p>The song was offered as a demo to Chris Farlowe prior to The
    Beatles recording it, but he turned it down as he considered it
    "too soft."</p>
      <p>Ostensibly simple, featuring only McCartney playing an
    Epiphone Texan steel-string acoustic guitar backed by a string
    quartet in one of The Beatles' first use of session musicians, 
    <i>Yesterday</i>has two contrasting sections, differing in
    melody and rhythmicity, producing a sense of disjunction.</p>
      <p>The first section ("Yesterday, all my troubles seemed so far
    away...") opens with a positive F-major chord, then moving to
    E-minor before resolving to its relative A-major and thence to
    D-minor. In this sense, the opening chord is a decoy; as
    musicologist Alan Pollack points out, the home key (F-major)
    has little time to establish itself before "heading towards the
    relative D-minor." He points out that this diversion is a
    compositional device commonly used by Lennon and McCartney,
    which he describes as "delayed gratification".</p>
      <p>The second section ("Why she had to go I don't know...") is,
    according to Pollack, less musically surprising on paper than
    it sounds. Starting with E-minor, the harmonic progression
    quickly moves through the relative A-major, D-minor, and
    (closer to F-major) B-flat, before resolving back to F-major,
    and at the end of this, McCartney holds F whilst the strings
    descend to resolve to the home key to introduce the restatement
    of the first section, before a brief hummed closing phrase.</p>
      <p>Pollack described the scoring as "truly inspired", citing it
    as an example of "[Lennon &amp; McCartney's] flair for creating
    stylistic hybrids"; in particular, he praises the "ironic
    tension drawn between the schmaltzy content of what is played
    by the quartet and the restrained, spare nature of the medium
    in which it is played."</p>
      <p>The track was recorded at Abbey Road Studios (immediately
    following on from taping "I'm Down") on the 14 June 1965. There
    are conflicting accounts of how the song was recorded, the most
    quoted one being that McCartney recorded the song by himself,
    without bothering to involve the other band members.
    Alternative sources, however, state that McCartney and the
    other Beatles tried a variety of instruments, including drums
    and an organ, and that George Martin later persuaded them to
    allow McCartney to play his Epiphone Texan steel-string
    acoustic guitar, later on editing-in a string quartet for
    backup. Regardless, none of the other band members were
    included in the final recording. However, the song was played
    with the other members of the band in concert during 1966.</p>
      <p>McCartney performed two takes of "Yesterday" on 14 June
    1965. Take 2 was deemed best and used as the master take. A
    string quartet was overdubbed on take 2 and that version was
    released. Take 1, without the string overdub, was later
    released on the 
    <i>Anthology 2</i>compilation. On take 1, McCartney can be
    heard giving chord changes to George Harrison before starting,
    but George does not appear to actually play. Take 2 had two
    lines transposed from the first take: "There's a shadow hanging
    over me"/"I'm not half the man I used to be," though it seems
    clear that their order in take 2 was the correct one, because
    McCartney can be heard, in take 1, suppressing a laugh at his
    mistake.</p>
      <p>George Martin later said:</p>
      <p>Although McCartney had fallen in love with the song, he had
    a much harder time convincing the other members of the band
    that it was worthy of an album place, the main objection being
    that it did not fit in with their image, especially considering
    that "Yesterday" was extremely unlike other Beatles' songs at
    the time. This feeling was so strong that the other
    Beatles—Lennon, Harrison and Ringo Starr—refused to permit the
    release of a single in the United Kingdom. This did not prevent
    Matt Monro from recording the first of many cover versions of
    "Yesterday" to come. His version made it into the top ten in
    the UK charts soon after its release in the autumn of 1965.</p>
      <p>The Beatles' influence over their U.S. record label,
    Capitol, was not as strong as it was over EMI's Parlophone in
    Britain. A single was released in the U.S., pairing "Yesterday"
    with "Act Naturally", a track which featured vocals by Starr.
    The single was charting by 29 September 1965, and topped the
    charts for a full month, beginning on 9 October. The song spent
    a remarkable total of 11 weeks in the American charts, selling
    a million copies within five weeks. "Yesterday" was the
    most-played song on American radio for eight consecutive years,
    its popularity refusing to abate.</p>
      <p>"Yesterday" was the third of six number one singles in a row
    on the American charts, a record at the time. The singles were
    "I Feel Fine", "Eight Days a Week", "Ticket to Ride", "Help!",
    "Yesterday", and "We Can Work It Out". The record was equaled
    by The Bee Gees in the 1970s and surpassed by Mariah Carey in
    the 1990s. "Yesterday" also marked a turning point in who wrote
    number one singles for the group. Lennon wrote five through
    "Help!", whereas afterwards McCartney wrote eight starting with
    "Yesterday".</p>
      <p>On 4 March 1966, "Yesterday" was released as an EP in the
    UK, joined by "Act Naturally" on the A-side with "You Like Me
    Too Much" and "It's Only Love" on the B-side. By 12 March, it
    had begun its run on the charts. On 26 March 1966, the EP went
    to number one, a position it held for two months. Later that
    same year, "Yesterday" was included as the title track for the
    U.S.-only 
    <i>Yesterday and Today</i>album, which was originally packaged
    in the "butcher sleeve".</p>
      <p>Ten years later on 8 March 1976, "Yesterday" was released by
    Parlophone as a single in the UK, featuring "I Should Have
    Known Better" on the B-side. Entering the charts on 13 March,
    the single stayed there for seven weeks, but it never rose
    higher than number 8 (however, by this time the song had been
    featured on no less than three top 5 albums and an EP which
    topped the charts). The release came about due to the
    expiration of The Beatles' contract with EMI, Parlophone's
    parent. EMI released as many singles by The Beatles as they
    could on the same day, leading to 23 of them hitting the top
    100 in the United Kingdom charts, including six in the top
    50.</p>
      <p>"Yesterday" has been recognised as the most recorded song in
    the history of popular music; its entry in the 
    <i>Guinness Book of Records</i>suggests over 1600 different
    cover versions to date, by an eclectic mix of artists including
    The Mamas and the Papas and Barry McGuire, The Seekers, Joan
    Baez, Michael Bolton, Bob Dylan, Liberace, Frank Sinatra, Elvis
    Presley, Ray Charles, Marvin Gaye, Daffy Duck, Jan &amp; Dean,
    Wet Wet Wet, Plácido Domingo, The Head Shop, Billy Dean, En
    Vogue, Muslim Magomayev and Boyz II Men. In 1976, David Essex
    did a cover version of the song for the ephemeral musical
    documentary 
    <i>All This and World War II</i>. After Muzak switched in the
    1990s to programs based on commercial recordings, Muzak's
    inventory grew to include about 500 "Yesterday" covers. At the
    2006 Grammy Awards, McCartney performed the song live as a
    mash-up with Linkin Park and Jay-Z's Numb/Encore. It is
    Vladimir Putin's favourite Beatles song.</p>
      <p>"Yesterday" won the Ivor Novello Award for 'Outstanding Song
    of 1965', and came second for 'Most Performed Work of the
    Year', losing out to another McCartney composition, "Michelle".
    The song has received its fair share of acclaim in recent times
    as well, ranking 13th on 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s 2004 list 
    <i>The 500 Greatest Songs of All Time</i>. In 1999, Broadcast
    Music Incorporated (BMI) placed "Yesterday" third on their list
    of songs of the 20th century most performed on American radio
    and television, with approximately seven million performances.
    "Yesterday" was surpassed only by The Association's "Never My
    Love" and the Righteous Brothers' "You've Lost That Loving
    Feeling".</p>
      <p>"Yesterday," however, has also been criticised for being
    mundane and mawkish; Bob Dylan had a marked dislike for the
    song, stating that "If you go into the Library of Congress, you
    can find a lot better than that. There are millions of songs
    like 'Michelle' and 'Yesterday' written in Tin Pan Alley".
    Ironically, Dylan ultimately recorded his own version of
    "Yesterday" four years later, but it was never released.</p>
      <p>Shortly before his death in 1980, Lennon explained that he
    thought the lyrics didn't "resolve into any sense... They're
    good—but if you read the whole song, it doesn't say anything;
    you don't know what happened. She left and he wishes it were
    yesterday—that much you get—but it doesn't really resolve. ...
    Beautiful—and I never wished I'd written it."</p>
      <p>"Yesterday" was voted Best Song of the 20th Century in a
    1999 BBC Radio poll.</p>
      <p>The tonic key of the song is F major (although, since
    McCartney tuned his guitar down a whole step, he was playing
    the chords as if it were in G), where the song begins before
    veering off into the key of D minor. It is this frequent use of
    the minor, and the ii-V7 chord progression (Em and A7 chords in
    this case) leading into it, that gives the song its melancholy
    aura. The A7 chord is an example of a secondary dominant,
    specifically a V/vi chord. The G7 chord in the bridge is
    another secondary dominant, in this case a V/V chord, but
    rather than resolve it to the expected chord, as with the A7 to
    Dm in the verse, McCartney instead follows it with the IV
    chord, a Bb. This motion creates a descending chromatic line of
    C B Bb A to accompany the title lyric.</p>
      <p>The string arrangement supplements the song's air of
    sadness, especially in the groaning cello melody and its blue
    seventh that connects the two halves of the bridge (on the
    line, "I don't know / she wouldn't say") as well as the
    descending line by the viola that segues the chorus back into
    the verses. This simple idea is so striking, McCartney mimics
    it with his vocal on the second pass of the chorus. This viola
    line and the high A sustained by the violin over the final
    verse are the only elements of the string arrangement
    attributable to McCartney rather than George Martin.</p>
      <p>When the song was performed on 
    <i>The Ed Sullivan Show</i>, it was done in the above-mentioned
    key of F, with McCartney as the only Beatle to perform, and the
    studio orchestra providing the string accompaniment. However,
    all of The Beatles played in a G-major version which was used
    in the Tokyo concerts during their 1966 tours.</p>
      <p>When McCartney appeared on 
    <i>The Howard Stern Show</i>, he stated that he owns the
    original lyrics to "Yesterday" written on the back of an
    envelope.</p>
      <p>In 2001 Ian Hammond speculated that McCartney subconsciously
    based "Yesterday" on Ray Charles' version of "Georgia On My
    Mind," but closed his article by saying that despite the
    similarities "Yesterday" is a "completely original and
    individual [work]."</p>
      <p>In July 2003, British musicologists stumbled upon
    similarities between the lyric and rhyming schemes of
    "Yesterday" and Nat King Cole's 
    <i>Answer Me, My Love</i>(originally a German song by Gerhard
    Winkler and Fred Rauch called 
    <i>Mütterlein</i>), leading to speculation that McCartney had
    been influenced by the song. McCartney's publicists denied any
    resemblance between "Answer Me" and "Yesterday". From the
    story:</p>
      <p>In 2006, Italian producer and songwriter Lilli Greco claimed
    "Yesterday" to be a cover of a 19th century Neapolitan song
    called Piccerè Che Vene a Dicere'. In the same occasion, Greco
    claimed that McCartney and Lennon had an "encyclopaedic
    knowledge" of world music and were particularly fond of
    Neapolitan songs. However, following researches didn't lead to
    any trace of the song in the archives.</p>
      <p>, 
    <span id="interwiki-uk-fa"/>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
