<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Want_Ads 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Want_Ads</songId>
   <title>Want Ads</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Honey_Cone</artistId>
      <artistName>The Honey Cone</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1971-06-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/c/c2/Honey_cone_want_ads.jpg/200px-Honey_cone_want_ads.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Honey-Cone+Want-Ads.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Sweet Replies/Soulful Tapestry, (1971)</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 1971</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Detroit , Michigan , 1971</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B / Soul / Funk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:10 (Album version)</length>
      <length>2:45 (Radio edit)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Hot Wax</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Greg Perry</writer>
      <writer>Barney Perkins</writer>
      <writer>and General Norman Johnson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Greg Perry</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Want Ads" was a R&amp;B/Soul/Funk song recorded by Honey
    Cone for their third album 
    <i>Sweet Replies</i>and also appears on their fourth album 
    <i>Soulful Tapestry</i>(both 1971 releases). The song was
    written by Greg Perry, Barney Perkins, and General Norman
    Johnson, and produced by Greg Perry.</p>
      <p>"Want Ads" was released as the first single off 
    <i>Soulful Tapestry</i>in the United States in the spring of
    1971 (see 1971 in music). It reached number one for one week on
    the Billboard Hot 100 and topped the R&amp;B singles chart for
    three weeks in the United States, becoming the group's most
    successful single and their only number one placement on the
    pop charts.</p>
      <p>Initially, Greg Perry and General Norman Johnson had written
    a song for a female singer called "Stick Up," the two decided
    that the song wasn't substantial as a release so they did a
    re-write with a change in chord progressions and new lyrics.
    With the catchy opener "Wanted, young man, single and free,"
    "Want Ads" was born.</p>
      <p>The idea for the song started when engineer Barney Perkins,
    while looking through the classified section of a newspaper,
    suggested that someone write a song about want ads. Greg Perry,
    producer and songwriter for the project, felt that the idea
    might work. The duo brought General Norman Johnson (leader of
    Chairmen of the Board) to contribute to the writing. After
    co-writing "Somebody's Been Sleeping (In My Bed)" (a number
    eight hit) with Perry for the Hot Wax group 100 Proof Aged in
    Soul, and proving that his writing skills were adequate,
    Johnson was allowed to take part in the writing duties on the
    label.</p>
      <p>The song was first recorded by another Hot Wax/Invictus act
    Scherrie Payne and the Glass House (the group responsible for
    the top ten Hot 100 single "Crumbs Off the Table") led by Freda
    Payne's younger sister Scherrie Payne. Payne didn't like the
    song and with Perry being equally unsatisfied with that
    version, she and Freda recorded the song themselves. Still
    unsatisfied with the recording, Payne later suggested that lead
    singer Edna Wright of Honey Cone record it after she had passed
    through the studio. The initial version of the song, titled
    "Stick Up," would eventually be recorded and released as the
    group's follow up to "Want Ads." It would peak at number eleven
    on the pop charts in August and number one on the R&amp;B
    charts in September.</p>
      <p>, This song was covered by Ullanda and made into a disco
    song for her 1979 album "Love Zone" and by Taylor Dayne in 1988
    for her hugely successful debut album Tell It to My Heart. The
    song was later used as a sample in "Heaven," Mary Mary's 2005
    lead-off single from their self-titled third studio album. The
    single made history breaking and setting records when it
    remained at number one for nine consecutive weeks on the
    Billboard Gospel Radio chart back in 2005. Edna Wright also
    makes a brief cameo appearance at the end of the music video
    singing along to the chorus and lip-synching to her own sampled
    vocals.</p>
      <p>"Want Ads" debuted on the Billboard Hot 100 at number 79 on
    April 10, 1971. Within nine weeks on the chart, "Want Ads" was
    at the number one position for the week starting June 12. The
    song also remained number one on the R&amp;B singles chart for
    three non-consecutive weeks for the week starting May 29, 1971
    and after being bumped for one week by Aretha Franklin's
    rendition of Simon and Garfunkel's Bridge over Troubled Water,
    the song stayed at number one for two more weeks starting June
    12 through June 19.</p>
      <p>The song would go on to receive gold certification selling
    more than one million units in the U.S. The song's popularity
    had DJs playing the long version that was available on the
    Sweet Replies album. This was rare at the time. The song is
    said to have been a major contributor to the structure, sound,
    and grit of the preceding disco movement that would rock the
    popular music world.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
