<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Get_Back_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Get_Back_(song)</songId>
   <title>Get Back</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles with Billy Preston</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1969-05-24</week>
      <week>1969-05-31</week>
      <week>1969-06-07</week>
      <week>1969-06-14</week>
      <week>1969-06-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>11 April 1969</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>27 January 1969</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Blues Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:14</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Apple Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Let It Be</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Get Back" is a song by The Beatles, written primarily by
    Paul McCartney and credited to Lennon/McCartney. The song was
    originally released as a single on 11 April 1969 and credited
    to "The Beatles with Billy Preston." An alternate mix of the
    song later became the closing track of 
    <i>Let It Be</i>(1970), which was The Beatles' last album
    released before the group formally split. The single version
    was later issued on CD on the second disc of the Past Masters
    compilation. The single reached number one in the United
    Kingdom, the United States, Canada, Australia, France, West
    Germany, and Mexico. It was The Beatles' only single that
    credited another artist (Preston), although Tony Sheridan had
    shared billing with The Beatles on his own single "My Bonnie"
    when issued in the UK in 1962 (and again in 1964).</p>
      <p>"Get Back" was The Beatles' first single release in true
    stereo in the U.S. In the UK, Beatles singles remained monaural
    until the following release, "The Ballad of John and Yoko."</p>
      <p>"Get Back" is unusual in The Beatles' canon in that almost
    every moment of the song's evolution has been extensively
    documented, from its beginning as an offhand riff to its final
    mixing. Much of this documentation is in the form of illegal
    (but widely available) bootleg recordings, and is recounted in
    the book 
    <i>Get Back: The Unauthorized Chronicle of The Beatles' Let It
    Be Disaster</i>by Doug Sulpy and Ray Schweighardt.</p>
      <p>The song's melody grew out of some unstructured jamming on 7
    January 1969 during rehearsal sessions on the sound stage at
    Twickenham Studios. Over the next few minutes McCartney
    introduced some of the lyrics, reworking "Get back to the place
    you should be" from fellow Beatle George Harrison's "Sour Milk
    Sea" into "Get back to where you once belonged." McCartney had
    played bass on Jackie Lomax's recording of the song a few
    months earlier. For the press release to promote the "Get Back"
    single McCartney wrote, "We were sitting in the studio and we
    made it up out of thin air... we started to write words there
    and then...when we finished it, we recorded it at Apple Studios
    and made it into a song to roller-coast by."</p>
      <p>The released version of the song is composed of two verses,
    with an intro, outro, and several refrains. The first verse
    tells the story of a man named Jojo, who leaves his home in
    Tucson, Arizona, for some 'California grass'. (Paul's
    soon-to-be wife Linda had attended the University of Arizona in
    Tucson, where the couple later owned a spacious ranch.) The
    second verse is about a sexually ambiguous character "Loretta
    Martin" who "thought she was a woman, but she was another man."
    The single version includes a coda urging Loretta to "get back"
    where she belongs, as well.</p>
      <p>The Beatles often played around with their lyrics during
    recording sessions, as evidenced by Lennon's introduction on
    the 
    <i>Let It Be</i>album: "Sweet Loretta Fart, she thought she was
    a cleaner, but she was a frying pan". The album version of the
    song famously ends with John Lennon quipping "I'd like to say
    thank you on behalf of the group and ourselves, and I hope we
    passed the audition". (Originally John said that on the rooftop
    concert, but Phil Spector edited it into the "Get Back" song on
    the 
    <i>Let It Be</i>album.)</p>
      <p>Around the time he was developing the lyrics to "Get Back",
    McCartney satirised the "Rivers of Blood speech" by former
    British Cabinet minister Enoch Powell in a brief jam that has
    become known as the "Commonwealth Song". The lyrics included a
    line "You'd better get back to your Commonwealth homes". The
    "Commonwealth Song" had no musical resemblance to "Get Back",
    but gives insight into McCartney's interests at the time. On 9
    January Paul introduced "Get Back" to the group, with the
    "Sweet Loretta" verse very near to its finished version.
    Improvising various temporary lyrics led to what has become
    known in Beatles folklore as the "No Pakistanis" version. This
    version is more racially charged, satirising right wing
    attitudes toward immigrants in America and the UK: "...don't
    need no Puerto Ricans living in the USA" and "don't dig no
    Pakistanis taking all the people's jobs". In an interview in 
    <i>Playboy</i>magazine in 1980, Lennon described it as "...a
    better version of 'Lady Madonna'. You know, a potboiler
    rewrite."</p>
      <p>On 23 January, the group (now in Apple Studios) tried to
    record the song properly; bootleg recordings preserve a
    conversation between McCartney and Harrison between takes
    discussing the song, and McCartney explaining the original
    "protest song" concept. The recording captures the group
    deciding to drop the third verse largely because McCartney
    doesn't feel the verse is of high enough quality, although he
    likes the 
    <i>scanning</i>of the word "Pakistani". Here the song
    solidifies in its two-verse, three-solo format.</p>
      <p>Billy Preston joined The Beatles on keyboards from 22
    January, having been recruited by Harrison partly with a view
    to deter bickering among The Beatles. The group with Preston
    playing Fender Rhodes electric piano recorded about ten takes
    on 23 January. On 27 January, they made a concerted effort to
    perfect "Get Back" , recording about 14 takes. By this time the
    song had the addition of a false ending and reprise coda, as
    heard on the bootlegs of the session which are widely
    available. After numerous takes the band jammed some old
    numbers and then returned to "Get Back" one last time in an
    attempt to record the master take. This performance (Take 11)
    was considered to be the best yet - it was musically tight and
    punchy without mistakes, though the song finishes without the
    restart. On the session tape, George Harrison comments "we
    missed that end"; this is the version heard on the 
    <i>Let It Be... Naked</i>album. On 28 January the group
    attempted to recapture the previous day's performance and
    recorded several new takes each including the coda. Whilst
    these takes were good, they didn't quite achieve the quality of
    the best take from the previous day.</p>
      <p>The Beatles had EMI produce a mono remix of the track on 4
    April (completed by Jeff Jarrett). When The Beatles heard it,
    they were unhappy with the mix; therefore on 7 April McCartney
    and Glyn Johns booked time at Olympic Studios to produce new
    remixes for the single release. They made an edited version
    using the best take—take eleven—from 27 January and the 'best
    coda' ending from 28 January. The edit is so precise that it
    appears to be a continuous take, achieving the desired ending
    the Beatles had wanted all along. This was a divergence from
    the concept of straight live performance without studio
    trickery, but a relatively minor one, and avoids the somewhat
    abrupt ending of the version that is used on the 
    <i>Let It Be... Naked</i>album.</p>
      <p>The Beatles performed "Get Back" (along with other songs
    from the album) as part of the "Beatles Rooftop Performance"
    which took place on the roof of Apple Studios in Savile Row,
    London on 30 January 1969. "Get Back" was performed in full
    three times; on the third and final time, The Beatles'
    performance was interrupted by the police, who had received
    complaints from office workers nearby. After the police spoke
    to Mal Evans, he turned off Lennon and Harrison's amplifiers
    only for Harrison to switch them back on, insisting that they
    finish the song. It was during this period that McCartney
    ad-libbed, "You've been playing on the roofs again, and that's
    no good, and you know your Mummy doesn't like that...she gets
    angry...she's gonna have you arrested! Get back!" None of the
    rooftop versions appear on record in their entirety although in
    the 
    <i>Let It Be</i>film an edited version of the rooftop
    performance was included, and is available on 
    <i>Anthology 3</i>.</p>
      <p>At the end of the last rooftop performance of "Get Back",
    the audience applauds and McCartney says "Thanks, Mo" in reply
    to Maureen Starkey's cheering. Lennon adds: "I'd like to say
    thank you on behalf of the group and ourselves and I hope we've
    passed the audition". Spector used some of the talk preceding
    the master take of 27 January and edited on these comments to
    make the album version sound different from the single.</p>
      <p>The stereo single version was the first Beatles recording to
    feature Starr's drum kit in 
    <i>true</i>stereo, mixed across the left and right channels.
    This utilised the then fairly new 8-track recording technology
    and was a result of the growing popularity of stereo over mono.
    The only other Beatles track to employ this recording method
    was "The End" on 
    <i>Abbey Road</i>.</p>
      <p>On 11 April 1969, Apple Records released "Get Back" as a
    single in the United Kingdom, paired with "Don't Let Me Down"
    on the B-Side. The single began its seventeen-week stay in the
    charts on 26 April at number one, a position it held for six
    weeks. It was the only Beatles single to enter the UK charts at
    the top. "Get Back"/"Don't Let Me Down" was released in the
    United States on 5 May. Five days later, "Get Back" began its
    first of twelve weeks on the chart. Two weeks after the song's
    chart debut it hit number one, a position it held for five
    weeks.</p>
      <p>In both the United Kingdom and the United States, the single
    was released by Apple, although EMI retained the rights to the
    song as part of their contract. It was the only Beatles single
    to include an accompanying artist's name, crediting "Get
    Back/Don't Let Me Down" to "The Beatles with Billy
    Preston".</p>
      <p>Apple launched a print ad campaign for the song concurrent
    with its release showing a photo of the band with the slogan 
    <i>The Beatles as Nature Intended</i>, indicating that the
    sound of "Get Back" harked to the group's earlier days.</p>
      <p>The single version of the song contains a tape echo effect
    throughout and a coda after a false ending, with the lyrics
    "Get back Loretta / Your mommy's waiting for you / Wearing her
    high-heel shoes / And her low-neck sweater / Get back home,
    Loretta." This does not appear on the album version; the single
    version's first LP appearance would come three years later on
    the 
    <i>1967–1970</i>compilation. This version also appeared in the
    albums 
    <i>20 Greatest Hits</i>, 
    <i>Past Masters</i>and 
    <i>The Beatles 1</i>. This single version was also included in
    the original line-up of the proposed 
    <i>Get Back</i>album that was scheduled to be released during
    the fall of 1969.</p>
      <p>In Britain and Europe "Get Back/Don't Let Me Down" was the
    Beatles' last single to be released in mono, but in the US the
    single was released in stereo. It was The Beatles' first single
    to be released in true stereo instead of mono as part of the
    "stereo only" movement gaining force in 1969. In both versions
    the lead guitar played by John Lennon is in the left channel
    and the rhythm guitar played by George Harrison is in the right
    channel. Normally George Harrison was the lead guitarist, but
    on "Get Back" John Lennon played the lead (Harrison had
    temporarily quit the group on 10 January and was absent when
    Lennon worked out the lead guitar). The single was also
    released in the experimental PocketDisc format by Americom in
    conjunction with Apple and Capitol in the late 1960s.</p>
      <p>When Phil Spector came to remix "Get Back" he decided to
    make it seem different from the version released as the single.
    Both of the previous unreleased 
    <i>Get Back</i>albums included elements of studio chatter to
    add to the live feel of the recordings. In this spirit, Spector
    included part of the studio chatter recorded immediately before
    the master take (recorded on 27 January) and added the close of
    the rooftop performance. This made the album version appear to
    be a live version, creating the impression that the single and
    album versions are different takes. The studio echo effect was
    also removed.</p>
      <p>In 1996, a different version of "Get Back" from the Rooftop
    Concert was released. It was the last song from the concert.
    The police had arrived and warned the Beatles to end their
    concert. After some bargaining, the group was given the chance
    to play one more song. During the last verse McCartney ad-libs,
    "Get back Loretta / You've been singing on the roof again! /
    ... Your mommy doesn't like that... / Oh no... she gets angry /
    She's gonna have you arrested!"</p>
      <p>In 2003 "Get Back" was re-released on the 
    <i>Let It Be... Naked</i>album, remixed by independent
    producers with the sanction of surviving Beatles Paul McCartney
    and Ringo Starr, with John Lennon's and George Harrison's
    widows. The "naked" version of "Get Back" is ostensibly a
    cleaned up version of the single version albeit much shorter as
    there is a fade immediately before the final "whoo" and coda.
    Apple also prepared a specially-created music video of the 
    <i>Let It Be... Naked</i>release of the song to promote that
    album in 2003. This video is edited together using stock
    footage of the band, along with Billy Preston, George Martin
    and others.</p>
      <p>In 2006 a newly mixed version of "Get Back" produced by
    George Martin and his son Giles was included on the album 
    <i>Love</i>. This version incorporates elements of "A Hard
    Day's Night" (the intro chord), "A Day in the Life" (the
    improvised orchestral crescendo), "The End" (Ringo Starr's drum
    solo and John Lennon and Paul McCartney's first two guitar
    solos), and "Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band (Reprise)"
    (Take 1's drum count-off intro). However, there are several
    edits in this piece, including an extended intro, and the
    second verse is removed completely.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
