<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walk_Like_an_Egyptian 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walk_Like_an_Egyptian</songId>
   <title>Walk Like an Egyptian</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Bangles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Bangles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-01-03</week>
      <week>1987-01-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/00/The_Bangles_Walk_Like_An_Egyptian.jpg/200px-The_Bangles_Walk_Like_An_Egyptian.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Bangles+Walk-Like-an-Egyptian.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Different Light</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>September 1, 1986 (UK)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" maxi</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Sunset Sound Factory (1985)</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:24</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Liam Sternberg</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>David Kahne</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Walk Like an Egyptian" is a number-one hit from the album 
    <i>Different Light</i>by The Bangles in 1986.</p>
      <p>Liam Sternberg wrote the song after seeing people on a ferry
    walking awkwardly to keep their balance, which reminded him of
    figures in Ancient Egyptian reliefs. The opening lyrics state,
    "All the old paintings on the tombs/They do the sand dance
    don't you know". The reference to the sand dance possibly
    refers to a music hall routine performed by Wilson, Keppel and
    Betty where Wilson and Keppel danced around in the postures
    portrayed on the reliefs wearing the fez while Betty
    watched.</p>
      <p>Sternberg offered his song to Toni Basil, who turned it
    down. David Kahne, the producer of 
    <i>Different Light</i>, took the song to the Bangles who agreed
    to record it. Kahne had each member of the group sing the
    lyrics to determine who would sing each verse, with Susanna
    Hoffs, Vicki Peterson and Michael Steele each singing lead
    vocals on a verse in the final version.</p>
      <p>"Walk Like an Egyptian" was released as the third single
    from 
    <i>Different Light</i>. It debuted on the Hot 100 in September
    1986. The song reached a peak of number three on the UK Singles
    Chart in November 1986 and reached number one in the U.S. on
    December 20, staying at the top of the Hot 100 for four weeks,
    carrying it over into January 1987. The song is the first song
    by an all-female group playing their own instruments to top the
    
    <i>Billboard</i>singles chart. The success of the song and
    "Manic Monday" propelled 
    <i>Different Light</i>to number two on the 200 chart, making it
    the group's most successful album.</p>
      <p>On the 
    <i>American Top 40 Top 100 of 1987</i>radio show, host Casey
    Kasem reported the song was added to the album as a joke, to
    which he added, "Some joke. Here's the punchline: The Bangles'
    sand dance of the ancient pharaohs walks away with the pyramid
    prize of the year!" contrasting how the song was added to the
    album with how popular it became, as it topped the year-end 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 singles chart, which is the chart the
    American Top 40 was using at the time.</p>
      <p>The song was also the Bangles' last non-cover Top 40 hit
    that wasn't co-written by at least one band member. Subsequent
    charted singles (with the exception of "Hazy Shade of Winter",
    which is a cover) were co-written by Susanna Hoffs and Debbie
    Peterson.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Walk Like an Egyptian" was nominated
    for Best Group Video in the 1987 MTV Video Music Awards. It
    featured people dancing in a pose similar to the pose depicted
    in the Ancient Egyptian reliefs that inspired songwriter Liam
    Sternberg. In a popular scene from the video, Hoffs was filmed
    in a close-up where her eyes moved from side-to-side, looking
    left and right. When asked about the scene in an interview with
    online magazine PlanetOut.com, Hoffs explained that she was
    actually looking at individual audience members during the
    video shoot, which took place with a live audience. Looking
    directly at individual audience members was a technique she
    used to overcome stage fright, and she was unaware that the
    camera had a close-up on her while she was employing this
    technique, switching between one audience member on her left
    and one on her right.</p>
      <p>"Walk Like an Egyptian" was one of the songs deemed
    inappropriate by Clear Channel following the September 11, 2001
    attacks, presumably due to its reference to Egypt.</p>
      <p>Additional sources used:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
