<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Yellow_Rose_of_Texas 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Yellow_Rose_of_Texas</songId>
   <title>The Yellow Rose of Texas " Mitch Miller</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>"The Yellow Rose of Texas" Mitch Miller</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1955-09-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Yellow Rose of Texas" is a traditional folk song about
    a mulatto prostitute which has long been popular in the United
    States and is considered an unofficial state song of Texas. The
    actual author is unknown; the original publisher (Firth, Pond
    &amp; Co.) only stated that it was composed and arranged
    expressly for Charles H. Brown by "J.K." The A. Henry Moss
    Papers in the Center for American History has an unpublished
    early handwritten version of what may be a similar song,
    perhaps dating from the time of the Battle of San Jacinto in
    1836.</p>
      <p>The soundtrack to the TV miniseries 
    <i>James A. Michener's Texas</i>dates a version of the song to
    1927 and co-credits the authorship thereof to Gene Autry.
    However, Don George ('I'm Beginning to See the Light') reworked
    the original version of the song, which Mitch Miller made into
    a popular recording in 1955 that knocked Bill Haley's "(We're
    Gonna) Rock Around The Clock" from the top of the Best Sellers
    chart in the U.S. Miller's version was featured in the motion
    picture 
    <i>Giant</i>. Actor James Dean, who starred in the movie, died
    when Miller's version was atop the Best Sellers chart.</p>
      <p>A twentieth century myth has turned the 
    <i>Yellow Rose</i>into one Emily D. West, a housekeeper in a
    hotel in New Washington, Texas, during the Texas
    Revolution.</p>
      <p>Briefly stated, the song is based on a Texas legend from the
    days of the Texas War of Independence. According to the legend,
    a woman named Emily D. West — a mulatto, and hence, the song's
    reference to her being "yellow" — who was seized by Mexican
    forces during the looting of Galveston seduced General Antonio
    López de Santa Anna, President of Mexico and commander of the
    Mexican forces. The legend credits her supposed seduction with
    lowering the guard of the Mexican army and facilitating the
    Texan victory in the battle of San Jacinto waged in 1836 near
    present-day Houston. Santa Anna's opponent was General Sam
    Houston, who won the battle literally in minutes, and with
    almost no casualties.</p>
      <p>Historians assert that if West was with Santa Anna, it was
    not by her choice, nor did she play any part in deciding the
    battle. The seduction legend was largely unknown until the
    publication of English tourist William Bollaert's diary in the
    1950s, when amateur historians propagated an embellished
    version.</p>
      <p>The basic facts appear to be that Emily West migrated to
    Texas from New York City in late 1835. Sources describe her as
    a teen or as a woman of twenty. According to one version of the
    legend, she became an indentured servant on the plantation of
    James Morgan near what was then called New Washington and is
    now Morgan's Point. Because of her indenture to Morgan, some
    historians say, she became known by his surname, as was the
    custom for indentured servants as well as slaves.</p>
      <p>Santa Anna reportedly saw West in April 1836 when he invaded
    New Washington prior to the Battle of San Jacinto. Legend
    states that she was forcibly placed in his camp. Allegedly,
    Santa Anna was with her when Texan General Sam Houston's troops
    arrived, forcing him to flee without weapons or armor and
    enabling his capture the next day.</p>
      <p>The song became popular with Confederate Army troops,
    especially those from Texas, though the last verse and the
    chorus are slightly different.</p>
      <p>(Last verse)</p>
      <p>This refers to famous Confederate generals Joseph Johnston,
    Robert E. Lee, P. G. T. Beauregard, and John Bell Hood.</p>
      <p>The chorus substitutes the word "darky" with "soldier". The
    same substitution is made throughout the song.</p>
      <p>In 1984, country music artists Johnny Lee and Lane Brody
    recorded a song called "The Yellow Rose". This song, which
    retained the original melody of "The Yellow Rose of Texas" but
    wrote new lyrics for it, was used as the title theme to a TV
    series also entitled 
    <i>The Yellow Rose</i>and was a Number One country hit that
    year.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
