<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Girl_(The_Temptations_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Girl_(The_Temptations_song)</songId>
   <title>My Girl</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Temptations</artistId>
      <artistName>The Temptations</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1965-03-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/c/c2/Tempts-mygirl-cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Temptations+My-Girl.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Temptations Sing Smokey</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 21, 1964</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Hitsville USA (Studio A); September 25, November 10 and November 17, 1964</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:59</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Gordy , G 7038</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Smokey Robinson</writer>
      <writer>Ronald White</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Smokey Robinson</producer>
      <producer>Ronald White</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Otis Blue</i>
      </p>
      <p>"My Girl" is a 1964 song recorded by The Temptations for the
    Gordy (Motown) label which became a number one hit in 1965.
    Written and produced by The Miracles members Smokey Robinson
    and Ronald White, the song became the Temptations' first U.S.
    number-one single, and is today their signature song.
    Robinson's inspiration for writing this song was his wife,
    Miracles member Claudette Rogers Robinson. The song was
    featured on the Temptations album 
    <i>The Temptations Sing Smokey</i>.</p>
      <p>The recorded version of "My Girl" was the first Temptations
    single to feature David Ruffin on lead vocals. Previously,
    Eddie Kendricks and Paul Williams had performed most of the
    group's lead vocals, and Ruffin had joined the group as a
    replacement for former Temptation Elbridge "Al" Bryant. While
    on tour as part of the Motortown Revue, a collective tour for
    most of the Motown roster, Smokey Robinson caught the
    Temptations' part of the show. The group had included a medley
    of soul standards in the show, one of which, The Drifters'
    "Under the Boardwalk", was a solo spot for Ruffin. Impressed,
    Robinson decided to produce a single with Ruffin singing lead.
    Robinson saw Ruffin as a "sleeping giant" in the group with a
    unique voice that was "mellow" yet "gruff".. Robinson thought
    that if he could write just the perfect song for Ruffin's
    voice, then he could have a smash hit. The song was to be
    something that Ruffin could "belt out" yet something that was
    also "melodic and sweet". After some persuasion from Ruffin's
    bandmates, Robinson had the Temptations record "My Girl"
    instead of The Miracles, and recruited Ruffin to sing the lead
    vocals. The signature guitar riff heard during the introduction
    and under the verses was played by Robert White of the Funk
    Brothers. This part can be heard without vocals on the 2004
    Deluxe Edition of the soundtrack from the 2002 documentary
    Standing in the Shadows of Motown.</p>
      <p>"My Girl" was later sampled for "Stay", a single from the
    Temptations' 1998 album 
    <i>Phoenix Rising</i>.</p>
      <p>The single was re-released in 1992. It did not reach the 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts, but did reach #2 in the UK Singles
    Chart.</p>
      <p>"My Girl" climbed to the top of the U.S. pop charts after
    its Christmas time 1964 release, making it the Temptations'
    first number-one hit. The single was also the first number-one
    hit on the reinstated R&amp;B Singles chart, which had gone on
    a fifteen-month hiatus from 1963 to 1965.. The success of this
    single launched a series of Ruffin-led hits, including "It's
    Growing" (1965), "Since I Lost My Baby" (1965), "My Baby"
    (1965), "Ain't Too Proud to Beg" (1966), "Beauty Is Only Skin
    Deep" (1966), "(I Know) I'm Losing You" (1966), "All I Need"
    (1967), "(Loneliness Made Me Realize) It's You That I Need"
    (1967), "I Wish It Would Rain" (1967), and "I Could Never Love
    Another (After Loving You)" (1968). The former background
    figure quickly became the group's main (and, excepting
    irregular leads by Kendricks and Williams, only) lead singer by
    the end of 1965. After many Ruffin-led hits, he started to
    develop a large ego. He was later fired from the group (see the
    Temptations main article for more details).</p>
      <p>In 2004, "My Girl" was ranked number 88 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's list of the 500 greatest songs
    of all time.</p>
      <p>In 1965, Otis Redding brought more of a traditional blues
    flavor to the song in his cover of "My Girl". This version,
    produced by Steve Cropper, was featured on Redding's critically
    acclaimed album 
    <i>Otis Blue: Otis Redding Sings Soul</i>, and was also on John
    Lennon's jukebox. Redding's version wasn't released as a single
    in the United States, but Atlantic UK released it in England to
    capitalize on the relative lack of success by the Temptations'
    original version, and Redding's cover eventually peaked at
    #11.</p>
      <p>A cover version was included on The Rolling Stones 
    <i>Flowers</i>in 1967. It was recorded two years earlier. The
    Mamas &amp; the Papas featured this song on the third album 
    <i>Deliver</i>(1967), and released it as a single that reached
    15 on the U.S. pop charts. Al Green included a cover version on
    his 1969 album 
    <i>Green Is Blues</i>. Michael Jackson covered the song for his
    album 
    <i>Ben</i>. It has also been a hit for Jamaican ska rocksteady
    legend, Prince Buster. In 1977, Dolly Parton included a country
    version of the song on her album 
    <i>New Harvest - First Gathering</i>. In 1980, Amii Stewart and
    Johnny Bristol recorded it as a duet in a medley with another
    Motown classic, "My Guy". In 1988, Suave had a Top 40 Pop hit
    &amp; Top 10 R&amp;B hit with the song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
