<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windy 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windy</songId>
   <title>Windy</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Association</artistId>
      <artistName>The Association</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1967-07-01</week>
      <week>1967-07-08</week>
      <week>1967-07-15</week>
      <week>1967-07-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/f/f0/Windy_by_The_Association_single_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Association+Windy.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Insight Out</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1967</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Sunshine Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:53</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Warner Bros. Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ruthann Friedman</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Windy" is a pop music song written by Ruthann Friedman and
    recorded by The Association. Released in 1967, the song reached
    number one on the Billboard Hot 100 in July of that year. Later
    in 1967, an instrumental version by jazz guitarist Wes
    Montgomery became his biggest Hot 100 hit when it peaked at
    number forty-four. "Windy" was The Association's second U.S.
    number-one, following "Cherish" in 1966.</p>
      <p>According to rumor, the original lyrics by Ruthann Friedman
    were about a man, and The Association changed them to be about
    a woman.</p>
      <p>"There are many explanations of who Windy actually was in
    Ruthann's life. She would have you know, she being me Ruthann
    Friedman, that none of them are true. Windy was, indeed, a
    female and purely a fictitious character who popped into my
    head one fine day in 1967...</p>
      <p>During the recording session the Association members, sure
    that they were in the middle of recording a hit,called the song
    writer, me again, in to sing on the fade at the end. I can be
    heard singing a blues harmony as the song fades out..."</p>
      <p>Session musician Hal Blaine was brought in to play
    drums.</p>
      <p>The song was featured in an episode of 
    <i>The Drew Carey Show</i>, where the character Nigel Wick
    (played by Craig Ferguson) played it on the harp. It was also
    featured recently in the second season finale of HBO's 
    <i>Big Love</i>, where Teeny Henrickson leads a children's
    dance troupe while the song is playing for the annual Pioneers
    Festival. In 2009 the song, with slightly altered lyrics, was
    sung by actor Brad Garrett in an advertisement for 7-Up.</p>
      <p>A version of the song was used as the theme tune on the
    nightly 
    <i>Today</i>programme broadcast on Thames Television from 1968
    to 1977.</p>
      <p>Comedy rockers Paul and Storm did a parody version called
    “Lindsay“ about Lindsay Lohan.</p>
      <p>Barry Manilow and The Association covered this song along
    with "Cherish" on the 2006 album 
    <i>The Greatest Songs of the Sixties</i>. Also recorded by
    Astrud Gilberto on her album 
    <i>Windy</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
