<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daydream_Believer 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daydream_Believer</songId>
   <title>Daydream Believer</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Monkees</artistId>
      <artistName>The Monkees</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1967-12-02</week>
      <week>1967-12-09</week>
      <week>1967-12-16</week>
      <week>1967-12-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/b/b2/Monkees_daydream_believer.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Monkees+Daydream-Believer.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Birds, The Bees &amp; the Monkees</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 30, 1967</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>June 14, 1967 and August 9, 1967</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:07</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Colgems</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>John Stewart</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>The Monkees</producer>
      <producer>Chip Douglas</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Daydream Believer" is a song composed by John Stewart
    shortly before he left the Kingston Trio. The song was
    originally recorded by The Monkees, with Davy Jones singing
    lead vocals. The single hit the number one spot on the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100 chart in December 1967, remaining there for
    four weeks, and peaked at number five in the UK Singles Chart.
    It was The Monkees' last number one hit in the U.S. It was also
    recorded by Anne Murray in 1979, whose version reached #3 on
    the U.S. country singles chart and #12 on the Billboard Hot
    100.</p>
      <p>Producer Chip Douglas introduced the Monkees to the song. It
    was recorded during the sessions for their 1967 album 
    <i>Pisces, Aquarius, Capricorn &amp; Jones Ltd.</i>but was
    ultimately included on their 1968 album 
    <i>The Birds, The Bees &amp; the Monkees</i>(it proved to be
    bandmember Peter Tork's only appearance on the album). All four
    Monkees appear on the track, with Michael Nesmith on lead
    guitar, Peter Tork on piano (he also came up with the
    arrangement), and Micky Dolenz on backing vocals. Davy Jones
    wasn't sure of the song's potential at first, and admitted
    later that he'd recorded the vocal with a hint of annoyance at
    the ongoing takes. His feelings changed when the song became a
    hit.</p>
      <p>John Stewart's original lyrics in the second stanza were
    "You once thought of me as a white knight on a steed, Now you
    know how funky I can be". When the Monkees recorded the song,
    "funky" was changed to "happy", removing any sense of contrast
    or meaning to the lyric. The song is also known for its
    humorous opening:</p>
      <p>In 1986, three of the four Monkees (Dolenz, Jones, and Tork)
    mounted a successful reunion tour and had a major hit with the
    newly recorded "That Was Then, This Is Now." Arista Records,
    who owned the Monkees' masters at the time, re-released
    "Daydream Believer" as a followup single, re-mixed with a
    heavier drum track by Michael Lloyd (who had produced "That Was
    Then, This Was Now"). The re-released single was a minor hit
    the second time out, garnering some brief airplay on Top 40
    radio stations of the day.</p>
      <p>Anne Murray included it on her 1979 album 
    <i>I'll Always Love You</i>; the following year her single
    peaked at number one on the U.S. Adult Contemporary chart,
    number three on the country chart, and number twelve on the pop
    chart. She re-released the song as a duet with Nelly Furtado in
    her 2008 
    <i>Anne Murray Duets: Friends and Legends</i>album.</p>
      <p>Numerous other artists have covered the song:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
