<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Every_Breath_You_Take 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Every_Breath_You_Take</songId>
   <title>Every Breath You Take</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Police</artistId>
      <artistName>The Police</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1983-07-09</week>
      <week>1983-07-16</week>
      <week>1983-07-23</week>
      <week>1983-07-30</week>
      <week>1983-08-06</week>
      <week>1983-08-13</week>
      <week>1983-08-20</week>
      <week>1983-08-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/b/bd/Every_Breath_You_Take_single_cover.png</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Police+Every-Breath-You-Take.png</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Synchronicity</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 1983</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl record (7")</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>December 1982</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:14</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>A&amp;M - AM 117</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Sting</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>The Police</producer>
      <producer>Hugh Padgham</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Every Breath You Take" is a song by The Police on the
    band's 1983 album 
    <i>Synchronicity</i>, written by Sting. The single was one of
    the biggest of 1983, topping the Billboard Hot 100 singles
    chart for eight weeks and the UK Singles Chart for four weeks.
    It also topped the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Top Tracks chart for nine weeks. Sting won Song
    of the Year and The Police won Best Pop Performance by a Duo or
    Group with Vocal at the Grammy Awards of 1984 for "Every Breath
    You Take". The song ranked #84 on the 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All Time
    and #25 on 
    <i>Billboard</i>'s Hot 100 All-Time Top Songs. This song is
    considered to be The Police's signature song.</p>
      <p>The track was written during the collapse of Sting's
    marriage to Frances Tomelty; the lyrics are the words of a
    sinister, controlling character, who is watching "every breath
    you take; every move you make".</p>
      <p>Sting later said he was disconcerted by how many people
    think the song is more positive than it is. He insists it's
    about unrequited love (the song was written at the time he and
    his then wife divorced), about the obsession with the lost
    lover, the jealousy and surveillance that followed. "One couple
    told me 'Oh we love that song; it was the main song played at
    our wedding!' I thought, 'Well, good luck.'" When asked why he
    appears angry in the music video Sting told BBC Radio 2, "I
    think the song is very, very sinister and ugly and people have
    misinterpreted it as being a gentle, little love song."</p>
      <p>According to the 
    <i>Back to Mono</i>box-set book, "Every Breath You Take" is
    said to be influenced by a Gene Pitney song titled "Every
    Breath I Take". The song is composed in Classical rondo form
    with its ABACABA structure. The lyrics are very similar to the
    opening lines of a short story by science fiction author Judith
    Merrill titled "Whoever You Are". The chorus appears to borrow
    heavily from the Leo Sayer track, "More Than I Can Say",
    recorded a couple of years before. The lyrics "Every breath I
    take" and "Every move I make", with the replacement of 
    <i>I</i>with 
    <i>you</i>, appear in the song "D'yer Mak'er" by Led
    Zeppelin.</p>
      <p>"Every Breath You Take" is played by Sting on double bass
    and lead vocals, Andy Summers on electric guitar, piano and
    backing vocals, Stewart Copeland on drums and backing vocals,
    and a group of four violinists.</p>
      <p>The demo of the song originally featured a synthesizer.
    While recording, Summers came up with a guitar part inspired by
    Béla Bartók that would later become a trademark lick, and
    played it straight through in one take. He was asked to put
    guitar onto what was to him an already finished song and just
    played what came to mind. As he finished his take, everyone in
    the control room burst into applause.</p>
      <p>The song had a music video (directed by duo Godley &amp;
    Creme) that was praised for its black-and-white cinematography.
    Both MTV (1999) and VH1 (2002) named it as one of the best
    music videos ever, placing it 16th and 33rd in their respective
    top 100 lists. Daniel Pearl won the first MTV cinematography
    award for his work on the video.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by artists including Dilana, UB40,
    Tina Arena, Juliana Hatfield, Millencolin, and Copeland. "Weird
    Al" Yankovic included a polka interpretation in his medley
    "Polkas on 45". Sergio Blass ( ex Menudo (band)) remade the
    song as "Siempre Te Amaré" in 1994. Also, a cover version of
    the song is used extensively in the 1985 film "Cat's Eye." The
    song was also covered in 2004 by UB40 for the "50 First Dates"
    Soundtrack. A cover by Mason Dixon reached #69 on the Hot
    Country Songs charts in 1983.</p>
      <p>In 1986 Sting changed the lyrics to the song for a sequence
    at the end of a Spitting Image special. The title was altered
    to "Every Bomb You Make" and the video featured several of the
    puppets of world leaders projected over a setting sun. On the
    line "I'll be watching you", the puppet of Death appears. Sting
    himself performed the re-recording.</p>
      <p>Sting also riffs on the lyrics in his song 
    <i>Love Is the Seventh Wave</i>, singing "Every breath you
    take/every move you make/every cake you bake/every leg you
    break..."</p>
      <p>In 1999, "Every Breath You Take" was listed as one of the
    Top 100 Songs of the Century by BMI. In 2003, VH1 ranked the
    song the #2 greatest Break-up song of all time. And also as of
    2003, Sting was still taking in an average of $2000 per day in
    royalties for the then 20-year-old song "Every Breath You
    Take."</p>
      <p>Australia's Seven Network also used a cover version of the
    song for their bumpers and promotions in 1999.</p>
      <p>In October 2007, Sting was awarded a Million-Air certificate
    for 9 million airplays of "Every Breath You Take" at the
    prestigious BMI Awards show in London, England with only Van
    Morrison's "Brown Eyed Girl" a close second at 8 million air
    plays.</p>
      <p>This song was also featured by in October 2008 Nintendo
    music simulation game, 
    <i>Wii Music</i>.</p>
      <p>The song's opening riff formed the basis for the Puff Daddy
    hit, I'll Be Missing You, a tribute to slain rapper The
    Notorious B.I.G.. When the song was played at that year's MTV
    Video Awards, Sting joined in alongside Puff Daddy and Faith
    Evans.</p>
      <p>It was covered by Filipino acoustic band MYMP in 2006, and
    again by Filipina diva Jessa Zaragosa in 2009.</p>
      <p>In 2009 it was also covered by David May feat. Kelvin Scott
    under 
    <i>I'll Be Watching You</i>title.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
