<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eternal_Flame_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eternal_Flame_(song)</songId>
   <title>Eternal Flame</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Bangles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Bangles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1989-04-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/3d/The_Bangles_Eternal_Flame.jpg/200px-The_Bangles_Eternal_Flame.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Bangles+Eternal-Flame.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Everything</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 11, 1989</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl record (7")</format>
      <format>CD (3")</format>
      <format>Cassingle</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Ocean Way, Studio 55 (1988)</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:56</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>CBS</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Susanna Hoffs</writer>
      <writer>Tom Kelly</writer>
      <writer>Billy Steinberg</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Davitt Sigerson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Eternal Flame" is a song by The Bangles which became a hit
    single in 1989, peaking at number one in the charts in six
    countries, including Australia, the United Kingdom, and the
    United States. It was written by popular songwriters Billy
    Steinberg and Tom Kelly and the Bangles' own Susanna Hoffs.</p>
      <p>It was a ballad, unlike the rest of the garage-band pop
    songs on their album 
    <i>Everything</i>. Co-writer Billy Steinberg describes it as
    "The Beatles meet The Byrds".</p>
      <p>The song was inspired by two eternal flames: one for Elvis
    Presley that Michael Steele saw when the band was at Graceland,
    and one at a local synagogue in Palm Springs which Steinberg
    attended as a child. Steinberg recalled to Songfacts: "Susanna
    was talking about The Bangles having visited Graceland, and she
    said there was some type of shrine to Elvis that included some
    kind of eternal flame. As soon as those words were mentioned, I
    immediately thought of the synagogue in the town of Palm
    Springs, California where I grew up. I remember during our
    Sunday school class they would walk us through the sanctuary.
    There was one little red light and they told us it was called
    the eternal flame."</p>
      <p>It spent one week at number one on the Billboard Hot 100,
    preceded by "The Living Years" by Mike + The Mechanics and
    followed by "The Look" by Roxette.</p>
      <p>The song debuted on the UK Singles Chart in February 1989 at
    number 81 and peaked at number one in April spending four weeks
    there and went on to spend twenty weeks in the chart and was
    the UK's third best-selling song of 1989.</p>
      <p>The song also spent seven weeks at the #1 position in the
    Dutch Top 40. It also topped the U.S. adult contemporary chart
    for two weeks.</p>
      <p>The song was Australia's biggest selling single of '89 and
    was sent-up on the Australian TV show 
    <i>Fast Forward</i>.</p>
      <p>The song provided the musical backdrop for the closing
    montage of Season 1, Episode 21 of 
    <i>Cold Case</i>.</p>
      <p>Eternal Flame was featured in an episode of 
    <i>True Blood</i>on HBO and 
    <i>Pushing Daisies</i>on ABC, where it was sung by Kristin
    Chenoweth.</p>
      <p>, "What I Meant To Say" is a non-album track</p>
      <p>A cover version by Atomic Kitten was released as a single
    and reached number one for two weeks on the UK charts in 2001.
    Susanna Hoffs liked the cover version and subsequently teamed
    up with Atomic Kitten and once again with Eternal Flame writers
    Billy Steinberg and Tom Kelly and wrote "Love Doesn't Have to
    Hurt" for their next album 
    <i>Feels So Good</i>.</p>
      <p>The original version of the song ran a total of 3:37 and is
    featured on Atomic Kitten's debut album, 
    <i>Right Now</i>. This version was more similar to the original
    version released by The Bangles. For the single release the
    song was re-recorded with a new musical arrangement and new
    vocals, cutting the song down to 3:17. This version is
    available on the "Greatest Hits" and the physical CD
    single.</p>
      <p>Atomic Kitten's version was remixed by Love to Infinity
    (T-Club Mix: 7:20).</p>
      <p>Atomic Kitten made the song another massive success,
    entering at #1 in the UK, staying there for two weeks, with
    over 140,000 in its first week and 70,000 in its second week.
    The song has sold over 400,000 copies in the UK, and has been
    certified Gold. The single entered the top 5 in over ten
    countries.</p>
      <p>The single went to number 2 in the French singles chart, a
    huge success, considering it is their only single to get
    anywhere into the top 20! This meant that they were one-hit
    wonders there. It was certified gold for sales of over 150,000
    copies.</p>
      <p>The single was a moderate success in Canada, getting into
    the top 20 at number 15, outdoing Whole Again, which only
    peaked at 20.</p>
      <p>Eternal Flame was certified Gold in United Kingdom, Sweden,
    and New Zealand.</p>
      <p>The single was, without doubt a worldwide success, entering
    the top 10 in every country it was released, except from
    Norway, where it was close to the top 10, at 13, and Australia,
    where it peaked at 47. This was disappointing compared to the
    rest of the countries it was released.</p>
      <p>Eternal Flame went on to sell over one million copies
    worldwide.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered in 2008 by Human Nature on their
    album: "A Symphony of Hits"</p>
      <p>Additional sources used:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
