<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hey_Jude 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hey_Jude</songId>
   <title>Hey Jude</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1968-09-28</week>
      <week>1968-10-05</week>
      <week>1968-10-12</week>
      <week>1968-10-19</week>
      <week>1968-10-26</week>
      <week>1968-11-02</week>
      <week>1968-11-09</week>
      <week>1968-11-16</week>
      <week>1968-11-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>26 August 1968</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>31 July 1968 at Trident Studios , London</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>7:11</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Apple</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Hey Jude" is a song by the English rock band The Beatles.
    Credited to Lennon/McCartney, the ballad evolved from "Hey
    Jules", a song Paul McCartney wrote to comfort John Lennon's
    son Julian during his parents' divorce. "Hey Jude" begins with
    a verse-bridge structure based around McCartney's vocal
    performance and piano accompaniment; further details are added
    as the song progresses to distinguish sections. After the
    fourth verse, the song shifts to a fade-out coda that lasts for
    more than four minutes.</p>
      <p>"Hey Jude" was released in August 1968 as the first single
    from The Beatles' record label Apple Records. More than seven
    minutes in length, "Hey Jude" was at the time the longest
    single ever to top the British charts. It also spent nine weeks
    as number one in the United States—the longest run at the top
    of the American charts for a Beatles single. The single has
    sold approximately eight million copies and is frequently
    included on professional lists of the all-time best songs.</p>
      <p>In 1968, John Lennon and his wife Cynthia Lennon separated
    due to the former's affair with Yoko Ono. Soon afterwards, Paul
    McCartney drove out to visit Cynthia and Julian, her son with
    Lennon. "We'd been very good friends for millions of years and
    I thought it was a bit much for them suddenly to be 
    <i>personae non gratae</i>and out of my life," McCartney said.
    Cynthia Lennon recalled, "I was truly surprised when, one
    afternoon, Paul arrived on his own. I was touched by his
    obvious concern for our welfare.... On the journey down he
    composed 'Hey Jude' in the car. I will never forget Paul's
    gesture of care and concern in coming to see us."</p>
      <p>The song's original title was "Hey Jules", and it was
    intended to comfort Julian Lennon from the stress of his
    parents' divorce. McCartney said, "I started with the idea 'Hey
    Jules', which was Julian, don't make it bad, take a sad song
    and make it better. Hey, try and deal with this terrible thing.
    I knew it was not going to be easy for him. I always feel sorry
    for kids in divorces ... I had the idea [for the song] by the
    time I got there. I changed it to 'Jude' because I thought that
    sounded a bit better." Julian Lennon discovered the song had
    been written for him almost twenty years later. He remembered
    being closer to McCartney than to his father: "Paul and I used
    to hang about quite a bit—more than Dad and I did. We had a
    great friendship going and there seems to be far more pictures
    of me and Paul playing together at that age than there are
    pictures of me and my dad."</p>
      <p>Although McCartney originally wrote the song for Julian
    Lennon, John Lennon thought it had actually been written for
    him:</p>
      <p>But I always heard it as a song to me. If you think about
    it... Yoko's just come into the picture. He's saying. 'Hey,
    Jude—Hey, John.' I know I'm sounding like one of those fans who
    reads things into it, but you can 
    <i>hear</i>it as a song to me ... Subconsciously, he was
    saying, Go ahead, leave me. On a conscious level, he didn't
    want me to go ahead.</p>
      <p>Other people believed McCartney wrote the song about them,
    including Judith Simons, a journalist with the 
    <i>Daily Express</i>. Still others, including John Lennon, have
    speculated that McCartney's failing long-term relationship with
    Jane Asher when he wrote "Hey Jude" was an unconscious "message
    to himself". In fact, when Lennon mentioned that he thought the
    song was about him, McCartney denied it, and told Lennon he had
    written the song about himself.</p>
      <p>Writer Mark Hertsgaard noted "many of the song's lyrics do
    seem directed more at a grown man on the verge of a powerful
    new love, especially the lines 'you have found her now go and
    get her' and 'you're waiting for someone to perform with.'" Tim
    Riley wrote, "If the song is about self-worth and
    self-consolation in the face of hardship, the vocal performance
    itself conveys much of the journey. He begins by singing to
    comfort someone else, finds himself weighing his own feelings
    in the process, and finally, in the repeated refrains that
    nurture his own approbation, he comes to believe in
    himself."</p>
      <p>McCartney changed the title to "Hey Jude" because the name
    Jude was easier to sing. Much as he did with "Yesterday",
    McCartney played the song for other musicians and friends. Ron
    Griffith of Badfinger, the first band to join the Beatles-owned
    record label Apple Records, recalled that on their first day in
    the studio, "Paul walked over to the grand piano and said, 'Hey
    lads, have a listen', and he sat down and gave us a full
    concert rendition of 'Hey Jude'. We were gobsmacked."</p>
      <p>When McCartney introduced Lennon to his new composition, he
    came to "the movement you need is on your shoulder" and told
    Lennon "I'll fix that bit." Lennon asked why, and McCartney
    answered "...it's a stupid expression; it sounds like a
    parrot." Lennon parried with "You won't, you know. That's the
    best line in the song." McCartney thus left the line in, and
    later said "...when I play that song, that's the line when I
    think of John, and sometimes I get a little emotional during
    that moment."</p>
      <p>"Hey Jude" begins with McCartney singing lead vocals and
    playing the piano. The patterns McCartney plays are based on
    three chords: F, C and B-flat (I, V and IV); the second verse
    adds accompaniment by guitar and a single tambourine. The main
    chord progression is "flipped on its head" for the coda, as the
    C chord is replaced by E-flat. Writer Tim Riley notes, "As
    Ringo offers a restrained tom-tom and cymbal fill, the piano
    shifts downward to add a flat seventh to the tonic chord,
    making the downbeat of the bridge the point of arrival ('And
    any time you feel the 
    <i>pain'</i>)." At the end of each bridge, McCartney sings a
    brief phrase ("Na-na-na na . . .") and plays a piano fill which
    leads to the next verse; the phrase McCartney sings serves to
    "reorient the harmony for the verse as the piano figure turns
    upside down into a vocal aside." Additional details, such as
    tambourine on the third verse and subtle harmonies that
    accompany the lead vocal, are added to sustain the interest of
    the listener throughout the four-verse, two-bridge song.</p>
      <p>The verse-bridge structure of the song persists for
    approximately three minutes, after which the band leads into a
    four-minute long coda. During the coda, the rest of band,
    backed by an orchestra that also provides backing vocals,
    repeat the phrase "Na-na-na na" followed by the words "Hey
    Jude" until the song gradually fades out. 
    <i>Time</i>magazine described the coda as "a fadeout that
    engagingly spoofs the fadeout as a gimmick for ending pop
    records." Riley notes the repeated chord progression of the
    coda (I-flat VII-IV-I) "answers all the musical questions
    raised at the beginnings and ends of bridges," for "The flat
    seventh that pose dominant turns into bridges now has an entire
    chord built on it." This three-chord refrain allows McCartney
    "a bedding [. . .] to leap about on vocally", as he ad-libs his
    vocal performance for the rest of the song. Riley concludes
    that the song "becomes a tour of Paul's vocal range: from the
    graceful inviting tones of the opening verse, through the
    mounting excitement of the song itself, to the surging raves of
    the coda."</p>
      <p>The Beatles recorded 25 takes of "Hey Jude" at Abbey Road
    Studios in two nights, 29 July and 30 July 1968. These were
    mostly rehearsals, however, as they planned to record the
    master track at Trident Studios to utilise their eight-track
    recording machine (Abbey Road was still limited to
    four-tracks). One take from 29 July is available on the 
    <i>Anthology 3</i>CD. The master rhythm track was recorded on
    31 July at Trident. Four takes were recorded; take one was
    selected. The song was completed on 1 August with additional
    overdubs including a 36-piece orchestra for the song's long
    coda, scored by George Martin. The orchestra consisted of ten
    violins, three violas, three cellos, two flutes, one contra
    bassoon, one bassoon, two clarinets, one contra bass clarinet,
    four trumpets, four trombones, two horns, percussion, and two
    string basses. While adding backing vocals, The Beatles asked
    the orchestra members if they would clap their hands and sing
    along to the refrain in the song's coda. Most complied (for a
    double fee), but one declined, saying "I'm not going to clap my
    hands and sing Paul McCartney's bloody song!"</p>
      <p>Ringo Starr almost missed his drum cue. He left for a toilet
    break—unnoticed by the other Beatles—and the Beatles started
    recording. In 1994, McCartney said, "Ringo walked out to go to
    the toilet and I hadn't noticed. The toilet was only a few
    yards from his drum booth, but he'd gone past my back and I
    still thought he was in his drum booth. I started what was the
    actual take, and 'Hey Jude' goes on for hours before the drums
    come in and while I was doing it I suddenly felt Ringo
    tiptoeing past my back rather quickly, trying to get to his
    drums. And just as he got to his drums, boom boom boom, his
    timing was absolutely impeccable."</p>
      <p>At 2:58 of the song, McCartney can be heard to say, "Oh,
    fucking hell!" Before this, at 2:56, you can hear McCartney say
    "hit the wrong chord!" According to sound engineers Ken Scott
    and Geoff Emerick, it was Lennon's idea to leave the mistake in
    the final mix. "'Paul hit a clunker on the piano and said a
    naughty word,' Lennon gleefully crowed, 'but I insisted we
    leave it in, buried just low enough so that it can barely be
    heard. Most people won't ever spot it…but we'll know it's
    there.'"</p>
      <p>George Harrison and McCartney had a disagreement over this
    song. According to McCartney, during a rehearsal Harrison
    played an answer to every line of the vocal. This did not fit
    with McCartney's idea of the song's arrangement, and he vetoed
    it. In a 1994 interview, McCartney said, "We were joking when
    we made the 
    <i>Anthology</i>: I was saying: 'I realise I was a bossy git.'
    And George said, 'Oh no, Paul, you never did anything like
    that!' ... But it was essential for me and looking back on it,
    I think, Okay. Well, it was bossy, but it was ballsy of me,
    because I could have bowed to the pressure." Ron Richards, who
    worked for George Martin at both Parlophone at AIR Studios, and
    who discovered The Hollies, was present for many Beatle
    recording sessions. He said McCartney was "oblivious to anyone
    else's feelings in the studio," and that he was driven to make
    the best possible record, at almost any cost.</p>
      <p>"Hey Jude" was released on 26 August 1968 in the United
    States and 30 August in the United Kingdom, backed with
    "Revolution" on the B-side of a 7" single. The single was the
    debut release of the Beatles' record label Apple Records; in
    the US, it was also the first Beatles single to be issued in a
    paper sleeve instead of a picture cover. Even though "Hey Jude"
    was recorded during the sessions for the album 
    <i>The Beatles</i>, also known as The White Album, it was
    always intended as a single and not an album track. Lennon
    wanted "Revolution" to be the A-side of the single, but the
    other Beatles did not agree. In his 1970 interview with 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>, he said "Hey Jude" was worthy of an
    A-side, "but we could have had both." Ten years later in 1980,
    he told 
    <i>Playboy</i>he still disagreed with the decision.</p>
      <p>"Hey Jude" began its sixteen-week run on the British charts
    on 7 September 1968, claiming the top spot a week later. It
    only lasted two weeks on top before being knocked off by
    another single from Apple, Mary Hopkin's "Those Were the Days".
    The single was certified gold by the Recording Industry
    Association of America on 13 September; that same week 
    <i>NME</i>reported that two million copies of the single had
    been sold. The song entered the U.S. charts on 14 September
    1968, where it stayed for the next nineteen weeks. Two weeks
    later, "Hey Jude" was number one in the charts, and held that
    position for the following eight weeks, totalling nine weeks.
    setting the U.S. record for the longest time spent by a Beatles
    single at number one, as well as being the longest-playing
    single to reach number one.</p>
      <p>American radio stations were averse to playing anything
    longer than the usual three to three-and-a-half minutes, and
    Capitol Records pressed a shortened version of the song
    specifically for airplay. "Hey Jude" clocked in at seven
    minutes and eleven seconds. The only other chart-topping song
    worldwide in the 1960s that ran over seven minutes was Richard
    Harris' "MacArthur Park". In the UK, where "MacArthur Park" did
    not top the chart, "Hey Jude" remained the longest number-one
    hit for nearly a quarter of a century, until it was surpassed
    in 1993 by Meat Loaf's "I'd Do Anything for Love (But I Won't
    Do That)", which ran seven minutes fifty-eight seconds as a
    single.</p>
      <p>On 30 November 1968 
    <i>NME</i>reported that sales had reached nearly six million
    copies worldwide. "Hey Jude" became the biggest-selling debut
    release for a record label ever, selling an estimated eight
    million copies worldwide and topping the charts in eleven
    countries. It remains the Beatles' most commercially successful
    single. "Hey Jude" was the top Billboard Hot 100 single for
    1968, according to year-end charts. While the record was
    certified gold the day before it entered the U.S. charts, it
    took almost thirty years to be certified platinum, on 17
    February 1999. The single has since been certified four times
    platinum (four million copies shipped) in the United
    States.</p>
      <p>Upon the release of the "Hey Jude" single, 
    <i>Time</i>contrasted it with its B-side "Revolution". 
    <i>Time</i>wrote, "The other side of the new disk urges
    activism of a different sort" as McCartney "liltingly exhorts a
    friend to overcome his fears and commit himself in love." Music
    analyst Alan Pollack praised "Hey Jude" saying, "it's such a
    good illustration of two compositional lessons—how to fill a
    large canvas with simple means, and how to use diverse elements
    such as harmony, bassline, and orchestration to articulate form
    and contrast." He also said it is unusual for a long song
    because it uses a "binary form that combines a fully developed,
    hymn-like song together with an extended, mantra-like jam on a
    simple chord progression." Pollack described the song's long
    coda and fadeout as "an astonishingly transcendental effect,"
    while Unterberger observed, "What could have very easily been
    boring is instead hypnotic".</p>
      <p>"Hey Jude" was nominated for the Grammy Awards of 1969 in
    the Record of the Year, Song of the Year and Best Pop
    Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal categories, but failed
    to win any of them. It did win the 1968 Ivor Novello Award for
    "A-Side With the Highest Sales". In the 
    <i>NME</i>1968 Readers' Poll, "Hey Jude" was named the best
    single of the year. In 2001, "Hey Jude" was inducted into the
    National Academy of Recording Arts and Sciences Grammy Hall of
    Fame. In 2004, it was ranked number 8 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's list of the 500 greatest songs
    of all time. It came in third on Channel 4's list of 100
    Greatest Singles. The Amusement &amp; Music Operators
    Association ranked "Hey Jude" the 11th-best jukebox single of
    all time.</p>
      <p>The Beatles hired Michael Lindsay-Hogg to shoot the "Hey
    Jude" promotional film (he had previously directed a 'promo'
    film for "Paperback Writer") and they settled on the idea of
    filming with a live, albeit controlled audience. Hogg shot the
    film at Twickenham Film Studios on 4 September 1968, with
    McCartney himself designing the set. Tony Bramwell, a friend of
    the Beatles, later described the set as "the piano, there;
    drums, there; and orchestra in two tiers at the back." The
    event is also memorable as it marked Starr's return to the
    group after a two-week hiatus, during which he had announced
    that he had left the band. The eventual, final film was a
    combination of several different takes and included filmed
    'introductions' to the song by David Frost (who introduced the
    Beatles as "the greatest tea-room orchestra in the world") and
    Sir Cliff Richard, for their respective, eponymous TV
    programmes. As filming wore on, Lennon repeatedly asked
    Lindsay-Hogg if he had the footage he needed. After twelve
    takes, McCartney said, "I think that's enough" and filming
    concluded. It was first aired in the UK on 8 September 1968 and
    the film was later broadcast for the United States on 
    <i>The Smothers Brothers Comedy Hour</i>on 6 October 1968.
    Footage of the performance can be seen in the 
    <i>Anthology</i>DVD series.</p>
      <p>In 1996, Julian Lennon paid £25,000 for the recording notes
    to "Hey Jude" at an auction. Lennon spent another £35,000 at
    the auction buying John Lennon memorabilia. John Cousins,
    Julian Lennon's manager, stated, "He has a few photographs of
    his father, but not very much else. He is collecting for
    personal reasons, these are family heirlooms if you like."</p>
      <p>In 2002, the original handwritten lyrics for the song were
    nearly auctioned off at Christie's in London. The sheet of
    notepaper with the scrawled lyrics had been expected to fetch
    up to £80,000 at the auction, which was scheduled for 30 April
    2002. McCartney went to court to stop the auction, claiming the
    paper had disappeared from his West London home. Richard
    Morgan, representing Christie's, said McCartney had provided no
    evidence that he had ever owned the piece of paper on which the
    lyrics were written. The courts decided in McCartney's favour
    and prohibited the sale of the lyrics. They had been sent to
    Christie's for auction by Frenchman Florrent Tessier, who said
    he purchased the piece of paper at a street market stall in
    London for £10 in the early 1970s. In the original catalogue
    for the auction, Julian Lennon had written, "It's very strange
    to think that someone has written a song about you. It still
    touches me."</p>
      <p>
         <span id="interwiki-es-fa"/>
         <span id="interwiki-fr-fa"/>
         <span id="interwiki-pl-fa"/>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
