<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_House_of_the_Rising_Sun 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_House_of_the_Rising_Sun</songId>
   <title>The House of the Rising Sun</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Animals</artistId>
      <artistName>The Animals</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1964-09-05</week>
      <week>1964-09-12</week>
      <week>1964-09-19</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>June 1964 (UK) , August 1964 (U.S.)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>18 May 1964</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Folk Rock</genre>
      <genre>Blues Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:29 (full - UK)</length>
      <length>2:58 (edited - U.S. original)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia Graphophone DB7301 (UK) , MGM Records 13264 (U.S.)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Trad.</writer>
      <writer>arranged Alan Price</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mickie Most</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The House of the Rising Sun" is a folk song from the United
    States. Also called "House of the Rising Sun" or occasionally
    "Rising Sun Blues", it tells of a life gone wrong in New
    Orleans. The most successful version was recorded by the
    English rock group The Animals in 1964, which was a number one
    hit in the United Kingdom, United States, Sweden and
    Canada.</p>
      <p>Like many classic folk ballads, the authorship of "The House
    of the Rising Sun" is uncertain. Some musicologists say that it
    is based on the tradition of broadside ballads such as the 
    <i>Unfortunate Rake</i>of the 18th century which were taken to
    America by early settlers. Many of these had the theme of "if
    only" and after a period of evolution, they emerge as American
    songs like "Streets of Laredo". The tradition of the blues
    combined with these in which the telling of a sad story has a
    therapeutic effect.</p>
      <p>Alan Price of the Animals has claimed that the song was
    originally a sixteenth-century English folk song about a Soho
    brothel, and that English emigrants took the song to America
    where it was adapted to its later New Orleans setting.</p>
      <p>The oldest known existing recording is by versatile
    Appalachian artists Clarence "Tom" Ashley and Gwen Foster and
    was made in 1933. Ashley said he had learned it from his
    grandfather, Enoch Ashley. Alger "Texas" Alexander's 
    <i>The Risin' Sun</i>, which was recorded in 1928, is sometimes
    mentioned as the first recording, but this is a completely
    different song.</p>
      <p>The song might have been lost to obscurity had it not been
    collected by folklorist Alan Lomax. Lomax and his father were
    curators of the Archive of American Folk Song for the Library
    of Congress from 1932. They searched the country for songs. On
    an expedition with his wife to eastern Kentucky Lomax set up
    his recording equipment in Middlesborough, Kentucky in the
    house of a singer and activist called Tilman Cadle. On 15 Sept
    1937 he recorded a performance by Georgia Turner, the 16
    year-old daughter of a local miner. He called it 
    <i>The Risin' Sun Blues</i>. Lomax later recorded a different
    version sung by Bert Martin and a third sung by Daw Henson,
    both eastern Kentucky singers. Lomax, in his seminal 1941
    songbook 
    <i>Our Singing Country</i>, credited the lyrics to Turner, with
    reference to Martin's version. According to his later writing,
    the melody bears similarities to a traditional English ballad, 
    <i>Matty Groves</i>.</p>
      <p>Roy Acuff, who recorded the song commercially on November 3,
    1938, may have learned the song from Clarence Ashley with whom
    he sometimes performed. In 1941, Woody Guthrie recorded a
    version. A recording made in 1947 by Josh White, who is also
    credited with having re-written new words and music that have
    subsequently been popularised in the versions made by many
    other later artists, was released Mercury Records in 1950. In
    late 1948 Lead Belly recorded a version called "In New Orleans"
    in the sessions that later became the album 
    <i>Lead Belly's Last Sessions</i>(1994, Smithsonian Folkways).
    In 1957 Glenn Yarbrough recorded the song for Elektra Records.
    The song is also credited to Ronnie Gilbert on one of the old
    Weavers albums with Pete Seeger that was released in the late
    '40s or early '50s. Frankie Laine recorded the song then titled
    "New Orleans" on his 1959 "Balladeer" album. Joan Baez recorded
    it in 1960 on her eponymous debut album. In 1960 Miriam Makeba
    recorded the song on her eponymous RCA album LSP2267.</p>
      <p>In late 1961, Bob Dylan recorded the song for his
    self-titled, first album, 
    <i>Bob Dylan</i>, released in March 1962. Dylan claims a
    writer's credit for the song. In an interview on the
    documentary 
    <i>No Direction Home</i>, Dave Van Ronk said that he was
    intending to record it at that time, and that Bob Dylan copied
    his version of the song. He recorded it himself soon thereafter
    on 
    <i>Just Dave Van Ronk</i>.</p>
      <p>Nina Simone recorded her first version of the Rising Sun on
    Nina at the Village Gate in 1962, the song was recorded
    earlier. In 1965 in Latin America the Colombian group Los
    Speakers recorded a version in Spanish called "La casa del sol
    naciente", which was also the title of their second album. They
    earned a silver record (for sales of over 15,000 copies), an
    astronomical number for that time period.</p>
      <p>During the Get Back Sessions, The Beatles recorded a
    version, but it has not been issued on any official release by
    the group.</p>
      <p>An interview with Eric Burdon of The Animals revealed that
    he first heard the song in a club in Newcastle, where it was
    sung by a Northumbrian folk singer called Johnny Handle. The
    Animals were on tour with Chuck Berry and chose it because they
    wanted something distinctive to sing. This interview refutes
    assertions that the inspiration for The Animals' arrangement
    came directly from Dylan's recording. Regardless, the Animals
    enjoyed a huge hit with the song, much to Dylan's chagrin when
    his version was referred to as a cover of The Animals'
    version—the irony of which was not lost on Van Ronk. Dave Van
    Ronk went on record as saying that the whole issue was a
    "tempest in a teapot", and that Dylan stopped playing the song
    after The Animals' hit because fans accused Dylan of
    plagiarizing the Animals' version. Dylan has said he first
    heard The Animals' version on his car radio and "jumped out of
    his car seat" because he liked it so much. The Chambers
    Brothers recorded a version on "Feelin' The Blues", released on
    VAULT records.</p>
      <p>Dave Marsh described The Animals' take on "The House of the
    Rising Sun" as "the first folk-rock hit," sounding "as if
    they'd connected the ancient tune to a live wire," while writer
    Ralph McLean of the BBC agreed that "it was arguably the first
    folk rock tune," calling it "a revolutionary single" after
    which "the face of modern music was changed forever." Dave Van
    Ronk claims that this version was based on his arrangement of
    the song.</p>
      <p>The Animals' version transposes the narrative of the song
    from the point of view of a woman led into a life of
    degradation, to that of a male, whose 
    <i>father</i>was now a gambler and drunkard, as opposed to the 
    <i>sweetheart</i>in earlier versions.</p>
      <p>The Animals had begun featuring their arrangement of "House
    of the Rising Sun" during a joint concert tour with Chuck
    Berry, using it as their closing number to differentiate
    themselves from acts which always closed with straight rockers.
    It got a tremendous reaction from the audience, convincing
    initially reluctant producer Mickie Most that it had hit
    potential, and between tour stops the group went to a small
    recording studio on Kingsway in London to capture it.</p>
      <p>Recorded in just one take on 18 May 1964, it started with a
    famous electric guitar A minor chord arpeggio by Hilton
    Valentine. The performance took off with Eric Burdon's lead
    vocal, which has been variously described as "howling",
    "soulful", and "deep and gravelly as the north-east English
    coal town of Newcastle that spawned him." Finally, Alan Price's
    pulsating organ part (played on a Vox Continental) completed
    the sound. Burdon later said, "We were looking for a song that
    would grab people's attention," and they succeeded: "House of
    the Rising Sun" was a true trans-Atlantic hit, topping both the
    UK pop singles chart (in July 1964) and the U.S. pop singles
    chart (two months later in September 1964, when it became the
    first British Invasion number one unconnected with The
    Beatles); it was the group's breakthrough hit in both countries
    and became their signature song. The song was also a hit in a
    number of other countries.</p>
      <p>The Animals' rendition of the song is recognized as one of
    the classics of the British Invasion. Writer Lester Bangs
    labeled it "a brilliant rearrangement" and "a new standard
    rendition of an old standard composition." It ranked number 122
    on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's 500 Greatest Songs of All Time
    list. It is also one of The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame's 500
    Songs that Shaped Rock and Roll. The RIAA placed it as number
    240 on their Songs of the Century list. In 1999 it received a
    Grammy Hall of Fame Award. And besides critical acclaim, it has
    long since become a staple of oldies and classic rock radio
    formats. A 2005 Five poll ranked it as Britons' fourth
    favourite number one song of all time.</p>
      <p>As recorded, "House of the Rising Sun" ran four and a half
    minutes, regarded as far too long for a pop single at the time.
    Producer Most, who otherwise minimized his role on this
    occasion — "Everything was in the right place ... It only took
    15 minutes to make so I can't take much credit for the
    production" — nonetheless was now a believer and declared it as
    a single at its full length, saying "We're in a microgroove
    world now, we will release it."</p>
      <p>In the United States, though, the original single (MGM
    13264) 
    <i>was</i>a 2:58 version that sounded as if it had been hastily
    edited. The MGM Golden Circle reissue (KGC 179) featured the
    unedited 4:29 version, although the label shows the edited
    playing time of 2:58. The edited version was included on the
    group's 1964 U.S. debut album 
    <i>The Animals</i>, while the full version was later included
    on their best-selling 1966 U.S. greatest hits album 
    <i>The Best of The Animals</i>. However, the very first
    American release of the full-length version was on a 1965 album
    of various groups entitled 'Mickie Most Presents British Go-Go'
    (MGM SE-4306), the cover of which, under the listing of "House
    Of The Rising Sun," boasted "Original Uncut Version." Americans
    also had a chance to hear the complete version in the movie 'Go
    Go Mania' (aka 'Pop Gear') in the spring of 1965.</p>
      <p>"House of the Rising Sun" was not included on any of the
    group's British albums. Rather, it was reissued as a single
    twice in subsequent decades, charting both times: to number 25
    in 1972, and to number 11 in 1982.</p>
      <p>The arranging credit went only to Alan Price. According to
    Burdon, this was simply because there was insufficient room to
    name all five band members on the record label, and Alan
    Price's name was first alphabetically. However, this meant that
    only Price received songwriter's royalties for the hit, a fact
    that has caused bitterness ever since, especially with
    Valentine.</p>
      <p>The only rendition other than The Animals' to become a hit
    came in early 1970, when Detroit-based Frijid Pink released
    their take on the song. Sometimes described as done in
    psychedelic music style, Pink's rendition is actually more
    aligned with the proto-metal/proto-punk sound of fellow
    contemporaneous Detroit acts MC5 and The Stooges. The Frijid
    Pink version of the song is in 4/4 time signature (like Dave
    Van Ronk's version, and most earlier versions, rather than the
    6/8 used by The Animals. The performance was driven by Gary Ray
    Thompson's distorted guitar with fuzz and wah wah effects, set
    against frenetic drumming from Richard Stevers. Lead singer Tom
    Beaudry's (aka:Kelly Green) vocal phrasing almost exactly
    matched Eric Burdon's.</p>
      <p>Regardless of its merits, the recording was indeed again a
    trans-Atlantic success, reaching number 7 on the U.S. Billboard
    Hot 100 pop singles chart, number 4 on the UK Singles Chart,
    and number 3 in Canada. It was awarded gold record status in
    the U.S. in May 1970 for selling a million copies. It also hit
    number one in a number of European countries, including West
    Germany and Norway. It would be Frijid Pink's only top ten
    hit.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by many other well-known artists,
    including Muse, Tommy Emmanuel, The Beatles, The White Stripes,
    The Eagles, Bob Dylan, Gregory Isaacs and Nina Simone. Siobhan
    Magnus performed it during the top 16 semifinals of season nine
    of American Idol on Tuesday, March 9, 2010.</p>
      <p>Various places in New Orleans, Louisiana have been proposed
    as the inspiration for the song, with varying plausibility. The
    phrase "House of the Rising Sun" is often understood as a
    euphemism for a brothel, but it is not known whether or not the
    house described in the lyrics was an actual or fictitious
    place. One theory speculated the song is about a daughter who
    killed her father, an alcoholic gambler who had beaten his
    wife. Therefore, the House of the Rising Sun may be a
    jail-house, from which one would be the first person to see the
    sun rise (an idea supported by the lyric mentioning "a ball and
    chain," though that phrase has been used as slang to describe
    marital relationships for at least as long as the song has been
    in print). Because the song was often sung by women, another
    theory is that the House of the Rising Sun was where
    prostitutes were detained while they were treated for syphilis.
    Since cures with mercury were ineffective, going back was very
    likely</p>
      <p>Only two candidates have historical documentation as using
    the name "Rising Sun", both having listings in old period city
    directories. The first was a small short-lived hotel on Conti
    Street in the French Quarter in the 1820s. It burned down in
    1822. An excavation and document search in early 2005 found
    evidence supporting this claim, including an advertisement with
    language that may have euphemistically indicated prostitution.
    An unusually large number of pots of rouge and cosmetics were
    found by archaeologists at the site.</p>
      <p>The second possibility was a late 19th century "Rising Sun
    Hall" on the riverfront of the uptown Carrollton neighborhood,
    which seems to have been a building owned and used for meetings
    of a Social Aid &amp; Pleasure Club, commonly rented out for
    dances and functions. It also is no longer extant. Definite
    links to gambling or prostitution (if any) are undocumented for
    either of these buildings.</p>
      <p>Another claim is that The House of the Rising Sun actually
    existed between 1862 and about 1874 and was run by a Madam
    Marianne LeSoleil Levant whose name translates from French as
    "the rising sun". 
    <i>Bizarre New Orleans</i>, a guide book on New Orleans,
    asserts that the real house was at 1614 Esplanade Avenue
    between 1862 and 1874 and was purportedly named for its madam,
    Marianne LeSoleil Levant.</p>
      <p>It is also possible that the "House of the Rising Sun" is a
    metaphor for either the slave pens of the plantation, the
    plantation house, or the plantation itself, which were the
    subjects and themes of many traditional blues songs. Dave van
    Ronk claimed in his autobiography that he had seen pictures of
    the old Orleans Parish Women's Prison, the entrance to which
    was decorated with a rising sun design. He considered this
    proof that the House of the Rising Sun had been a nickname for
    the prison.</p>
      <p>The gender of the singer is flexible. Earlier versions of
    the song are often sung from the female perspective, a woman
    who followed a drunk or a gambler to New Orleans and became a
    prostitute in the House of the Rising Sun (or, depending on
    one's interpretation, an inmate in a prison of the same name),
    such as in Joan Baez's version on her self-titled 1960 debut
    album. The Animals version was sung from a perspective of a
    male, warning about gambling and drinking. Bob Dylan's 1962
    version and Shawn Mullins' recent covered version on his album
    "9th Ward Pickin' Parlor" is sung from the female
    perspective.</p>
      <p>Not everyone, however, believes that the house even existed
    at all. On the BBC's h2g2 database, Pamela D. Arceneaux, a
    research librarian working at the Williams Research Center in
    New Orleans, is quoted as saying:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
