<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/He%27s_a_Rebel 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/He%27s_a_Rebel</songId>
   <title>He's a Rebel</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Crystals</artistId>
      <artistName>The Crystals</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1962-11-03</week>
      <week>1962-11-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>August 1962</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:13</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Philles , 106</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Gene Pitney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Phil Spector</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"He's a Rebel" is a pop song credited to the The Crystals,
    but actually recorded by The Blossoms which went to #1 on the
    Billboard Hot 100 charts in November 1962. Written by Gene
    Pitney and produced by Phil Spector, it is considered one of
    the definitive examples of the Spector-produced girl group
    sound.</p>
      <p>In 2004, the song was ranked #263 on Rolling Stone's 500
    Greatest Songs of All Time.</p>
      <p>The song is about a girl in love with a young man who spurns
    society's conventions. Despite his being misunderstood by
    others, the singer claims that he is sweet and faithful, and
    she vows to be the same towards him. Studio musician Steve
    Douglas performs a saxophone solo during the song's bridge. The
    piano riff at the beginning was contributed by Al DeLory.
    Unusually for Spector productions, no strings played on the
    track.</p>
      <p>Pitney had originally written "He's a Rebel" for The
    Shirelles, but they declined. Spector learned that Vikki Carr
    was soon to record the song for Liberty Records as her debut
    single, and decided he had to rush his own version to stores.
    The Crystals were touring on the east coast at the time, and so
    Spector instead had Darlene Love sing lead on the track, backed
    by The Blossoms, a Los Angeles-based group. Spector gave The
    Crystals credit on the record; Mary Thomas later recalled that
    "our mouths fell open" when she and her groupmates heard a
    radio disc jockey announce "the new Crystals song." The quintet
    was then obliged to add "He's a Rebel" to their live
    repertoire, even though lead singer Barbara Alston's soft voice
    could not mimic Love's hearty delivery. For this reason,
    fifteen-year-old Dolores "LaLa" Brooks was promoted to the role
    of lead singer the following year starting with their follow-up
    single "Then He Kissed Me".</p>
      <p>The single, with the artist listed simply as "The Crystals,"
    was released in late August 1962, with the b-side "I Love You
    Eddie." By November 3, "He's a Rebel" had reached #1 on the
    Billboard Hot 100 chart. The number two song that week was Gene
    Pitney's "Only Love Can Break a Heart", giving him (as a
    songwriter and/or performer) the two top-selling singles in the
    U.S. Pitney would never hit #1 as a performer. In the United
    Kingdom, "He's a Rebel" peaked at #19.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
