<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/We_Can_Work_It_Out 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/We_Can_Work_It_Out</songId>
   <title>We Can Work It Out</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1966-01-08</week>
      <week>1966-01-15</week>
      <week>1966-01-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>3 December 1965 ( UK ) , 6 December 1965 ( US )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>20 October 1965 , Abbey Road</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:15</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Parlophone (UK) , Capitol (US)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"We Can Work It Out" is a song written by John Lennon and
    Paul McCartney and released by The Beatles as a "double
    A-sided" single with "Day Tripper", the first time both sides
    of a single were so designated in an initial release. Both
    songs were recorded during the 
    <i>Rubber Soul</i>sessions. The song is an example of
    Lennon/McCartney collaboration at a depth that happened only
    rarely after they wrote the hit singles of 1963. This song, "A
    Day in the Life", and "I've Got A Feeling" are among the
    notable exceptions.</p>
      <p>McCartney wrote the words and music to the verses and the
    chorus, with lyrics that "might have been personal" and thus a
    reference to his relationship with Jane Asher. McCartney then
    took the song to Lennon: "I took it to John to finish it off
    and we wrote the middle together." According to Lennon, he "did
    the middle eight."</p>
      <p>With its intimations of mortality, Lennon's contribution to
    the twelve-bar bridge contrasts typically with what Lennon saw
    as McCartney's cajoling optimism. As Lennon told 
    <i>Playboy</i>in 1980, "You've got Paul writing, 'We can work
    it out / We can work it out'—real optimistic, y'know, and me,
    impatient: 'Life is very short, and there's no time / For
    fussing and fighting, my friend.'" Based on those comments,
    some critics overemphasized McCartney's optimism, neglecting
    the toughness in passages written by McCartney, such as "Do I
    have to keep on talking until I can't go on?". Lennon's middle
    shifts focus from McCartney's concrete reality to a
    philosophical perspective in B minor, illustrating this with a
    waltz-time section suggested by George Harrison that leads back
    to the verse, possibly meant to suggest tiresome struggle.
    Music critic Ian MacDonald said, "[Lennon's] passages are so
    suited to his Salvation Army harmonium that it's hard to
    imagine them not being composed on it. The swell-pedal
    crescendos he adds to the verses are, on the other hand,
    textural washes added in the studio, the first of their kind on
    a Beatles record and signposts to the enriched sound-palette of
    
    <i>Revolver</i>." Oasis guitarist Noel Gallagher described the
    song as "the song that defines The Beatles".</p>
      <p>The Beatles recorded "We Can Work It Out" on 20 October
    1965, four days after its accompanying single track, with an
    overdub session on 29 October. They spent nearly 11 hours on
    the song, by far the longest expenditure of studio time up to
    that point.</p>
      <p>In a discussion about what song to release as a single,
    Lennon argued "vociferously" for "Day Tripper", differing with
    the majority view that "We Can Work It Out" was a more
    commercial song. As a result, the single was marketed as the
    first "double A-side," but airplay and point-of-sale requests
    soon proved "We Can Work It Out" to be more popular, and it
    reached No. 1 on both sides of the Atlantic, The Beatles'
    fastest-selling single since "Can't Buy Me Love," their
    previous McCartney-led A-side in the UK.</p>
      <p>"We Can Work It Out" was the last of six number one singles
    in a row on the American charts, a record at the time. It was
    preceded by "I Feel Fine", "Eight Days a Week", "Ticket to
    Ride", "Help!", and "Yesterday". The record was equaled by The
    Bee Gees in the 1970s and surpassed by Whitney Houston in the
    1980s.</p>
      <p>The Beatles made 10 black-and-white promo films for
    television broadcasters on 23 November 1965, at Twickenham Film
    Studios in London, as they were often unable to make personal
    appearances by that time. Three of the films were mimed
    performances of "We Can Work It Out", in all of which Lennon
    was seated at a harmonium. The most frequently-broadcast of the
    three versions was a straightforward performance piece with the
    group wearing black suits. Another had the group wearing the
    stage suits from their Shea Stadium performance on 15 August;
    the third opens with a shot of Lennon with a sunflower in front
    of his eye.</p>
      <p>In 1991, McCartney played an acoustic version of the song
    for his MTV Unplugged performance, memorable for his flubbing
    the first verse and his good-natured reaction, later released
    on 
    <i>Unplugged (The Official Bootleg)</i>.</p>
      <p>MacDonald was not sure whether or not Harrison sang a
    harmony vocal part. MacDonald praised the tambourine playing
    and noted that some sources attribute it to Harrison, not
    Starr.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
