<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leader_of_the_Pack 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leader_of_the_Pack</songId>
   <title>Leader of the Pack</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Shangri-Las</artistId>
      <artistName>The Shangri-Las</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1964-11-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1964</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
      <genre>Teenage Tragedy</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:49</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Red Bird</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>George "Shadow" Morton</writer>
      <writer>Jeff Barry</writer>
      <writer>Ellie Greenwich</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George "Shadow" Morton</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Leader of the Pack" is a 1964 pop song recorded by girl
    group The Shangri-Las. It became number one on the Billboard
    Hot 100 on November 28, 1964.</p>
      <p>The tune was credited to producer George "Shadow" Morton
    with Jeff Barry and Ellie Greenwich. According to Morton, he
    wrote the song for the Goodies (also known as the Bunnies), but
    instead it was needed as a follow-up to the Shangri-Las hit
    "Remember (Walking in the Sand)". Morton claimed he credited
    Barry and Greenwich as co-writers for business reasons; his
    recollection has been questioned by Ellie Greenwich.</p>
      <p>In July 1964, Morton recorded the vocals for the song with
    the Shangri-Las at the Ultrasonic Sound studio on the second
    floor of a Manhattan hotel. These vocals were dubbed over the
    instrumental parts which had been previously recorded at the
    Ultrasonic Recording Studios in Hempstead, New York. Billy
    Joel, then a young session musician, claimed he played piano on
    "Leader of the Pack", but this has been denied by Greenwich. In
    fact, the piano part was played by Roger Rossi, a staff
    musician for Ultrasonic Recording Studios at the time. Rossi
    said, "I remember the date like it was yesterday, there were no
    written charts, so unfortunately, some musicians kept making
    mistakes. As I recall, it took 63 recording takes before Shadow
    Morton was satisfied." Rossi added, "By the end of the session,
    in take 62, I also messed up and Morton laughingly yelled out,
    Ohhhh, noooo. Not you, too!!"</p>
      <p>According to legend, to add the authentic sound of a
    motorcycle engine, one was driven through the lobby of the
    hotel and up to the floor of the recording studio. No one was
    arrested, but a ticket was issued. However, in an interview
    four decades later, Shangri-Las lead singer Mary Weiss said the
    motorcycle sound was taken from an effects record. The Zombies'
    drummer Hugh Grundy recalls revving up a motorcycle backstage
    when the Shangri-Las performed on a U.S. tour.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom, the song was refused airplay by the
    BBC, probably due to its death theme, although some have
    speculated that it was considered likely to encourage violence
    between mods and rockers. It still charted four times in the UK
    between 1965 and 1976, peaking at number 3 in 1972 (by which
    time the BBC ban had been lifted). The record also reached
    number 1 in Australia. In 1990, it featured in the soundtrack
    of the Martin Scorsese film 
    <i>Goodfellas</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2004, 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>ranked the song among the 500 Greatest
    Songs of All Time, at #447.</p>
      <p>The song is about a girl named Betty, asked by friends to
    confirm that she is dating Jimmy, the leader of a motorcycle
    gang. After singing of love at first sight ("
    <i>I met him at the candy store/He turned around and smiled at
    me/You get the picture?/That's when I fell for the Leader of
    the Pack</i>"), Betty's heart turns to despair as she bemoans
    her parents' disapproval. The parents claim Jimmy hails from
    "the wrong side of town" and will be a bad influence on her.
    They ask Betty to tell Jimmy goodbye and find someone new.</p>
      <p>Betty does as she is asked, and an upset Jimmy — after
    putting up his bravado — speeds off on his motorcycle. Moments
    later, Jimmy crashes on a rain-slickened surface and dies;
    Betty's pleas for Jimmy to slow down were in vain. In the end,
    Betty is left to deal with heartbreak but vows never to forget
    her fling with Jimmy, the "Leader of the Pack."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
