<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/He%27s_So_Fine 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/He%27s_So_Fine</songId>
   <title>He's So Fine</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Chiffons</artistId>
      <artistName>The Chiffons</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1963-03-30</week>
      <week>1963-04-06</week>
      <week>1963-04-13</week>
      <week>1963-04-20</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>He's So Fine</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 1962</released>
   <formats>
      <format>45 rpm record</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>December 1962</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Doo Wop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>1:53</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Laurie Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ronald Mack</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Phil Margo</producer>
      <producer>Mitch Margo</producer>
      <producer>Jay Siegal</producer>
      <producer>and Hank Medress</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"He's So Fine" is a recording by the Chiffons which topped
    the Billboard Hot 100 for four weeks in the spring of 1963. One
    of the most instantly recognizable Golden Oldies with its 
    <i>doo-lang doo-lang doo-lang</i>background vocal, "He's So
    Fine" is also renowned as the plaintiff song in a famous
    plagiarism case against George Harrison's "My Sweet Lord".</p>
      <p>"He's So Fine" was written by Ronald Mack, an acquaintance
    of the Chiffons' members who set himself up as their manager
    after overhearing them sing in their high school's lunch room.
    Mack elicited the interest of Bright Tunes Corporation, a
    production company run by the Tokens who produced the Chiffons
    singing "He's So Fine" and two other Mack compositions at
    Capitol Recording Studios; the Tokens themselves - who'd never
    previously played on a recording session - provided the
    instrumentation. Originally, "Oh My Lover", one of the two
    other songs, was considered the potential hit but the completed
    track for "He's So Fine" with its now classic 
    <i>Doo-lang doo-lang doo lang</i>background vocal - the
    suggestion of the session's sound engineer Johnny Cue - seemed
    an obvious smash, although Capitol Records for whom the Tokens
    were house producers rejected the track: Jay Siegal of the
    Tokens would recall Capitol president Boyle Gilmore dismissing
    the track as "too trite...too simple". The Tokens shopped "He's
    So Fine" to ten labels before placing it with Laurie Records.
    Siegal - "We played it and they locked the doors and said,
    'You're not getting out of here. We want that record.'...Of
    course, we'd already been turned down by ten companies - give
    us eighty cents and we'd have given you the record." [1][2]</p>
      <p>Released in December of 1962, "He's So Fine" entered the
    national charts in February of 1963 attaining the #1 position
    on March 30 and remaining #1 for a four week period and also
    made it to number one one the soul singles chart. "He's So
    Fine" was also a #16 hit in the UK.</p>
      <p>The Chiffons' two later Top 10 hits both contain echoes of
    "He's So Fine", although neither song was written by Ronald
    Mack, who died soon after the Chiffons had recorded his song.
    "One Fine Day" was written by Carole King and Gerry Goffin who
    had had Little Eva record the song before shopping it to the
    Chiffons after the group hit with "He's So Fine", and "Sweet
    Talking Guy" - in which the background vocalists sing: "He's so
    fine" - was co-written by the co-founder of Laurie Records,
    Eliot Greenberg. Also after the Chiffons had had hits with
    "He's So Fine" and "One Fine Day" the Tokens especially wrote
    the song "A Love So Fine" to be their next single: it managed a
    #40 peak.</p>
      <p>Jody Miller had a #5 C&amp;W hit with her 1971 remake of
    "He's So Fine"; this version - which omits the original's 
    <i>doo lang</i>background vocal, and plays on the similarities
    with "My Sweet Lord" by playing the same notes in the guitar
    solos - also crossed over to #53 on the Pop charts and gave
    Miller her career best chart placing with a #2 ranking on the
    Easy Listening charts.</p>
      <p>1978 saw two disparate remakes of "He's So Fine" chart.
    First in May Jane Olivor's remake reached #77: her version of
    "He's So Fine" - in the vein of Cissy Houston's 1971 take on
    the Ronettes' Be My Baby - reinvented the girl-group classic as
    a lush ballad. Two months later an attempted replication of the
    original "He's So Fine" credited to Kristy and Jimmy McNichol
    reached #70. The latter version only featured Kristy, the duo
    credit reflecting the track's parent 
    <i>Kristy and Jimmy McNichol</i>album which was produced by
    Phil and Mitch Margo who - as members of the Tokens - had
    produced the Chiffons' original.</p>
      <p>In 1987 Jonathan King put his 1971 version of "He's So Fine"
    as the B-side of his remake of Cat Stevens' "Wild World". King
    remade "Wild World" to corroborate his contention that the Pet
    Shop Boys has plagiarized it with their hit "It's a Sin": he
    chose "He's So Fine" as the B-side to stress his position due
    to the song's involvement in the plagiarism suit described in
    the following section. His version was played in the court room
    by the Chiffons legal team.</p>
      <p>On February 10, 1971, Bright Tunes Music Corporation filed
    suit alleging that the current George Harrison hit "My Sweet
    Lord" was a plagiarism of "He's So Fine". The case did not go
    to trial until February 1976 when the judge ruled on the
    liability portion of the suit in favor of Bright Tunes,
    determining that Harrison was guilty of "subconscious"
    plagiarism. The suit to determine damages was scheduled for
    November 1976 but delayed until February 1981, by which time
    Allen Klein, Harrison's onetime manager who had been his legal
    adviser in the first phase of the suit, had become the
    plaintiff by virtue of purchasing Bright Tunes. The final
    decision was that Harrison himself would purchase Bright Tunes
    from Klein for $587,000—the amount Klein had paid for the
    corporation—and although litigation continued for at least ten
    more years that decision was upheld.</p>
      <p>In 1975 the Chiffons would record a version of "My Sweet
    Lord", attempting to capitalize on the publicity generated by
    the lawsuit. Harrison's "This Song" was written in reaction to
    the plagiarism suit.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
