<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Long_and_Winding_Road 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Long_and_Winding_Road</songId>
   <title>The Long and Winding Road" / "For You Blue</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1970-06-13</week>
      <week>1970-06-20</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a1/Beatles-singles-the-long-and-winding-road-1.jpg/200px-Beatles-singles-the-long-and-winding-road-1.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Beatles+The-Long-and-Winding-Road-For-You-Blue.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Let It Be</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>11 May 1970 (USA)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>vinyl record (7")</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>26 January 1969</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:37</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Apple Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
      <producer>Reproduced for disc by Phil Spector</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"The Long and Winding Road" is a ballad written by Paul
    McCartney (credited to Lennon/McCartney) that originally
    appeared on The Beatles' album 
    <i>Let It Be</i>. It became The Beatles' last number-one song
    in the United States on 23 May 1970, and was the last single
    released by the quartet. "The Long and Winding Road" was listed
    with "For You Blue" as a double-sided hit when the single hit
    number one on the U.S. Hot 100 in 1970.</p>
      <p>While the released version of the song was very successful,
    the post-production modifications to the song by producer Phil
    Spector angered McCartney to the point that when he made his
    case in court for breaking up The Beatles as a legal entity,
    McCartney cited the treatment of "The Long and Winding Road" as
    one of six reasons for doing so.</p>
      <p>McCartney originally wrote the song at his farm in Scotland,
    and was inspired by the growing tension among The Beatles.
    McCartney said later:</p>
      <p>McCartney recorded a demo version of the song, with Beatles'
    engineer Alan Brown assisting, in September 1968, during the
    recording sessions for 
    <i>The Beatles</i>.</p>
      <p>The song takes the form of a piano-based ballad, with
    conventional chord changes. The song's home key is in E-flat
    major but also uses relative minor; the key of C minor.
    Lyrically, it is a sad and melancholic song, with an evocation
    of an as-yet unrequited, though apparently inevitable,
    love.</p>
      <p>The "long and winding road" of the song was claimed to have
    been inspired by the B842, a thirty-one mile (50 km)
    winding road in Scotland, running along the east coast of
    Kintyre into Campbeltown, and part of the eighty-two mile
    (133 km) drive from Lochgilphead. In an interview in 1994,
    McCartney described the lyric more obliquely:</p>
      <p>The opening theme is repeated throughout, the song lacks a
    traditional chorus, and the melody and lyrics are ambiguous
    about the opening stanza's position in the song; it is unclear
    whether the song has just begun, is in the verse, or is in the
    bridge.</p>
      <p>The Beatles recorded "The Long and Winding Road" on 26 and
    31 January 1969, the day after the group's legendary final
    performance on the roof of their Apple headquarters, with
    McCartney on piano, John Lennon on bass guitar, George Harrison
    on guitar, Ringo Starr on drums, and Billy Preston on Hammond
    organ. This was during a series of sessions for an album
    project then known as 
    <i>Get Back</i>. Lennon, who played bass only occasionally,
    made several mistakes on the recording. Some writers, such as
    Ian MacDonald, have postulated that the disenchanted Lennon's
    ragged bass playing was purposeful.</p>
      <p>In May 1969, Glyn Johns, who had been asked to mix the 
    <i>Get Back</i>album by The Beatles, selected the 26 January
    recording as the best version of the song. The Beatles had
    recorded a master version as part of the 'Apple studio
    performance' on 31 January, which had different lyrics and
    structure, but was not released. Bootlegs of the recording
    sessions of that day, and the film, show the band recording
    numerous takes of the song in a concerted effort to create a
    master. For both the 1969 and 1970 versions of the 
    <i>Get Back</i>album, Glyn Johns used the 26 January mix as
    released on the 
    <i>Anthology 3</i>album in 1996. When the project was handed
    over to Phil Spector he also chose the 26 January recording. In
    the spring of 1970, Lennon and The Beatles' manager, Allen
    Klein, turned over the recordings to Phil Spector with the hope
    of salvaging an album, which was then titled, 
    <i>Let It Be</i>.</p>
      <p>Spector made various changes to the songs, but his most
    dramatic embellishments would occur on 1 April 1970, when he
    turned his attention to "The Long and Winding Road". At Abbey
    Road Studios, he recorded the orchestral and choir
    accompaniment for the song. The only member of The Beatles
    present was Starr. Already known for his eccentric behaviour in
    the studio, Spector was in a peculiar mood that day, as balance
    engineer Pete Bown recalled: "He wanted tape echo on
    everything, he had to take a different pill every half hour and
    had his bodyguard with him constantly. He was on the point of
    throwing a wobbly, saying 'I want to hear this, I want to hear
    that. I must have this, I must have that.'" Bown and the
    orchestra eventually became so annoyed by Spector's behaviour
    that the orchestra refused to play any further, and at one
    point, Bown left for home, forcing Spector to telephone him and
    persuade him into coming back after Starr had told Spector to
    calm down.</p>
      <p>Finally, Spector succeeded in remixing "The Long and Winding
    Road", using 18 violins, four violas, four cellos, three
    trumpets, three trombones, two guitars, and a choir of 14
    women. The orchestra was scored and conducted by Richard
    Hewson, who would later work with McCartney on his album, 
    <i>Thrillington</i>. This lush orchestral treatment was in
    direct contrast to The Beatles' stated intentions for a "real"
    recording when they began work on 
    <i>Get Back</i>.</p>
      <p>When McCartney first heard the Spector version of the song,
    he was outraged. Nine days after Spector overdubbed "The Long
    and Winding Road", McCartney announced The Beatles' breakup. On
    14 April, he sent a sharply worded letter to Apple Records
    business manager Allen Klein, demanding that the added
    instrumentation be reduced, the harp part eliminated, and
    "Don't ever do it again." These requests went unheeded, and the
    Spector version was included on the album.</p>
      <p>In an interview published by the 
    <i>Evening Standard</i>in two parts on 22 April and 23 April
    1970, McCartney said: "The album was finished a year ago, but a
    few months ago American record producer Phil Spector was called
    in by Lennon to tidy up some of the tracks. But a few weeks
    ago, I was sent a re-mixed version of my song 'The Long and
    Winding Road' with harps, horns, an orchestra, and a women's
    choir added. No one had asked me what I thought. I couldn't
    believe it." The Beatles' usual producer, George Martin,
    agreed, calling the remixes "so uncharacteristic" of The
    Beatles. McCartney asked Klein to dissolve The Beatles
    partnership, but was refused. Exasperated, he took the case to
    court, naming Klein and the other Beatles as defendants. Among
    the six reasons McCartney gave for dissolving The Beatles was
    that Klein's company, ABKCO, had caused "intolerable
    interference" by overdubbing "The Long and Winding Road"
    without consulting McCartney.</p>
      <p>Spector claimed that he was forced into remixing "The Long
    and Winding Road", because of the poor quality of Lennon's bass
    playing. While the poor quality of the bass playing has been
    noted by other sources (in his book 
    <i>Revolution in the Head</i>, a track-by-track analysis of the
    Beatles' records, Ian MacDonald described it as "atrocious" to
    the point of sabotage), its basis as the full-scale re-working
    of the track by Spector has been questioned. McCartney has
    argued that Spector could have merely edited out the relevant
    mistakes and rerecorded them, a technique Spector used
    elsewhere on the album. Specifically, it would have been a
    simple matter of having McCartney overdub a more appropriate
    bass part to replace the Lennon bass line that was judged to be
    inadequate.</p>
      <p>The controversy surrounding the song did not prevent a
    chart-topping single from being released in the United States
    on 11 May 1970, joined by "For You Blue" on the B-side. 1.2
    million copies were sold in the first two days, and the song
    began its ten-week long chart run on 23 May. On 13 June, it
    became The Beatles' twentieth and final number one single in
    America, according to 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine. "The Long and Winding Road" brought
    the curtain down on The Beatles' six years of domination in
    America that began with "I Want to Hold Your Hand" in 1964. The
    Beatles achieved twenty number one singles in a mere space of
    74 months, achieving an average of one number one single per
    3.7 months.</p>
      <p>The original Glyn Johns mix of the 26 January take without
    the orchestration and Spector overdubs was included on 
    <i>Anthology 3</i>released in 1996. This version included a
    bridge section spoken, rather than sung, by McCartney.</p>
      <p>In 2003, the remaining Beatles and Yoko Ono released 
    <i>Let It Be... Naked,</i>touted as the band's version of 
    <i>Let It Be</i>remixed by independent producers. McCartney
    claimed that his long-standing dissatisfaction with the
    released version of "The Long and Winding Road" (and the entire
    
    <i>Let It Be</i>album) was in part the impetus for the new
    version. The album included a different take, Take 19, of "The
    Long and Winding Road" recorded on 31 January. Although a
    different take, this version is nonetheless closer to
    McCartney's original intention than the original 
    <i>Let it Be</i>version, with no strings or other added
    instrumentation beyond that which was played in the studio at
    the time. This take is the one seen in the film 
    <i>Let It Be</i>.</p>
      <p>Ringo Starr was impressed with the 
    <i>Naked</i>version of the song: "There's nothing wrong with
    Phil's strings, this is just a different attitude to listening.
    But it's been 30-odd years since I've heard it without all that
    and it just blew me away." Spector himself argued that
    McCartney was being hypocritical in his criticism: "Paul had no
    problem picking up the Academy Award for the 
    <i>Let It Be</i>movie soundtrack, nor did he have any problem
    in using my arrangement of the string and horn and choir parts
    when he performed it during 25 years of touring on his own. If
    Paul wants to get into a pissing contest about it, he's got me
    mixed up with someone who gives a shit."</p>
      <p>After its original release, "The Long and Winding Road"
    became a staple of McCartney's post-Beatles concert repertoire.
    On the 1976 Wings Over the World Tour, where it was one of the
    few Beatles songs played, it was performed on piano in a sparse
    and effective arrangement using a horn section.</p>
      <p>On McCartney's 1989 solo tour and since, it has generally
    been performed on piano with an arrangement using a synthesiser
    mimicking strings, but this string sound has been much more
    restrained than on the Spector recorded version. McCartney also
    played the song to close the Live 8 concert in London.</p>
      <p>In 1990, McCartney released a live version as a 12" single
    with other live tracks from his repertoire.</p>
      <p>McCartney re-recorded "The Long and Winding Road" for the
    soundtrack to his 1984 film, 
    <i>Give My Regards to Broad Street</i>. Some of the elements of
    the 1970 Spector remix that McCartney had disliked—a choir and
    a lush string arrangement—were repeated by McCartney and
    producer George Martin for the soundtrack re-recording.</p>
      <p>McCartney made another studio recording of the song during
    the 1989 
    <i>Flowers in the Dirt</i>sessions; it was released that year
    as a B-side to the single "This One".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
