<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Row_the_Boat_Ashore 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Row_the_Boat_Ashore</songId>
   <title>Michael</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Highwaymen_(folk_band)</artistId>
      <artistName>The Highwaymen</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1961-09-04</week>
      <week>1961-09-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Michael, Row the Boat Ashore" (or "Michael, Row Your Boat
    Ashore") is an African-American spiritual. It was first noted
    during the American Civil War at St. Helena Island, one of the
    Sea Islands of South Carolina.</p>
      <p>It was sung by former slaves whose owners had abandoned the
    island before the Union navy would arrive to enforce a
    blockade. Charles Pickard Ware, an abolitionist and Harvard
    graduate who had come to supervise the plantations on St.
    Helena Island from 1862 to 1865, wrote the song down in music
    notation as he heard the freedmen sing it. Ware's cousin,
    William Francis Allen reported in 1863 that while he rode in a
    boat across Station Creek, the former slaves sang the song as
    they rowed.</p>
      <p>The song was first published in 
    <i>Slave Songs of the United States</i>, by Allen, Ware, and
    Lucy McKim Garrison, in 1867.</p>
      <p>The oldest published version of the song runs in a series of
    unrhymed couplets:</p>
      <p>As this song originated in oral tradition, there are many
    versions of the lyrics. It begins with the refrain, "Michael,
    row the boat ashore, Hallelujah." The lyrics describe crossing
    the River Jordan, as in these lines from Pete Seeger's
    version:</p>
      <p>The River Jordan can be viewed as a metaphor for death.
    According to Allen, the song refers to the Archangel Michael.
    In Christian tradition, Michael is often regarded as a
    psychopomp, or conductor of the souls of the dead.</p>
      <p>One of the earliest recordings of the song is by folksinger
    Bob Gibson, who included it on his 1957 
    <i>Carnegie Concert</i>album. After The Weavers included an
    arrangement in 
    <i>The Weavers' Song Book</i>, published in 1960, the American
    folk quintet The Highwaymen had a number-one hit on both the
    pop and "easy listening" charts in the U.S. with it (under the
    simpler title of "Michael") in 1961; this version also went to
    #1 in the United Kingdom. Lonnie Donegan reached #6 in the UK
    Singles Chart with his cover version in 1961. Harry Belafonte
    recorded a popular version of it for his 1962 
    <i>Midnight Special</i>album; Pete Seeger included it in his 
    <i>Children's Concert at Town Hall</i>in 1963. Trini Lopez had
    a hit with it in 1964.</p>
      <p>The Smothers Brothers did a fairly straightforward version
    of the song on their album 
    <i>It Must Have Been Something I Said!</i>, before turning it
    into a comic sing-along on 
    <i>Golden Hits of the Smothers Brothers, Vol. 2</i>(which is
    also included on their album 
    <i>Sibling Revelry: The Best of the Smothers Brothers</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
