<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hang_on_Sloopy 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hang_on_Sloopy</songId>
   <title>Hang on Sloopy</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_McCoys</artistId>
      <artistName>The McCoys</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1965-10-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/7d/The_McCoys.jpg/200px-The_McCoys.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-McCoys+Hang-on-Sloopy.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Hang On Sloopy</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1965</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl</format>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Cpop Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:57</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Bang Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Wes Farrell</writer>
      <writer>Bert Russell</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Hang On Sloopy" is a song by the pop group The McCoys which
    was #1 in America in October 1965 and is the official rock song
    of the state of Ohio and The Ohio State University. It was
    written by Wes Farrell and Bert Russell and is named for singer
    Dorothy Sloop (1913-1998), who used the name "Sloopy" on
    stage.</p>
      <p>The song was originally titled "My Girl Sloopy" and was
    first recorded by The Vibrations in 1964 on Atlantic Records
    (45-2222), becoming a top thirty hit. It was the title track of
    a live 1965 recording (released on Rhapsody in 1966) by the
    Ramsey Lewis Trio which earned a gold record. It has also been
    recorded by The Ventures (Liberty 1965) as well as by Arseno
    Rodriguez (Bang 1966), The Supremes (Motown 1966), The Kingsmen
    (WAND 1966), Little Caesar and the Consuls, The Yardbirds,
    Saving Jane, Jan &amp; Dean (Liberty-LP "Folk'n'Roll" 1965),
    David Porter (Enterprise "Into A Real Thing" 1971) and Die
    Toten Hosen (2002). It has also been performed by Johnny
    Thunders and the Oddballs in a medley with "Louie Louie" and
    can be heard on the "Add Water and Stir" live Japan
    bootleg.</p>
      <p>In 1965, The Strangeloves, a rock band who purported to be
    from Australia, decided to make the song the follow-up to their
    hit single "I Want Candy", and began performing the song in
    concert. However, the Dave Clark Five, whom they were touring
    with, told the Strangeloves that they were going to record
    their own version of the song, copying the Strangeloves'
    arrangement. The Strangeloves realized that the Dave Clark
    Five's version would probably outsell their own, but they were
    still enjoying success with "I Want Candy" and did not want to
    release a new single yet. So the trio—who were, in reality,
    three successful writer/producers from Brooklyn, New York—
    recruited a group from Union City, Indiana, Rick and the
    Raiders, to record the song instead. The group's name was
    changed to The McCoys (to avoid confusion with another popular
    band of the era, Paul Revere and the Raiders), and their
    16-year-old leader, Rick Zehringer, became known as Rick
    Derringer. The group added vocals and a guitar solo to the
    already-completed Strangeloves backing track, and the single
    was released on Bang Records. It entered the chart on August
    14, 1965, effectively beating the Dave Clark Five to the
    charts. The single went on to hit number one on October 2.</p>
      <p>Originally written and recorded with three verses, "Hang On
    Sloopy" was edited down to two verses for the single and
    original 
    <i>Hang On Sloopy</i>album. The unedited three-verse version
    first appeared on the 1970 Bang various artists compilation 
    <i>Bang &amp; Shout Super Hits</i>(BLPS-220), then again in
    1995 on the Sony Legacy compilation 
    <i>Hang On Sloopy: The Best Of The McCoys</i>
      </p>
      <p>The song gained an association with The Ohio State
    University after its marching band began playing it at football
    games; it first played it October 9, 1965 after a band member,
    John Tatgenhorst, begged the director to try playing it. After
    finally convincing the director, Tatgenhorst arranged the song
    and the band played. After the crowd reaction, the band began
    to play it at every game and now it is a Saturday tradition to
    play the song before the start of the fourth quarter of every
    Buckeye game. Since then, "Sloopy" has been appearing on the
    band's CDs and as a free download on its website.</p>
      <p>The song has also become a feature at all Cincinnati Bengals
    and Cleveland Browns home games where, as is the case at Ohio
    State, it is traditionally played before the fourth quarter.
    The Cincinnati Bengals have been phasing the song out, due to
    their large Kentucky fan base. Fans usually chant the letters
    "O, H, I, O" during the pauses in the chorus while mimicking
    the shape of the letters with their arms. It is also often done
    at home games of the Cleveland Cavaliers and Cleveland Indians.
    The Cleveland Browns, Cleveland Indians and, the Columbus Blue
    Jackets use the song the most, along with Ohio State
    University.</p>
      <p>The "O, H, I, O" chant was incorporated into a version of
    the song recorded by the Columbus, Ohio based rock band Saving
    Jane. The song was also a staple of Big Bear grocery store
    commercials in the Columbus area</p>
      <p>At least one source includes a possible connection between
    the song and Charles J. Givens</p>
      <p>Bruce Springsteen and the E Street Band also covered this
    song live in concert on May 2, 2009 in Greensboro, North
    Carolina.</p>
      <p>The basic riff of the song became a staple of garage bands
    during the 1960s, being used on such songs as The Weeds' "It's
    Your Time" and Kit and the Outlaws' "Dude and the Sundowners"
    "Don't Tread on Me." The song was covered by The Beau Brummels
    on the band's 1966 album 
    <i>Beau Brummels '66</i>. A 1973 cover version by Ramsey Lewis
    won the Grammy Award for Best R&amp;B Instrumental Performance
    in 1974. Punk rock band, Youth In Asia (New Jersey) recorded
    the song on their 1984 album Pulling Out The Plug. A parody
    named "Hang on Snoopy" was included on Swiss rock group Patent
    Ochsner's 1994 album 
    <i>Gmües</i>. All-girl Japanese punk band Lolita No. 18 covered
    the song, which is a testament to its far-reaching influences.
    The song was also covered by the German punk-rock band Die
    Toten Hosen as b-side for their 2000 single "Bayern." Also in
    2000, Aaron Carter recorded his version, included as a bonus
    track on his second album, 
    <i>Aaron's Party (Come Get It)</i>. In 2006, the rock group
    Saving Jane recorded the song also. There is a character in the
    novel 
    <i>The Wanderers</i>by Richard Price named "Hang On Sloopy."
    The song also appears in several 
    <i>Peanuts</i>cartoons but the words are altered slightly to
    "Hang on Snoopy". The family of the late Bert Russell Berns
    call their music publishing company Sloopy II Music. In Mexico
    was covered by the Rock &amp; Roll group Los Teen Tops 
    <i>(The Teen Tops)</i>and known as "Lupita mi Amor" 
    <i>(Lupita, My Love)</i>. The Smashing Pumpkins also released a
    cover of the song in their Live Smashing Pumpkins album series.
    Islands (band) uses the chorus in a b-side named "Two
    Dogs."</p>
      <p>"Sloopy" is commonly misheard as "Snoopy" in the song
    (Snoopy is a dog from the comic strip Peanuts by Charles
    Schultz).</p>
      <p>In April 1985, a columnist for the 
    <i>Columbus Citizen-Journal</i>, Joe Dirck, saw a wire service
    story about a proposal to designate "Louie, Louie" the state
    rock song of Washington and wrote a column about it. This
    goaded the 116th Ohio General Assembly into action and it
    designated "Hang on Sloopy" the state rock song by House
    Concurrent Resolution 16 on November 20, 1985, with clauses
    including:</p>
      <p>and</p>
      <p>"Hang on Sloopy" is now also the official song of the Major
    League Baseball team the Cleveland Indians who play at
    Progressive Field in Cleveland, Ohio. The song is played during
    the middle of the 8th inning. It was chosen in response to a
    tradition in many ballparks of choosing an 8th inning song for
    the fans and team. It has received overwhelming support from
    the fanbase and has high participation.</p>
      <p>"Hang On Sloopy" was used as the entrance song for deaf
    fighter Matt Hamill at UFC 96.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
