<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_(song)</songId>
   <title>Human</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Human_League</artistId>
      <artistName>The Human League</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-11-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/79/Human_League_Human.jpg/200px-Human_League_Human.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Human-League+Human.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Crash</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 1986</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>February 1986, Flyte Time Studios, Minneapolis</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Synthpop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:24 (full album version)</length>
      <length>3:48 (single "fade-out" version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>A&amp;M , Virgin</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Human" is a song recorded by British synthpop band The
    Human League. It was released as the first single from their
    1986 album 
    <i>Crash</i>. The track was written and produced by US
    producers Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis.</p>
      <p>In 1985 the recording sessions for the Human League's fifth
    album were not going well; and the band did not like the
    results which was causing internal conflict. Virgin Records
    executives, worried by the lack of progress from their
    at-the-time most-profitable signing, suggested the band accept
    an offer to work with producers Jimmy Jam and Terry Lewis who
    already had material to work with; and had expressed an
    interest in the band from their U.S. releases. Jam and Lewis
    had recently emerged as in-demand talent due to their success
    with Janet Jackson and her 
    <i>Control</i>album.</p>
      <p>Of the ten songs on 
    <i>Crash</i>, Jam and Lewis wrote three, "Human" being one of
    them. It is a mid-tempo ballad which lyrically is an exchange
    between a man and a woman in a relationship who have reunited
    after a separation. In the first two verses Philip Oakey is
    apologizing to his partner for being unfaithful during her
    absence, and in the song's breakdown Joanne Catherall's
    spoken-word confession reveals that she too was unfaithful. The
    song's title is derived from the chorus, in which both parties
    in the relationship explain that they are "only human" and
    "born to make mistakes".</p>
      <p>"Human" became the second million-selling number-one single
    for The Human League on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 (after
    "Don't You Want Me") and their second chart-topper on the U.S.
    Hot Dance Club Play chart (after "(Keep Feeling) Fascination").
    Jam and Lewis' R&amp;B-based production was also popular on
    American urban radio, bringing the Human League into the top
    ten of the U.S. R&amp;B chart for the first time. In the UK,
    where R&amp;B was less popular "Human" peaked at number eight
    in the UK singles chart.</p>
      <p>It was a welcome success for the Human League, who were
    starting to suffer from creative stagnation and a slight
    decline in fortunes after a hugely successful start to the
    1980s.</p>
      <p>"Human" was reworked and re-released in 2003 as a remix in
    the form of "The Chinese Whispers Mix", principally in Asia. It
    was the creation of Hong Kong based British producer Ian
    Widgery who had recently had major success in the Asian music
    market with the album 
    <i>Shanghai Lounge Divas</i>. Widgery took the original, mixed
    in traditional Chinese instruments and recorded a new chorus in
    Mandarin by female Chinese vocalist Li Ya, which is interwoven
    with Oakey, Catherall and Sulley's vocals. Oakey's lead vocals
    are faded to give the music greater impact.</p>
      <p>The remix was so popular that it crossed over to the UK and
    U.S. markets where it received radio airplay and play on music
    television stations during the height of the electroclash
    revival. Although it was not released as a single in either
    country it appears on some versions of the band's 
    <i>The Very Best of the Human League</i>album of 2003.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Human" was filmed in London during June
    1986, in a studio using Chroma key overlay. It is heavily
    stylized to give a 'water reflective' effect and blue hue
    throughout. In the first time that the band had been presented
    as a "Phil and the girls" trio, images of Oakey, Catherall and
    Sulley are constantly layered and blended. The video was
    conceived and directed by Andy Morahan.</p>
      <p>In 2003, a new video was created and released to promote the
    Chinese Whispers mix. This music video used the original
    footage of Oakey, Sulley and Catherall from 1986 and interlaced
    it with traditional Chinese imagery of silhouetted water grass,
    water lilies and Cantonese characters. It was subject of a U.S.
    MTV featurette which was introduced by Oakey and featured Ian
    Widgery talking about the creative process in the reworking of
    the original Human.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
