<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kokomo_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kokomo_(song)</songId>
   <title>Kokomo</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beach_Boys</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beach Boys</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1988-11-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/4c/Kokomo.jpg/200px-Kokomo.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Beach-Boys+Kokomo.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Still Cruisin'</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 18, 1988 (US) , October 1988 (UK)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" maxi</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>March 22, 1988, April 5–6, 1988</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:35</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Elektra Records , Capitol (reissue)</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Terry Melcher</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Kokomo" is a song written by John Phillips, Scott McKenzie,
    Mike Love and Terry Melcher and recorded by The Beach Boys in
    1988. It was released as a single in 1988 at Elektra Records
    and became a No. 1 Hit in the United States, Japan and
    Australia (where it topped for about two months). The single
    was released to coincide with the release of the Tom Cruise
    movie 
    <i>Cocktail</i>, and its subsequent soundtrack. It was
    nominated in the Grammy Award category: Best Song written
    specifically for a Motion Picture or Television in 1988, but
    lost to Phil Collins's "Two Hearts" (from the film
    "Buster").</p>
      <p>The name "Kokomo" in the song is imaginary, and does not
    refer to the city in Indiana. The name was later applied to
    resorts in Sandals Cay, Jamaica, and Grassy Key, Florida. The
    song also mentions many places in and around the Caribbean,
    including Aruba, Jamaica, Bermuda, Bahama(s), Key Largo,
    Montego, Martinique, Montserrat, and Port-au-Prince
    (Haiti).</p>
      <p>In addition to the Beach Boys' signature layered-singing
    style, the song's instrumentation makes heavy use of steel
    drums played by Terry Melcher. Van Dyke Parks, who had worked
    on some of the group's earlier albums, played accordion, while
    session veteran Jim Keltner played drums. Other players are
    Jeffrey Foskett (acoustic guitar), Ed Carter (bass), Joel
    Peskin (saxophone) and Stevie Heger (additional drums).</p>
      <p>In the original version, lead vocals were performed by Mike
    Love and Carl Wilson. The harmonies include Al Jardine and
    Bruce Johnston. The only active Beach Boys member not involved
    with the recording was Brian Wilson, who, according to his
    autobiography, was given short notice of the recording session
    and unable to attend. He was, however, included in concert
    recordings of the song, including a live concert filmed for the
    television show 
    <i>Full House</i>(episode 028). The 2008 A&amp;E Network 
    <i>Biography</i>on Brian Wilson stated that Mike Love would
    "brag" about having a #1 hit without Wilson's help.</p>
      <p>Despite being recorded in 1988, the song is often played on
    oldies playlists, simply because it has the "style of an oldie"
    and was recorded by a band known for their 1960s success.</p>
      <p>The "Kokomo" single backed with "Tutti Frutti" by Little
    Richard was first released through Elektra Records in July
    1988. It peaked at the #1 position on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts on November 5, 1988 after knocking out
    "A Groovy Kind of Love" by Phil Collins. This meant that it was
    The Beach Boys' first #1 hit in the United States since "Good
    Vibrations" in 1966, making it the longest time span between
    two number one hits in America for a band (22 years). It is
    also their only #1 hit not written or produced by Brian Wilson.
    After spending just one week at the top of the charts, the
    single was knocked out of the number one spot by The Escape
    Club song "Wild, Wild West". After being signed to Capitol
    Records following the success of the initial single, Capitol
    clearly tried to take advantage of the song's popularity by
    issuing the song in the United States for a second time. On the
    second occasion the song was released in July 1989 as the
    B-side of the "Still Cruisin'" single, which peaked at number
    93 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>chart. Capitol again re-issued the song just
    two months later as the B-side of the "Somewhere Near Japan"
    single, however on that occasion the single failed to
    chart.</p>
      <p>In the United Kingdom, the single was first issued by
    Elektra in October 1988. The single peaked at number 25 on the
    charts. After Capitol had signed the band, as they had in the
    U.S., they released the single for the second time as the
    B-side of the "Still Cruisin'" single, however it failed to
    make any impact on the charts. In Australia the single became
    the band's third number one hit in Australia after "Do It
    Again" in 1968 and "Cottonfields" in 1970. In New Zealand the
    single peaked at the number 5 position. In the Dutch singles
    chart, the single peaked at the number 6 position. The song
    also peaked at number 19 in Belgium and at number 7 in
    Germany.</p>
      <p>"Kokomo" was first released on an album in 1989 on the
    band's 
    <i>Still Cruisin'</i>album. The band had been given a one-off
    album contract by their former label Capitol Records after the
    song became a number 1 hit in both the United States and
    Australia. Brian Wilson, who did not perform on the original
    recording of the song, did later contribute vocals to a
    Spanish-language version.</p>
      <p>In 2006, Beach Boys member Mike Love recorded a critically
    panned Christmas remake of the song, titled "Santa's Going To
    Kokomo".</p>
      <p>The video for Kokomo was filmed at the then-recently opened
    Grand Floridian Resort at Walt Disney World in Florida. The
    members of the Beach Boys in the video are: Carl Wilson
    (playing guitar), Al Jardine (playing tambourine), Bruce
    Johnston (playing bass guitar), and Mike Love (playing
    saxophone). Actor and part time Beach Boys band member John
    Stamos can be seen playing the conga steel drums.</p>
      <p>"Kokomo" appeared on VH1's "40 Most Awesomely Bad No. 1
    Songs". However, it received a Golden Globe nomination for Best
    Original Song - Motion Picture in 1989. The song also ranked at
    #12 on 
    <i>Blender</i>magazine's list of the "50 Worst Songs Ever",
    while the music video was named the #3 worst video of 1988 on
    MuchMoreMusic's Back In... '88.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
