<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Want_to_Hold_Your_Hand 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Want_to_Hold_Your_Hand</songId>
   <title>I Want to Hold Your Hand</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1964-02-01</week>
      <week>1964-02-08</week>
      <week>1964-02-15</week>
      <week>1964-02-22</week>
      <week>1964-02-29</week>
      <week>1964-03-07</week>
      <week>1964-03-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>29 November 1963  (1963-11-29) (UK) , 26 December 1963  (1963-12-26) (US)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>17 October 1963 , Abbey Road</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:24</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Parlophone (UK) , Capitol Records (US)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Want to Hold Your Hand" is a song by the English rock
    band The Beatles. Written by John Lennon and Paul McCartney,
    and recorded in October 1963, it was the first Beatles record
    to be made using four-track equipment. Lennon and McCartney did
    not have any particular inspiration for the song. Instead, they
    had received specific instructions from manager Brian Epstein
    to write a song with the American market in mind.</p>
      <p>"I Want to Hold Your Hand" was the band's first number-one
    hit on the Hot 100 chart, starting the British Invasion of the
    United States music charts. The song entered the chart on 18
    January 1964 at number 45; it later held the number one spot
    for seven weeks, and ended up charting for 15 weeks. It also
    held the top spot in the United Kingdom charts. A million
    copies of the single had already been ordered on its release.
    "I Want to Hold Your Hand" became The Beatles' best-selling
    single worldwide.</p>
      <p>Brian Epstein was getting worried about The Beatles' lack of
    commercial success in America—their earlier singles had flopped
    there—and so he encouraged Lennon and McCartney to write a song
    that would appeal to American listeners. McCartney had recently
    moved into 57 Wimpole Street, London W1, where he was living as
    a guest of Dr. Richard and Margaret Asher, whose daughter,
    actress Jane Asher, had become McCartney’s steady girlfriend
    after meeting him earlier in the year. This location briefly
    became Lennon and McCartney’s new writing base, taking over
    from McCartney’s Forthlin Road home in Liverpool. Margaret
    Asher taught the oboe in a "small, rather stuffy music room" in
    the basement and it was here that Lennon and McCartney sat at
    the piano and composed 'I Want to Hold Your Hand'. In September
    1980, Lennon told 
    <i>Playboy</i>magazine:</p>
      <p>In 1994, McCartney agreed with Lennon's description of the
    circumstances surrounding the composition of "I Want to Hold
    Your Hand" saying:</p>
      <p>The Beatles started recording "I Want to Hold Your Hand" at
    Abbey Road Studios in Studio 2 on 17 October 1963. This song,
    along with the single's flip side "This Boy", was the first
    Beatles song to be recorded with four-track technology. Both
    songs were recorded on the same day, and each needed seventeen
    takes to complete. Also the Beatles were experimenting with
    organ sounding guitars which was achieved by extreme
    compression on John Lennon rhythm guitar. Mono and stereo
    mixing was done by George Martin on 21 October 1963, and
    further stereo mixes were done on 8 June 1965, for compilations
    released by EMI affiliates in Australia and the Netherlands,
    and on 7 November 1966.</p>
      <p>"I Want to Hold Your Hand" was one of two Beatles songs
    (along with "She Loves You" as "
    <i>Sie liebt dich</i>") to be later recorded in German,
    entitled "Komm, gib mir deine Hand". Odeon, the German arm of
    EMI (the parent company of The Beatles' record label,
    Parlophone Records) was convinced that The Beatles' records
    would not sell in Germany unless they were sung in German. The
    Beatles detested the idea, and when they were due to record the
    German version on 27 January 1964 at EMI's Pathe Marconi
    Studios in Paris (where The Beatles were performing 18 days of
    concerts at the Olympia Theatre) they chose to boycott the
    session. Their record producer, George Martin, having waited
    some hours for them to show up, was outraged, and insisted that
    they give it a try. Two days later, The Beatles recorded "Komm,
    gib mir deine Hand", one of the few times in their career that
    they recorded outside of London. However, Martin later
    conceded: "They were right, actually, it wasn’t necessary for
    them to record in German, but they weren’t graceless, they did
    a good job".</p>
      <p>"Komm, gib mir deine Hand" appeared in full stereo on the US
    Capitol LP 'Something New' and currently on the new Capitol CD
    compilation called "The Capitol Albums Vol. I".</p>
      <p>The track was a big hit in Germany, but today the English
    versions are much better known in Germany (The Beatles Red and
    Blue albums feature the English hits on the German
    pressings).</p>
      <p>In the UK, "She Loves You" (released in August) had shot
    back to the number one position in November following blanket
    media coverage of The Beatles (described as Beatlemania). Mark
    Lewisohn later wrote: “'She Loves You' had already sold an
    industry-boggling three quarters of a million before these
    fresh converts were pushing it into seven figures. And at this
    very moment, just four weeks before Christmas, with everyone
    connected to the music and relevant retail industries already
    lying prone in paroxysms of unimaginable delight, EMI pulled
    the trigger and released 'I Want To Hold Your Hand'. And then
    it was bloody pandemonium".</p>
      <p>On 29 November 1963, Parlophone Records released "I Want to
    Hold Your Hand" in the United Kingdom, with "This Boy" joining
    it on the single's B-side. Demand had been building for quite a
    while, as evidenced by the one million advance orders for the
    single. When it was finally released, the response was
    phenomenal. A week after it entered the British charts, on 14
    December 1963, it knocked "She Loves You", another Beatles
    song, off the top spot, the first such instance of the same act
    taking over from itself at number one in British history,
    clinging to the top spot for five full weeks. It stayed in the
    charts for another fifteen weeks afterwards, and incredibly
    made a one-week return to the charts on 16 May 1964.
    Beatlemania was peaking at that time; during the same period,
    The Beatles set a record by occupying the top two positions on
    both the album and single charts in the United Kingdom.</p>
      <p>EMI and Brian Epstein finally convinced American label
    Capitol Records, a subsidiary of EMI, that The Beatles could
    make an impact in the United States, leading to the release of
    "I Want to Hold Your Hand" with "I Saw Her Standing There" on
    the B-Side as a single on 26 December 1963. Capitol had
    previously resisted issuing Beatle recordings in the U.S. This
    resulted in the relatively modest Vee-Jay and Swan labels
    releasing the group's earlier Parlophone counterparts in the
    U.S. Seizing the opportunity, Epstein demanded US$40,000 from
    Capitol to promote the single (the most The Beatles had ever
    previously spent on an advertising campaign was US$5,000). The
    single had actually been intended for release in mid-January
    1964, coinciding with the planned appearance of The Beatles on 
    <i>The Ed Sullivan Show</i>. However, a 15-year old fan of The
    Beatles, Marsha Albert, was determined to get hold of the
    single earlier. Later she said:</p>
      <p>James was the deejay for WWDC, a radio station in
    Washington, D.C. Eventually he decided to pursue Albert's
    suggestion to him and asked the station's promotion director to
    get British Overseas Airways Corporation to ship in a copy of
    "I Want to Hold Your Hand" from Britain. Albert related what
    happened next: "Carroll James called me up the day he got the
    record and said 'If you can get down here by 5 o'clock, we'll
    let you introduce it.'" Albert managed to get to the station in
    time, and introduced the record with: "Ladies and gentlemen,
    for the first time on the air in the United States, here are
    The Beatles singing 'I Want to Hold Your Hand.'"</p>
      <p>The song proved to be a huge hit, a surprise for the
    station, as they catered mainly to a more staid audience, which
    would normally be expecting songs from singers such as Andy
    Williams or Bobby Vinton instead of rock and roll. James took
    to playing the song repeatedly on the station, often turning
    down the song in the middle to make the declaration, "This is a
    Carroll James exclusive", to avoid theft of the song by other
    stations.</p>
      <p>Capitol threatened to seek a court order banning airplay of
    "I Want to Hold Your Hand", which was already being spread by
    James to a couple of deejays in Chicago and St. Louis. James
    and WWDC ignored the threat, and Capitol came to the conclusion
    that they could well take advantage of the publicity, releasing
    the single two weeks ahead of schedule on 26 December.</p>
      <p>The demand was insatiable; in the first three days alone, a
    quarter million copies had already been sold (10,000 copies In
    New York City every hour). Capitol was so overloaded by the
    demand, it contracted part of the job of pressing copies off to
    Columbia Records and RCA. By 18 January, the song had started
    its fifteen-week chart run, and on 1 February, The Beatles
    finally achieved their first number-one in America, emulating
    the success of another British group, the Tornados with
    "Telstar", which was number one on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts for three weeks over Christmas and New
    Year 1962/63. The Beatles finally relinquished the number one
    spot after seven weeks, passing the baton to the very song they
    had knocked off the top in Britain: "She Loves You". Hunter
    Davies's biography of the band states that "I Want to Hold Your
    Hand" received certification for sales of 5 million copies in
    the US alone. The replacement of themselves at the summit of
    the U.S. charts was the first time since Elvis Presley in 1956,
    with "Love Me Tender" beating out "Don't Be Cruel", that an act
    had dropped off the top of the American charts only to be
    replaced by another of their releases.</p>
      <p>With that, the "British Invasion" of America had been
    launched. Throughout 1964, only British artists flew high at
    the top of the American charts; including The Dave Clark Five,
    The Rolling Stones, The Kinks, The Hollies and Herman's
    Hermits.</p>
      <p>The American single's front and back sleeves featured a
    photograph of The Beatles with Paul McCartney holding a
    cigarette. In 1984, Capitol Records airbrushed out the
    cigarette for the re-release of the single.</p>
      <p>"I Want to Hold Your Hand" was also released in America on 
    <i>Meet The Beatles!</i>, which ground-breakingly altered the
    American charts by actually outselling the single. Beforehand,
    the American markets were more in favour of hit singles instead
    of whole albums; however, two months after the album's release,
    it had shipped more than three-and-a-half million copies, a
    little over a hundred thousand ahead of the "I Want to Hold
    Your Hand" single.</p>
      <p>The song was greeted by raving fans on both sides of the
    Atlantic but was dismissed by some critics as nothing more than
    another fad song that would not hold up to the test of time.
    Cynthia Lowery of the Associated Press expressed her
    exasperation with Beatlemania by saying of The Beatles: "Heaven
    knows we've heard them enough. It has been impossible to get a
    radio weather bulletin or time signal without running into 'I
    Want to Hold Your Hand'."</p>
      <p>Bob Dylan was impressed by The Beatles' innovation, saying,
    "They were doing things nobody was doing. Their chords were
    outrageous, just outrageous, and their harmonies made it all
    valid." For a time Dylan thought The Beatles were singing "I
    get high" instead of "I can't hide". He was surprised when he
    met them and found out that none of them had actually smoked
    marijuana.</p>
      <p>The song was nominated for the Grammy Award for Record of
    the Year, but the award went to Astrud Gilberto and Stan Getz
    for "The Girl from Ipanema". However, in 1998, the song won the
    Grammy Hall of Fame Award. It has also made the list in The
    Rock and Roll Hall of Fame's 500 Songs that Shaped Rock and
    Roll. In addition, the Recording Industry Association of
    America, the National Endowment for the Arts and Scholastic
    Press have named "I Want to Hold Your Hand" as one of the Songs
    of the Century. In 2004, it was ranked number 16 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's list of the 500 greatest songs
    of all time. It was ranked number two in Mojo's list on the
    "100 Records That Changed the World", after Little Richard's
    "Tutti Frutti". The song was ranked number thirty-nine on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top 100</i>"I Want to Hold Your Hand"
    is currently ranked as the twenty-third best song of all time,
    as well as the number three song of 1963, in an aggregation of
    critics' lists at acclaimedmusic.net.</p>
      <p>The Beatles' recording of this song also appeared as the
    opening track in the 1997 Time-Life 6-CD boxed set, 
    <i>Gold And Platinum: The Ultimate Rock Collection</i>.</p>
      <p>Starting at the song's final week at #1 on the American
    charts, The Beatles had a whopping record of seven #1 songs in
    one year. In order, these were "I Want to Hold Your Hand", "She
    Loves You", "Can't Buy Me Love", "Love Me Do" (a somewhat
    out-of-place 1962 re-release), "A Hard Day's Night", "I Feel
    Fine", and ending with "Eight Days a Week" one year later.</p>
      <p>Reminiscent of Tin Pan Alley and Brill Building techniques
    and an example of modified thirty-two-bar form, the song is
    written on a two-bridge model, with only an intervening verse
    to connect them. The song has no real "lead" singer or even a
    clearly defined melody, as Lennon and McCartney sing in harmony
    with each other. Lennon's vocals are more prominent on the
    recording; however, when The Beatles performed the song on 
    <i>The Ed Sullivan Show</i>on 9 February 1964, McCartney's
    vocals could be heard more clearly (although this may have been
    due to the audio mix, as their mikes weren't turned to the same
    sound level).</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
