<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Think_I_Love_You 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Think_I_Love_You</songId>
   <title>I Think I Love You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Partridge_Family</artistId>
      <artistName>The Partridge Family</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1970-11-21</week>
      <week>1970-11-28</week>
      <week>1970-12-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/00/The_Partridge_Family_-_I_Think_I_Love_You.jpg/200px-The_Partridge_Family_-_I_Think_I_Love_You.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Partridge-Family+I-Think-I-Love-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Partridge Family Album</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1970</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:54</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Bell Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Tony Romeo</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Wes Farrell</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Think I Love You" is a 1970 single by The Partridge
    Family, featuring David Cassidy, composed by songwriter Tony
    Romeo. The song was released at the same time as the debut of
    the network television sitcom 
    <i>The Partridge Family</i>. During the show's first season the
    song was featured on the show twice as it was climbing the
    actual Billboard charts. The song hit number one on the U.S.
    Billboard Pop Singles chart in November of that year.</p>
      <p>The only cast members of the television show to actually
    participate in the recording of the song were David Cassidy and
    Shirley Jones. The music on the song was played by veteran
    studio musicians such as Hal Blaine, Larry Knechtel, Joe
    Osborne, Louie Shelton, Tommy Tedesco, and others.</p>
      <p>On November 25, 1970, "I Think I Love You" was recorded by
    Perry Como, with Nick Perito's orchestra, at the International
    Hotel in Las Vegas, Nevada. The song was released by RCA Victor
    Records on an album, 
    <i>It's Impossible,</i>in December 1970, and reissued in 1975.
    RCA also released the recording on an EP in Mexico in 1971.</p>
      <p>In 1983, Ism's hardcore punk rendition of "I Think I Love
    You" topped the New Music charts at number six (compiled from a
    composite of radio, club and retail reports by 
    <i>CMJ New Music Report</i>, June 6, 1983); however, the
    controversial artwork on the cover led to major record
    retailers banning the single for sale. Their 1983 debut album 
    <i>A Diet for the Worms</i>also included the song and entered
    the number 65 slot on Progressive Radio's Top 100 (CMJ, New
    Music Report, January 16, 1984).</p>
      <p>In 1991, alternative rock band Voice of the Beehive covered
    the song on their album 
    <i>Honey Lingers</i>. Released as a single in the UK, their
    version hit number 25 on the UK Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>In 1992, the group "Nice and Smooth" sampled the intro from
    the Partridge Family's "I Think I Love You" in their rap hit
    "Hip Hop Junkies".</p>
      <p>Florida-based band Less Than Jake covered the song, and
    their version was included on the soundtrack to the 1998 film 
    <i>Scream 2</i>.</p>
      <p>Clam Abuse covered the song as the first proper song for
    their debut album "Stop Thinking" in 1999. A Recent re-issue
    also contains a remix of the cover.</p>
      <p>American pop singer Kaci released her version as a single in
    2002, hitting number 10 on the UK Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>Paul Westerberg covered it in 2004, and in 2005, as did
    Constantine Maroulis and Katie Cassidy (David's daughter). A
    section of the song appears towards the end of Westerberg's
    2008 release 49:00.</p>
      <p>David Cassidy himself did a soul remake of the song in 2003
    for the album 
    <i>Touch of Blue</i>.</p>
      <p>Declan Galbraith covered it in 2007 on his album, 
    <i>You and Me</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
