<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Hard_Day%27s_Night_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Hard_Day%27s_Night_(song)</songId>
   <title>A Hard Day's Night</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1964-08-01</week>
      <week>1964-08-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/67/Ahardday%27snight.jpg/200px-Ahardday%27snight.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Beatles+A-Hard-Day-s-Night.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>A Hard Day's Night</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>10 July 1964</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Abbey Road Studios , 16 April 1964</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:32</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Parlophone R5160 (UK) , Capitol 5222 (US)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"A Hard Day's Night" is a song by English rock band The
    Beatles. Written by John Lennon, with help from Paul McCartney,
    and credited to Lennon/McCartney; it was released on the movie
    soundtrack of the same name in 1964. It was later released as a
    single, with "Things We Said Today" as its B-side.</p>
      <p>The song featured prominently on the soundtrack to The
    Beatles' first feature film, 
    <i>A Hard Day's Night</i>, and was on their album of the same
    name. The song topped the charts in both the United Kingdom and
    United States when it was released as a single. Featuring a
    prominent and unique opening chord, the song's success
    demonstrated that The Beatles were not a one-hit wonder in the
    United States.</p>
      <p>The American and British singles of "A Hard Day's Night" as
    well as both the American and British albums of the same title
    all held the top position in their respective charts for a
    couple of weeks in August 1964, the first time any artist had
    done this.</p>
      <p>The song's title originated from something said by Ringo
    Starr, the Beatles' drummer. Starr described it this way in an
    interview with disc jockey Dave Hull in 1964: "We went to do a
    job, and we'd worked all day and we happened to work all night.
    I came up still thinking it was day I suppose, and I said,
    'It's been a hard day... and I looked around and saw it was
    dark so I said, '...night!' So we came to 'A Hard Day's
    Night.'"</p>
      <p>Starr's statement was the inspiration for the title of the
    movie, which in turn inspired the composition of the song.
    According to Lennon in a 1980 interview with 
    <i>Playboy</i>magazine: "I was going home in the car and Dick
    Lester [director of the movie] suggested the title, 'Hard Day's
    Night' from something Ringo had said. I had used it in 
    <i>In His Own Write</i>[a book Lennon was writing then], but it
    was an off-the-cuff remark by Ringo. You know, one of those
    malapropisms. A Ringo-ism, where he said it not to be funny...
    just said it. So Dick Lester said, 'We are going to use that
    title.'"</p>
      <p>In a 1994 interview for 
    <i>The Beatles Anthology</i>, however, McCartney disagreed with
    Lennon's recollections, basically stating that it was the
    Beatles, and not Lester, who had come up with the idea of using
    Starr's verbal misstep: "The title was Ringo's. We'd almost
    finished making the film, and this fun bit arrived that we'd
    not known about before, which was naming the film. So we were
    sitting around at Twickenham studios having a little
    brain-storming session... and we said, 'Well, there was
    something Ringo said the other day.' Ringo would do these
    little malapropisms, he would say things slightly wrong, like
    people do, but his were always wonderful, very lyrical... they
    were sort of magic even though he was just getting it wrong.
    And he said after a concert, 'Phew, it's been a hard day's
    night.'"</p>
      <p>In 1996, yet another version of events cropped up; in an
    Associated Press report, the producer of the film 
    <i>A Hard Day's Night</i>, Walter Shenson, stated that Lennon
    described to Shenson some of Starr's funnier gaffes, including
    "a hard day's night," whereupon Shenson immediately decided
    that that was going to be the title of the movie (replacing
    other alternatives, including 
    <i>Beatlemania</i>). Shenson then told Lennon that he needed a
    theme song for the film.</p>
      <p>Regardless of who decided on the title, Lennon immediately
    made up his mind that he would compose the movie's title track.
    He dashed off the song in one night, and brought it in for
    comments the following morning (the original manuscript lyrics
    may be seen in the British Library, scribbled in ballpoint on
    the back of an old birthday card). As he described in his 1980 
    <i>Playboy</i>interview, "...the next morning I brought in the
    song... 'cuz there was a little competition between Paul and I
    as to who got the A-side — who got the hits. If you notice, in
    the early days the majority of singles, in the movies and
    everything, were mine... in the early period I'm dominating the
    group.... The reason Paul sang on "A Hard Day's Night" (in the
    bridge) is because I couldn't reach the notes."</p>
      <p>In the Associated Press report, Shenson described his
    recollection of what happened. At 8:30 in the morning, "There
    were John and Paul with guitars at the ready and all the lyrics
    scribbled on matchbook covers. They played it and the next
    night recorded it." Shenson declared, "It had the right beat
    and the arrangement was brilliant. These guys were
    geniuses."</p>
      <p>On 16 April 1964, the Beatles gathered at Studio 2 of the
    Abbey Road Studios and recorded "A Hard Day's Night". It took
    them less than three hours to polish the song for its final
    release, eventually selecting the ninth take as the one to be
    released.</p>
      <p>"A Hard Day's Night" was first released to the United
    States, coming out on 13 June 1964 on the album 
    <i>A Hard Day's Night</i>, the soundtrack to the film, and
    released by United Artists. It was the first song to be
    released before single release (see below).</p>
      <p>"A Hard Day's Night" was the first Beatles single released
    in the UK not to use a pronoun in its title, following "Love 
    <i>Me</i>Do," "Please Please 
    <i>Me</i>," "From 
    <i>Me</i>to 
    <i>You</i>." "
    <i>She</i>Loves 
    <i>You</i>," "
    <i>I</i>Want to Hold Your Hand," and "Can't Buy 
    <i>Me</i>Love".</p>
      <p>The United Kingdom first heard "A Hard Day's Night" when it
    was released there on 10 July 1964, both on the album 
    <i>A Hard Day's Night</i>, and as a single, backed with "Things
    We Said Today" on the B-side. Both the album and single were
    released by Parlophone Records. The single began charting on 18
    July 1964, a week later ousting the Rolling Stones' "It's All
    Over Now" from the top spot on the British charts on 25 July
    1964, coincidentally the day when both the American and British
    albums too hit the peak of their respective charts. The single
    stayed on top for three weeks, and lasted another nine weeks in
    the charts afterwards.</p>
      <p>America first saw the single of "A Hard Day's Night" on 13
    July 1964, featuring "I Should Have Known Better" on the
    B-side, and released by Capitol Records. Capitol had been in a
    quandary about cashing in on the success of the movie 
    <i>A Hard Day's Night</i>, as United Artists held the
    publishing rights for the soundtrack (thus owning the rights to
    release the album of the same title). However, there was
    nothing preventing Capitol from releasing the songs in other
    forms, leading to six out of the seven songs from the movie's
    soundtrack coming out on singles.</p>
      <p>The American single began its 13-week chart run on five days
    after release, and on 1 August started a two-week long run at
    the top, setting a new record—nobody before had ever held the
    number one position on both the album and singles charts in the
    United Kingdom and the United States at the same time. The
    Beatles were the first to do so, and continued to be the only
    ones who had done this until 1970 when Simon and Garfunkel
    achieved the same feat with their album 
    <i>Bridge over Troubled Water</i>and its title track. "A Hard
    Day's Night" went on to sell one million copies in America
    within just over five weeks.</p>
      <p>In 1965, "A Hard Day's Night" won the Beatles the Grammy
    Award for Best Performance by a Vocal Group. In 2004, this song
    was ranked number 153 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's list of the 500 greatest songs
    of all time.</p>
      <p>"A Hard Day's Night" is immediately identifiable before the
    vocals even begin, thanks to George Harrison's unmistakable
    Rickenbacker 360/12 12-string guitar's "mighty opening chord".
    According to George Martin, "We knew it would open both the
    film and the soundtrack LP, so we wanted a particularly strong
    and effective beginning. The strident guitar chord was the
    perfect launch" having what Ian MacDonald calls "a significance
    in Beatles lore matched only by the concluding E major of "A
    Day in the Life", the two opening and closing the group's
    middle period of peak creativity". "That sound you just
    associate with those early 1960s Beatles records".</p>
      <p>
         <span class="unicode" style="white-space:nowrap;">
 Listen to the opening chord (·)
</span>
      </p>
      <p>Analysis of the chord has been the subject of considerable
    debate, with it being described as G7add9sus4, G7sus4, or
    G11sus4 and others below.</p>
      <p>The exact chord is an Fadd9 confirmed by Harrison during an
    online chat on 15 February 2001:</p>
      <p>According to Walter Everett, the opening chord has an
    introductory dominant function because McCartney plays D in the
    bass; Harrison and Martin play F A C G in twelve string guitar
    and piano, over the bass D, giving the chord a mixture-coloured
    neighbor, F; two diatonic neighbors, A and C; plus an
    anticipation of the tonic, G — the major subtonic as played on
    guitar being a borrowed chord commonly used by the Beatles,
    first in "P.S. I Love You" (see mode mixture), and later in
    "Every Little Thing", "Tomorrow Never Knows" and "Got to Get
    You into My Life" (in the latter two against a tonic
    pedal).</p>
      <p>In contrast, Alan W. Pollack interprets the chord as a
    surrogate dominant (surrogate V, the dominant preparing or
    leading to the tonic chord), in G major the dominant being D,
    with the G being an anticipation that resolves in the G major
    chord that opens the verse. He also suggests it is a mixture of
    d minor, F major, and G major (missing the B). Tony Bacon calls
    it a Dm7sus4 (D F G A C), which is the dominant seventh (plus
    the fourth, G). 
    <i>(For more information regarding chord functions see diatonic
    function.)</i>
      </p>
      <p>Everett points out that the chord relates to the Beatles'
    interest in pandiatonic harmony.</p>
      <p>Dominic Pedler has also provided an interpretation of the
    famous chord, with the Beatles and George Martin playing the
    following:</p>
      <p>This gives the notes: G-B-D-F-A-C (the B is a harmonic). One
    of the interesting things about this chord (as described by
    Pedler) is how McCartney's high bass note reverberates inside
    the soundbox of Lennon's acoustic guitar and begins to be
    picked up on Lennon's microphone or pickup during the sounding
    of the chord. This gives the chord its special "wavy" and
    unstable quality. Pedler describes the effect as a "virtual
    pull-off".</p>
      <p>Jason Brown, Professor for the Faculty of Computer Science
    at Dalhousie University in Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada, whose
    research interests include graph theory, combinatorics, and
    combinatorial algorithms, announced in October 2004 that after
    six months of research he succeeded in analyzing the opening
    chord by de-composing the sound into original frequencies using
    a mathematical technique known as the Fourier transform.
    According to Brown, the Rickenbacker guitar wasn't the only
    instrument used. "It wasn't just George Harrison playing it and
    it wasn't just the Beatles playing on it... There was a piano
    in the mix." Specifically, he claims that Harrison was playing
    the following notes on his 12 string guitar: a2, a3, d3, d4,
    g3, g4, c4, and another c4; McCartney played a d3 on his bass;
    producer George Martin was playing d3, f3, d5, g5, and e6 on
    the piano, while Lennon played a loud c5 on his six-string
    guitar.</p>
      <p>A repeated arpeggio outlining the notes of the opening chord
    ends the song in a circular fashion, fading out with the sound
    of helicopter blades. This provides "a sonic confirmation that
    the thirty-six hours we have just seen [in the movie] will go
    on and on and on". The song contains 12 other chords.</p>
      <p>The song is composed in the key of G major and in a 4/4 time
    signature. The verse features the ♭VII or major subtonic chord
    that was a part of the opening chord as an ornament or
    embellishment below the tonic. Transposed down a perfect fifth,
    the modal frame of the song though pentatonic features a ladder
    of thirds axially centered on G with a ceiling note of B♭ and
    floor note of E♭ (the low C being a passing tone)</p>
      <p>According to Middleton, the song, "at first glance
    major-key-with-modal-touches," reveals through its "Line of
    Latent Mode" "a deep kinship with typical blues melodic
    structures: it is centered on three of the notes of the
    minor-pentatonic mode (E♭-G-B♭), with the contradictory major
    seventh (B♮) set against that. Morever, the 
    <i>shape</i>assumed by these notes - the modal 
    <i>frame</i>- as well as the abstract scale they represent, is
    revealed, too; and this - an initial, repeated circling round
    the dominant (G), with an excursion to its minor third (B♭),
    'answered' by a fall to the 'symmetrical' minor third of the
    tonic (E♭) - is a common pattern in blues."</p>
      <p>Lennon opens the twelve measure-long verse and carries it
    along, suddenly joined at the end by McCartney, who then sings
    the bridge.</p>
      <p>The instrumental break, is often credited to George Harrison
    on a 12-string guitar. This is not entirely accurate. The break
    was played by George Harrison on 12-string guitar with George
    Martin doubling the solo on a piano.</p>
      <p>According to the book 
    <i>Recording the Beatles</i>, Martin plays a piano not
    harpsichord at half speed, speeded back up (see note at
    bottom).</p>
      <p>The song closes with Harrison playing the arpeggio during
    the fade-out, the first time the Beatles had used such a
    technique — most, if not all, of their earlier work had closed
    with a final chord (and cadence), such as "She Loves You" and
    "I Want to Hold Your Hand".</p>
      <p>The lyrics speak about the singer's undying devotion to his
    lover, and how he toils so she can purchase the items she
    fancies. The singer sings about his tiredness when he comes
    home from work, but how the things that his lover does perk him
    up.</p>
      <p>On the day the song was written, Lennon is purported to have
    shown reporter Maureen Cleave of London's 
    <i>Evening Standard</i>the lyrics, and she said that word
    "tiredness" sounded weak in the line "I find my tiredness is
    through/And I feel alright." Lennon subsequently replaced the
    lines in question with "I find the things that you do/They make
    me feel all right".</p>
      <p>The solo and outro features Harrison on his Rickenbacker 12
    and Martin simultaneously playing the same notes at half speed
    then speeding them backup to include on track 4 based on a
    detailed description of this recording in the book 
    <i>Recording the Beatles</i>by Brain Kehew and Kevin Ryan.</p>
      <p>During the recording of "A Hard Days Night", Lennon and
    McCartney double track their vocals throughout including the
    chorus. Lennon sings the main lead vocal and Paul sings the
    middle eight. During the chorus McCartney handles the high
    harmony and Lennon the low harmony. Take 7 reveals that the
    lyrics were still not set with Lennon singing "you make me feel
    all right" and McCartney still unsteady with his bass line
    during the middle eight which ends with Lennon chiding him with
    the line "I heard a funny chord".</p>
      <p>"A Hard Day's Night" was used as wakeup music on Space
    Shuttle Missions STS-30, STS-61, and STS-69.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
