<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Come_Softly_to_Me 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Come_Softly_to_Me</songId>
   <title>Come Softly to Me</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Fleetwoods</artistId>
      <artistName>The Fleetwoods</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1959-04-13</week>
      <week>1959-04-20</week>
      <week>1959-04-27</week>
      <week>1959-05-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1959</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Dolphin Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Gretchen Christopher</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>The Fleetwoods</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Come Softly to Me" is a popular song originally written as
    "Come Softly" by Gretchen Christopher, published in 1959, and
    performed by The Fleetwoods, consisting of Christopher, Gary
    Troxel and Barbara Ellis. It was the first release for the new
    Dolphin Records label, as No. 1. This may be the first time
    that a record label's first issue became a number one hit.</p>
      <p>The original title was "Come Softly," but was changed en
    route to its becoming a hit. Recorded at home, they sang it a
    cappella with the rhythmic shaking of Troxel's car keys. The
    tape was then sent to Los Angeles where the sparse instrumental
    accompaniment was added: an acoustic guitar played by Bonnie
    Guitar.</p>
      <p>Bob Reisdorf, the owner of Dolphin Records (changed in 1960
    to Dolton Records), was responsible for the title change. He
    thought that "Come Softly" might be misunderstood and
    considered risqué, so he had it changed to "Come Softly to Me".
    Released in 1959, the single reached number one on the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100 in April.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by other artists, including Sandy
    Salisbury, Bob Welch (with Christine McVie on backing vocals),
    Frankie Vaughan with The Kaye Sisters, who had a chart hit in
    the United Kingdom with it, and The Seekers, whose version
    reached #95 on the Billboard Hot 100 and #20 on the UK charts
    in 1972-73. A cover version, performed by The Roches, is
    repeated several times on the soundtrack of the movie 
    <i>Crossing Delancey</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
