<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sh-Boom 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sh-Boom</songId>
   <title>Sh-Boom</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Crew-Cuts</artistId>
      <artistName>The Crew-Cuts</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1954-08-07</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1954</released>
   <recorded>1954</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Vocal Pop</genre>
      <genre>Doo Wop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Traditional Pop Music</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:47</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Mercury records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>James Keyes</writer>
      <writer>Claude Feaster &amp; Carl Feaster</writer>
      <writer>Floyd F. McRae</writer>
      <writer>and James Edwards</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Sh-Boom" (sometimes referred to as "Life Could Be a Dream")
    is an early doo-wop song. It was written by James Keyes, Claude
    Feaster &amp; Carl Feaster, Floyd F. McRae, and James Edwards,
    members of the R&amp;B vocal group The Chords and published in
    1954. It was a U.S. top ten hit that year for both The Chords
    (who first recorded the song) and The Crew-Cuts.</p>
      <p>The song was first recorded on Atlantic Records' subsidiary
    label Cat Records by The Chords and would be their only hit
    song. Sh-Boom reached number 2 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>R&amp;B charts, and peaked at number 5 on the
    pop charts. It is sometimes considered to be the first doo-wop
    or rock 'n' roll record to reach the top ten on the pop charts
    (as opposed to the R&amp;B charts). This version was ranked
    #215 on Rolling Stone's list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time, and is the group's only song on the list.</p>
      <p>A more traditional version was made by The Crew-Cuts for
    Mercury Records, and was number one on the Billboard charts in
    for nine weeks during August and September 1954. The Crew Cuts
    performed the song on the Ed Sullivan Show.</p>
      <p>On the Cash Box magazine best-selling record charts, where
    both versions were combined, the song reached #1.</p>
      <p>British Doo-Wop revivalists Darts recorded Sh-Boom in the
    late 1970s, this time at a slower tempo. It was released as the
    B-side of the band's last charting single, reaching number 48
    in the UK charts in 1980.</p>
      <p>The record for most recordings of Sh-Boom by a single group
    probably belongs to the Harvard Din &amp; Tonics, an 
    <i>a cappella</i>men's singing group that has featured the song
    on eleven of their twelve albums (most recently "A Hint of
    Lime" in 2008 [1]). Their 1979 Crew Cuts-style arrangement was
    so popular that the group began performing Sh-Boom as their
    signature song at all their concerts, bringing all their alumni
    onstage to perform it across the United States and through ten
    world tours.</p>
      <p>Children's entertainers 
    <i>Sharon, Lois &amp; Bram</i>covered the song on their 1995
    album release titled 
    <i>Let's Dance!</i>.</p>
      <p>The song has appeared in the movie (alternate recording
    only), 
    <i>Happy Days</i>(alternate recording only), 
    <i>Liberty Heights</i>(1999), 
    <i>Cry-Baby</i>featuring Johnny Depp (1990), 
    <i>Two of Us</i>(represented as a favorite of John Lennon and
    Paul McCartney), 
    <i>Road House</i>starring Patrick Swayze (1989) and the
    mini-series "Lipstick on Your Collar" (1993), the last of
    writer Dennis Potter's works to be produced in his lifetime. It
    was briefly featured in the HBO mini-series "From the Earth To
    The Moon" (1998), Hearts in Atlantis (2001). More recently, The
    Trevor Horn Orchestra covered the song for the 
    <i>Mona Lisa Smile</i>(2003) soundtrack, and even more recently
    Pixar's used a recording of the song (2006).</p>
      <p>A remixed version is featured in the video game 
    <i>Destroy All Humans!</i>.</p>
      <p>New York television personality Clay Cole wrote about the
    early years of rock 'n' roll and live television in his
    memoirs, "Sh-Boom! The Explosion of Rock 'n' Roll (1953-1968)"
    published by Morgan James Books.</p>
      <p>Sh-Boom was parodied by Stan Freberg. Another parody, as a
    singing cigarette commercial by the Sportsmen Quartet, appeared
    on the October 31, 1954 Jack Benny radio show. More recently,
    comic Ronnie Golden wrote a parody, "Shoe Bomb", on the subject
    of the British terrorist Richard Reid.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
