<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Best_of_My_Love_(The_Emotions_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Best_of_My_Love_(The_Emotions_song)</songId>
   <title>Best of My Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Emotions</artistId>
      <artistName>The Emotions</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1977-08-20</week>
      <week>1977-08-27</week>
      <week>1977-09-03</week>
      <week>1977-09-10</week>
      <week>1977-09-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Rejoice</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1977</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:42</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Maurice White</writer>
      <writer>Al McKay</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Maurice White / CO-PRODUCER CLARENCE MC DONALD</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Best of My Love" is a disco song by the band The Emotions
    released as a single from their album 
    <i>Rejoice</i>(1977). The song was composed by Maurice White
    and Al McKay of Earth, Wind &amp; Fire Earth, Wind &amp; Fire
    would later team up with the Emotions for the 1979 hit "Boogie
    Wonderland". Best of My Love won a Grammy for Best R&amp;B
    Performance By A Duo Or Group With Vocal and also won an
    American Music Award for Favorite Soul/R&amp;B Single.</p>
      <p>The song was listed at #87 on 
    <i>Billboard's Greatest Songs of All Time.</i>[2] and it was
    the third biggest Pop song of 1977 and the fifth biggest
    R&amp;B song of 1977 Best of My Love has been certified
    Platinum by the RIAA.</p>
      <p>The song has an upbeat vibe, with a prominent bass line and
    horns accenting the drums between the verses and chorus.</p>
      <p>The single achieved huge success, remaining on top of the
    Billboard Hot 100 chart for 5 non-consecutive weeks. The song
    managed to stay at the top spot of the chart for four
    consecutive weeks, but was interrupted by Andy Gibb's "I Just
    Want To Be Your Everything". The single returned and spent an
    additional week on top of the Billboard Hot 100. On the disco
    chart, "Best of My Love" would peak at number eleven. .
    Eventually, the single received a Platinum certification from
    RIAA, becoming The Emotions' biggest hit to date and their only
    single to receive a certification.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered numerous times by various artists,
    including Christina Milian with Carol Duboc and Minae Noji,
    featured in the film 
    <i>Be Cool</i>), Sakura, Dee Lewis (1988) and Lisa. Mary J.
    Blige also covered the song in 2004 for the GAP clothing store
    company. Pop diva Sheena Easton covered the song for her disco
    album "Fabulous" in 2001. Phoebe Snow does a version on her
    1989 album 
    <i>Something Real</i>with a horn section backing her up that
    includes Randy Brecker, Tom Scott and John Faddis.</p>
      <p>The song has also been used in reality shows, such as in
    Australian Idol 2006, in which it was sung by Lavina Williams,
    in the fourth season of American Idol, in which it was sung by
    Vonzell Solomon, in the second season of Pinoy Dream Academy,
    in which it was sung by Liezel Garcia, and in the sixth season
    of the American Dancing with the Stars (Jason Taylor and Edyta
    Sliwinska danced to it in the sixth week of competition).</p>
      <p>There is also a Dutch version of the song, sung by former
    Dutch 
    <i>Idols</i>-finalist Dewi Pechler. This version is called "Het
    Beste Van Mij" and is an exclusive airplay single for the Dutch
    radio station 100%NL.</p>
      <p>The song has appeared in many films, including 
    <i>Boogie Nights</i>(1997), 
    <i>Summer of Sam</i>(1999), 
    <i>The Wendell Baker Story</i>(2005), 
    <i>Mission Impossible III</i>(2006) and 
    <i>The Holiday</i>(2006).</p>
      <p>The song was also covered by Christina Milian, Carol Duboc
    and Minae Noji featured in the film 
    <i>Be Cool</i>(2005).</p>
      <p>"Best of My Love" was allegedly sampled without permission
    in Mariah Carey's single "Emotions", resulting in a
    lawsuit..</p>
      <p>The rap group 3rd Bass sampled the song in their song
    'Brooklyn-Queens'</p>
      <p>The tune was used for WNBC-TV in New York to promote their
    News 4 New York newscasts in 1980.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
