<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Boyfriend%27s_Back_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Boyfriend%27s_Back_(song)</songId>
   <title>My Boyfriend's Back</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Angels_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>The Angels</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1963-08-31</week>
      <week>1963-09-07</week>
      <week>1963-09-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1963</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1963</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Romantic Balad</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>N/A</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Smash Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bob Feldman</writer>
      <writer>Jerry Goldstein</writer>
      <writer>Richard Gottehrer</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"My Boyfriend's Back" was a hit song in 1963 for The Angels,
    an American girl group. It was written by the songwriting team
    of Feldman, Goldstein and Gottehrer. The recording was
    originally intended as a demo for The Shirelles, but ended up
    being released as recorded. The result was a single that spent
    three weeks at number one on the Billboard Hot 100 chart, and
    number two on the R&amp;B Billboard.</p>
      <p>The song is a word of warning to a would-be suitor who,
    after the narrator of the song rebuffed his advances, went on
    to spread nasty rumours accusing the narrator of romantic
    indiscretions. Now, the narrator declares, her boyfriend is
    back in town and ready to settle the score, and she tells the
    rebuffed would-be suitor to watch his back.</p>
      <p>The inspiration for the song was when co-writer Bob Feldman
    overheard a conversation between a high school girl and the boy
    she was rebuffing.</p>
      <p>"My Boyfriend's Back" has been the subject of several
    notable cover versions.</p>
      <p>Rival girl groups The Chiffons and Martha and the Vandellas
    recorded covers shortly after The Angels' original release.
    Nearly twenty years later, Melissa Manchester released a
    faithful cover version as a single in 1983 which became a minor
    Adult Contemporary hit. More than twenty years after that, the
    song was also covered by former 
    <i>American Idol</i>contestant Paris Bennett on her 2007 album
    "Princess P."</p>
      <p>The song has also been covered in punk rock-influenced
    recordings by Me First and the Gimme Gimmes, The Raveonettes,
    Bracket, and Australian female punk trio The Spazzys.</p>
      <p>UK Powerpop originators The Pleasers featured the song as a
    highspot of their live stage shows as 'My Girlfriends Back' and
    recorded it for their Thamesbeat Album in 1978.</p>
      <p>Bette Bright and the Illuminations released a cover version
    in 1978 as their single debut.</p>
      <p>The rap group Bone Thugs-N-Harmony's track "Guess Who's
    Back" borrows heavily from the structure and lyrics of "My
    Boyfriend's Back".</p>
      <p>The song is featured in the 2006 Tony award winning musical,
    
    <i>Jersey Boys</i>. It was also featured on the U.S. television
    show "American Dreams," where it was sung by Christian Pop
    singer Stacie Orrico playing the lead singer of the Angels.
    Orrico was backed by series stars Brittany Snow (Meg Pryor) and
    Vanessa Lengies (Roxanne Bojarski).</p>
      <p>A version of the tune has been used in a commercial jingle
    for the Hess toy truck, sung as "The Hess Truck's Back".</p>
      <p>A cover by Australian band The Chantoozies featured in the
    film "The Crossing" (1990).</p>
      <p>The song was parodied by Bob Ricci on his debut album 
    <i>Get a Life</i>as "My Girlfriend's Back".</p>
      <p>Sarah Brightman released a cover version of the song on a
    single in 1981.</p>
      <p>In 1981, the band Dire Straits made a reference to the song
    in their hit Romeo and Juliet, from the album Making
    Movies.</p>
      <p>The song figured prominently in the 1989 made for television
    film 
    <i>My Boyfriend's Back</i>, which featured Jill Eikenberry,
    Sandy Duncan and Judith Light as former members of a fictitious
    girl group named The Bouffants. In the story, "My Boyfriend's
    Back" was their only hit song.</p>
      <p>The song title was referenced for the 1993 film 
    <i>My Boyfriend's Back</i>, directed by Bob Balaban.</p>
      <p>The Disney Channel did a DTV music video of the song set to
    clips from the 
    <i>Legend of Sleepy Hollow</i>segment of 
    <i>The Adventures of Ichabod and Mr. Toad</i>.</p>
      <p>Comedian Frank Caliendo often sings a cover of the song,
    with the lyrics changed to be about Brett Favre, when doing his
    John Madden impersonation. (My Brett Favre's back and your
    defense is in trouble/Hey now, hey now, my Brett Favre's Back!)
    A viral video was later posted on YouTube, with Caliendo's
    lyrics put over the original song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
