<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Can%27t_Buy_Me_Love 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Can%27t_Buy_Me_Love</songId>
   <title>Can't Buy Me Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1964-04-04</week>
      <week>1964-04-11</week>
      <week>1964-04-18</week>
      <week>1964-04-25</week>
      <week>1964-05-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/9a/Can%27t_Buy_Me_Love.jpg/200px-Can%27t_Buy_Me_Love.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Beatles+Can-t-Buy-Me-Love.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>A Hard Day's Night</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>16 March 1964 ( US ) , 20 March 1964 ( UK )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>29 January 1964 , Pathé Marconi Studios, Paris</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:11</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Parlophone R5114 ( UK ) , Capitol 5150 ( US )</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Can't Buy Me Love" is a song composed by Paul McCartney
    (credited to Lennon/McCartney) and released by The Beatles on
    the A-side of their sixth British single, "Can't Buy Me
    Love/You Can't Do That."</p>
      <p>When pressed by American journalists in 1966 to reveal the
    song's "true" meaning, McCartney denied that "Can't Buy Me
    Love" was about prostitution, stating that, although it was
    open to interpretation, that suggestion was going too far,
    saying: "The idea behind it was that all these material
    possessions are all very well, but they won't buy me what I
    really want." Although he was to later comment: "It should have
    been 
    <i>'Can</i>Buy Me Love' " when reflecting on the perks that
    money and fame had brought him.</p>
      <p>While in Paris, The Beatles stayed at the five star George V
    hotel and had an upright piano moved into one of their suites
    so that song writing could continue. It was here that McCartney
    wrote "Can't Buy Me Love." The song was written under the
    pressure of the success achieved by "I Want to Hold Your Hand"
    which had just reached number one in America. When producer
    George Martin first heard "Can't Buy Me Love" he felt the song
    needed changing: "I thought that we really needed a tag for the
    song’s ending, and a tag for the beginning; a kind of intro. So
    I took the first two lines of the chorus and changed the
    ending, and said 'Let's just have these lines, and by altering
    the second phrase we can get back into the verse pretty
    quickly.'" And they said, "That's not a bad idea, we’ll do it
    that way".</p>
      <p>The song's verse is a twelve bar blues in structure, a
    formula that The Beatles seldom applied to their own
    material.</p>
      <p>"Can't Buy Me Love" was recorded on 29 January 1964 at EMI's
    Pathe Marconi Studios in Paris, France, where The Beatles were
    performing 18 days of concerts at the Olympia Theatre. At this
    time, EMI's West Germany branch, Odeon, insisted that The
    Beatles would not sell records in any significant numbers in
    Germany unless they were actually sung in the German language
    and The Beatles reluctantly agreed to re-record the vocals to
    "She Loves You" and "I Want to Hold Your Hand" prior to them
    being released in Germany. George Martin travelled to Paris
    with a newly mastered rhythm track for what was to be "Komm,
    Gib Mir Deine Hand". "Sie Liebt Dich" (She Loves You) required
    The Beatles to record a new rhythm track as the original two
    track recording had been scrapped. EMI sent a translator to be
    present for this recording session which had been hurriedly
    arranged to tie in with The Beatles Paris commitments. This was
    accomplished well within the allotted studio time allowing The
    Beatles an opportunity to record the backing track, with a
    guide vocal, to the recently composed "Can't Buy Me Love".
    McCartney's final vocal was overdubbed at Abbey Road Studios,
    London, on 25 February.</p>
      <p>The song also included some vocal harmonies in the
    background, which at the time became characteristic of the
    Beatles. After listening to the first take of the song, the
    band concluded that the song didn't need them. Therefore, 
    <i>Can't Buy Me Love</i>became the first single the Beatles
    released without their characteristic background harmonies.</p>
      <p>Also re-recorded on this day at Abbey Road was George
    Harrison's modified guitar solo, although his original solo can
    still just be heard in the background. Harrison said: "What
    happened was, we recorded first in Paris and re-recorded in
    England. Obviously they'd tried to overdub it, but in those
    days they only had two tracks, so you can hear the version we
    put on in London, and in the background you can hear a quieter
    one." Helen Shapiro, a friend of The Beatles and present at
    this overdub session, says that Ringo Starr also added extra
    cymbals "over the top" and that "apparently this was something
    he did quite often on their records". "Can't Buy Me Love" is
    also the only English-language Beatles track that The Beatles
    themselves recorded in a studio outside the UK, although the
    instrumental portion of The Beatles' B-side "The Inner Light"
    was recorded in India by Indian session musicians.</p>
      <p>The Beatles established four records on the Billboard Hot
    100 with "Can't Buy Me Love" at number one:</p>
      <p>
         <i>Rolling Stone</i>ranked "Can't Buy Me Love" at #289 on their
    list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All Time.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Can't Buy Me Love</i>became The Beatles' fourth UK
    number-one single and their third single to sell over a million
    copies in the UK.</p>
      <p>The song was also released in the following albums: 
    <i>A Hard Day's Night</i>(both the American United Artists and
    British Parlophone versions); 
    <i>Big Hits From England And The U.S.A.</i>, a various artists
    compilation album from Capitol issued in 1964; the British-only
    LP release 
    <i>A Collection Of Beatles Oldies</i>; the 1970 compilation 
    <i>Hey Jude</i>(also known as 
    <i>The Beatles Again</i>); the 1973 double disc collection 
    <i>1962–1966</i>(the Red Album); the 1982 release 
    <i>Reel Music</i>, which features songs from Beatles films; the
    1982 compilation 
    <i>20 Greatest Hits</i>(both in England and America); and 
    <i>1</i>, released in November 2000.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
