<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smoke_Gets_in_Your_Eyes 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smoke_Gets_in_Your_Eyes</songId>
   <title>Smoke Gets in Your Eyes</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Platters</artistId>
      <artistName>The Platters</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1959-01-19</week>
      <week>1959-01-26</week>
      <week>1959-02-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1958</released>
   <formats>
      <format>45 rpm</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Doo Wop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:40</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Mercury</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Otto Harbach</writer>
      <writer>Jerome Kern</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Smoke Gets in Your Eyes" is a show tune written by American
    composer Jerome Kern and lyricist Otto Harbach for their 1933
    operetta 
    <i>Roberta</i>. It was performed by Irene Dunne for the 1935
    film adaptation, costarring Fred Astaire, Ginger Rogers and
    Randolph Scott. It has been covered by numerous artists,
    beginning with Paul Whiteman and His Orchestra with Bob
    Lawrence on vocal, which went to the top of the charts in 1934,
    and including Nat "King" Cole who first covered it in 1946. It
    also featured in "Lovely to Look At", a 1952 remake of
    "Roberta", where it was sung by Kathryn Grayson. Possibly the
    most famous version was recorded in 1958 by the doo wop group
    The Platters, which became a number one hit on the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100 and reached number three on the R&amp;B
    charts in 1959 .</p>
      <p>In 1956, Vic Damone covered this song with a very dramatic
    and different rendition. "Smoke Gets in Your Eyes" became one
    of Vic Damone's most famous songs. A 1972 remake by British
    band Blue Haze also became popular. Saxophone player Boots
    Randolph did an acoustic cover of the song on the B-side of his
    LP Yakety Sax. Bryan Ferry recorded a quavering, briefly
    popular version of the song in 1974 on the album 
    <i>Another Time, Another Place</i>, which reached number 17 on
    the UK charts in September 1974. Jerry Garcia, who was named
    after Jerome Kern, released a music video in the early 1990s
    covering the classic tune, with actress Ashley Judd sitting in
    the background listening. Similarly in the early 1990s the song
    was performed by Eartha Kitt as part of her work with a small
    jazz combo in Germany; these recordings are preserved under the
    name Thinking Jazz.</p>
      <p>Australian singer Jason Donovan recorded the song for his
    album "Let It Be Me" (2008).</p>
      <p>The song has been featured in several films, including
    George Lucas's 
    <i>American Graffiti</i>(1973) (The Platters recording) and
    much later in the 2004 Golden Globe-winning film 
    <i>Being Julia</i>, directed by István Szabó. J.D. Souther's
    rendition is the centerpiece song to Steven Spielberg's 1989
    film 
    <i>Always</i>, and features significantly in both the plot and
    soundtrack of Hou Hsiao-Hsien's 2005 film, 
    <i>Three Times</i>. It has also appeared in Rainer Werner
    Fassbinder's "The Bitter Tears of Petra von Kant".
    Additionally, Cher's character briefly sings the last verse of
    the song during the 1999 film 
    <i>Tea With Mussolini</i>. "Smoke Gets in Your Eyes" is the
    title of the 2007 pilot episode of the AMC original drama 
    <i>Mad Men</i>. It appears in the end of Tropic Thunder. In
    Catcher in the Rye, Holden Caulfield listens to this song when
    he is at the carousel. The song title is also mentioned in the
    lyrics of the CAKE song "Wheels".</p>
      <p>A parody of the song was used in the British TV advert for
    Esso Blue paraffin (kerosene) rewording it as "They asked me
    how I knew / It was Esso Blue / I of course replied / With
    lower grades one buys / Smoke gets in your eyes".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
