<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sugar,_Sugar 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sugar,_Sugar</songId>
   <title>Sugar, Sugar</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Archies</artistId>
      <artistName>The Archies</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1969-09-20</week>
      <week>1969-09-27</week>
      <week>1969-10-04</week>
      <week>1969-10-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/d7/Sugar%2C_sugar.jpg/200px-Sugar%2C_sugar.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Archies+Sugar-Sugar.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Everything's Archie</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1969</released>
   <recorded>1969</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Bubblegum Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:48</length>
   </lengths>
   <writers>
      <writer>Andy Kim</writer>
      <writer>Jeff Barry</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jeff Barry</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Sugar, Sugar" is a pop song written by Jeff Barry and Andy
    Kim. It was a four-week 1969 number-one hit single by fictional
    characters The Archies. Produced by Jeff Barry, the song was
    originally released on the album 
    <i>Everything's Archie.</i>The album is the product of a group
    of studio musicians managed by Don Kirshner. Ron Dante's lead
    vocals were accompanied by those of Toni Wine (who sang the
    line "I'm gonna make your life so sweet"), Andy Kim, and Ellie
    Greenwich. Together they provided the voices of the various
    Archies using multitracking. Ray Stevens, the comic singer,
    provided the hand claps to the song.</p>
      <p>The Archies' "Sugar, Sugar" was the 1969 number-one single
    of the year. It spent four weeks at the top of the Billboard
    Hot 100 from September 20, 1969 and eight weeks at the top of
    the UK singles chart. The song lists at #63 on 
    <i>Billboard's Greatest Songs of All Time.</i>It also peaked at
    one in the South African Singles Chart. On February 5, 2006,
    "Sugar, Sugar" was inducted into the Canadian Songwriters Hall
    of Fame, as co-writer Andy Kim is originally from Montreal,
    Quebec.</p>
      <p>The song was earlier offered to The Monkees, although
    additional rumors that it was recorded using session musicians
    with Davy Jones providing all the vocals, but never released,
    are false. Don Kirshner has said that Mike Nesmith put his fist
    through the wall of the Beverley Hills hotel refusing to do
    "Sugar, Sugar." Jones confirmed that Kirshner had offered it to
    them, but stated they turned it down, and he never recorded it.
    The band thought it seemed cheesy and at that point they were
    looking to mature their sound. However, Monkees archival expert
    Andrew Sandoval has suggested that the band may instead
    actually have been offered a tune called "Sugar Man", but with
    the passage of time the parties involved simply mis-remembered
    it as being "Sugar, Sugar", in large part because it made a
    better anecdote.</p>
      <p>On September 4, 2006, Dante and Wine performed the song
    together on the Jerry Lewis MDA Telethon. This was the first
    time they had publicly performed the song together. They
    performed it again at one of Toni Wine's performances at the
    Genghis Cohen in West Hollywood.</p>
      <p>Former President George W. Bush has said "Sugar, Sugar" is
    one of his favorite songs. The song played in Jenna Bush's
    wedding party in May, 2008.</p>
      <p>In the TV Movie 
    <i>Archie: To Riverdale and Back again</i>(VHS reissued title, 
    <i>Return to Riverdale</i>), the now-older Jughead plays the
    original version of the song to his son; later he uses it to
    bridge the 'age gap' between them when he finds out his son is
    shy around girls — the two perform a 'rap' version of the
    song.</p>
      <p>The song was featured in the episode 
    <i>That's All There Is</i>in the 1998 HBO Mini-Series From the
    Earth to the Moon. Astronauts Al Bean and Dick Gordon are seen
    singing the song in their Command Module during their 4 day
    trip to the moon on Apollo 12 in November of 1969.</p>
      <p>Millions upon millions of copies of this record were
    distributed through an unusual distribution mode. A record of
    the song was embossed directly onto the backs of Kelloggs
    breakfast cereal boxes (Sugar Pops &amp; Sugar Smacks) and the
    cardboard record could be cut out and played on a
    turntable.</p>
      <p>The song is featured in 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>episodes "Boy-Scoutz N the Hood" and "Sweets
    and Sour Marge". In the former, Homer has a hallucination about
    dancing ice cream cones while trapped on a raft; he was
    listening to the song on Rod Flanders' personal stereo, but as
    the batteries run down, the song gradually slows down and stops
    and the ice creams melt, ending his dream.</p>
      <p>In the 1970's Filmation cartoon, Sabrina the Teenage Witch
    is seen dancing to the song on the record player in the first
    few minutes of "Weatherbee's Disasterpiece".</p>
      <p>English hard rock band Def Leppard got the idea for their
    1987 hit "Pour Some Sugar on Me" from the song.</p>
      <p>The original recording can be heard in the 
    <i>Dreamworks</i>Film 
    <i>Bee Movie</i>while Barry, played by 
    <i>Jerry Seinfeld</i>, is dreaming.</p>
      <p>The song was adapted for a TV commercial for Equal brand
    artificial sweetener in the late '80s -- 
    <i>"Sugar (no no no no no no)/Now there's Equal (yeah yeah yeah
    yeah yeah yeah)".</i>
      </p>
      <p>The song is adapted for a TV commercial for table sugar
    product called "Gulaku" in Indonesia. They use many different
    versions of the song, depending on the storyline that is being
    depicted in the commercial. It is one of the most expensive
    advertisements in Indonesia, and the TV commercial reintroduced
    the song to Indonesian listeners.</p>
      <p>The song was played in the 1996 movie 
    <i>A Very Brady Sequel</i>when Greg saw a beautiful girl coming
    out of the swimming pool and later saw that it was Marcia.</p>
      <p>The song was sung by Richie in an episode of 
    <i>Family Matters</i>when he and 3J were trying to win
    affection of a girl to be their Valentine. 3J thought the song
    too childish and it hurt Richie's feelings, but the girl
    decided to pick him over 3J.</p>
      <p>The gingerbread man in 
    <i>Dreamworks</i>Film 
    <i>Shrek 2</i>sings the song in the DVD's special feature "Far
    Far Away Idol".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
