<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eight_Days_a_Week_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eight_Days_a_Week_(song)</songId>
   <title>Eight Days a Week</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1965-03-13</week>
      <week>1965-03-20</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Beatles for Sale</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>4 December 1964</released>
   <recorded>Abbey Road , 6 October 1964</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:43</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Parlophone , PMC 1240 (mono) , PCS 3062 (stereo) , CDP 7 46438 2</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Beatles for Sale</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Eight Days a Week" is a song written by John Lennon and
    Paul McCartney, which was recorded by The Beatles and released
    on their December 1964 album 
    <i>Beatles for Sale</i>.</p>
      <p>The inspiration of the song has been attributed to at least
    two different sources by Paul McCartney. In a 1984 interview
    with Playboy, he credited the title to Ringo Starr, who was
    noted for his malapropisms, which are credited as the source of
    other song titles (such as "A Hard Day's Night").</p>
      <p>PAUL: Yeah, he said it as though he were an overworked
    chauffeur. (in heavy accent) 'Eight days a week.' (laughter)
    When we heard it, we said, 'Really? Bing! Got it!'</p>
      <p style="font-size:smaller;text-align: right">
         <cite style="font-style:normal;">—Paul McCartney &amp; Linda
      McCartney, 1984 Playboy Interview</cite>
      </p>
      <p>However, he has also credited the the title to an 
    <i>actual</i>chauffeur who once drove him to Lennon's house in
    Weybridge.</p>
      <p style="font-size:smaller;text-align: right">
         <cite style="font-style:normal;">—Paul McCartney, The Beatles
      Anthology</cite>
      </p>
      <p>"Eight Days a Week" is the first song which the Beatles took
    into the studio unfinished to work on arrangement during the
    session, which would later become common. The song was mainly
    recorded in two recording sessions on 6 October devoted
    exclusively to this song, which lasted nearly seven hours with
    a fifteen-minute break in between. Lennon and McCartney tried
    several ideas for the intro and outro of the song. The first
    take featured a simple acoustic guitar introduction. The second
    take introduced an "oo"-ing vocal that was experimented with
    until the sixth take, when it was abandoned in favour of the
    final guitar intro. The final outro (along with unused intro
    takes) was recorded separately on 18 October. The final version
    of the song incorporated another Beatles first and pop music
    rarity: the song begins with a fade-in, as opposed to the
    common fade-out ending. The instrumentation includes acoustic
    guitar, electric guitar, drums, bass and overdubbed handclaps.
    The fade-in and coda both include more guitar overdubs.</p>
      <p>The song, along with two others from the album ("Baby's in
    Black" and "No Reply") was planned as a single release. In the
    end, it was released as a single only in the US on 15 February
    1965 becoming a number-one hit. Its B-side was "I Don't Want to
    Spoil the Party". The single release in the US was the result
    of DJs playing the song from imported copies of the 
    <i>Beatles for Sale</i>album as an exclusive since it was not
    included on the album's US counterpart 
    <i>Beatles '65</i>. Later, it made a US album appearance on 
    <i>Beatles VI</i>.</p>
      <p>While not one of The Beatles' best known or most popular #1
    songs, "Eight Days a Week" was a significant record-setter on
    the American singles chart. It became the second of six #1
    songs in a row on the American charts - a record eventually
    equaled by The Bee Gees in the late 1970s, and surpassed by
    Mariah Carey in the early 1990s. In order they were "I Feel
    Fine", "Eight Days a Week", "Ticket to Ride", "Help!",
    "Yesterday", and "We Can Work It Out". Additionally, the song
    became the record-setting seventh #1 song in a 52-week period
    on the American charts. This list starts with the final week of
    "I Want to Hold Your Hand" at number one, then "She Loves You",
    "Can't Buy Me Love", "Love Me Do" (a somewhat out-of-place 1962
    re-release), "I Feel Fine", and ending with "Eight Days a
    Week".</p>
      <p>Although it was a huge American hit, the group didn't think
    highly of the song (Lennon called it "lousy"), and never
    performed it live.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
