<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_Vibrations 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_Vibrations</songId>
   <title>Good Vibrations</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beach_Boys</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beach Boys</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1966-12-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/b2/Good_Vibrations_single.jpg/200px-Good_Vibrations_single.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Beach-Boys+Good-Vibrations.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Smiley Smile</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 10, 1966</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>February–September 1966</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Psychedelic Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:39</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Brian Wilson / Mike Love</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Brian Wilson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Good Vibrations" is a psychedelic pop song by American rock
    group The Beach Boys. Composed and produced by Brian Wilson,
    the song's lyrics were written by Wilson and Mike Love.</p>
      <p>Released as a single on October 10, 1966 (backed with the 
    <i>Pet Sounds</i>instrumental "Let's Go Away For Awhile"), it
    was the band's third U.S. number-one hit, after "I Get Around"
    and "Help Me, Rhonda", reaching the top of the Billboard Hot
    100 chart in December 1966, as well as being their first
    British chart-topper. Initiated during the sessions for the 
    <i>Pet Sounds</i>album, it was not taken from or issued as a
    lead single for an album, but as a stand-alone single, and
    later placed on the album 
    <i>Smiley Smile</i>eleven months after its release.</p>
      <p>Wilson's publicist Derek Taylor described "Good Vibrations"
    as a "pocket symphony". It featured instruments unusual for a
    pop song, including prominent use of the cello and an
    electro-theremin. It is #6 on Rolling Stone's 500 Greatest
    Songs of All Time. The song "Good Vibrations" is part of the
    The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame's 500 Songs that Shaped Rock and
    Roll list.</p>
      <p>Wilson recounted the genesis of the title "Good Vibrations"
    in his 1995 biopic, 
    <i>I Just Wasn't Made for These Times</i>, and at other times.
    When he was a child, his mother told him that dogs could pick
    up "vibrations" from people, so that the dog would bark at "bad
    vibrations". Wilson turned this into the general idea of
    vibrations (and Mike Love putting "good" in front of
    vibrations), and developed the idea of people being able to do
    the same with emotions.</p>
      <p>Wilson first enlisted 
    <i>Pet Sounds</i>lyricist Tony Asher for help in putting words
    to the idea. Soon after they met, Wilson asked his new writing
    partner Van Dyke Parks to pen lyrics for the song, but Parks
    declined. Beach Boys bandmate Mike Love supplied the final
    version of the lyrics around August 24, 1966.</p>
      <p>According to Wilson, when he re-recorded "Good Vibrations"
    for his 2004 version of 
    <i>Smile</i>, his wife, Melinda, suggested he use the original
    lyrics written by Tony Asher.</p>
      <p>Originally composed during the Pet Sounds sessions with
    original lyrics by Tony Asher, Wilson recorded the song in
    sections, at different studios in order to capture the sound he
    heard in his head. Building upon the layered production
    approach he had begun to use with the 
    <i>Pet Sounds</i>album, Wilson devoted months of effort to this
    single track.</p>
      <p>The instrumental of the first version of the song was
    recorded on February 17, 1966. It was described in the session
    log as 
    <i>#1 Untitled</i>(or as 
    <i>Good, Good, Good Vibrations</i>), though on the tape Brian
    Wilson distinctly says "Good Vibrations, Take One". After 26
    takes, a rough mono mix completed the session. Rough guide
    vocals were recorded the following day. By February 25, Wilson
    had placed the recording on hold in order to devote attention
    to the 
    <i>Pet Sounds</i>album. The track was revisited on May 24,
    1966, and worked on until June 18, at which time he put it
    aside again until August 24. The various sections of the song
    were edited together in a sort of musical collage, similar to
    The Beatles' later "Strawberry Fields Forever" and "A Day in
    the Life" records, both inspired by the works of Brian Wilson
    (according to Paul McCartney).</p>
      <p>The distinctive high-pitched sliding electronic sound in the
    choruses and at the end of the track was created with an
    electro-theremin, played by Paul Tanner, and first used by
    Wilson on the track "I Just Wasn't Made for These Times".</p>
      <p>The production of the song is reported to have spanned
    seventeen recording sessions at four different recording
    studios, and used over 90 hours of magnetic recording tape,
    with an eventual budget of $50,000. According to Wilson, the
    electro-theremin work itself cost $15,000. Wilson is credited
    with developing the use of the recording studio as an
    instrument: He, the Beach Boys, and dozens of top studio
    musicians, including members of The Wrecking Crew, recorded and
    re-recorded seemingly unrelated musical and vocal sections for
    the song, then edited and mixed these sections into a 3:35
    track.</p>
      <p>The recording and production style used on the "Good
    Vibrations" single established Wilson's new method of
    operation: The recording and re-recording of specific sections
    of music, followed by rough mixes of the sections edited
    together, further recording as required, and the construction
    of the final mix from the component elements. This was the
    modular approach to recording that was next used on 
    <i>Smile</i>.</p>
      <p>David Leaf, author of the critically-acclaimed biography, 
    <i>The Beach Boys and The California Myth</i>, said of the
    song, "Nothing but perfection here. The Beach Boys' first
    million-selling #1 hit...was a major technical
    breakthrough...the record that showed that anything was
    possible in the studio."</p>
      <p>There has never been an official true stereo release of the
    final track, although bootlegs of this mix have been issued
    over the internet. It has been said that not enough stems exist
    to actually create a new stereo mix (This is because the vocal
    tracks are currently missing; Bruce Johnston has stated that he
    believes they were accidentally destroyed in 1967 during a
    cleaning of the Capitol Records tape vault). However, a stereo
    version of the instrumental backing track was issued in 2006 on
    the 40th "Good Vibrations" EP.</p>
      <p>Inspired by the success of the song and the positive
    reaction to 
    <i>Pet Sounds</i>, and wanting to top The Beatles'
    recently-released 
    <i>Revolver</i>album, Wilson and lyricist Van Dyke Parks
    embarked on the 
    <i>Smile</i>project, intended as an entire album using the
    writing and production techniques devised for "Good
    Vibrations." That album was never released as Wilson descended
    into depression, drug use, and paranoia; several tracks
    salvaged from those sessions were re-recorded in greatly
    simplified versions for the 
    <i>Smiley Smile</i>album instead, on which "Good Vibrations"
    made its first LP appearance.</p>
      <p>In 2004, a re-recorded version of was finally completed by
    Wilson, Parks, and Darian Sahanaja, with Wilson's touring band
    in place of the other Beach Boys and studio musicians. It was
    released in September of that year, to widespread critical
    acclaim. "Good Vibrations" was released as a single prior to
    the album, also featuring a live version of the song. In
    addition to incorporating most of the original Tony Asher
    lyrics, the Smile version also includes the "Hum-Be-Num"
    harmony section not included in the 1966 release.</p>
      <p>According to Badman, the single sold over 230,000 copies in
    the first four days of its release, and entered the 
    <i>Cash Box</i>chart at number six on October 22.</p>
      <p>Both the 
    <i>New Musical Express</i>and 
    <i>Melody Maker</i>gave positive reviews at the time of the
    single's release.</p>
      <p>Praise was not universal, however, and Pete Townshend of The
    Who was quoted at the time as saying "'Good Vibrations' was
    probably a good record but who's to know? You had to play it
    about 90 bloody times to even hear what they were singing
    about", and feared that the single would lead to over-produced
    records in general.</p>
      <p>"Good Vibrations" earned The Beach Boys a Grammy nomination
    for Best Vocal Group performance in 1966 and the song was
    eventually inducted into the Grammy Hall of Fame in 1994. It
    has featured highly in many 'Top 100 Records of All Time'
    charts and was voted #1 in the Mojo Top 100 Records of All Time
    chart in 1997. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine ranked "Good Vibrations" as the
    sixth best song of all time. The song was also voted #24 in the
    RIAA and NEA's listing of Songs of the Century. "Good
    Vibrations" is currently ranked as the #3 song of all time in
    an aggregation of critics' lists at acclaimedmusic.net.</p>
      <p>In celebration of its 40th year, the 
    <i>Good Vibrations: 40th Anniversary Edition</i>single was
    released. The single includes five versions of "Good
    Vibrations" including:</p>
      <p>Except as indicated, all tracks are in mono.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
