<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turn!_Turn!_Turn!_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turn!_Turn!_Turn!_(song)</songId>
   <title>Turn! Turn! Turn! (To Everything There Is a Season)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Byrds</artistId>
      <artistName>The Byrds</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1965-12-04</week>
      <week>1965-12-11</week>
      <week>1965-12-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/78/TheByrdsTurnTurnTurn.jpg/200px-TheByrdsTurnTurnTurn.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Byrds+Turn-Turn-Turn-To-Everything-There-Is-a-Season.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Turn! Turn! Turn!</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 29, 1965</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" Single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>September 1, September 10, September 14 – September 16, 1965, Columbia Studios, Hollywood, CA</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Folk Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:49</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Book of Ecclesiastes</writer>
      <writer>Pete Seeger</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Terry Melcher</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Turn! Turn! Turn! (to Everything There is a Season)", often
    abbreviated to "Turn! Turn! Turn!", is a song adapted entirely
    from the Book of Ecclesiastes in the Bible (with the exception
    of the last line) and put to music by Pete Seeger in 1959.
    Seeger waited until 1962 to record it, releasing the song on
    his 
    <i>The Bitter and The Sweet</i>album on Columbia Records. 45%
    of the royalties for the song are donated to the Israeli
    Committee Against House Demolitions, due, in Seeger's own
    words, to the fact that "[in addition to the music] I did write
    six words."</p>
      <p>The lyrics are taken almost verbatim from the book of
    Ecclesiastes, as found in the King James Version (1611) of the
    Bible(Ecclesiastes 3:1), though the sequence of the words was
    rearranged for the song. Ecclesiastes is traditionally ascribed
    to King Solomon and for a time, the book was prohibited by the
    rabbis, who deemed it too cynical and depressing.</p>
      <p>The Biblical text posits there being a time and place for
    all things: laughter and sorrow, healing and killing, war and
    peace, and so on. The lines are open to myriad interpretations,
    but as a song they are commonly performed as a plea for world
    peace, with an emphasis on the closing line: "a time for peace,
    I swear it's not too late." This line and the title phrase
    "Turn! Turn! Turn!" are the only parts of the lyric written by
    Seeger himself.</p>
      <p>The song is one of a few mainstream songs to set a large
    portion of scripture to music, other examples being The
    Melodians' "Rivers of Babylon", Sister Janet Mead's "The Lord's
    Prayer" and U2's "40".</p>
      <p>The song was published in illustrated book form by Simon
    &amp; Schuster in September 2003, with an accompanying CD which
    contained both Seeger &amp; The Byrds recordings of the song
    (ISBN 0689852355 &amp; ISBN 978-0689852350). Wendy Anderson
    Halperin created a set of detailed illustrations for each set
    of opposites which are reminiscent of mandalas. The book also
    includes the Ecclesiastes text from the King James version of
    the Bible.</p>
      <p>Handwritten lyrics to the song were among the documents
    donated to New York University by the Communist Party USA in
    March 2007.</p>
      <p>The song was first released by the folk group The Limeliters
    on their 1962 album 
    <i>Folk Matinee</i>, under the title "To Everything There Is a
    Season". The Limeliters' version predated the release of
    Seeger's own version by several months. One of The Limeliter's
    backing musicians at this time was Jim McGuinn (aka Roger
    McGuinn), who would later work with folk singer Judy Collins,
    rearranging the song for her 1963 album, 
    <i>Judy Collins 3</i>. Collins' recording of the song was
    retitled as "Turn! Turn! Turn! (To Everything There Is a
    Season)", a title that would be used intermittently by
    McGuinn's later band The Byrds, when they released a cover of
    the song in 1965.</p>
      <p>"Turn! Turn! Turn!" was the third single by the American
    folk rock band The Byrds and was released on October 1, 1965 by
    Columbia Records (
    <i>see</i>1965 in music). The song was also included on the
    band's second album, 
    <i>Turn! Turn! Turn!</i>, which was released on December 6,
    1965. The Byrds' single (b/w "She Don't Care About Time") is
    the most successful recorded version of the song, having
    reached #1 on the U.S. Hot 100 charts and #26 on the UK Singles
    Chart. The Byrds' version distinguishes the song as the #1 pop
    hit with the oldest lyrics, dating back to the Book of
    Ecclesiastes. Many biblical scholars believe Ecclesiastes 1:1
    implies King Solomon as the book's author; thus, if true,
    giving Solomon lyrical credit for a number one hit.</p>
      <p>The song had first been arranged by The Byrds' lead
    guitarist Jim McGuinn in a chamber-folk style during sessions
    for Judy Collins' 1963 album, 
    <i>Judy Collins 3</i>. The idea of reviving the song came to
    McGuinn during The Byrds' 1965 American tour when his future
    wife, Dolores, requested the tune on the Byrds' tour bus. The
    rendition that McGuinn dutifully played came out sounding not
    like a folk song but more like a rock/folk hybrid, perfectly in
    keeping with The Byrds' current status as pioneers of the folk
    rock genre. McGuinn explained "It was a standard folk song by
    that time, but I played it and it came out rock ‘n’ roll
    because that’s what I was programmed to do like a computer. I
    couldn’t do it as it was traditionally. It came out with that
    samba beat, and we thought it would make a good single."</p>
      <p>The master recording of the song reputedly took 78 takes,
    spread over five days of recording, to complete. The song's
    plea for peace and tolerance struck a nerve with the American
    record buying public as the Vietnam War continued to escalate.
    The single also solidified folk rock as a chart trend and, like
    the band's previous hits, continued The Byrds' successful mix
    of vocal harmony and jangly twelve-string Rickenbacker guitar
    playing. During 1965 and 1966, the band performed the song on
    the television programs 
    <i>Hollywood A Go-Go</i>, 
    <i>Shindig!</i>, 
    <i>The Ed Sullivan Show</i>, and 
    <i>Where the Action Is</i>, as well as in the concert film, 
    <i>The Big T.N.T. Show</i>. Additionally, the song would go on
    to become a staple of The Byrds' live concert repertoire, until
    their final disbandment in 1973. The song was also performed
    live by a reformed line-up of The Byrds featuring Roger
    McGuinn, David Crosby and Chris Hillman in January 1989. In
    addition to its appearance on the 
    <i>Turn! Turn! Turn!</i>album, the song also appears on several
    Byrds' compilations, including 
    <i>The Byrds' Greatest Hits</i>, 
    <i>History of The Byrds</i>, 
    <i>The Original Singles: 1965–1967, Volume 1</i>, 
    <i>The Byrds</i>, 
    <i>20 Essential Tracks from the Byrds Box Set (1965-1990)</i>, 
    <i>The Very Best of The Byrds</i>, 
    <i>The Essential Byrds</i>and 
    <i>There Is a Season</i>.</p>
      <p>Nearly three decades after the Byrds released the song as a
    single, the recording was featured prominently in the 1994
    movie 
    <i>Forrest Gump</i>. The song was also featured in Jim
    Sheridan's 2002 film, 
    <i>In America</i>, although it was not included on the official
    soundtrack. Following Joe Cocker's cover of "With a Little Help
    from My Friends", the song was the first to play on the first
    episode of the television series 
    <i>The Wonder Years</i>. It was also used in a 
    <i>Wonder Years</i>parody, during 
    <i>The Simpsons'</i>episode, "Three Men and a Comic Book".</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by a number of other artists:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
