<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hello,_Goodbye 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hello,_Goodbye</songId>
   <title>Hello, Goodbye</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1967-12-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>24 November 1967</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2 October – 2 November 1967 , Abbey Road</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:27</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Parlophone</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Hello, Goodbye" is a song written by Lennon/McCartney and
    first recorded by the English rock band The Beatles. The song
    was released as a single in November 1967, and topped the
    charts in both the United States and Britain.</p>
      <p>Though the songwriting credit is Lennon/McCartney, it was
    written solely by Paul McCartney.</p>
      <p>Alistair Taylor, who worked for the Beatles' manager, Brian
    Epstein, had asked McCartney how he wrote his songs, and
    McCartney took him into his dining room to give him a
    demonstration on his harmonium. He asked Taylor to shout the
    opposite of whatever he sang as he played the instrument—black
    and white, yes and no, stop and go, hello and goodbye. Taylor
    later said, "I wonder whether Paul really made up that song as
    he went along or whether it was running through his head
    already."</p>
      <p>Under the working title "Hello Hello", the Beatles recorded
    the backing track on 2 October 1967, and added vocals and a
    guitar overdub on the 19th. After further overdubs of bass
    guitar and viola, recording was completed on the 2nd November,
    and mixing on the 6th.</p>
      <p>The song features a coda which came spontaneously in the
    studio. Of this, McCartney said "I remember the end bit where
    there's the pause and it goes 'Heba, heba hello'. We had those
    words and we had this whole thing recorded but it didn't sound
    quite right, and I remember asking Geoff Emerick if we could
    really whack up the echo on the tom-toms. And we put this echo
    full up on the tom-toms and it just came alive."</p>
      <p>"Hello, Goodbye" was released as a single on 24 November
    1967. In the US, the song was also included on the 
    <i>Magical Mystery Tour</i>album released three days later, but
    the song was not made available in the UK on an album (or in
    stereo) until the release of the 1973 compilation album 
    <i>1967–1970</i>.</p>
      <p>With the release of the song, McCartney gave an explanation
    of its meaning in an interview with 
    <i>Disc</i>: "The answer to everything is simple. It's a song
    about everything and nothing. If you have black you have to
    have white. That's the amazing thing about life."</p>
      <p>Three promotional films were made for the song; directed by
    McCartney, they were filmed on the 10th November at the Saville
    Theatre in London. The films were not aired by the BBC due to
    the Musicians Union's strict rules on miming; with no such
    restriction in the US, one of the films was screened on The Ed
    Sullivan Show on the 26th November.</p>
      <p>In the US, Capitol Records omitted the comma in the song’s
    title in the packaging of the single (as did some of EMI’s
    partners in other countries), and also the 
    <i>Magical Mystery Tour</i>LP (which was subsequently adopted
    for the CD release of this album).</p>
      <p>"Hello, Goodbye" topped the charts in both the United States
    and Britain where it spent seven weeks at number one, and was
    the Christmas number one for 1967.</p>
      <p>The song’s coda plays over the end titles of the Beatles’
    1967 
    <i>Magical Mystery Tour</i>film.</p>
      <p>Air Canada in 1993 used a cover version in their ad
    campaign, while in 2006 another cover version of the song was
    used to advertise Telstra's Next G mobile phone network, and in
    2008, American retailer Target featured various renditions of
    the song as part of its "Hello Good Buy" campaign.</p>
      <p>The song is used as leader for a Dutch television program
    (the program is called also Hello, Goodbye) from the NCRV,
    where people are interviewed at the Amsterdam Airport Schiphol
    in the Netherlands who are waiting for family or friends to
    come home after a long period (Hello) or who have come to say
    goodbye to family or friends who will leave for a long
    time.</p>
      <p>It is a playable song in 
    <i>The Beatles: Rock Band</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was used in a commercial to welcome David Beckham
    to the Los Angeles Galaxy.</p>
      <p>The song has also been covered by Jump5 and the Jonas
    Brothers. It has been recorded by the cast of Glee in the
    episode "Hello".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
