<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Can%27t_Get_Next_to_You 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Can%27t_Get_Next_to_You</songId>
   <title>I Can't Get Next to You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Temptations</artistId>
      <artistName>The Temptations</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1969-10-18</week>
      <week>1969-10-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/7b/Tempts-cant-get-next-1969.jpg/200px-Tempts-cant-get-next-1969.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Temptations+I-Can-t-Get-Next-to-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Puzzle People</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>July 30, 1969</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Hitsville USA (Studio A); June 23, June 24, June 27, June 30, July 2, and July 3, 1969</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Psychedelic Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:51</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Gordy , G 7093</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Norman Whitfield</writer>
      <writer>Barrett Strong</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Norman Whitfield Platinum ( RIAA )</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Can't Get Next to You" is a 1969 number-one single
    recorded by The Temptations and produced by Norman Whitfield
    for the Gordy (Motown) label. The song was the number-one
    single on the Billboard Top Pop Singles chart for two weeks in
    1969, from October 11 to October 25, replacing "Sugar, Sugar"
    by The Archies and replaced by "Suspicious Minds" by Elvis
    Presley. The single was also a number-one hit on the Billboard
    Top R&amp;B Singles for five weeks,. from October 4 to November
    1, replacing "Oh, What a Night" by The Dells, and replaced by
    another Motown song, "Baby I'm For Real" by The Originals.</p>
      <p>The single was the second of the Temptations' four
    number-one hits on the United States pop charts, and was also
    one of the best-selling singles the group released.</p>
      <p>ABC, a song released in the following year by fellow Motown
    act The Jackson Five, uses the same bridge section, featuring
    identifiable use of the stated "ya!" as well as the
    percussion.</p>
      <p>Building on the foundation set by their previous
    "psychedelic soul" records from the 
    <i>Cloud Nine</i>album, "I Can't Get Next to You" is a marked
    departure from with the Temptations' David Ruffin-led hits.
    Although it is in essence a love song like those earlier Smokey
    Robinson-crafted singles, "I Can't Get Next to You's" backing
    track features a high tempo, and a focus on piano, electric
    guitar, and drums that gives the song the feel of a Sly &amp;
    the Family Stone recording.</p>
      <p>"I Can't Get Next to You" features all five Temptations
    trading verses about how having all the powers in the world
    means nothing if a man cannot impress the woman he loves—very
    similar to the lyrics of Ira Gershwin's 1935 standard "I Can't
    Get Started With You". Each member of the group sings a
    separate line of the song's verses; for example, the first
    verse begins:</p>
      <p>Each verse continues in this fashion, with Edwards or
    Kendricks delivering the pre-chorus and all five members
    singing the chorus of "I can't get next to you, babe/I can't
    get next to you." When performing the song live, the
    Temptations would perform the number with a stiff-legged dance
    routine that Kendricks devised from similar dance moves his
    children did around the house.</p>
      <p>The single opens with the sound of applause, similar to a
    lively party. Dennis Edwards then interrupts the proceedings
    ("Hold on, everybody, hold it, hold on...listen!"), and the
    song proper begins. After a bluesy piano solo from Earl Van
    Dyke, the rest of the Funk Brothers studio band joins in and
    the first verse begins. "I Can't Get Next to You's" intro was
    sampled for the album version of the next major Temptations
    hit, "Psychedelic Shack", one of the earliest uses of such a
    technique.</p>
      <p>"I Can't Get Next to You" was the second single from the
    1969 Temptations LP 
    <i>Puzzle People</i>, with "Running Away (Ain't Gonna Help
    You)", a slow ballad led by Paul Williams, as the b-side. The
    single was a number-one hit on both the Billboard Hot 100 chart
    and the Billboard Top R&amp;B Singles charts. The song has been
    frequently covered, with the most notable cover being a 1970
    version by Al Green, which strips the composition of its fast
    pace and multi-lead vocals, and instead renders it as a
    slow-burning plea for love. Green's cover, the title track of
    his 1971 LP 
    <i>Al Green Gets Next to You</i>, reached number sixty on the
    Billboard Pop Singles chart, and number eleven on the R&amp;B
    chart.</p>
      <p>It was also later covered by Annie Lennox on her 
    <i>Medusa</i>album.</p>
      <p>In 1971 the British group Savoy Brown included a much slower
    and bluesier version in their album 
    <i>Street Corner Talking</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2002, Toto covered the song on their album Through the
    Looking Glass.</p>
      <p>In 2006, San Francisco band Thee More Shallows covered the
    song on their EP Monkey vs. Shark.</p>
      <p>In 2008, Lil' Wayne sampled parts of the song for his song
    "I Can't Get Next to You" for his mixtape "Da Drought is Over
    5" altering the chorus of the song in similar fashion.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
