<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dominique 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dominique</songId>
   <title>Dominique</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Singing_Nun</artistId>
      <artistName>The Singing Nun</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1963-12-07</week>
      <week>1963-12-14</week>
      <week>1963-12-21</week>
      <week>1963-12-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Dominique" is a popular song in French by 
    <i>Soeur Sourire</i>(Sister Smile, born Jeanine Deckers), of
    Belgium, also known as The Singing Nun. It is about Saint
    Dominic, a Spanish-born priest and founder of the Dominican
    Order, from which she was a member (as Sister Luc-Gabrielle).
    The English version of the song was written by Noël Regney. In
    addition to French and English, Deckers recorded versions in
    Dutch, German, Hebrew and Japanese.</p>
      <p>"Dominique" reached the top ten in eleven countries in late
    1963 and early 1964, topping the hit lists in the United
    States, Canada and New Zealand. It reached the Top 5 in Norway,
    Denmark, Ireland, Australia and South Africa, with the song
    making it into the lower reaches of the Top 10 in the
    Netherlands, West Germany and the United Kingdom. The song
    reached and stayed at #1 on both the U.S. pop chart and "easy
    listening chart" (since renamed the Adult Contemporary chart)
    for four weeks in December of 1963. It was the second foreign
    language song to hit #1 on the Hot 100 in 1963, the other being
    "Sukiyaki" by Kyu Sakamoto. (Another one is "Volare (Nel blu di
    pinto di blu)" by Domenico Modugno in 1958). No other foreign
    language song reached the US Billboard charts until the Spanish
    language hit Eres tú hit the US charts in 1973.</p>
      <p>Jeanine Deckers never again reached the same success and
    continued to lead a colourful, but tragic life. She and her
    long-time friend, Annie Pescher, both committed suicide in
    1985, as a result of financial and tax problems stemming from
    the recording of the song.</p>
      <p>"Dominique" outsold Elvis during its stay on the Billboard
    Pop Charts in 1963.</p>
      <p>"Dominique" became a worldwide hit in 1963 and as of 2009 is
    still the only Belgian number one hit single in the American 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts. (Technotronic's "Pump Up The Jam"
    reached number two in 1989).</p>
      <p>It is remembered chiefly for its refrain, which went:</p>
      <p>In English:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
