<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light_My_Fire 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light_My_Fire</songId>
   <title>Light My Fire</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Doors</artistId>
      <artistName>The Doors</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1967-07-29</week>
      <week>1967-08-05</week>
      <week>1967-08-12</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/55/The_Doors_-_Light_My_Fire.jpg/200px-The_Doors_-_Light_My_Fire.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Doors+Light-My-Fire.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Doors</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 1967</released>
   <recorded>August 1966</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Psychedelic Rock</genre>
      <genre>Acid Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>7:05 (album version)</length>
      <length>4:40 (long radio version)</length>
      <length>2:52 (single version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Elektra</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>The Doors</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Paul A. Rothchild</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Light My Fire" is a song originally performed by The Doors
    which was recorded in August 1966 and released the first week
    of January, 1967. It spent three weeks at #1 on the Billboard's
    Hot 100, and one week on the Cashbox Top 100. It was
    re-released in 1968, peaking at #87. The song was largely
    written by Robby Krieger, and credited to the entire band. A
    live version was released in 1983 on their album 
    <i>Alive, She Cried</i>, the first of several live or
    compilation albums released in subsequent decades to include
    the song.</p>
      <p>"Light My Fire" also achieved modest success in Australia,
    where it peaked at #22 on the ARIA chart. The single originally
    reached #49 in the UK in 1967, but experienced belated success
    in that country in 1991 when a re-issue peaked at #7. The
    re-issue occurred on the back of revived interest in the band
    following Oliver Stone's film biopic "The Doors". The single
    has been certified in 1967 a gold by the Recording Industry
    Association of America.</p>
      <p>The song is #35 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time. It was also included in the Songs of the Century list and
    was ranked number 7 in VH1's 100 Greatest Songs of All Time
    list.</p>
      <p>José Feliciano's cover version won a 1969 Grammy Award for
    Best Male Pop Vocal Performance, the same year he won another
    Grammy for Best New Artist.</p>
      <p>The song originated as a Robby Krieger unfinished
    composition, which the other band members then expanded upon.
    There was also a radio edit that was shortened to just under
    three minutes with nearly all the instrumental break removed.
    The single was released only to AM radio stations.</p>
      <p>When the song, which is 7 minutes and 5 seconds on the
    album, was released as a 2-minute 52-second single, the band
    appeared on various TV shows, such as American Bandstand,
    miming to a playback of the single. However, "Light My Fire"
    was performed live by The Doors on 
    <i>The Ed Sullivan Show</i>broadcast on September 17, 1967. The
    Doors were asked by producer Bob Precht, Sullivan's son-in-law,
    to change the line "girl, we couldn't get much higher", as the
    sponsors were uncomfortable with the possible reference to
    drug-taking. The band agreed to do so, and did a rehearsal
    using the amended lyrics; however, during the live performance,
    Morrison sang the original lyric. Ed Sullivan didn't shake
    Morrison's hand as he left the stage. The band had been
    negotiating a seven-episode deal with the producers; however,
    after breaking the agreement not to perform the line, they were
    informed they would never be on the Sullivan show again.</p>
      <p>John Densmore recalls that Buick offered $75,000 in October,
    1968 to adapt the song for use in a Buick Opel TV commercial
    ("Come on, Buick, light my fire".) Morrison, however, was still
    in London after a European tour had just ended on September 20
    and could not be reached by the other group members who agreed
    to the deal in his absence. As the band had agreed in 1965 to
    both equal splits and everyone having veto power in decisions,
    Morrison consequently called Buick and threatened to smash an
    Opel with a sledgehammer on television should the (presumably
    ready) commercial be aired. Various sources claim that this was
    a turning point in the band's career and Jim started losing
    faith in the other members for selling out just for quick
    cash.</p>
      <p>The song's chord progression, based on John Coltrane's
    version of My Favorite Things, and catchy rhythm (particularly
    Ray Manzarek's swirling, barrel organ-style keyboard motif)
    lent itself readily to pop or MOR styled cover versions.</p>
      <p>Cover versions were recorded by Astrud Gilberto, Will Young
    (whose version hit number one in the United Kingdom), Amii
    Stewart (whose version got to number 5 in the United Kingdom,
    in 1979, and to number 7 as a remix in 1985) Natalia Oreiro,
    Jose Feliciano (whose version won a Grammy in 1969 Best Pop
    song of the year), Nancy Sinatra, Julie London, Friedrich
    Gulda, Julie Driscoll &amp; the Brian Auger Trinity, Shirley
    Bassey, Erma Franklin, Baccara, Cibo Matto, Africa, Divididos,
    UB40, Massive Attack, The Mike Flowers Pops, the LN
    Elektronische Ensemble. Amorphis, Hide, Minnie Riperton, Stevie
    Wonder, Lil' Brown who was eventually sampled by J Dilla, Tammi
    Lynn, Type O Negative, Al Green, Electric Screwdrivers, B.J.
    Thomas, Ananda Shankar, Trini Lopez, John Tartaglia, Zacharias
    and Train, whose version can be found on the tribute
    compilation 
    <i>Stoned Immaculate: The Music of The Doors</i>. The
    Challengers did an instrumental version in 1969, as title track
    to one of their last albums.</p>
      <p>NB The Massive Attack cover actually sampled a combination
    of the Young-Holt Unlimited cover of “Light My Fire” (1969) and
    the Jackie Wilson cover version of Light My Fire from his Do
    Your Ting Album.</p>
      <p>Vocalist and guitarist José Feliciano experienced
    significant international success when he released his version
    of "Light My Fire" in 1968 as a single on the RCA Victor label.
    It is perhaps the best known cover of this song, reaching #3 on
    the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 charts, only a year after the
    original had been a #1 hit on the same chart. Feliciano's
    remake blended Latin influences, including a mixture of classic
    Spanish guitar and flamenco, with American pop sounds and
    Feliciano saying "Light my fire light my fire light my fire"
    over and over again. The single helped to spur the worldwide
    success of its album, 
    <i>Feliciano!</i>, which was nominated for multiple Grammy
    awards in 1969. Feliciano's arrangement of "Light My Fire" has
    influenced several subsequent versions, including that by Will
    Young and same writer Robby Krieger says in an interview about
    the cover: "It's really a great feeling to have written a
    classic. I think I owe a big debt to Jose Feliciano because he
    is actually the one, when he did it, everybody started doing
    it. He did a whole different arrangement on it."</p>
      <p>
         <i>Pop Idol</i>UK series 1 winner Will Young covered the song
    in 2002. Young originally performed a piano version the song in
    the final 50 of 
    <i>Pop Idol</i>, and again, with a backing track, in the final
    10. It was later released as his second single. It went
    straight to the number one spot in the UK Singles Chart,
    selling 177,000 copies in its first week of release. The single
    stayed at number one for two weeks. The cover version was
    recorded in the style of José Feliciano's version.</p>
      <p>Young also performed the song on 
    <i>World Idol</i>, where he came in fifth place.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
