<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Centerfold_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Centerfold_(song)</songId>
   <title>Centerfold</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_J._Geils_Band</artistId>
      <artistName>The J. Geils Band</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1982-02-06</week>
      <week>1982-02-13</week>
      <week>1982-02-20</week>
      <week>1982-02-27</week>
      <week>1982-03-06</week>
      <week>1982-03-13</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/d0/Centerfold.jpg/200px-Centerfold.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-J-Geils-Band+Centerfold.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Freeze Frame</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 25, 1981</released>
   <recorded>1981</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:36</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>EMI</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Seth Justman</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Seth Justman</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Centerfold" was a single released by The J. Geils Band from
    their album 
    <i>Freeze Frame</i>. The song is about a man who is shocked to
    discover that his high school crush appeared in a centerfold
    spread for a male-oriented magazine. The song could be a
    reference to actress Angel Tompkins' relationship with Peter
    Wolf.</p>
      <p>It was released in autumn 1981, and eventually went to
    number one on the US Hot 100 in February 1982, and stayed there
    for six weeks. It was the first single released from the album 
    <i>Freeze Frame</i>and was an early staple on MTV. The band's
    lead singer Peter Wolf revealed on 
    <i>In the Studio with Redbeard</i>that "Angel in Blue" was
    going to be the album's first single. Then during the "Angel in
    Blue" video shoot, Peter got a call from the president of EMI
    America Records suggesting that the band change the single's
    title to "Centerfold".</p>
      <p>In February 1983, a year after the song hit #1 in the US,
    "Centerfold" peaked at #3 in the UK Top 40, earning The J.
    Geils Band their only major hit single in the UK, although
    follow-up "Freeze-Frame" was also a minor UK hit.</p>
      <p>The song lists at #52 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top Songs.</i>[1]</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by organist Seth Justman's
    brother. The "school" where the video was shot had a girls'
    dance school on the floor above; the girls from the school were
    the ones appearing in the video.</p>
      <p>The music video starts out with Peter Wolf going to the
    classroom and looking through a magazine which he mentions his
    girlfriend is in. Some girls then start dancing in a line
    wearing slips. Afterwards, more girls appear in the whole
    classroom in negligees dancing, smiling, and playing patty
    cake. Wolf then hands a couple of uniforms to two of the girls.
    Later on, the girls appear in cheerleading sweatshirts
    resembling a 1980s style dress. After Wolf is knocked out by
    the girls with books, a party begins with the cheerleaders. The
    video ends with Wolf running out of the school in the company
    of four girls doing cartwheels.</p>
      <p>For a long time it was believed that MTV VJ Martha Quinn
    appeared in the video, but this turned out to be a case of
    mistaken identity: one of the dancers merely bore a striking
    resemblance to Quinn.</p>
      <p>Estonian short-lived new wave project Totu Kuul (featuring
    future film director Hardi Volmer) covered this song in 1983
    under the title "Kelleks saada?" ("To Become Who?"). Estonian
    text talked about pains of young people choosing occupation and
    ironized about powerful bureaucracy ("This is power when the
    heart is full of papers").</p>
      <p>The song was covered by German speed/thrash metal band
    Tankard on 1993's 
    <i>Stone Cold Sober</i>.</p>
      <p>Logorrheic indie rock band Nothing Painted Blue covered
    Centerfold on the bonus 7" that shipped with vinyl versions of
    their 1998 album The Monte Carlo Method.</p>
      <p>The ska-punk band Against All Authority covered the song
    which featured on a split 7" record with Less Than Jake as did
    Hayseed Dixie on their 2004 album 
    <i>Let There Be Rockgrass</i>.</p>
      <p>English Ska-punk Spunge also covered this song on their
    album, 
    <i>That Should Cover It!</i>, also released in 2004.</p>
      <p>German Europop group Captain Jack has also covered this
    song; "Centerfold (130BPM move it remix)" can be found on the
    game 
    <i>Dance Dance Revolution SuperNOVA</i>.</p>
      <p>A cover version by Adam Austin was a minor UK hit single in
    February 1999.</p>
      <p>The English rock group Status Quo covered this song on their
    2003 cover album 
    <i>Riffs</i>.</p>
      <p>Shwayze and Cisco Adler recorded a cover entitled "Angel Is
    a Centerfold".</p>
      <p>Music parodist Robert Lund released a Larry Craig-themed
    parody of this song, entitled "(My Men's Room Date's a)
    Senator", which was included on his CD 
    <i>Politicked Off</i>.</p>
      <p>Also the German Fun-Metal Band J.B.O. made a cover of this
    song, but their version is translated to German. The Song is
    called "Mei Alde is im Playboy drin", which means "My wife is
    in Playboy".</p>
      <p>"Centerfold" was played in 
    <i>The Office</i>episode "Customer Survey." Dwight Schrute,
    focused on the fact that there is a conspiracy as to how badly
    he and Jim Halpert did on their reports, plays it blatantly
    loud on his car stereo. Pam Beesly, who is secretly tucked away
    in Jim's ear via Bluetooth begins humming it afterward.
    "Centerfold" is also one of the songs featured in the musical 
    <i>Back to the 80's</i>.</p>
      <p>"Centerfold" was briefly used in an episode of My Name is
    Earl, Jump for joy</p>
      <p>"Centerfold" also appeared in a "King of Queens"
    episode.</p>
      <p>Danced by Jonathan Roberts, Macy Gray, Melissa Joan Hart,
    Mark Ballas, Louis Van Amstel, Kelly Osbourne, and Mya and
    Dmitry Chaplin on Dancing with the Stars season 9 for a Cha Cha
    Relay.</p>
      <p>"Centerfold" was sung by Mr. Steven Crocker about Miss
    Sheena Brannigan in the musical Back to the 80s.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
