<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frankenstein_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frankenstein_(song)</songId>
   <title>Frankenstein</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edgar_Winter</artistId>
      <artistName>The Edgar Winter Group</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1973-05-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>They Only Come Out at Night</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1973</released>
   <recorded>1972</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Hard Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:44 (Album Version - Original Edit); 3:28 (Single Version - Further Edited)</length>
   </lengths>
   <descr>
      <p>"Frankenstein" is a rock instrumental by The Edgar Winter
    Group from their album 
    <i>They Only Come Out At Night</i>. In live performances of the
    song, Edgar Winter further pioneered the advancement of the
    synthesizer as a lead instrument by becoming the first person
    ever to strap a keyboard instrument around his neck, giving him
    the on-stage mobility and audience interaction of guitar
    players. The song topped the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 chart for a
    week starting in May 1973, and sold over one million copies. It
    was knocked from the #1 spot by Paul McCartney's "My Love". 
    <i>Frankenstein</i>reached #18 in the UK the following
    month.,</p>
      <p>The song's title, coined by the band's drummer Chuck Ruff,
    derives from the fact that the original recording of the song
    was much longer than the final version, as the band would often
    deviate from the arrangement into less structured jams. The
    track required numerous edits to shorten it. The end result was
    pieced together from many different sections of recording tape
    using a razor blade and splicing tape. Winter frequently refers
    to the appropriateness of the name also in relation to its
    "monster-like, lumbering beat". (One riff was first used by
    Winter in the song "Hung Up", on his jazz-oriented first album 
    <i>Entrance</i>. He later tried a variation on it, "Martians"
    on the 
    <i>Standing on Rock</i>album.) Winter played many of the
    instruments on the track, including keyboards, saxophone and
    timbales. As the release's only instrumental cut, the song was
    not initially intended to be on the album, and was only
    included on a whim as a last-minute addition. It was originally
    released as the B-side to "Hangin' Around", but the two were
    soon reversed by the label when disc jockeys nationwide were
    inundated with phone calls and realized this was the hit. The
    song features a "double" drum solo, with Ruff on drums and
    Winter on percussion. In fact, the working title of the song
    was "The Double Drum Solo".</p>
      <p>The song was actually performed three years previously when
    Edgar was playing with his older brother Johnny Winter at the
    Royal Albert Hall in 1970. This rare recording was recently
    released as one of several live bonus tracks included in the
    two disc Deluxe Edition CD of Johnny Winter's 
    <i>Second Winter</i>.</p>
      <p>The song "Hocus Pocus" by Focus is often mislabeled as this
    song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
