<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Dooley_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Dooley_(song)</songId>
   <title>Tom Dooley</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Kingston_Trio</artistId>
      <artistName>The Kingston Trio</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1958-11-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Tom Dooley" is an old North Carolina folk song based on the
    1866 murder of a woman named Laura Foster in Wilkes County,
    North Carolina. It is best known today because of a hit version
    recorded in 1958 by The Kingston Trio. This version was a
    multi-format hit, reaching #1 in Billboard, the Billboard
    R&amp;B listing, and appearing in the Cashbox country music top
    20.</p>
      <p>It was selected as one of the Songs of the Century by the
    Recording Industry Association of America (RIAA), the National
    Endowment for the Arts, and Scholastic Inc.</p>
      <p>In the documentary 
    <i>Appalachian Journey</i>(1991), folklorist Alan Lomax
    describes Frank Proffitt as the "original source" for the song.
    Since the song predates Frank Proffitt's early version, it
    appears that Lomax means that Proffitt's version is the one
    that has become most well known to us because the Kingston Trio
    derived their interpretation from it. Certainly, there is at
    least one earlier known recording, by Grayson and Whitter made
    in 1929, approximately 10 years before Proffitt cut his own
    recording.</p>
      <p>Impoverished Confederate veteran Tom Dula (Dooley), Laura
    Foster's lover and probable fiancé, was convicted of her murder
    and hanged in 1868. Foster was stabbed to death with a large
    knife; the brutality of the attack partly accounted for the
    widespread publicity the murder and subsequent trial
    received.</p>
      <p>Dula had a second lover, Anne Melton. It was her comments
    that led to the discovery of Foster's body, but Melton was
    acquitted in a separate trial based on Dula's word. Dula's
    enigmatic statement on the gallows that he had not harmed
    Foster but still deserved his punishment led to press
    speculation that Melton was the actual killer and that Dula
    simply covered for her. Melton, who had once expressed jealousy
    of Dula's purported plans to marry Foster, died insane a few
    years after the homicide. Thanks to the efforts of newspapers
    such as 
    <i>The New York Times</i>, and to the fact that former North
    Carolina governor Zebulon Vance represented Dula 
    <i>pro bono</i>, Dula's murder trial and hanging were given
    widespread national publicity. A local poet, Thomas C. Land,
    wrote a popular song about Dula's tragedy after the
    hanging.</p>
      <p>A man named "Grayson," mentioned in the song as pivotal in
    Dula's downfall, has sometimes been characterized as a romantic
    rival of Dula's or a vengeful sheriff who captured him and
    presided over his hanging. Some variant lyrics of the song
    portray Grayson in that light, and the spoken introduction to
    the Kingston Trio version did the same. Col. James Grayson was
    actually a Tennessee politician who had hired Dula on his farm
    when the young man fled North Carolina under suspicion and was
    using a false name. Grayson did help North Carolinians capture
    Dula and was involved in returning him to North Carolina, but
    otherwise played no role in the case.</p>
      <p>Dula was tried in Statesville, because it was believed he
    could not get a fair trial in Wilkes County. He was given a new
    trial on appeal but he was again convicted, and hanged on May
    1, 1868. His alleged accomplice, Jack Keaton, was set free. On
    the gallows, Dula reportedly stated, "Gentlemen, do you see
    this hand? I didn't harm a hair on the girl's head."</p>
      <p>Dula's last name was pronounced "Dooley," leading to some
    confusion in spelling over the years. (The pronunciation of a
    final "a" like "y" is an old feature in Appalachian speech, as
    in the term "Grand Ole Opry"). The confusion was probably
    compounded by the fact that Dr. Tom Dooley, an American
    physician known for international humanitarian work, was at the
    height of his fame in 1958, when the Kingston Trio version
    became a major hit.</p>
      <p>The doleful ballad was probably first sung shortly after the
    execution and is still commonly sung in North Carolina.</p>
      <p>Several notable recordings have been made:</p>
      <p>
         <i>Tom Dooley</i>prompted a number of parodies, either as part
    of other songs (Ella Fitzgerald drops an altered line from the
    song into a recording of 
    <i>Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer</i>) or as entire songs,
    including one called 
    <i>Hang Down Your Head Tom Dooley, Your Tie's Caught In Your
    Zipper</i>by the Incredible Bongo Band in 1972.</p>
      <p>The song and legend were parodied by a one-record novelty
    act called Waldo, Dudley and Dora on a 45 rpm 
    <i>Grayson Goofed</i>, issued as Awful Records release #PU-1.
    Verses sung to the Tom Dooley melody alternate with mini-skits,
    as "John" Grayson's public reputation erodes from "a fine man"
    to "a stoolie" (i.e., stool pigeon) to "a gink".</p>
      <p>The song was often parodied by the Smothers Brothers as 
    <i>Tom Crudely</i>.</p>
      <p>In Episode #705 of 
    <i>Mystery Science Theater 3000</i>, Crow T. Robot, motivated
    by one actor's resemblance to Thomas Dewey, sang a version
    beginning "Hang down your head, 
    <i>Tom Dewey</i>."</p>
      <p>In Ally McBeal (season 5 episode 18) Tom Dooley is the name
    of the episode in which John Cage sings a version of the song
    with his Mexican band.</p>
      <p>The Kingston Trio hit inspired a quickie feature film, 
    <i>The Legend of Tom Dooley</i>(1959), starring actor Michael
    Landon, with a cast including Richard Rust. The film was
    essentially a Western set just after the Civil War. Despite the
    title, it was not about any traditional Tom Dula legends or
    about the facts of the actual case, but was a fictional
    treatment obviously tailored to fit the lyrics of the song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
