<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wedding_Bell_Blues 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wedding_Bell_Blues</songId>
   <title>Wedding Bell Blues</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_5th_Dimension</artistId>
      <artistName>The 5th Dimension</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1969-11-08</week>
      <week>1969-11-15</week>
      <week>1969-11-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>The Age of Aquarius</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>Early October 1969</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Music</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:42</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Soul City Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Laura Nyro</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bones Howe</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Wedding Bell Blues" is a song written and recorded by Laura
    Nyro in 1966 that became a number one hit for The 5th Dimension
    in 1969 and subsequently a popular phrase in American culture.
    The song is written from the perspective of a woman whose
    boyfriend has not yet proposed to her, who wonders, "am I ever
    gonna see my wedding day?" The song carries dual themes of
    adoring love and frustrated lament.</p>
      <p>Nyro wrote "Wedding Bell Blues" at the age of 18 as in
    effect a "mini-suite," featuring several dramatic rhythmic
    changes — a trait Nyro expanded on future albums. It was to be
    recorded in 1966 for Verve Folkways label as part of what would
    become her 
    <i>More Than a New Discovery</i>album. However, producer Herb
    Bernstein did not allow Nyro to record this version, which led
    to Nyro more or less disowning the entire album.</p>
      <p>What was recorded was fairly similar in content and
    arrangement to the later, much more familiar 5th Dimension
    version, albeit with a somewhat more soulful vocal line. It was
    released as a single in September 1966 and remained on the
    Billboard Pop Singles "Bubbling Under" charts segment for
    several weeks, peaking at #103.</p>
      <p>The 5th Dimension had already found hits with Nyro's "Stoned
    Soul Picnic" and "Sweet Blindness" during 1968. When recording
    tracks for their upcoming album 
    <i>The Age of Aquarius</i>, producer Bones Howe suggested it
    would be amusing to record another Nyro song, this one about a
    woman trying to get someone named Bill to commit to marriage.
    As it happened, 5th Dimension singer Marilyn McCoo was engaged
    to another member, Billy Davis, Jr., though they had not set a
    wedding date. So the group recorded it, and in May 1969 the
    album was released. The first single ahead of the album,
    "Aquarius/Let the Sunshine In", was a tremendous hit, while
    success of the second single, "Workin' On a Groovy Thing", was
    much more moderate. Then a disc jockey in San Diego began
    playing "Wedding Bell Blues" off the album, Soul City Records
    saw its potential, and in October 1969 it was put out as a
    single.</p>
      <p>"Wedding Bell Blues" quickly soared to number one on the
    U.S. pop singles chart, spending three weeks there in November,
    1969. It also reached the top spot on the U.S. adult
    contemporary chart, made one of the group's somewhat rare
    appearances on the U.S. R&amp;B singles chart, was a Top Five
    hit in Canada, and placed in the Top 20 on the UK Singles Chart
    (and their only hit there save for the earlier "Aquarius/Let
    the Sunshine In").</p>
      <p>In 1969 television appearances, McCoo would explicitly sing
    parts of the song to Davis; Davis would respond with quizzical
    looks. (As it happens, they would indeed marry in 1969.) The
    rest of The 5th Dimension's early hits featured more unison
    singing than this, and McCoo's prominent vocal and stage role
    on "Wedding Bell Blues" may have led to her being more featured
    in the group's early 1970s productions.</p>
      <p>Lesley Gore recorded her own version of the song for Mercury
    Records; this version was released in September 1969, and
    failed to chart, overwhelmed by the attention given to The 5th
    Dimension's recording.</p>
      <p>The phrase "wedding bell blues" soon became cultural
    shorthand for anyone in doubt about the subject event or the
    state of being unmarried in general. As such many written or
    dramatic works have been named after the song title. These
    include:</p>
      <p>The song also features on 'Being There', a Series One
    episode of 
    <i>Ally McBeal</i>, during one of Ally's 'fantasy sequences' in
    the law firm office. The song is here sung by Vonda
    Shepard.</p>
      <p>The song was also used in a scene with an erotic dancing
    hologram in the 1993 television mini-series Wild Palms.</p>
      <p>The song was parodied in the second episode of the
    thirteenth season of 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>, The Parent Rap. Homer sings incorrect
    lyrics to the song over the radio, and the radio station deejay
    says that the song was "Weddings are Nice" by the 5th
    Dimension.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
