<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heartbreak_Hotel 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heartbreak_Hotel</songId>
   <title>Heartbreak Hotel "/ "I Was the One" Elvis Presley</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Poor_People_of_Paris</artistId>
      <artistName>"The Poor People of Paris" Les Baxter</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1956-04-21</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>January 27, 1956</released>
   <formats>
      <format>single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>January 10, 1956</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock And Roll</genre>
      <genre>Blues</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:08</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA Records , RCA 47-6420</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Mae Boren Axton</writer>
      <writer>Thomas Durden</writer>
      <writer>and Elvis Presley</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Steve Sholes</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Heartbreak Hotel" is a rock and roll song recorded and
    performed by Elvis Presley. Recorded in January 1956 in
    Nashville, the song was Presley's first single for RCA Records
    and introduced him to the American national music
    consciousness. It was released with the B-side "I Was the One"
    on January 27, 1956, becoming the first #1 pop record by
    Presley and the best selling single of 1956.</p>
      <p>Inspired by the suicide of a young man who left a note with
    the line, "I walk a lonely street", songwriters Tommy Durden,
    then a steel-guitarist in Smiling Jack Herring and his Swing
    Billies, and Mae Boren Axton, a teacher in Jacksonville,
    Florida, wrote 
    <i>Heartbreak Hotel</i>in thirty minutes in 1955. She was a
    publicist for Hank Snow whose manager, Colonel Tom Parker,
    would later also manage Presley.</p>
      <p>So sure that the song would be a hit, Axton presented it to
    Presley's then manager, Bob Neal, and insisted it would be his
    first million-seller. On November 10, 1955, upon hearing the
    demo for the first time, Presley agreed and promised to record
    the song. Axton offered Presley a third of the royalties if he
    made the song his first single release from his new label, RCA.
    Presley first performed the song in Swifton, Arkansas on
    December 9, 1955 and declared it his "first hit".</p>
      <p>The song was the second recorded by Presley at RCA Victor on
    January 10, 1956 during his debut session at 1525 McGavock
    Street in Nashville, at that time owned by the United Methodist
    Television, Radio and Film Commission . He arrived at the
    studio with the song ready to record without seeking approval
    from RCA and, although producer Steve Sholes was worried, he
    recorded the song taking it on faith that Presley knew what he
    was doing. Most others at RCA Victor believed that it was a
    mistake, especially after hearing that the finished recording
    sounded nothing like Presley's previous recordings at Sun
    Records. As well as being accompanied by his regular band of
    Scotty Moore, Bill Black, and D.J. Fontana, Presley was joined
    by established RCA musicians Chet Atkins on guitar, and Floyd
    Cramer on piano.</p>
      <p>Steve Sholes used a hallway at the studio to get a
    noticeably unusual echo for the single. Sholes was attempting
    to recapture the Sun Records sound, but he was unaware that Sam
    Phillips had used two tape recorders and a slight time delay to
    create the echo on previous Presley recordings. When Phillips
    first heard 
    <i>Heartbreak Hotel</i>, he remarked that it was a "morbid
    mess".</p>
      <p>The song is an example of simple verse form based on the
    eight-bar blues progression. In an interview, Durden conceded
    that he did not recognize the song after Presley had made the
    changes to it in the studio, including changes to the tempo,
    phrasing, lyrics, and overall sound. In subsequent recordings,
    these major changes to existing material became a normal
    proceedure for Presley who took over the role of producer
    (although Steve Sholes was still credited) justifying Presley
    regularly being added to the writing credits of his
    recordings.</p>
      <p>The single was released on January 27, 1956 with "I Was The
    One" as the B-side, a song that was also recorded during
    Presley's RCA debut sessions. Billboard described the single as
    "a strong blues item wrapped up in his usual powerful style and
    a great beat."</p>
      <p>Presley made his national television debut on January 28,
    appearing on the CBS television variety program, 
    <i>Stage Show</i>, starring Tommy and Jimmy Dorsey. However,
    despite the single having been released only a day before, CBS
    would not allow Presley to perform it on their show. Instead he
    performed Shake, Rattle and Roll mixed with 
    <i>Flip, Flop and Fly</i>, and 
    <i>I Got A Woman</i>. For his second appearance, on February 4,
    Presley was again told he would not be allowed to perform the
    single. For his third appearance a week later, after some
    strong pressure from Steve Sholes, CBS finally allowed Presley
    to perform "Heartbreak Hotel". This also coincided with the
    official release of "Heartbreak Hotel" as a single in its own
    right.</p>
      <p>Because the vocals on the original record featured such a
    heavy use of reverb, the song was immediately lampooned in
    radio humorist Stan Freberg's parody of the song, where the
    lead singer repeatedly asks for "more echo on [his] voice."
    When Presley recorded "Hound Dog" a few months later, he had
    completely taken over the role of producer, using what he
    learned at Sun Records (although Steve Sholes was still
    credited) and decided not to use echo.</p>
      <p>"Heartbreak Hotel" charted on March 3, 1956, entering the 
    <i>Pop</i>chart at #68 and the 
    <i>Country and Western</i>chart at number #9. In less than two
    months it had reached #1 on both charts; for eight weeks and
    seventeen weeks respectively. It also peaked at #5 on the R 'n'
    B chart.</p>
      <p>Touring, television appearances, and regular airplay helped
    make the single a million-seller by April, resulting in
    Presley's first Gold record which he was awarded in Nashville
    during the recording of his follow-up single, 
    <i>I Want You, I Need You, I Love You</i>, the same month. The
    song would eventually go on to be the biggest selling single of
    1956.</p>
      <p>In the UK, the single reached #2 on the Pop singles
    charts.</p>
      <p>"Heartbreak Hotel" became an instantly recognizable part of
    Presley's live set. He would perform it during most of his live
    shows between 1956 and 1977, and it was re-released in 1971 for
    the UK market where it charted at #10. In 1995, the song was
    inducted into the Grammy Hall of Fame, and was re-released in
    1996 to coincide with the fortieth anniversary of its
    recording.</p>
      <p>It was ranked #45 on Rolling Stone's list of the 500
    Greatest Songs of All Time in 2004, and in 2005, Uncut Magazine
    ranked the first performance of "Heartbreak Hotel" in 1956 by
    Presley as the second greatest and most important cultural
    event of the rock and roll era. In 2006, again to celebrate the
    anniversary of its recording, "Heartbreak Hotel" was
    re-released as a 3-track CD single that returned to #1 on the
    Billboard Hot Singles Sales Chart. , and in 2007 Serbian rock
    musician, journalist and writer Dejan Cukić wrote about
    "Heartbreak Hotel" as one of the forty-six songs that changed
    history of popular music, in his book 
    <i>45 obrtaja: Priče o pesmama</i>.</p>
      <p>There is now a real hotel named after the song located
    across the street from Presley's home, Graceland, in Memphis,
    Tennessee. It features 128 rooms and offers 24-hour Presley
    videos for its guests.</p>
      <p>A movie with the same title, based on a mythical incident
    involving the kidnapping of Presley, was released theatrically
    in 1988. It starred David Keith as Elvis Presley, and was
    directed by Chris Columbus.</p>
      <p>Willie Nelson and Leon Russell had a no. 1 cover version in
    1979 on the country charts. The song was Russell's only #1 hit
    on the charts.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
