<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Want_You_Back 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Want_You_Back</songId>
   <title>I Want You Back</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Jackson_5</artistId>
      <artistName>The Jackson 5</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1970-01-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Diana Ross Presents the Jackson 5</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 7, 1969 ( U.S. )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl record (7" 45 RPM)</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>May 1969 , The Sound Factory, West Hollywood</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:59</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Motown , M 1157</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>The Corporation</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>The Corporation</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Want You Back" is a 1969 number-one smash hit single
    recorded by The Jackson 5 for the Motown label. The song,
    backed with a cover of Smokey Robinson &amp; the Miracles'
    "Who's Lovin' You", was the only single from the first Jackson
    5 album, 
    <i>Diana Ross Presents the Jackson 5</i>. It went to number one
    on the soul singles chart for four weeks and held the
    number-one position on the Billboard Hot 100 singles chart for
    the week ending January 31, 1970.</p>
      <p>Originally considered for Gladys Knight &amp; the Pips and
    later for Diana Ross, as "I Wanna Be Free", "I Want You Back"
    explores the theme of a lover who decides that he was too hasty
    in dropping his partner. An unusual aspect about "I Want You
    Back" was that its main lead vocal was performed by a preteen,
    Michael Jackson.</p>
      <p>The single was a notable first in many respects: it was the
    first Jackson 5 single to be released on Motown the first of
    four Jackson 5 number-ones released in a row (the others being
    "ABC", "The Love You Save", and "I'll Be There"), and the first
    song written and produced by The Corporation, a team comprising
    Motown chief Berry Gordy, Freddie Perren, Alphonzo Mizell, and
    Deke Richards.</p>
      <p>"I Want You Back" was also the first Jackson 5 song recorded
    in Los Angeles, California; the quintet had previously been
    recording Bobby Taylor-produced covers, including "Who's Lovin'
    You", the B-side to "I Want You Back", at Hitsville U.S.A. in
    Detroit, Michigan.</p>
      <p>Although Gladys Knight and Bobby Taylor of the Vancouvers
    had been the ones to bring the Jackson brothers to Motown,
    Motown credited Ross with discovering them, not only to help
    promote the Jackson 5, but also to help ease Ross' transition
    into a solo career., a career begun soon after the Jackson 5
    became a success.</p>
      <p>The Jackson 5 performed "I Want You Back," along with Sly
    &amp; the Family Stone's "Sing a Simple Song," The Delfonics'
    "Can You Remember," and James Brown's "There Was a Time" during
    their first television appearance on 
    <i>The Hollywood Palace</i>in an episode hosted by Diana Ross
    &amp; the Supremes.</p>
      <p>It has sold 6 million copies worldwide. In 1999, "I Want You
    Back" was also inducted into the Grammy Hall of Fame.</p>
      <p>"I Want You Back" ranks number 120 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s list of the '500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time'. It also ranks ninth on 
    <i>Rolling Stone's</i>list of the '100 Greatest Pop Songs since
    1963'.</p>
      <p>In 2006, Pitchfork Media named it the second best song of
    the 1960s, adding that the chorus contains "possibly the best
    chord progression in pop music history." A June 2009 article by
    
    <i>The Daily Telegraph</i>called it "arguably the greatest pop
    record of all time".</p>
      <p>The song is featured in the Lego Rock Band video game.
    However, it sounds different than the original version as
    vocals from the other Jacksons are not heard.</p>
      <p>A "live" version by Graham Parker and The Rumour garnered
    mild success in 1979; its title is sometimes shown as "I Want
    You Back (Alive)". David Ruffin recorded a version with The
    Funk Brothers at Hitsville in Detroit with the familiar Motown
    sound. It was to be included on his unreleased LP "David".</p>
      <p>Canadian girl group West End Girls had a top-10 single in
    1991 with their cover.</p>
      <p>British girl group Cleopatra released their cover version,
    which reached number four in the UK official top 40 in
    1998.</p>
      <p>A progressive bluegrass version of "I Want You Back",
    featuring mandolin and guitar, was performed by American
    acoustic trio Nickel Creek on their "Farewell (For Now) Tour"
    in 2007.</p>
      <p>The song has been repeatedly sampled, with notable uses by
    Kris Kross ("Jump", 1992), Tamia ("Imagination, 1998), Jay-Z
    ("Izzo (H.O.V.A.)", &amp; the mash up "Izzo/In The End" with
    Linkin Park), 2001), and Lil Romeo ("My Baby", 2001). The song
    was interpolated by BLACKstreet and Mya featuring Ma$e and
    Blinky Blink for the remix of "Take Me There" from the 
    <i>Rugrats Movie</i>soundtrack. A lesser-known sample was the
    one used in "Fantastic" by will.i.am.</p>
      <p>The single was re-issued in the UK in 1988 as a remix by
    Pete Waterman's PWL label. They remixed the song to include a
    snippet of "ABC". The remix reached #8 in the UK.</p>
      <p>The Swedish singer Tove Naess covers the track on the album 
    <i>Remixed Records 22</i>, 1988.</p>
      <p>The Mexican cumbia band Los Super Reyes covers the track in
    Spanish with the title "Quédate Más (I Want You Back)" on their
    2007 debut album 
    <i>El Regreso De Los Reyes</i>.</p>
      <p>The band Discovery, featuring members of Ra Ra Riot and
    Vampire Weekend, cover the track on their 2009 debut album, 
    <i>LP</i>.</p>
      <p>The British singer Mika sang the song during on of his
    Europeans tours, and the song appears on the 
    <i>Live in Cartoon Motion</i>DVD.</p>
      <p>British singer-songwriter KT Tunstall performed the song on
    an edition of "Later... with Jools Holland" using her trademark
    loop pedal.</p>
      <p>Korean singer 박봄 (Park Bom) from 2NE1 sang "I Want You Back"
    on KBS's sketchbook as a solo.</p>
      <p>Guns N' Roses played a short version of the song in Tokyo,
    2009, on their Chinese Democracy World Tour.</p>
      <p>Richie Kotzen ex-member of the bands Poison and Mr. Big made
    a cover in the 2009 japanese version of his album Peace
    Sign.</p>
      <p>The John Butler Trio performed the song on the Triple J
    segment Like a Version in January 2010.</p>
      <p>Virginia-based powerpop/rock band The Bigger Lights made a
    cover of this song available on their MySpace on December 15,
    2009.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
