<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mr._Tambourine_Man 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mr._Tambourine_Man</songId>
   <title>Mr. Tambourine Man</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Byrds</artistId>
      <artistName>The Byrds</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1965-06-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Bringing It All Back Home</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 22, 1965 (album)</released>
   <recorded>January 15, 1965, Columbia Recording Studios, New York City</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Folk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:29</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Bob Dylan</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Tom Wilson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Bringing It All Back Home</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Mr. Tambourine Man" is a song written and performed by Bob
    Dylan and featured on his 1965 album 
    <i>Bringing It All Back Home</i>, produced by Tom Wilson (
    <i>see</i>1965 in music). The Byrds also recorded a version
    that was their first single on Columbia Records and the title
    track of their first album, and which reached #1 on both the
    Hot 100 chart and the UK Singles Chart. The Byrds had access to
    a recording of the song by Dylan and Ramblin' Jack Elliot, from
    when Dylan attempted to record it during the session for his 
    <i>Another Side of Bob Dylan</i>album, before it was released
    on 
    <i>Bringing It All Back Home</i>. As a result, The Byrds were
    able to release their own version just two weeks after Dylan's.
    The Byrds' recording of the song was influential in initiating
    the musical subgenre of folk rock, leading many contemporary
    bands to mimic its fusion of jangly guitars and intellectual
    lyrics in the wake of the single's success.</p>
      <p>The song has also been covered by many other artists,
    including Judy Collins, Odetta, Melanie, and William Shatner.
    The song's popularity led to Dylan recording it live many
    times, and it has been included in multiple Dylan and Byrds
    compilation albums. It has been translated into several
    languages, and has also been used in television shows and
    films, and referenced in several books.</p>
      <p>The song has a bright, expansive melody and has become
    famous in particular for its surrealistic imagery, influenced
    by artists as diverse as French poet Arthur Rimbaud and Italian
    filmmaker Federico Fellini. The lyrics call on the title
    character to play a song and the narrator will follow.
    Interpretations of the lyrics have included a paean to drugs
    such as LSD, a call to the singer's muse, a reflection of the
    audience's demands on the singer, and religious
    interpretations. Dylan sings the song in four verses, but only
    one of these was recorded by The Byrds. The song is one of just
    three that was included twice in 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time, since both The Byrds' version and Dylan's own version are
    included. Both versions also received Grammy Hall of Fame
    Awards.</p>
      <p>"Mr. Tambourine Man" was written in early 1964, about the
    same time as "Chimes of Freedom", which Dylan recorded later
    that spring for his last acoustic album, 
    <i>Another Side of Bob Dylan</i>. Dylan began writing "Mr.
    Tambourine Man" in February 1964, after partying in New Orleans
    during Mardi Gras while on a cross-country road trip with
    several friends, completing it sometime between mid-March and
    late April after returning to New York. Journalist Al Aronowitz
    claimed that Dylan completed the song at his home but folk
    singer Judy Collins (who later covered the song) has also
    claimed that Dylan completed the song at her home. Dylan
    premiered the song the following month during a visit to
    England in what is considered one of the landmark concerts of
    the 1960s, his solo May 17 appearance at London's Royal
    Festival Hall.</p>
      <p>Dylan first recorded "Mr. Tambourine Man" a few weeks later,
    on June 9, with Tom Wilson producing, during the 
    <i>Another Side of Bob Dylan</i>session. The take, recorded
    with Ramblin' Jack Elliott, was cut from the album because
    Dylan felt the song was special and their performance did not
    do it justice. More than six months passed before Dylan
    re-recorded the song, again with Tom Wilson in the producer's
    chair, during the final 
    <i>Bringing It All Back Home</i>session on January 15, 1965,
    the same day as "Gates of Eden", "It's Alright, Ma (I'm Only
    Bleeding)", and "It's All Over Now, Baby Blue" were recorded.
    It was long thought that the four songs were all recorded in
    one long take. However, in the biography 
    <i>Bob Dylan: Behind the Shades</i>, Clinton Heylin relates
    that the song required six attempts, possibly because of
    difficulties in working out the playoffs between Dylan's
    acoustic guitar and Bruce Langhorne's electric lead. The final
    take was selected for the album which was released on March 22,
    1965.</p>
      <p>The song has a bright, expansive melody, with Langhorne's
    electric guitar accompaniment, which provides a countermelody
    to the vocals, being the only instrument besides Dylan's
    acoustic guitar. Dylan plays a harmonica solo that evokes the
    narrator's internal daydream. Unusually, rather than beginning
    with the first verse, the song begins with an iteration of the
    chorus:</p>
      <p>The four verses expand on the narrator's situation using
    heavily embroidered imagery. Though weary, the narrator is
    unable to sleep and wants to hear Mr. Tambourine Man's song,
    believing that the song will fulfill his desire to be set
    free.</p>
      <p>There has always been speculation that the song is about
    drugs such as LSD or marijuana, particularly with lines such as
    "take me on a trip upon your magic swirling ship" and "the
    smoke rings of my mind." However, Dylan always denied the song
    is about drugs, and though he was using marijuana at the time
    the song was written, he was not introduced to LSD until a few
    months later. Other commentators have interpreted the song as a
    call to the singer's spirit or muse, or the singer's search for
    transcendence. The singer is praying to his muse for
    inspiration; ironically the song itself is evidence that the
    muse has already provided the sought-after inspiration. Mr.
    Tambourine Man has also been interpreted as a symbol for Jesus
    Christ and for the Pied Piper of Hamelin. The song may also
    reference gospel music, with Mr. Tambourine Man being the
    bringer of religious salvation.</p>
      <p>Dylan cited the influence of Federico Fellini's movie La
    strada on the song, while other commentators found echoes of
    the poetry of Arthur Rimbaud. The lyrics "in the jingle jangle
    morning I'll come following you" are taken from a Lord Buckley
    recording. In addition to providing the electric guitar
    accompaniment for the song, Dylan has said that Bruce Langhorne
    was the inspiration for the tambourine man image in the song.
    Langhorne used to play a giant, four-inch-deep Turkish
    tambourine, and had brought it to a previous Dylan recording
    session.</p>
      <p>"Mr. Tambourine Man" was included on 
    <i>Bob Dylan's Greatest Hits</i>in 1967 and several later Dylan
    compilation albums, including 
    <i>Biograph</i>, 
    <i>Masterpieces</i>, and 
    <i>The Essential Bob Dylan</i>. The song has always been a
    personal favorite of Dylan's, and he has said that "it's the
    only song I tried to write 'another one'", although he did not
    succeed.</p>
      <p>The song has been in Dylan's live concert repertoire ever
    since it was written. At Dylan's appearance at the Newport Folk
    Festival on July 25, 1965, after he was heckled by acoustic
    folk music fans during his electric set, Dylan returned to play
    acoustic versions of "Mr. Tambourine Man" and "It's All Over
    Now, Baby Blue". That performance of "Mr. Tambourine Man" is
    included in Murray Lerner's film 
    <i>The Other Side of the Mirror</i>., and in Martin Scorsese's
    documentary 
    <i>No Direction Home</i>. Dylan also played it as part of his
    evening set at the August 1, 1971, Concert for Bangladesh, a
    benefit concert organized by George Harrison and Ravi Shankar.
    That performance is included on 
    <i>The Concert for Bangladesh</i>album, although it was
    excluded from the film of the concert. A live version from
    Dylan's famous May 17, 1966, concert in Manchester, England
    (popularly but mistakenly known as the Royal Albert Hall
    Concert) is included on 
    <i>The Bootleg Series Vol. 4: Bob Dylan Live 1966, The "Royal
    Albert Hall" Concert</i>. Another live version from the Rolling
    Thunder Revue tour of 1975 is on 
    <i>The Bootleg Series Vol. 5: Bob Dylan Live 1975, The Rolling
    Thunder Revue</i>, and yet another live version from 1978 is on
    
    <i>Bob Dylan at Budokan</i>.</p>
      <p>Two 1964 recordings of the song by Dylan have been made
    available on compact disc. A live performance at New York's
    Philharmonic Hall dating from October 31, 1964, was released on
    
    <i>The Bootleg Series Vol. 6: Bob Dylan Live 1964, Concert at
    Philharmonic Hall</i>. A version recorded with Ramblin' Jack
    Elliott on backing vocals during sessions for 
    <i>Another Side of Bob Dylan</i>was included on 
    <i>The Bootleg Series Vol. 7: No Direction Home</i>.</p>
      <p>"Mr. Tambourine Man" was the debut single by the American
    folk rock band The Byrds, released on April 12, 1965 by
    Columbia Records. The song was included on the band's debut
    album, 
    <i>Mr. Tambourine Man</i>, released on June 21, 1965. The
    single, along with the album of the same name, was influential
    in originating the musical style known as folk rock, with the
    single becoming the first folk rock smash hit. Indeed, the term
    "folk rock" was first coined by the U.S music press to describe
    the band's sound at the same time as "Mr. Tambourine Man"
    peaked at #1 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>chart.</p>
      <p>The single initiated the folk rock explosion of 1965 and
    1966, with many acts imitating the band's hybrid of a rock
    beat, jangly guitar playing and poetic or socially conscious
    lyrics. This hybrid had its antecedents in the folk revival of
    the early 1960s, The Animals' recording of "The House of the
    Rising Sun", the folk-influenced songwriting of The Beau
    Brummels, and the twelve-string guitar jangle of The Searchers
    and The Beatles. However, it was The Byrds who first melded
    these disparate elements into a unified whole, creating the
    template for folk rock heard around the globe during the
    mid-1960s. Although Dylan's recording of "Mr. Tambourine Man"
    was not itself a direct influence on the genre, his recordings
    with an electric rock backing on the albums 
    <i>Bringing It All Back Home</i>and 
    <i>Highway 61 Revisited</i>certainly were.</p>
      <p>Most of the members of The Byrds had a background in folk
    music, since Jim McGuinn, Gene Clark, and David Crosby had all
    worked as folk singers during the early 1960s. They had also
    spent time, independently of each other, in various folk
    groups, including The New Christy Minstrels, The Limeliters,
    The Chad Mitchell Trio, and Les Baxter's Balladeers. In early
    1964, McGuinn, Clark and Crosby formed The Jet Set and started
    developing a fusion of folk-based lyrics and melodies with
    arrangements in the style of The Beatles. While the band
    rehearsed at World Pacific Studios, their manager Jim Dickson
    acquired an acetate disc of "Mr. Tambourine Man" from Dylan's
    publisher, featuring a performance by Dylan and Ramblin' Jack
    Elliott. Although the band were initially unimpressed with the
    song, they eventually agreed to begin rehearsing and demoing
    it. In an attempt to make it sound more like The Beatles, the
    band and Dickson elected to give the song a full, electric rock
    band treatment, effectively creating the musical subgenre of
    folk rock. To further bolster the group's confidence in the
    song, Dickson invited Dylan to hear the band's rendition at
    World Pacific. Dylan was impressed, enthusiastically commenting
    "Wow, You can dance to that!" and his endorsement erased any
    lingering doubts the band had about the song. During this
    period, drummer Michael Clarke and bass player Chris Hillman
    joined and the band changed their name to The Byrds over
    Thanksgiving 1964. The two surviving demos of "Mr. Tambourine
    Man" recorded at World Pacific feature an incongruous marching
    band drum part from Clarke but overall the arrangement, which
    utilized a 4/4 time signature instead of Dylan's 2/4
    configuration, is very close to the later single version.</p>
      <p>The master take of "Mr. Tambourine Man" was recorded on
    January 20, 1965, at Columbia Studios in Hollywood, prior to
    the release of Dylan's own version. The song's jangling,
    melodic guitar playing (played by McGuinn on a 12-string
    Rickenbacker guitar) was immediately influential and has
    remained so to the present day. The group's complex harmony
    work, as featured on "Mr. Tambourine Man", became another major
    characteristic of their sound. Due to producer Terry Melcher's
    initial lack of confidence in The Byrds' musicianship, McGuinn
    was the only Byrd to play on "Mr. Tambourine Man" and its
    B-side, "I Knew I'd Want You". Rather than using band members,
    Melcher hired The Wrecking Crew, a collection of top L.A.
    session musicians, who (with McGuinn on guitar) provided the
    backing track over which McGuinn, Crosby, and Clark sang. By
    the time the sessions for their debut album began in March
    1965, however, Melcher was satisfied that the band was
    competent enough to record its own musical backing.</p>
      <p>The Byrds' recording of the song opens with a distinctive,
    Bach-inspired guitar introduction played by McGuinn and then,
    like Dylan's version, goes into the song's chorus. Although
    Dylan's version contains four verses, The Byrds only perform
    the song's second verse, before repeating the chorus, followed
    by a variation on the song's introduction which then fades out.
    The Byrds' arrangement of the song had been shortened during
    rehearsals at World Pacific in 1964, at the suggestion of Jim
    Dickson, in order to accommodate commercial radio stations
    which did not want to play songs that were over two-and-a-half
    minutes long. Thus, while Dylan's version is five-and-a-half
    minutes long, The Byrds' runs just short of two-and-a-half
    minutes. The lead vocal on The Byrds' version of "Mr.
    Tambourine Man" was sung by McGuinn, who attempted to modify
    his singing style to fill what he perceived as a gap in the
    popular music scene of the day, somewhere between the vocal
    sound of John Lennon and Bob Dylan. The song also took on a
    spiritual aspect for McGuinn during the recording sessions, as
    he told The Byrds' biographer Johnny Rogan in 1997: "I was
    singing to God and I was saying that God was the Tambourine Man
    and I was saying to him, 'Hey, God, take me for a trip and I'll
    follow you.' It was a prayer of submission."</p>
      <p>The single reached #1 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100, and #1 on the UK Singles Chart. "Mr.
    Tambourine Man" thus became the first recording of a Dylan song
    to reach #1 on any pop music chart. In the wake of "Mr.
    Tambourine Man" the influence of The Byrds could be heard in
    many recordings released by American acts, including The
    Turtles, Simon &amp; Garfunkel, The Lovin' Spoonful, Barry
    McGuire, The Mamas &amp; the Papas, Jefferson Airplane, We
    Five, Love, and Sonny &amp; Cher. In addition, by late 1965 The
    Beatles themselves were assimilating the sound of folk rock,
    and in particular The Byrds, into the material found on their 
    <i>Rubber Soul</i>album, most notably on the songs "Nowhere
    Man" and "If I Needed Someone". As the 1960s came to a close,
    folk rock changed and evolved away from this jangly template
    but the influence of The Byrds could still be heard in the
    early 70's music of bands like Fairport Convention and
    Pentangle. The Byrds folk rock sound has continued to influence
    bands from the 1970s through to the present day, including Big
    Star, Tom Petty and the Heartbreakers, R.E.M., The Long Ryders,
    The Smiths, The Bangles, The Stone Roses, Teenage Fanclub, The
    Bluetones, and Delays.</p>
      <p>In addition to appearing on The Byrds' debut album, the song
    is included on several Byrds' compilation and live albums,
    including 
    <i>The Byrds Greatest Hits</i>, 
    <i>Live at Royal Albert Hall 1971</i>, 
    <i>The Original Singles: 1965–1967, Volume 1</i>, 
    <i>The Very Best of The Byrds</i>, 
    <i>The Essential Byrds</i>, 
    <i>The Byrds Play Dylan</i>, and the live disc of The Byrds' 
    <i>(Untitled)</i>album. The Byrds' version of the song also
    appears on compilation albums that include hit songs by
    multiple artists. Two earlier demo recordings of the song, from
    the World Pacific sessions, can be heard on The Byrds' archival
    albums 
    <i>Preflyte</i>, 
    <i>In the Beginning</i>, and 
    <i>The Preflyte Sessions</i>.</p>
      <p>"Mr. Tambourine Man" has been covered by many artists, and
    at least 13 times in 1965 alone, including versions by Odetta,
    Judy Collins, The Four Seasons, The Barbarians, and Chad and
    Jeremy. Other artists who have covered the song include The
    Beau Brummels (1966), The Lettermen (1966), Kenny Rankin
    (1967), Melanie (1969), Gene Clark (1984), Les Fradkin (2007),
    and Bob Sinclar (2009). William Shatner also covered the song
    in a spoken-word recitation on his 1968 album, 
    <i>The Transformed Man</i>. Indie bands, such as Cloud Cult,
    have also covered the song. A reunited line-up of The Byrds,
    featuring Roger McGuinn, Chris Hillman, and David Crosby,
    performed "Mr. Tambourine Man" with Dylan at a Roy Orbison
    tribute concert on February 24, 1990. This live performance of
    the song was included on the 1990 box set, 
    <i>The Byrds</i>. At the October 1992 Bob Dylan 30th
    anniversary tribute concert at Madison Square Garden, McGuinn
    performed the song, backed by Tom Petty, Mike Campbell, and
    Benmont Tench, among others.</p>
      <p>The song has been translated and recorded in several
    languages. Müslüm Gürses has covered the song with different
    lyrics written in Turkish. The Turkish version of the song was
    called 
    <i>Hayat Berbat</i>. It was translated into Romanian by Florian
    Pittiş, and sung by Pasărea Colibri on their 1995 album "În
    căutarea cuibului pierdut".</p>
      <p>The song has appeared in films and television shows. Former 
    <i>American Idol</i>contestant Jason Castro covered this song
    on the show in 2008, forgetting one line. He later mentioned in
    an interview that, "Someone told me I Shot the Tambourine Man";
    a reference to him also singing "I Shot the Sheriff" by Bob
    Marley that same week. The students in the movie 
    <i>Dangerous Minds</i>study the poetry of "Mr. Tambourine Man",
    and possible drug-related meanings are discussed.</p>
      <p>"Mr. Tambourine Man" has also been referenced in books. In
    Tom Wolfe's non-fiction novel 
    <i>The Electric Kool-Aid Acid Test</i>, "Mr. Tambourine Man" is
    referenced regarding Dylan's "raunching and rheuming." In
    Stephen King's book 
    <i>Carrie</i>, the song is mentioned as one of the songs to be
    sung as the entertainment portion of the famous prom scene
    alongside "500 Miles", "Cabaret", "Lemon Tree", "Raindrops Keep
    Fallin' on My Head", and "Bridge over Troubled Waters".</p>
      <p>The song has been played at funerals. Journalist Hunter S.
    Thompson requested the song be played at his funeral while his
    ashes were shot out of a cannon, and also dedicated his novel 
    <i>Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas</i>to Dylan because of the
    song. And Pete Townshend played this song at the funeral of
    Neil Aspinall, The Beatles' road manager and personal
    assistant.</p>
      <p>The Byrds' version of "Mr. Tambourine Man" was listed as the
    #79 song on 
    <i>Rolling Stone'</i>s list of the 500 Greatest Songs of All
    Time, and Dylan's version was ranked #106. It is one of three
    songs to place twice, along with "Walk This Way" by both
    Aerosmith and Run-DMC with Perry and Tyler, and "Blue Suede
    Shoes" by both Carl Perkins and Elvis Presley. The Byrds
    version was honored with a Grammy Hall of Fame Award in 1998,
    and Dylan's version was honored with the same award in
    2002.</p>
      <p>In 1989 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>listed The Byrds' version of "Mr.
    Tambourine Man" as the #86 single of the prior 25 years. That
    same year, music critic Dave Marsh listed it as #207 in his
    list of the top 1001 singles ever made. In 1999, National
    Public Radio in the United States listed this version as one of
    the 300 most important American records of the 20th century. In
    the UK, music critic Colin Larkin listed The Byrds' version as
    the #1 single of all time. Other UK publishers that have listed
    this song as one of the top songs or singles include 
    <i>Mojo</i>, 
    <i>New Musical Express</i>, and 
    <i>Sounds</i>. Australian music critic Toby Creswell included
    the song in his book 
    <i>1001 Songs: The Great Songs of All Time and the Artists,
    Stories and Secrets Behind Them</i>.</p>
      <p>In a 2005 reader's poll reported in 
    <i>Mojo</i>, Dylan's version of "Mr. Tambourine Man" was listed
    as the #4 all-time greatest Bob Dylan song, and a similar poll
    of artists ranked the song #14. In 2002, 
    <i>Uncut</i>listed it as the #15 all-time Dylan song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
