<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_You_Want_Me 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_You_Want_Me</songId>
   <title>Don't You Want Me</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Human_League</artistId>
      <artistName>The Human League</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1982-07-03</week>
      <week>1982-07-10</week>
      <week>1982-07-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e5/Humanleaguecoverdontyouwant.jpg/200px-Humanleaguecoverdontyouwant.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Human-League+Don-t-You-Want-Me.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Dare</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>27 November 1981</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1981</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>New Wave</genre>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>Synthpop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:52</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Virgin</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Philip Oakey</writer>
      <writer>Jo Callis</writer>
      <writer>Philip Adrian Wright</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Martin Rushent</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Don't You Want Me" is a single by British synthpop group
    The Human League, released from their third album 
    <i>Dare</i>on 27 November 1981. It is the band's best known and
    most commercially successful recording to date, topping the
    Billboard Hot 100 in the US, and was the Christmas number one
    in the UK where it sold over 1,400,000 copies, making it the
    25th most successful single in UK Singles Chart history. The
    song has been covered multiple times, most notoriously by
    Alcazar.</p>
      <p>The lyrics were originally inspired after lead singer Philip
    Oakey read a story in a "trashy tabloid". Originally conceived
    as a male solo, Oakey was inspired by the film 
    <i>A Star Is Born</i>and decided to turn the song into a
    conflicting duet with one of the band’s two teenage female
    vocalists. Susan Ann Sulley was asked to take on the role. Up
    until then, she and the other female vocalist Joanne Catherall
    had only been assigned backing vocals; Sulley says she was
    chosen only through luck of the draw. There are two more
    realistic explanations: that Sulley was the better singer
    and/or that Catherall, more introverted, shied away from the
    role. Musicians Jo Callis and Philip Adrian Wright created a
    synthesizer score to accompany the lyrics which was much
    harsher than the version that was actually released. Initial
    versions of the song were recorded but Virgin Records-appointed
    producer Martin Rushent was unhappy with them. He and Callis
    remixed the track, giving it a softer, and in Oakey's opinion,
    "poppy" sound. Oakey hated the new version and thought it the
    weakest track on 
    <i>Dare</i>, resulting in one of his infamous rows with
    Rushent. Oakey disliked it so much that it was relegated to the
    last track on the album.</p>
      <p>Before the release of 
    <i>Dare</i>, two of its tracks—"The Sound of the Crowd" and
    "Love Action (I Believe in Love)"—had already been issued as
    successful singles. To promote the new album, Virgin released
    "Open Your Heart" in October 1981, which hit #6 in the UK
    Singles Chart. With a hit album and three hit singles in a row,
    Virgin's Simon Draper decided to issue one more single from the
    album before the end of 1981. His choice, "Don't You Want Me",
    instantly caused a row with Oakey who did not want another
    single released because he was convinced that "
    <i>the public were now sick of hearing The Human League</i>"
    and the choice of the "
    <i>poor quality filler track</i>" would almost certainly be a
    disaster, wrecking the group's new found popularity. Virgin
    were adamant that a fourth single would be released and Oakey
    finally agreed on the condition that a large colour poster
    accompany the 7" single, because he felt fans would "feel
    ripped off" by the 'substandard' single alone.</p>
      <p>"Don't You Want Me" was released in the UK on 27 November
    1981. To the amazement of the band (and especially Oakey), it
    shot to number one on the UK charts. This success was repeated
    six months later in the U.S., with "Don't You Want Me" hitting
    #1 on the Billboard Hot 100 for three weeks. Billboard magazine
    ranked it as the sixth-biggest hit of 1982.</p>
      <p>The Human League often added cryptic references to their
    productions and the record sleeve of “Don’t You Want Me”
    featured the suffix of “100”. This was a reference to a
    restaurant/bar in Sheffield.</p>
      <p>Today, the song is widely considered a classic of its era.
    Oakey still describes it as overrated but acknowledges his
    initial dismissal was misguided and claims pride in the track.
    Susan Sulley is often irritated that she constantly has to
    refute the mistaken assumption that the song is a reference to
    her and Catherall. At only 17 years old when the song was
    recorded, she was legally too young by UK law to have been a
    cocktail waitress and was, in fact, still at school. Oakey is
    also at pains to point out another misconception that it is not
    a love song but "a nasty song about sexual power politics".</p>
      <p>The song was remixed and re-released in 1995, peaking at #16
    on the UK chart.</p>
      <p>In 1981 record company Virgin were becoming aware that
    promotional music video was evolving into an important
    marketing tool, with MTV being launched that year. Because it
    was agreed that the video for Open Your Heart had looked "cheap
    and nasty", Virgin commissioned a much more elaborate and
    expensive promotional video for "Don't You Want Me".</p>
      <p>The video for the song was filmed in Slough in November 1981
    and has the theme of the filming and editing of a
    murder-mystery film, featuring the band members as characters
    and production staff. Due to it being a "making of" video, both
    crew and camera apparatus appear throughout. It was conceived
    and directed by filmmaker Steve Barron, and has at its core the
    interaction between a successful actress played by Susan Ann
    Sulley walking out on 'film director' Philip Oakey on a film
    set. It is loosely based on the film 
    <i>A Star Is Born</i>.</p>
      <p>Filmed on a cold, wet, winter night, it was shot on 35mm
    film instead of the cheaper video tape prevalent at the time.
    Susan Sulley states now that Steve Baron was heavily influenced
    by the cinematography of the video for the Ultravox single
    "Vienna". Steve Baron was also influenced by François Truffaut
    and his film Day for Night and because of that the clapper
    board seen in the video bears the inscription "Le League
    Humaine" as a tribute to Truffaut.</p>
      <p>The video is credited for making Oakey, Sulley and Catherall
    visual icons of the early 1980s; but became controversial later
    for a scene where Oakey shoots Sulley with a pistol from a car
    window (a Saab 99 turbo). The scene is often edited out of the
    DVD version and on music television. The other car that was
    used in the video is a gold W-Reg Rover SD1.</p>
      <p>The video was released in December 1981, just as the music
    video culture was becoming a standard in music, and it was a
    major contribution to the song's commercial success.</p>
      <p>The Human League as a matter of principle do not permit the
    use of their music in commercials. However Virgin Records own
    the rights to the material recorded when the band were signed
    to them 1978-1990, and the lack of consent from the band has
    not been enough to prevent the use of re-recorded versions of
    this song in commercials.</p>
      <p>Don't You Want Me Baby is a Pop song written by Philip
    Oakey, Jo Callis and Philip Adrian Wright. In 1989 Mandy Smith
    covered this song. The song was released after her album 
    <i>Mandy</i>(1988). It was also Smith's final single. This song
    has a B-side, "If It Makes You Feel Good", which appeared on
    Smith's debut album.</p>
      <p>CD Single</p>
      <p>7" Single</p>
      <p>12" Single</p>
      <p>Don't You Want Me is a eurodance song performed by Swedish
    band Alcazar and released internationally in 2002. The song was
    included to the European version of "Casino" together with a
    few other, and was recorded in Stockholm at first, but when
    they wanted it for a new pan-European single, a whole new
    version was made.</p>
      <p>Alcazar went to England to record new vocals with the famous
    Almighty team. Almighty has become famous because of excellent
    remixes made for the European dancefloors. They ended up with a
    new version of "Don't You Want Me" with an even more modern
    beat than the album version, and everybody was extremely happy
    with the result.</p>
      <p>The single was released in Australia as a follow up to the
    megahit single "Crying at the Discoteque" and the release
    includes the "Ivan's X Mix" of CATD as a bonus. The white
    12 inch was released in Europe and distributed to DJs to
    get maximum airplay at the disco arenas.</p>
      <p>So far Don't You Want Me is the biggest hit for the group in
    United States, climbing # 30 in the Billboard Hot-100 Singles
    staying in the charts for respective 15 Weeks. It Also became
    huge favorite in the Clubs and US Radio Stations.</p>
      <p>The Human League themselves have said that they like this
    version, as it is fairly true to the original; and Alcazar
    still performs this track at their live shows around the
    world.</p>
      <p>The song is playable on the Karaoke Revolution games.</p>
      <p>The video was filmed at Filmhuset in Stockholm, and once
    again Jesper Ganslandt directed it all. As always in Alcazar
    videos the storyline takes place in "Alcazar world" - and this
    time it all took place in "Circus Alcazar". The video is filled
    with horses, ducks, an evil parrot, acrobats and the Alcazar
    ballet.</p>
      <p>The cover to the single was shot during a break in the video
    shoots, so there you can see what the group looked like. The
    clothes were especially designed by the Swedish designer Lars
    Wallin. He managed to clash a lot of humour, bits of glamour
    and a little bit of tackiness in the very same outfits.</p>
      <p>The whole video shoot took almost 23 hours, and actually
    includes Annikafiore's boyfriend juggling with fire in the
    background The Alcazar dog Selma was styled in a pink ballerina
    dress and waited the whole day for the filming of her scene
    where she would perform jumps in the circus arena. By the time
    the scene was ready she was too tired to perform, and as a
    result the scene was deleted.</p>
      <p>These are the formats and track listings of promotional
    single releases of "Don't You Want Me".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
