<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Let_It_Be_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Let_It_Be_(song)</songId>
   <title>Let It Be</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1970-04-11</week>
      <week>1970-04-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>6 March 1970</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl record 7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Apple Studios , 31 January 1969 , EMI Studios, Abbey Road , 30 April 1969 , 4 January 1970</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:50</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Apple Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin and Chris Thomas</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Let It Be</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Let It Be" is a song by The Beatles, released in March 1970
    as a single, and (in an alternate mix) as the title track of
    their album 
    <i>Let It Be</i>. It was written by Paul McCartney and credited
    to Lennon/McCartney.</p>
      <p>The single reached number one in the U.S., Germany,
    Australia, Italy, Norway and Switzerland and number two in the
    UK. It was the final single released by the Beatles while the
    band was officially considered an active group. Both the 
    <i>Let It Be</i>album and the single, "The Long and Winding
    Road", were released after McCartney's announced departure from
    and subsequent break-up of the group.</p>
      <p>McCartney said he had the idea of "Let It Be" after a dream
    he had about his mother during the tense period surrounding the
    sessions for 
    <i>The Beatles</i>(the "White Album"). McCartney explained that
    his mother—who died of cancer when McCartney was fourteen—was
    the inspiration for the "Mother Mary" lyric. McCartney later
    said, "It was great to visit with her again. I felt very
    blessed to have that dream. So that got me writing 'Let It
    Be'." He also said in a later interview about the dream that
    his mother had told him, "It will be all right, just let it
    be."</p>
      <p>The first recording of "Let It Be" took place at Twickenham
    Film Studios on 3 January 1969, where The Beatles had the
    previous day begun what would become the 
    <i>Let It Be</i>film. During this stage of the film the group
    was only recording on the mono decks used for syncing to the
    film cameras, and were not making multi-track recordings for
    release. A single take was recorded, with just McCartney on
    piano and vocals. The first group attempt was made on 8
    January. Work continued on the song throughout the month.
    Multi-track recordings commenced on 23 January at Apple
    Studios.</p>
      <p>The master take was recorded on 31 January 1969, as part of
    the 'Apple studio performance' for the project 
    <i>Get Back</i>. McCartney played piano (a Blüthner Flügel from
    Leipzig), Lennon played bass, Billy Preston played organ and
    George Harrison and Ringo Starr assumed their conventional
    roles on guitar and drums. This was one of two performances of
    the song that day. The first version, designated take 27-A,
    would serve as the basis for all officially released versions
    of the song. The other version, take 27-B, was performed as
    part of the 'live studio performance', along with "Two of Us"
    and "The Long and Winding Road". This performance, in which
    Lennon and Harrison harmonised with McCartney's lead vocal and
    Harrison contributed a subdued guitar solo, can be seen in the
    film 
    <i>Let It Be</i>.</p>
      <p>On 30 April 1969, Harrison overdubbed a new guitar solo on
    the best take from 31 January that year. He overdubbed another
    solo on 4 January 1970. The first overdub solo was used for the
    original single release, and the second overdub solo was used
    for the original album release. Some fans mistakenly believe
    that there were two versions of the basic track—based mostly on
    the different guitar solos, but also on some other differences
    in overdubs and mixes.</p>
      <p>The single used the same cover photograph as the 
    <i>Let It Be</i>album, and was originally released on 6 March
    1970, backed by "You Know My Name (Look Up the Number)", with a
    production credit for George Martin. This version includes
    orchestration and backing vocals overdubbed on 4 January
    1970—under the supervision of Martin and McCartney—with backing
    vocals that included the only known contribution by Linda
    McCartney to a Beatles song. It was during this same session
    that Harrison recorded the second overdubbed guitar solo. The
    intention at one point was to have the two overdub solos
    playing together. This idea was dropped for the final mix of
    the single, and only the 30 April solo was used, although in
    practice the 4 January overdub can he heard faintly during the
    final verse. Martin mixed the orchestration very low in this
    version.</p>
      <p>The single mix was included on the 
    <i>1967–1970</i>compilation album. Original pressings
    erroneously show the running time of 4:01 (from the 
    <i>Let It Be</i>album), and not the single version's running
    time of 3:52. This version was also included on 
    <i>20 Greatest Hits,</i>
         <i>Past Masters Volume 2</i>, and 
    <i>1.</i>
      </p>
      <p>On 26 March 1970, Phil Spector remixed the song for the 
    <i>Let It Be</i>album. This version features the "more
    stinging" 4 January 1970 guitar solo, no backing vocals (except
    during the first chorus), an echo effect on Ringo's cymbals,
    and more prominent orchestration. The other guitar solo can be
    heard faintly through the right speaker, as the original was
    planned. The final chorus has three "let it be..." lines, as
    the "there will be an answer" line is repeated twice (instead
    of once as on the single) before the "whisper words of wisdom"
    line to close the song. On the album, as the preceding song
    "Dig It" ends, Lennon is heard saying in a falsetto voice,
    mimicking Gracie Fields: "That was 'Can You Dig It' by Georgie
    Wood, and now we'd like to do 'Hark, The Angels Come'," and
    then giggles. Allen Klein brought in Spector to mix the album
    without telling McCartney or asking for his agreement, because
    McCartney had not signed Klein's management contract. McCartney
    has complained many times that that he was not happy with
    Spector's production of the recording.</p>
      <p>Another version appears in the 
    <i>Let It Be</i>film. The film poster also used the same photos
    on the single cover, and was titled "an intimate bioscopic
    experience with THE BEATLES". In this version, McCartney makes
    several improvisations on piano, placing fill-in notes and
    sometimes substituting long notes for several short notes. As
    with the album version, McCartney repeats the "there will be in
    an answer" line in the chorus. Unlike the album version,
    however, he does this during the second chorus, not the final
    chorus. During the final verse and final chorus, McCartney also
    substitutes the lines "speaking words of wisdom" and "there
    will be an answer," replacing them with "there will be no
    sorrow." This version also uses Ringo's more simplified
    drumming, but has a more sophisticated guitar solo played by
    Harrison. The film version, which has never been officially
    released on record, has a running time of 4:01.</p>
      <p>An early version of the song also appears on 
    <i>Anthology 3</i>(Volume 3) which was released on 28 October
    1996. This version, Take 1, was recorded on 25 January 1969. It
    is a much more simplified version, as McCartney had still not
    written the final verse yet ("And when the night is cloudy...I
    wake up to the sound of music..."). Instead, the first verse is
    simply repeated. The song also features studio talk between
    Lennon and McCartney prior to another take:</p>
      <p>Paul: Yeah., John: OK., Paul: This'll-this is gonna knock
    you out, boy.</p>
      <p>Also, following the end of the recording, John can be heard
    saying, "I think that was rather grand. I'd take one home with
    me. OK let's track it. (Gasps) You bounder, you cheat!" The
    running time of the "Anthology" version is 4:05.</p>
      <p>Still another version of the song appeared on the 
    <i>Let It Be… Naked</i>album in 2003. Starr disliked Spector's
    version where his drumming was augmented by Spector's
    "tape-delay-effect" to his hi-hats during the song's second
    verse and added shakers, so 
    <i>Let It Be… Naked</i>features his original
    "stripped-down-approach" drumming. Also departed were the
    tom-tom overdub rolls, heard after the guitar solo during the
    third verse. The guitar solo used in this version—similar to
    the single version—was taken from the subsequent take as seen
    in the film "Let It Be". Starr also commented that after the
    release of 
    <i>Naked</i>, he would now have to listen to McCartney saying,
    "I told you so", when talking about Spector's production. The
    song's running time on 
    <i>Let It Be… Naked</i>is 3:52.</p>
      <p>McCartney released live performances of the song in 1990, on
    
    <i>Tripping the Live Fantastic</i>(as well as its abridged 
    <i>Tripping the Live Fantastic: Highlights!</i>version), and in
    2002, on 
    <i>Back in the U.S.</i>The former was performed in Miami, and
    the latter in New York City. On 
    <i>Tripping the Live Fantastic</i>, following the second verse,
    McCartney sings the chorus line only once, rather than twice,
    as he had done in most previous versions. On 
    <i>Back in the US</i>, he sings the chorus line twice again.
    Both versions also feature heavier guitar solos and a shorter
    singing rhythm.</p>
      <p>Glyn Johns mixed the song on 28 May 1969 as he finished the
    mixing for the 
    <i>Get Back</i>album. This version was never released. He used
    the same mix in a 5 January 1970, which was an attempt to
    compile an acceptable version of the LP. Again, this version of
    the LP was never officially released. Both versions, however,
    have made their way onto bootlegs over the years usually along
    with bootlegged versions of Johns' two attempts at mixing the
    Get Back Sessions into a cohesive whole.</p>
      <p>The piano introduces the song, through a series of chords in
    the right hand over single notes in the left hand.</p>
      <p>Critical reception for "Let It Be" has been positive. In
    2004, it was ranked number 20 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's list of the 500 greatest songs
    of all time. Allmusic said it was one of "The Beatles' most
    popular and finest ballads". Ian MacDonald had a dissenting
    opinion, writing that the song "achieved a popularity well out
    of proportion to its artistic weight" and that it was "'Hey
    Jude', without the musical and emotional release."</p>
      <p>John Lennon also commented on "Let It Be". Prior to a take
    during the 31 January 1969 recording session, he asked, "Are we
    supposed to giggle in the solo?" (This is a similar quote to
    Lewisohn's "The Complete Beatles Recording Sessions" (p170) but
    Lennon says "during the solo" not "in the solo" as quoted
    here). In Lennon's Playboy interview in 1980, he disavowed any
    involvement with composing the song. He said,</p>
      <p>As MacDonald explained, Lennon is wrong about "Bridge over
    Troubled Water" being McCartney's inspiration: "Let It Be" was
    recorded approximately a year before 'Bridge over Troubled
    Water' was released, and half a year before the latter was
    written.</p>
      <p>Interestingly, "Let It Be" knocked "Bridge over Troubled
    Water" out of the top spot as the Billboard Hot 100 number-one
    single in the United States on 11 April 1970.</p>
      <p>Although the song is performed regularly during McCartney's
    performances, there are a few notable performances.</p>
      <p>"Let It Be" has been covered numerous times by various
    artists, but this is just a short selection:</p>
      <p>Kris Allen did a version of this song on the ninth season of
    American Idol, on February 25, 2010, during eliminations. This
    song was later made available on iTunes for download, with all
    proceeds going toward disaster relief for the Haiti Earthquake.
    On the chart week of March 6, 2010, "Let It Be" made a debut at
    #63 on the Billboard Hot 100 chart based on sales of the
    digital single.</p>
      <p>United States: 86,000</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
