<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paperback_Writer 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paperback_Writer</songId>
   <title>Paperback Writer</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1966-06-25</week>
      <week>1966-07-09</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>30 May 1966 ( US ) , 10 June 1966 ( UK )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>13 April 1966, , Abbey Road Studios , London</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:18 (stereo version)</length>
      <length>2:26 (mono single version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Parlophone R5452 (UK) , Capitol 5651 (US)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Paperback Writer" is a 1966 rock song recorded and released
    by The Beatles. Credited to Lennon/McCartney, the song was
    released as the A-side of their eleventh single. The single
    went to the number one spot in the United States, United
    Kingdom, West Germany, Australia, New Zealand and Norway.
    Written in the form of a letter from an aspiring author to a
    publisher, "Paperback Writer" was the first UK Beatles single
    that was not a love song (though "Nowhere Man", which was a
    single in the US, was their first album song released with that
    distinction). On the US Billboard Hot 100, the song was at
    number one for two non-consecutive weeks, being interrupted by
    Frank Sinatra's "Strangers in the Night".</p>
      <p>"Paperback Writer" was the last new song by The Beatles to
    be featured in their 1966 touring.</p>
      <p>The track was recorded between 13 April and 14 April
    1966.</p>
      <p>"Paperback Writer" is marked by the boosted bass guitar
    sound throughout, partly in response to Lennon demanding to
    know why the bass on a certain Wilson Pickett record far
    exceeded the bass on any Beatles records. This changed with the
    "Paperback Writer" single.</p>
      <p>"'Paperback Writer' was the first time the bass sound had
    been heard in all its excitement," said Beatles' engineer Geoff
    Emerick in Mark Lewisohn's book 
    <i>The Complete Beatles Recording Sessions</i>. "To get the
    loud bass sound, Paul played a different bass, a Rickenbacker.
    Then we boosted it further by using a loudspeaker as a
    microphone. We positioned it directly in front of the bass
    speaker and the moving diaphragm of the second speaker made the
    electric current."</p>
      <p>Emerick stated that the "Paperback Writer" / "Rain" single
    was cut louder than any other Beatles record up to that time,
    due to a new piece of equipment used in the mastering process,
    referred to as "Automatic Transient Overload Control", which
    was devised by the EMI maintenance department.</p>
      <p>"Paperback Writer" appears on subsequent re-releases
    including 
    <i>1962-1966</i>(1973), 
    <i>Past Masters, Volume Two</i>(1988), and 
    <i>1</i>(2000).</p>
      <p>According to disc jockey Jimmy Savile, McCartney wrote the
    song in response to a request from an aunt who asked if he
    could "write a single that wasn't about love." Savile said,
    "With that thought obviously still in his mind, he walked
    around the room and noticed that Ringo was reading a book. He
    took one look and announced that he would write a song about a
    book." In a 2007 interview, McCartney recalled that he wrote
    the song after reading in the 
    <i>Daily Mail</i>about an aspiring author, possibly Martin
    Amis. The 
    <i>Daily Mail</i>was Lennon's regular newspaper and copies were
    in Lennon's Weybridge home when Lennon and McCartney were
    writing songs.</p>
      <p>The song's lyrics are in the form of a letter from an
    aspiring author addressed to a publisher. The author badly
    needs a job and has written a paperback version of a book by a
    "man named Lear." This is a reference to the Victorian painter
    Edward Lear, who wrote nonsense poems and songs of which John
    Lennon was very fond (though Lear never wrote novels).</p>
      <p>Aside from deviating from the subject of love, McCartney had
    it in mind to write a song with a melody backed by a single,
    static chord. "John and I would like to do songs with just one
    note like 'Long Tall Sally.' We got near it in 'The Word.'"
    McCartney claimed to have barely failed to achieve this goal
    with "Paperback Writer," as the verse remains on G until the
    end, at which point it pauses on C. The backing vocals during
    this section are from the French children's song "Frère
    Jacques"."</p>
      <p>In Britain the single was promoted with the infamous
    "butcher cover" art, depicting The Beatles with raw meat and
    decapitated baby dolls tossed about. This photograph was also
    originally used as the cover for the Capitol US-only album 
    <i>Yesterday and Today</i>. The image was soon replaced with a
    normal picture of the band as it had caused great controversy
    in America. For the American release of the "Paperback Writer"
    single, the cover depicted The Beatles playing live, but with
    John Lennon and George Harrison's images reflected so that it
    appears that they are playing left-handed. (See the image at
    the top of the page).</p>
      <p>Michael Lindsay-Hogg directed four promotional films for the
    song shot on 19 and 20 May 1966. On the first day they recorded
    a colour performance at Abbey Road, for 
    <i>The Ed Sullivan Show</i>, which was shown on 5 June, and two
    black and white performance clips for British television. These
    were shown on 
    <i>Ready Steady Go!</i>and 
    <i>Thank Your Lucky Stars</i>on 3 June and 25 June,
    respectively.</p>
      <p>On 20 May, another colour film was made at Chiswick House in
    west London. The Beatles mimed to the song, and they were shown
    in and around the conservatory in the grounds of the house. The
    clip was first broadcast in black and white on BBC-TV's 
    <i>Top of the Pops</i>on 2 June.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
