<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Help_Me,_Rhonda 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Help_Me,_Rhonda</songId>
   <title>Help Me, Rhonda</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beach_Boys</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beach Boys</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1965-05-29</week>
      <week>1965-06-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>The Beach Boys Today!</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 8, 1965</released>
   <recorded>track: January 8, 1965 , vocals: January 19, 1965</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:04</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Brian Wilson / Mike Love</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Brian Wilson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>The Beach Boys Today!</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Help Me, Rhonda" is a song written by Brian Wilson and Mike
    Love for their American pop band The Beach Boys. The song is
    notable for being the first Beach Boys song (with the exception
    of their 
    <i>Christmas Album</i>) to feature a lead vocal by Al Jardine.
    It was first released in March 1965 on the album 
    <i>The Beach Boys Today!</i>as "Help Me, Ronda". By that time,
    it had already been re-recorded; this version was released as a
    single through Capitol Records in April 1965, re-titled with
    the more well-known "Rhonda" spelling.</p>
      <p>The single peaked at number one in the United States,
    becoming their second U.S. number one single after "I Get
    Around". The song is featured on most Beach Boys hits
    compilations; typically the single version is used.</p>
      <p>The original version of the song was recorded over two dates
    at Western Recording Studios in Hollywood on January 8 and 19,
    1965, with Chuck Britz as the engineer and production by Brian
    Wilson.</p>
      <p>The instrumental track has Carl Wilson, Bill Pitman, and
    Glen Campbell on guitar, Billy Strange on ukulele, Ray Pohlman
    on bass guitar, Leon Russell on piano, Hal Blaine on drums and
    timbales, Julius Wechter on claves, Billy Lee Riley on
    harmonica, Steve Douglas and Plas Johnson on tenor saxophone,
    and Jay Migliori on baritone saxophone. Al Jardine sang the
    lead vocal with backing vocals by Carl, Dennis and Brian
    Wilson, and Mike Love.</p>
      <p>The song was originally considered to be an album cut only,
    but radio stations began to play the track and Brian decided to
    rework and re-record it. The single version of the song was
    recorded at Universal and Radio Recorders studios in Hollywood
    on February 24, 1965, again with Chuck Britz as the engineer
    and Brian Wilson as producer. Featured on the instrumental
    track were regular Wrecking Crew members such as Hal Blaine on
    drums and Carol Kaye on bass guitar. Beach Boys who contributed
    to the instrumental track were Carl Wilson (guitar) and Brian
    Wilson (acoustic piano and Hammond B-3). The single version
    features Al Jardine on lead vocals with backing vocals by Carl,
    Dennis and Brian Wilson, Mike Love, and Bruce Johnston.</p>
      <p>The recording session of this song was infamously
    interrupted by the Wilson brothers' father, Murry, who openly
    criticized the Boys' enthusiasm. His criticisms drove Brian
    Wilson to breaking point and Brian screamed an expletive,
    removed his headphones and confronted his father. Shortly after
    defending his actions, Murry Wilson left the studio and The
    Beach Boys continued with the session. The recording reel
    continued to roll and recorded the entire confrontation which
    circulates among fans.</p>
      <p>The first version of the song appears on the 1965 album 
    <i>The Beach Boys Today!</i>as "Help Me, Ronda", released March
    8, 1965. This version runs over three minutes with no guitar
    solo, and has a number of false endings with the volume fading
    in and out; it is included on the 
    <i>Endless Summer</i>compilation album.</p>
      <p>The single version, which has a noticeably different
    arrangement, and one word changed in the lyrics, was released
    on April 5, 1965. In addition to topping the charts in the US,
    the single also reached #1 in Canada (on the 
    <i>RPM</i>national chart), #5 in Sweden, #10 in Germany and
    Australia, #2 in Singapore, #3 in The Philippines, #5 in Hong
    Kong and #9 in Ireland. It peaked at number twenty-seven in the
    United Kingdom.</p>
      <p>The new single version was subsequently included on the
    album 
    <i>Summer Days (and Summer Nights!!)</i>, released June 28,
    1965. The instrumental backing track of this version was
    released in 1968 on the band's 
    <i>Stack-O-Tracks</i>album.</p>
      <p>A slight variation, called "Help Me, Rhonda (Alternate
    Single Version)", is included on the 1998 
    <i>Endless Harmony Soundtrack</i>album. This version adds a
    wordless falsetto from Brian Wilson over the chorus.</p>
      <p>After becoming The Beach Boys second number one hit in the
    United States, it immediately became a regular in the band's
    live set. It has been released on two Beach Boys official live
    albums: 1973's 
    <i>The Beach Boys In Concert</i>and 
    <i>Good Timin': Live at Knebworth England 1980</i>. The song
    was also released by Brian Wilson on his own 2000 live album 
    <i>Live at the Roxy Theatre</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was performed by Ricky Martin at 2001's "An
    All-Star Tribute to Brian Wilson".</p>
      <p>Johnny Rivers' cover in 1975 on his 
    <i>New Lovers And Old Friends</i>album (with an assist from
    Brian Wilson on back-up vocals) reached #22 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100.</p>
      <p>A slow, reflective cover of the song appears on the 1998
    album 
    <i>Toxic Swamp And Other Love Songs</i>by Kenny Young And The
    Eggplants.</p>
      <p>Do You Wanna Dance
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Good to My Baby
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Don't Hurt My
    Little Sister
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>When I Grow Up
    (To Be a Man)
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Help Me, Ronda
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Dance, Dance,
    Dance
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Please Let Me
    Wonder
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>I'm So Young
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Kiss Me, Baby
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>She Knows Me Too
    Well
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>In the Back of My
    Mind
    <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>Bull Session with
    the "Big Daddy"</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
