<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Can_Dream,_Can%27t_I%3F 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Can_Dream,_Can%27t_I%3F</songId>
   <title>I Can Dream, Can't I?</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Andrews_Sisters</artistId>
      <artistName>The Andrews Sisters</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1950-01-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Can Dream, Can't I?" is a popular song written by Sammy
    Fain and the lyrics by Irving Kahal. The song was published in
    1938, included in a flop musical, 
    <i>Right This Way.</i>
      </p>
      <p>In 1938 the song was a hit for Tommy Dorsey, but a postwar
    revival of the song was an even bigger hit.</p>
      <p>The best-known version was recorded by The Andrews Sisters
    and Gordon Jenkins' orchestra, with another version also done
    by Toni Arden with Hugo Winterhalter's orchestra. A United
    Kingdom version was recorded by Alan Dean with Carroll Gibbons'
    orchestra, while an Australian version was done by the Tune
    Twisters with Art Wranzer &amp; his orchestra.</p>
      <p>The song was also recorded by The Carpenters on their 1975
    album 
    <i>Horizon.</i>
      </p>
      <p>The recording by The Andrews Sisters was recorded on July
    15, 1949 and released by Decca Records as catalog number 24705.
    It first reached the Billboard magazine charts on September 16,
    1949 and lasted 27 weeks on the chart, peaking at #1.</p>
      <p>The Toni Arden recording was recorded on September 16, 1949
    and released by Columbia Records as catalog number 38612.</p>
      <p>On the Cash Box magazine Best-Selling record charts, which
    combined all recorded versions, the song also reached #1.</p>
      <p>The Alan Dean recording was recorded on December 9, 1949 and
    released by UK Columbia Records as catalog number FB 3539.</p>
      <p>The Tune Twisters' recording was recorded in May, 1950 and
    released by Artransa Records of Australia as catalog number A
    009.</p>
      <p>Cass Elliot recorded the song on her 1969 album 
    <i>Bubble Gum, Lemonade &amp; Something for Mama</i>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
