<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wild_Thing_(Chip_Taylor_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wild_Thing_(Chip_Taylor_song)</songId>
   <title>Wild Thing</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Troggs</artistId>
      <artistName>The Troggs</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1966-07-30</week>
      <week>1966-08-06</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1966</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:30</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Fontana 267570TF (UK) , Fontana 1548 (US) , Atco 6415 (US) , Hansa 18940AT (FRG)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Chip Taylor</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Larry Page</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Wild Thing" is a hit song written by New York City-born
    songwriter Chip Taylor and originally recorded by The Wild Ones
    in 1965. The song is best known for its 1966 cover by the
    English band The Troggs, which reached the number one spot on
    the Billboard Hot 100 in July 1966. The song charted one
    position lower in Britain, reaching #2.</p>
      <p>The song as sung by The Troggs is ranked #257 on the 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's list of The 500 Greatest Songs
    of All Time.</p>
      <p>The song's central guitar riff is immediately recognizable
    and frames the central lyric:</p>
      <p>The music stops for the counter lyric:</p>
      <p>The Second counter lyric is as follows:</p>
      <p>The song is in the key of A major, and is based around the
    chord progression (I - IV - V - IV), which is the basis for the
    main riff, and the instrumental parts during the chorus.
    However, the guitars are not strictly tuned to middle C in the
    Troggs version and the slightly sharp tuning causes the chords
    to actually be midway between A and Bb. This has, of course,
    mystified many guitar players trying to play along with the
    record. The middle eight was originally someone whistling, but
    in the Troggs' version this was replaced by Colin Fretcher,
    musical director, playing an ocarina.</p>
      <p>The Troggs version was recorded in mono in one piece on the
    second take at Olympic Studios which was then at Carton Street,
    off Baker Street in London, by engineer Keith Grant.</p>
      <p>Because of a distribution dispute, the Troggs single was
    available on two competing labels: Atco and Fontana. Because
    both pressings were taken from the identical master recording,
    Billboard combined the sales for both releases, making it the
    only single to simultaneously reach #1 for two companies.</p>
      <p>The song has remained popular ever since The Troggs' hit
    single, and has been covered again many times — perhaps most
    notably by Jimi Hendrix, whose stage performance of the song
    was featured in the 1967 documentary 
    <i>Monterey Pop</i>. Hendrix recorded the song live and it can
    be heard in the compilation album 
    <i>The Ultimate Experience</i>.</p>
      <p>In 1967, the novelty team of Senator Bobby released a
    version of "Wild Thing". Sung by comedian Bill Minkin in the
    verbal style of Democratic Senator Bobby Kennedy while a
    recording engineer is heard giving instructions, the stammering
    single charted at #20 in the United States. The flip side of
    the Senator Bobby 45 featured "Senator Everett McKinley" (an
    impression of Republican Senator Everett McKinley Dirksen)
    doing the same song; the initial voiceover by the recording
    engineer encourages Senator Bobby to respond to his "hit
    single" (the Senator Everett McKinley version also had some
    radio airplay at the time). The songs were credited to The
    Hardly-Worthit Players, and the Senator Bobby version was
    included as a bonus track on reissues of their 1962 Parkway LP
    called 
    <i>The Hardly-Worthit Report</i>(the rest of the album is a
    comedic takeoff on the NBC national news broadcast 
    <i>The Huntley-Brinkley Report</i>).</p>
      <p>The British group Fancy recorded a version of the song in
    1974, which reached #14 on the Billboard Hot 100. The British
    comedy troupe The Goodies recorded a version of the song, and
    performed it during a 1976 episode of their television series.
    In 1983 the song was covered by the psychobilly band The
    Meteors for their 
    <i>Wreckin' Crew</i>album, and was also performed by the
    Australian pub band Cold Chisel during their Last Stand
    concert. Sister Carol did a reggae version in 1986.</p>
      <p>The Runaways performed a live version of the song on their
    live album, "Live in Japan". Drummer Sandy West sang on the
    track.</p>
      <p>Comedian Sam Kinison recorded a hit novelty version in 1988,
    with a music video featuring cameos from Rodney Dangerfield as
    well as many well-known rock musicians including Steven Tyler
    and Joe Perry from Aerosmith, Slash, Billy Idol, Steve Vai,
    Dweezil Zappa, Sebastian Bach, Richie Sambora and Jon Bon Jovi
    of Bon Jovi, and Tommy Lee, and a raunchy "roll on the mat"
    dance with Jessica Hahn. A cover by the Los Angeles-based punk
    band X was used in the 1989 film 
    <i>Major League</i>and its 1994 sequel, 
    <i>Major League II</i>. The 1990 cartoon version of the comic
    book character Swamp Thing had a theme song that parodied the
    song, with the lyrics "Swamp Thing! You are amazing!" Cheap
    Trick recorded the song for the soundtrack to 
    <i>Encino Man</i>in 1992, possibly as a tribute to Kinison who
    had died that year. The Troggs recorded a new version in 1993,
    which charted in the lower reaches of the British charts. A
    cover version was recorded by Hank Williams, Jr. in 1995.
    Australian rock group Divinyls covered the song in 1993 for the
    soundtrack of the movie Reckless Kelly. Prince interpolated the
    chorus of the song into his cover of Tommy James and the
    Shondells' "Crimson and Clover".</p>
      <p>Bruce Springsteen and the E Street Band performed the song
    on numerous occasions during their Working on a Dream Tour.</p>
      <p>The Swedish rock band Trash Cans made a cover of Wild Thing
    in 2010.</p>
      <p>The 1989 baseball film 
    <i>Major League</i>used "Wild Thing" recorded by L.A. punk band
    X as the theme song for Rick Vaughn, the team's erratic relief
    pitcher. Life soon imitated art, when the Philadelphia Phillies
    closer Mitch Williams adopted the song for his entrances from
    the bullpen, including in the 1993 World Series. During the
    late 2000s, the song is played at Fenway Park whenever Boston
    Red Sox closer Jonathan Papelbon comes in from the bullpen,
    followed by "I'm Shipping Up to Boston" by the Dropkick
    Murphy's.</p>
      <p>In 1992, the Troggs' version was used in the film 
    <i>D2: The Mighty Ducks</i>. That same year a version by Cheap
    Trick was used for the film 
    <i>Encino Man</i>. In 2003, Aerosmith recorded a version of the
    song with a video, which was used for commercials and teasers
    advertising ABC's coverage of the NFL Wild Card playoffs.</p>
      <p>In the UK the song was used heavily by television programme
    "You've Been Framed", for clips generally involving
    animals.</p>
      <p>Japanese Pro Wrestler Atsushi Onita used the X cover of the
    song as his entrance theme.</p>
      <p>The song was featured in a prominent scene in the 1997
    miniseries 
    <i>Painted Lady</i>featuring Helen Mirren.</p>
      <p>In 1998, the song was used in The Vicar of Dibley episode 
    <i>Love and Marriage</i>- the choir at St. Barnabus' Church
    sang the song after Hugo and Alice made their vows and were
    pronounced man and wife.</p>
      <p>In the Full House episode, "Just Say No Way," Jesse
    Katsopalis plays this song with the marching band at DJ's
    school dance (replacing Dogface, a popular high school band,
    who broke up hours beforehand).</p>
      <p>, The title of the 1986 film 
    <i>Something Wild</i>was itself an inversion of the song title.
    The film features a scene where two main characters (played by
    Jeff Daniels and Melanie Griffith) pick up some hitch-hikers in
    their convertible and the party then sing "Wild Thing".</p>
      <p>
         <i>I Am a Photograph</i>
         <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Sweet Revenge</i>
         <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Never Trust a Pretty Face</i>
         <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Diamonds for Breakfast</i>
         <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Incognito</i>
         <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Tam-Tam</i>
         <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Secret Passion</i>
         <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
         <i>Uomini Più Uomini</i>
         <span style="font-weight:bold;"> ·</span>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
