<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rum_and_Coca-Cola 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rum_and_Coca-Cola</songId>
   <title>Rum and Coca-Cola</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>The Andrews Sisters</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1945-02-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>“Rum and Coca-Cola” is the title of a popular calypso.
    Originally composed by Lord Invader and Lionel Belasco, it was
    copyrighted in the United States by entertainer Morey Amsterdam
    and became a huge hit in 1945 for the Andrews Sisters, spending
    ten weeks at the top of 
    <i>Billboard's</i>U.S. Pop Singles chart.</p>
      <p>Although the song was published in the United States with
    Amsterdam listed as the lyricist and Jeri Sullavan and Paul
    Baron as musical composers, the melody had been previously
    published as the work of Trinidadian calypso composer Lionel
    Belasco on a song titled “L'Année Passée,” which was in turn
    based on a folksong from Martinique. The original lyrics to
    “Rum and Coca-Cola” were written by Rupert Grant, another
    calypso musician from Trinidad who went by the stage name of
    Lord Invader. (The true credits for music and lyrics were
    restored in a plagiarism lawsuit won by famous attorney Louis
    Nizer, the account of which can be read in his book, 
    <i>My Life in Court</i>.)</p>
      <p>According to Lord Invader, “Calypso is the folklore of
    Trinidad, a style of poetry, telling about current events in
    song. Back home in the West Indies, Trinidad, where I'm from,
    it's a small island, I'm proud of it. I was traveling on a bus,
    someplace they call Point Cumana, a bathing resort, and I
    happened to see the G.I.s in the American social invasion in
    the West Indies, Trinidad. You know the girls used to get the
    candies and stuff like that, and they go to the canteens with
    the boys and so on, have fun. So I noticed since the G.I.s came
    over there, they really generally chase with soda, ordinary
    soda, but their chaser was Rum and Coke. They drink rum, and
    they like Coca-Cola as a chaser, so I studied that as an idea
    of a song, and Morey Amsterdam had the nerve to say that he
    composed that song back here.”</p>
      <p>The song became a local hit and was at the peak of its
    popularity when Amsterdam visited the island in September 1943
    as part of a U.S.O. tour. Although he subsequently claimed
    never to have heard the song during the month he spent on the
    island, the lyrics to his version are clearly based on the Lord
    Invader version, with the music and chorus being virtually
    identical. However, Amsterdam's version strips the song of its
    social commentary. The Lord Invader version laments that U.S.
    soldiers are debauching local women, who “saw that the Yankees
    treat them nice / and they give them a better price.” Its final
    stanza describes a newlywed couple whose marriage is ruined
    when “the bride run away with a soldier lad / and the stupid
    husband went staring mad.” The Amsterdam version also hints
    that women are prostituting themselves, preserving the Lord
    Invader chorus which says, “Both mother and daughter / Working
    for the Yankee dollar.”</p>
      <p>Since the Yankee come to Trinidad, They got the young girls
    all goin' mad, Young girls say they treat 'em nice, Make
    Trinidad like paradise</p>
      <p>The Andrews Sisters also seem to have given little thought
    to the meaning of the lyrics. According to Patty Andrews, “We
    had a recording date, and the song was brought to us the night
    before the recording date. We hardly really knew it, and when
    we went in we had some extra time and we just threw it in, and
    that was the miracle of it. It was actually a faked
    arrangement. There was no written background, so we just kind
    of faked it.” Years later, Maxine Andrews recalled, “The rhythm
    was what attracted the Andrews Sisters to 'Rum and Coca-Cola'.
    We never thought of the lyric. The lyric was there, it was
    cute, but we didn't think of what it meant; but at that time,
    nobody else would think of it either, because we weren't as
    morally open as we are today and so, a lot of stuff — really,
    no excuses — just went over our heads.”</p>
      <p>The song was the top single of 1945 in the United States.
    Despite its popularity, it was controversial and was banned by
    network radio stations because it mentioned an alcoholic
    beverage. The fact that it mentioned a commercial product by
    name also meant that it could be construed as free advertising
    when broadcast.</p>
      <p>After the release of the Andrews Sisters' version of “Rum
    and Coca-Cola,” Belasco and Lord Invader sued for copyright
    infringement of the song's music and lyrics, respectively. In
    1948, after years of litigation, both plaintiffs won their
    cases, with Lord Invader receiving an award of $150,000 in owed
    royalties. However, Morey Amsterdam was allowed to retain
    copyright to the song. Lord Invader also wrote a follow-up song
    to “Rum and Coca-Cola”, titled “Yankee Dollar”.</p>
      <p>Leonard Cohen sometimes quoted a line from the song in live
    performances of his song “Field Commander Cohen”. A version is
    available on the live album of the same name released in
    2000.</p>
      <p>Julio Iglesias recorded a Spanish edition of this song,
    titled “Ron y Coca-Cola”, on his album 
    <i>Hey!</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
