<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Get_Around_(Beach_Boys_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Get_Around_(Beach_Boys_song)</songId>
   <title>I Get Around</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beach_Boys</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beach Boys</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1964-07-04</week>
      <week>1964-07-11</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e2/Beach_Boys_-_I_Get_Around.jpg/200px-Beach_Boys_-_I_Get_Around.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Beach-Boys+I-Get-Around.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>All Summer Long</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 11, 1964</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Western Studios , April 2, 1964 , April 10, 1964</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Music</genre>
      <genre>Surf Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:12</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol 5174</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Wilson / Love</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Brian Wilson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Get Around" is a song written by Brian Wilson and Mike
    Love for The Beach Boys. The song features Love on lead vocal
    for the verse, and Wilson for the chorus. It is noteworthy for
    its back to front structure - it starts with a chorus and has
    two short verses. It was a single which was released in 1964
    through Capitol Records; the B-side of the single was "Don’t
    Worry Baby", which itself charted at number 24 in the United
    States. "I Get Around" was The Beach Boys' first number-one hit
    song in the United States. The single also charted at number
    seven in the United Kingdom, which was the band's first top ten
    single there. The song's first album release was on 
    <i>All Summer Long</i>in 1964.</p>
      <p>In November 1969, the Wilson's father Murry Wilson, sold the
    copyrights to the band's songs to Irving Almo for approximately
    $700,000. Many years later in April 1992, just after Brian
    Wilson had won a lawsuit which recovered many of the copyrights
    to his songs, Mike Love filed a lawsuit against Brian Wilson
    claiming that he had not been given credit, and therefore
    hadn't received royalties, on over thirty of the band's songs,
    many of them hit singles. One of these songs was "I Get
    Around". The original credit only credited Wilson, but Love
    insisted that he had a hand in writing the lyrics. In an
    interview with Goldmine, published September 18, 1992, Love
    insisted that he and not Wilson "came up with 'round round get
    around'". Mike Love won the lawsuit and the song-writing credit
    was amended, therefore ensuring future royalties on all of the
    songs that he had claimed he had a hand in writing.</p>
      <p>As far as researchers can gather, the instrumental track was
    recorded on April 2, 1964. The session, produced by Brian
    Wilson, was also notable as being the session that most likely
    saw the sacking of the band's manager and the Wilsons' father,
    Murry Wilson. The bed instrumental track of the song without
    any instrumental overdubs was released on the 1993 five-disc
    box set 
    <i>Good Vibrations: Thirty Years of The Beach Boys</i>.</p>
      <p>The vocals were recorded during a session eight days later
    on April 10. The lead vocal features Mike Love on the verses
    and Brian Wilson on the choruses with backing vocals from
    Brian, Carl &amp; Dennis Wilson, Mike Love and Alan Jardine
    (the soaring falsetto is Brian Wilson).</p>
      <p>The "I Get Around" single backed with "Don't Worry Baby" was
    released in the United States on May 11, 1964. The single
    entered the 
    <i>Billboard</i>chart on June 6 at #17. The song reached the #1
    spot on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts on July 4, replacing "A World Without
    Love" by Peter and Gordon and thus becoming the band's first #1
    hit in the United States. The song remained at #1 for two weeks
    before being replaced by "Rag Doll" by The Four Seasons. The
    single also reached #1 on the United States 
    <i>Variety</i>charts on July 1.</p>
      <p>According to Songfacts, Billboard and Cash Box magazines
    rated I Get Around 1964's fifth biggest selling song, and
    indicated it sold close to 2 million units in the U.S.</p>
      <p>Released in June 1964 in the United Kingdom the single
    peaked at #7 on the 
    <i>Record Retailer</i>chart and thus becoming the band's first
    top ten hit in the United Kingdom. According to some sources,
    Mick Jagger, when appearing on the U.K. television show Ready
    Steady Go!, stated that he thought the song was a great record.
    This most likely played a part in boosting the singles success,
    while also helping the band become more popular in the United
    Kingdom.</p>
      <p>In Germany the single peaked at #38 on the 
    <i>Hit Bilanz</i>chart, which was only the band's second single
    to chart in Germany. The single was the band's first charting
    single in the Netherlands, charting at #38 on the Netherlands
    singles charts. The single also reached the top 10 in both the
    Canadian and Swedish singles charts, peaking at #10 in both
    countries.</p>
      <p>The song was first released on an album in 1964 on the
    band's 
    <i>All Summer Long</i>album. In the following year, the band
    re-recorded the song as a medley along with "Little Deuce
    Coupe" for their 1965 
    <i>Beach Boys' Party!</i>album. The medley was a send-up of the
    original recording. The mock recording replaces lyrics such as
    "we always take my car cause it's never been beat" with "we
    always take my car although it's a heap". The original
    recording of the song was later re-released on the band's 1989
    studio album 
    <i>Still Cruisin'</i>. On the 1996 country styled studio
    release 
    <i>Stars and Stripes Vol. 1</i>the band re-recorded the song
    for the album which featured country band Sawyer Brown as
    guests on the track who played several of the instruments on
    the recording as well as featuring a lead vocal by band member
    Mark Miller. The harmonies on the re-recorded track were
    provided by Brian &amp; Carl Wilson, Alan &amp; Matt Jardine,
    Mike Love and Bruce Johnston.</p>
      <p>The song frequently appears on many of the groups Greatest
    Hits compilations including the 1974 #1 hit compilation album 
    <i>Endless Summer</i>; the 1999 compilation 
    <i>The Greatest Hits - Volume 1: 20 Good Vibrations</i>; the
    2002 compilation 
    <i>Classics Selected by Brian Wilson</i>, which was hand-picked
    by Brian Wilson himself; the 2003 compilation 
    <i>Sounds of Summer: The Very Best of The Beach Boys</i>as well
    as the 1993 box set 
    <i>Good Vibrations: Thirty Years of The Beach Boys</i>.</p>
      <p>After the song became the band's first United States number
    one hit song, it immediately became a regular in The Beach Boys
    live set. During the band's first British tour in 1964, they
    performed this song as well as "When I Grow Up (To Be a Man)"
    on their first television appearance in Britain on Ready Steady
    Go! Several live renditions of the song have been officially
    released on various Beach Boys releases. It was first released
    on their first live album 
    <i>Beach Boys Concert</i>in 1964. A concert from Anaheim
    Stadium on July 3, 1976 which featured the song was filmed and
    produced by Lorne Michaels for a Beach Boys television special
    which first aired in the United States in August, 1976. The TV
    special was later released on video and DVD as 
    <i>Good Vibrations Tour</i>. In 1980, a live rendition was
    recorded, though not released until 2002 on the 
    <i>Good Timin': Live at Knebworth England 1980</i>live album.
    Footage from the concert was also released on video and DVD
    format. Another live recording of the song from a concert in
    1989 was released on the 2006 album Songs from Here &amp;
    Back.</p>
      <p>The first film in which the song appeared was the 1984 film 
    <i>Surf II</i>. In 1986, the song was heard in the Disney
    science-fiction comedy, 
    <i>Flight of the Navigator</i>. The song was later featured in
    two films in 1987, both 
    <i>Good Morning, Vietnam</i>and 
    <i>The Big Bang</i>. Two years later the song was used in the
    1989 film 
    <i>Look Who's Talking</i>. The 1990 film 
    <i>Downtown</i>also used the song during the movie. It was also
    featured in the 1997 films 
    <i>Bean</i>and 
    <i>Toothless</i>. It was again used in the 1999 film 
    <i>Three Kings</i>. More recently the song was used in the 2000
    film 
    <i>Last Resort</i>.</p>
      <p>A version of the song was featured on various Hoveround
    advertisements, advertising electronically powered
    wheelchairs.</p>
      <p>In one episode of 
    <i>The Muppet Show</i>, Ms. Piggy along with other pig members
    of the cast, sing this song while riding Harley Davidson
    motorcycles.</p>
      <p>In an episode of The Wonder Years, the song appears during
    the ending credits.</p>
      <p>The song also featured in the Wii game, 
    <i>Imagine Fashion Party</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was also used by the Bondi Surf Club (Surf Life
    Saving Australia) for their march as a part of the Sydney Gay
    &amp; Lesbian Mardi Gras parade in 2009.</p>
      <p>In a Kidsongs video and DVD, "Let's Play Ball", the music
    video shows about driving race cars.</p>
      <p>The song is also used in the Wes Anderson film, "Fantastic
    Mr. Fox".</p>
      <p>The Song was used in the novel Boy's Life and was the song
    Reverend Blessett hated.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
