<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walk_Right_In 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walk_Right_In</songId>
   <title>Walk Right In</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Rooftop_Singers</artistId>
      <artistName>The Rooftop Singers</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1963-01-26</week>
      <week>1963-02-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Walk Right In</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1962</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" (45 rpm)</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1962</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Folk Music</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:33</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Vanguard Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Gus Cannon</writer>
      <writer>Hosie Woods</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Erik Darling</producer>
      <producer>Bill Svanoe</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Walk Right In" is the title of a popular song from 1962 by
    the American folk trio The Rooftop Singers. The song was
    written by blues singer and musician Gus Cannon and originally
    recorded by Cannon and His Jug Stompers in the late 1920s.</p>
      <p>In the U.S., the song spent two weeks at #1 on the Hot 100
    chart in early 1963. It spent five weeks atop the Easy
    Listening chart, which would later become known as the Adult
    Contemporary chart. In addition, "Walk Right In" reached both
    the R&amp;B chart (peaking at #4) as well as the country music
    chart (peaking at #23). The song reached #1 in Australia on the
    Kent Music Report in 1963, and it made the Top 10 on the UK
    Singles Chart in the United Kingdom, peaking at #10.</p>
      <p>The album containing this song was also called 
    <i>Walk Right In</i>and was nominated for a Grammy Award in the
    category Best Folk Recording.</p>
      <p>Group member Erik Darling recruited two friends to record a
    folk version of "Walk Right In" after hearing the original
    Cannon recording. Darling wanted the record to have a
    distinctive sound, so he and group member Bill Svanoe both
    played twelve string guitars on the song, although they had
    some difficulty in acquiring the instruments. Darling is quoted
    as saying that prior to the making of this record, "you
    couldn't buy a 12-string guitar...I ordered one from the Gibson
    Company, but in order to record [the song] with two 12-strings,
    we had to wait for the company to build a second one for Bill!"
    The success of the song was a boon to Cannon, who was in his
    late 70s and had been forced to pawn his banjo the previous
    winter in order to pay his heating bill; he received royalties
    as a songwriter and saw renewed interest in his music, which
    led to a recording contract of his own.</p>
      <p>Other acts who have recorded or performed "Walk Right In"
    include Chet Atkins, Sammy Davis Jr., Ella Fitzgerald, Earl
    Grant, Janis Joplin, Jerry Lee Lewis, Trini Lopez, Otis Taylor,
    and Dr. Hook &amp; the Medicine Show. The Rooftop Singers'
    version appears on the soundtrack to the Tom Hanks film 
    <i>Forrest Gump</i>. Roger Branigin's campaign adapted the song
    en route to his eventual victory in the 1964 Indiana
    gubernatorial race.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
