<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ticket_to_Ride 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ticket_to_Ride</songId>
   <title>Ticket to Ride</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1965-05-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/b/bd/Ticket_to_Ride.jpg/200px-Ticket_to_Ride.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/The-Beatles+Ticket-to-Ride.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Help!</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>9 April 1965</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>15 February 1965 , Abbey Road Studios</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:10</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Parlophone</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Ticket to Ride" is a song by The Beatles from their 1965
    album, 
    <i>Help!</i>. It was recorded 15 February 1965 at Abbey Road
    Studios and released two months later. In 2004, this song was
    ranked number 384 on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine's list of the 500 greatest songs
    of all time.</p>
      <p>The song was written primarily by John Lennon (credited to
    Lennon/McCartney), with Paul McCartney's contributions in
    dispute. Lennon said that McCartney's contribution was limited
    to "the way Ringo played the drums". McCartney said that was an
    incomplete response, and that "we sat down and wrote it
    together... give him 60 percent of it... we sat down together
    and worked on that for a full three-hour songwriting session."
    Lennon said the double-time ending section (with the lyric "My
    baby don't care") was one of his "favourite bits" in the song.
    This song was also the first song by the band in which
    McCartney was featured on lead guitar.</p>
      <p>Lennon proudly claimed that it was the first heavy metal
    song given the droning bassline, repeating drums, and loaded
    guitar lines.</p>
      <p>The song also features an unrelated coda in a form of a
    tempo change.</p>
      <p>While the song lyrics describe a girl "riding out of the
    life of the narrator", the inspiration of the title phrase is
    unclear. McCartney said it was "a British Railways ticket to
    the town of Ryde on the Isle of Wight", and Lennon said it
    described cards indicating a clean bill of health carried by
    Hamburg prostitutes in the 1960s. The Beatles played in Hamburg
    early in their musical career, and "ride/riding" was slang for
    having sex.</p>
      <p>"Ticket to Ride" was released as a single on 9 April 1965 in
    the UK and 19 April in the US with "Yes It Is" as its B-side,
    topping the Hot 100 for a week in the US and the UK Singles
    Chart for three weeks in the UK. The American single's label
    declared that the song was from the United Artists release 
    <i>Eight Arms to Hold You</i>. This was the original title of
    The Beatles' second movie; the title changed to 
    <i>Help!</i>after the single was initially released. The song
    was also included on the 
    <i>Help!</i>album released on 6 August in the UK and on 13
    August in the US.</p>
      <p>The song was the third of six number one singles in a row on
    the American charts, a record at the time. The singles were "I
    Feel Fine", "Eight Days a Week", "Ticket to Ride", "Help!",
    "Yesterday", and "We Can Work It Out". The record was equaled
    by The Bee Gees in the 1970s</p>
      <p>Music critics Richie Unterberger of allmusic and Ian
    MacDonald both describe "Ticket to Ride" as an important
    milestone in the evolution of the musical style of the Beatles.
    Unterberger said, "the rhythm parts on 'Ticket to Ride' were
    harder and heavier than they had been on any previous Beatles
    outing, particularly in Ringo Starr's stormy stutters and
    rolls." MacDonald described it as "psychologically deeper than
    anything The Beatles had recorded before ... extraordinary for
    its time — massive with chiming electric guitars, weighty
    rhythm, and rumbling floor tom-toms. Macdonald also notes that
    the track uses the Indian basis of drone which might have
    influenced the Kinks' "See My Friends".</p>
      <p>MacDonald wrote that Lennon played a Jetglo Rickenbacker 325
    twelve-string guitar, and that George Harrison was "probably"
    playing his 12-string Rickenbacker 360/12 guitar.</p>
      <p>In 1969, it was released by The Carpenters on their album, 
    <i>Offering/Ticket to Ride</i>, and it became a minor hit. The
    song stalled at number #54 on the Billboard Hot 100 for three
    weeks and #19 on the adult contemporary. The Carpenters
    recorded the song as a slower ballad. They released their debut
    album of the same name.</p>
      <p>Many artists have covered "Ticket to Ride", including
    Vanilla Fudge (1967), The 5th Dimension (1967 on 
    <i>The Magic Garden</i>), The Punkles, Kids Incorporated
    (1993), and Atomic Kitten (2007).</p>
      <p>An orchestral version of the song is barely audible in the
    fadeout at the very end of the Pink Floyd album 
    <i>The Dark Side of the Moon</i>. Initially this phenomenon was
    considered a mistake in remastering. However it is audible on
    high quality vinyl pressings from the time before the CD era as
    well. The Beatles and Pink Floyd both recorded at Abbey Road
    Studios.</p>
      <p>The song is referenced in "Artificial Energy", by The Byrds,
    the opening track of 
    <i>The Notorious Byrd Brothers</i>from 1968.</p>
      <p>The title of this song is referenced to in the Red Dwarf
    episode Tikka to Ride, in accordance with the theme of curry on
    which the storyline focuses.</p>
      <p>In a 
    <i>Doctor Who</i>episode titled "The Executioners," the Doctor
    and his companions Ian Chesterton, Barbara Wright, and Vicki
    watch the Beatles perform "Ticket To Ride" on the Doctor's
    recently acquired time/space visualiser. The clip shown is
    about 15 seconds long and was of a mime performance they gave
    on 
    <i>Top of the Pops</i>very recent to the recording of the 
    <i>Doctor Who</i>episode and is the only footage of this
    performance known to exist. The episode transmitted on 22 May
    1965 on BBC1 and was watched by 10 million viewers. This story
    was released on VHS in 1993, and on DVD in the UK as part of a
    box set with The Space Museum on 3 March 2010.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
