<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/People_Got_to_Be_Free 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/People_Got_to_Be_Free</songId>
   <title>People Got to Be Free</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Rascals</artistId>
      <artistName>The Rascals</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1968-08-17</week>
      <week>1968-08-24</week>
      <week>1968-08-31</week>
      <week>1968-09-07</week>
      <week>1968-09-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>July 1, 1968</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>May 14, 1968</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>White Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:01</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atlantic Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Felix Cavaliere</writer>
      <writer>Eddie Brigati</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>The Rascals</producer>
      <producer>with Arif Mardin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"People Got to Be Free" is a song released in 1968 by The
    Rascals. Written by group members Felix Cavaliere and Eddie
    Brigati and featuring a lead vocal from Cavaliere, it is an
    upbeat but impassioned plea for tolerance and freedom:</p>
      <p>It became a big hit in the turbulent summer of 1968,
    spending five weeks atop the Billboard Pop Singles chart, the
    group's longest such stay. It was also the group's second-most
    successful single on the Billboard Black Singles chart,
    reaching number 14 and trailing only the previous year's
    "Groovin'". "People Got to Be Free" was RIAA-certified as a
    gold record on August 23, 1968, and eventually sold over 4
    million copies. It later was included on the group's March 1969
    album 
    <i>Freedom Suite</i>.</p>
      <p>The single's picture sleeve photo was previously featured in
    the inner album cover of the Rascals' 
    <i>Time Peace: The Rascals' Greatest Hits</i>compilation. The
    B-side, "My World", was a track from the group's 
    <i>Once Upon a Dream</i>album.</p>
      <p>While "People Got to Be Free" was perceived by some as
    related to the assassinations of Martin Luther King, Jr. and
    Robert F. Kennedy earlier that year, it was recorded before the
    latter's death. In fact it was partly a reaction to an ugly
    encounter wherein the long-haired group was threatened by a
    group of rednecks after their tour vehicle broke down in Fort
    Pierce, Florida.</p>
      <p>The song is clearly a product of its times; however, two
    decades later writer Dave Marsh included it as number 237 in
    his book 
    <i>Heart of Rock and Soul: The 1001 Greatest Singles of All
    Time</i>, saying in reference to, and paraphrase of, the song's
    lyric, "Ask me my opinion, my opinion will be: Dated, but NEVER
    out of date."</p>
      <p>Since this song came out, the Rascals would only perform at
    concerts that featured an African American act, however, if
    those conditions were not met, the Rascals canceled several
    shows in protest.</p>
      <p>The 5th Dimension recorded "People Got to Be Free" in 1970
    as part of a medley with another socially relevant song, Sam
    Cooke's "A Change Is Gonna Come." The pairing reached number 60
    on the Billboard Pop Singles chart.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
