<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Feel_Fine 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Feel_Fine</songId>
   <title>I Feel Fine</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beatles</artistId>
      <artistName>The Beatles</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1964-12-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>23 November 1964 ( US ) , 27 November 1964 ( UK )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>18 October 1964 , Abbey Road Studios , London</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock And Roll</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:18 (stereo version)</length>
      <length>2:20 (untrimmed stereo version)</length>
      <length>2:25 (mono version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Capitol 5222 (US) , Parlophone R5160 (UK)</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lennon/McCartney</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Feel Fine" is a riff-driven rock song written primarily
    by John Lennon (credited to Lennon/McCartney) and released in
    1964 by the Beatles as the A-side of their eighth UK single.
    The single reached the top of the UK charts on 12 December of
    that year, displacing The Rolling Stones' "Little Red Rooster,"
    and remained there for five weeks. It also reached the top of
    the Billboard Hot 100 in late 1964. The B-side was "She's a
    Woman".</p>
      <p>"I Feel Fine" was the first of six number one songs in a row
    on the American charts, a record at the time. The subsequent
    singles were "Eight Days a Week", "Ticket to Ride", "Help!",
    "Yesterday", and "We Can Work It Out". The record was equaled
    by The Bee Gees in 1979 and surpassed by Whitney Houston in
    1988.</p>
      <p>Lennon wrote the guitar riff while in the studio recording
    "Eight Days a Week". "I wrote 'I Feel Fine' around that riff
    going on in the background," he recalled. "I told them I'd
    write a song specially for the riff. So they said, 'Yes. You go
    away and do that,' knowing that we'd almost finished the album 
    <i>Beatles for Sale</i>. Anyway, going into the studio one
    morning, I said to Ringo, 'I've written this song but it's
    lousy.' But we tried it, complete with riff, and it sounded
    like an A side, so we decided to release it just like that."
    George Harrison said that Lennon's riff was influenced by a
    riff in "Watch Your Step", a 1961 release written and performed
    by Bobby Parker and covered by The Beatles in concerts during
    1961 and 1962.</p>
      <p>Paul McCartney said the drums on "I Feel Fine" were inspired
    by Ray Charles's "What'd I Say".</p>
      <p>At the time of the song's recording the Beatles, having
    mastered the studio basics, had begun to explore new sources of
    inspiration in noises previously eliminated as mistakes
    (electronic goofs, twisted tapes, talkback). "I Feel Fine"
    marks the earliest example of the use of feedback as a
    recording effect. Artists such as Jimi Hendrix, The Kinks, and
    The Who used feedback, but Lennon remained proud of the fact
    that the Beatles were the first group to actually put it on
    vinyl.</p>
      <p>The intro to "I Feel Fine" starts with a single, percussive
    (yet pure-sounding) note (a high "A" harmonic) played on
    McCartney's Hofner bass guitar that sustains, perhaps beyond
    any song previously recorded. It is then transformed and
    distorted via feedback. According to McCartney, "John had a
    semi-acoustic Gibson guitar. It had a pick-up on it so it could
    be amplified... We were just about to walk away to listen to a
    take when John leaned his guitar against the amp. I can still
    see him doing it... it went, 'Nnnnnnwahhhhh!" And we went,
    'What's that? Voodoo!' 'No, it's feedback.' Wow, it's a great
    sound!' George Martin was there so we said, 'Can we have that
    on the record?' 'Well, I suppose we could, we could edit it on
    the front.' It was a found object, an accident caused by
    leaning the guitar against the amp."</p>
      <p>While sounding very much like an electric guitar, Lennon
    played it on an acoustic (a Gibson model J-160E), employing the
    guitar's onboard pickup and 1960s sound effect devices to make
    the acoustic guitar sound more electronic. The intro riff
    around a D major chord progresses to a C, then a G, where the G
    major vocals begin. Just before the coda, Lennon's intro riff
    (or ostinato), is repeated with a bright sound by George
    Harrison on electric guitar (a Gretsch Tennessean), followed by
    the more 
    <i>electric</i>sound of John on amped acoustic.</p>
      <p>In the US, the song was released on their Capitol album 
    <i>Beatles '65</i>, and is presented in a duophonic mix
    featuring a layer of reverb added by executive Dave Dexter,
    Jr..</p>
      <p>In the UK, the song was released on the LP format on 
    <i>A Collection of Beatles Oldies</i>. A true stereo version
    can be found on the 
    <i>Past Masters Vol 1</i>and 
    <i>Beatles 1</i>CDs.</p>
      <p>There is also another stereo version that sounds the same,
    but with whispering at the very beginning which appears on the
    original release of 
    <i>1962–1966</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
