<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mama_Told_Me_Not_to_Come 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mama_Told_Me_Not_to_Come</songId>
   <title>Mama Told Me (Not to Come)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three_Dog_Night</artistId>
      <artistName>Three Dog Night</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1970-07-11</week>
      <week>1970-07-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>It Ain't Easy</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1970</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1970</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop / Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:18</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Dunhill</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Randy Newman</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Richard Podolor</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Mama Told Me Not to Come" is a song by Randy Newman written
    for Eric Burdon's first solo album in 1966.</p>
      <p>Newman says that it is a lighthearted reflection on the Los
    Angeles music scene in the late 1960s. He recounts a wild
    party, and uses the lyrics to convey a sense of excitement and
    confusion. The song is loaded with the black humor, sarcasm,
    and double entendre that made Newman famous. Among other
    topics, he makes thinly veiled references to drugs, alcohol,
    and sex.</p>
      <p>The first recording of "Mama Told Me Not to Come" was made
    by Eric Burdon &amp; The Animals. A scheduled single-release of
    September 1966 was withdrawn but the song was eventually
    included on their 1967 album 
    <i>Eric Is Here</i>.</p>
      <p>Newman's own version of his song was released on the 1970
    album 
    <i>12 Songs</i>, and is characterized by a slow tempo and has a
    hint of funk influence. It failed to crack the charts.</p>
      <p>Since its release, the most famous being a longer, more funk
    inspired version released by Three Dog Night on 
    <i>It Ain't Easy</i>(titled "Mama Told Me (Not to Come)"), also
    in 1970. In contrast with Newman's version, the party is
    rendered as chaotic, confusing and terrifying.</p>
      <p>Three Dog Night's version made it to number one on the
    Billboard Hot 100 chart in July 1970. This version has the
    distinction of being the first number-one song on the 
    <i>American Top 40</i>countdown show with longtime host Casey
    Kasem. Newman mentions Three Dog Night's version is better than
    his, and his favorite of all versions.</p>
      <p>Tom Jones &amp; Stereophonics' treatment of the song reached
    number four on the UK Singles Chart in 2000. This version was
    produced by rising star producers Steve Bush and Marshall Bird,
    AKA 
    <i>Bird &amp; Bush</i>.</p>
      <p>P. J. Proby recorded one of the earliest versions of the
    song, in 1967, and since Three Dog Night's 1970 hit it has been
    recorded by diverse artists including Wilson Pickett, Lou
    Rawls, The Wolfgang Press, Yo La Tengo, Helmut Zerlett and The
    Slackers.</p>
      <p>Tea Leaf Green[1] and Widespread Panic[2] have also
    performed this song live. In 1971, the comic singer Patrick
    Topaloff released a french version named 
    <i>Maman, viens me chercher</i>. A German version, entitled 
    <i>Das War So Doch Nicht Geplant</i>, was published in 2005 by
    the German soul singer Stefan Gwildis.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
