<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joy_to_the_World_(Hoyt_Axton_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joy_to_the_World_(Hoyt_Axton_song)</songId>
   <title>Joy to the World</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three_Dog_Night</artistId>
      <artistName>Three Dog Night</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1971-04-17</week>
      <week>1971-04-24</week>
      <week>1971-05-01</week>
      <week>1971-05-08</week>
      <week>1971-05-15</week>
      <week>1971-05-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Naturally</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 1971</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1970</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:17 (single)</length>
      <length>3:40 (album version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Dunhill Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Hoyt Axton</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Three Dog Night</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Joy to the World" is a song written by Hoyt Axton, and made
    famous by the band Three Dog Night. The song is also popularly
    known by its opening words, "Jeremiah was a bullfrog". Some of
    the words are nonsensical. Axton wanted to convince his record
    producers to record a new melody he had written and the
    producers asked him to sing any words to the tune.</p>
      <p>Three Dog Night's version went to number one on the pop
    music charts in February 1971 and was the top single of the
    year in Billboard Magazine for 1971. The song was released on
    the band's album 
    <i>Naturally</i>. It was also released on their albums 
    <i>Around the World With Three Dog Night</i>(1973), 
    <i>Joy to the World: Their Greatest Hits</i>(1974), 
    <i>The Best of 3 Dog Night</i>(1982), and 
    <i>Celebrate: The Three Dog Night Story, 1965-1975</i>(1993).
    Three Dog Night never really wanted to record the song but they
    needed one last track for their 
    <i>Naturally</i>album. The group had been on an overseas tour
    when that album was released and were greatly surprised to hear
    that the song they didn't want to record ended up being a big
    hit.</p>
      <p>The edited single version (3:17) released on Dunhill Records
    (D-4272) varies from the version widely available on their
    Greatest Hits collections. The mono single has a guitar solo in
    the instrumental bridge at approximately 1:10 that is not heard
    on the stereo Greatest Hits version. Plus the trailing ad libs
    in the single were edited from the order in which they appear
    in the stereo version.</p>
      <p>In the 1990s, former Three Dog Night lead singer Chuck
    Negron recorded the Christmas carol "Joy to the World" and
    playfully included a few lyrics from the Three Dog Night/Hoyt
    Axton song — coming to a full stop in mid-song for the line
    "Jeremiah was a bullfrog." The refrain of Axton's song was also
    included in Mariah Carey's recording of the Christmas carol for
    her 1994 
    <i>Merry Christmas</i>album.</p>
      <p>In an episode of the TV series 
    <i>Sex and the City</i>, Carrie Bradshaw (played by Sarah
    Jessica Parker) and her friend Jeremiah (played by Samuel Ball)
    sing the "Jeremiah was a bullfrog" part of this song on the way
    home to Carrie's after a party.</p>
      <p>The song was also featured in an episode of the sitcom 
    <i>Friends</i>when Phoebe, Monica and Chandler have gone to a
    karaoke evening hosted by Phoebe's new boyfriend, Mike.
    Chandler stands up and opens with the line "Jeremiah was a
    bullfrog".</p>
      <p>It was also referenced in a cartoon from 
    <i>The Far Side</i>, where a frog says to his two friends,
    "Yeah, I remember Jerry. He was a good pal of mine...you know,
    I never understood a word he said, but he always had some
    mighty fine wine," parodying the first lines of the song.</p>
      <p>In 
    <i>The X-Files</i>television series, the song was referenced in
    the episode "Detour". Agent Mulder demands Agent Scully sing to
    him when they find themselves lost in a forest while attempting
    to capture a seemingly invisible predator. After declaring that
    she is unable to carry a tune, Scully proceeds to sing
    "Jeremiah was a bullfrog... Was a good friend of mine... Never
    understood a single word he said... But I helped him drink his
    wine...". Scully again sings a few lines in the season nine
    episode "William".</p>
      <p>In the 
    <i>Malcolm in the Middle</i>episode "Garage Sale", when Hal
    restarts his pirate radio station, he plays a tape with the
    starting lyrics of "Joy to the World", "Jeremiah was a
    bullfrog".</p>
      <p>A special version of song's main chorus was also employed as
    the opening and closing theme to the early-1980s episodes of 
    <i>Joy Junction</i>, a Christian children's television
    series.</p>
      <p>The song was sung by a child in the bath in 
    <i>The Big Chill</i>. The original Three Dog Night recording is
    then later played as the closing credits roll.</p>
      <p>The song was played in the film 
    <i>Forrest Gump</i>when Forrest is playing Ping Pong.</p>
      <p>The song was used as the ending theme song for the Japanese
    drama Lunch Queen.</p>
      <p>The song is the opening song for 
    <i>Raise Your Voice</i>, and the closing song for 
    <i>The Big Chill</i>. It is also found in 
    <i>28 Days</i>during one of the flashbacks of the main
    character's mother being drunk.</p>
      <p>The song also appears in the movie 
    <i>Amazon Women on the Moon</i>, performed by David Alan Grier
    as Don 'No Soul' Simmons.</p>
      <p>Two early-1970s clips of then-Chicago Bears coach Abe Gibron
    singing the song were used on NFL Films' 1981 documentary on
    "The NFL's Best Ever Coaches" and was recycled into 1985's "The
    Best of Football Follies".</p>
      <p>It is sometimes used in advertising during the Christmas
    season, as a play on the Christmas song "Joy to the World". It
    was used by JCPenney in 2004.</p>
      <p>The song has been included on the recent Sky Digital
    "Environment" advert.</p>
      <p>The Nintendo DS videogame 
    <i>Animal Crossing: Wild World</i>also referenced the song via
    the inclusion of a frog called Jeremiah. He is among the
    neighbor roster in the game, in which the player could have a
    maximum of eight.</p>
      <p>The video game 
    <i>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion</i>also makes a passing
    reference to the song. If the player listens in on some of the
    conversations between NPCs there is a chance that the NPCs will
    hold a conversation similar to the lyrics of the song.</p>
      <p>The Three Dog Night version is on the game 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Volume 3</i>.</p>
      <p>The Green Bay Bullfrogs mascot is named Jeremiah.</p>
      <p>This song substituted for Queen's "We Are The Champions" at
    the end of Super Bowl XXXII at Qualcomm Stadium in San Diego,
    California when the Denver Broncos won their first world
    championship.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
