<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Think_We%27re_Alone_Now 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Think_We%27re_Alone_Now</songId>
   <title>I Think We're Alone Now</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tiffany_(singer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Tiffany</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-11-07</week>
      <week>1987-11-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/c/c4/Tiffany-I_Think_We%27re_Alone_Now-12in.jpg/200px-Tiffany-I_Think_We%27re_Alone_Now-12in.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Tiffany+I-Think-We-re-Alone-Now.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Tiffany</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 10, 1987</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1987</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Synth Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:47</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MCA Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Ritchie Cordell</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Tobin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Think We're Alone Now" is a song written by Ritchie
    Cordell. It was initially a 1967 hit for American recording
    artists Tommy James &amp; the Shondells, reaching #4 on the
    Billboard Hot 100 during a 17-week stay. The recording was
    produced by Cordell and Bo Gentry.</p>
      <p>Rock critic Lester Bangs called the single "the bubblegum
    apotheosis." Cordell wrote or co-wrote many songs for James,
    including "Run, Run, Baby, Run" (the B-side to "I Think We're
    Alone Now"), the follow-up single "Mirage," and 1968's "Mony
    Mony." 
    <i>I Think Were Alone Now</i>stands out as one of Tommy James'
    most successful recordings, and was sampled in a scene in the
    1980s slasher film 
    <i>Mother's Day</i>.</p>
      <p>"I Think We're Alone Now" has since been covered on numerous
    occasions. In 1987, a version by Tiffany reached #1 in the US,
    UK, Canada and New Zealand. Several other cover versions have
    charted as well, including those by The Rubinoos (#45 US, 1977)
    and Girls Aloud (#4 UK, 2006).</p>
      <p>The song was re-popularized when American singer Tiffany
    covered the song for her first album 
    <i>Tiffany</i>(1987). Tiffany's version of the song spent two
    weeks at number-one on the Billboard Hot 100 (and was unusually
    followed on the top spot by another Tommy James &amp; the
    Shondells cover, "Mony Mony" by Billy Idol) and three weeks at
    number-one on the UK Singles Chart. The Tiffany version went
    quadruple platinum in the US in a thirteen week chart run. The
    video was shot in a shopping mall which echoed the way her
    early career had been promoted.</p>
      <p>When George Tobin, Tiffany's manager, gave Tiffany the
    cassette of the original version by Tommy James &amp; the
    Shondells, Tiffany hated the idea of recording a version of her
    own for her album mostly because she thought the song wasn't
    modern or hip enough. It turned out to be her biggest hit once
    she recorded it.</p>
      <p>"I Think We're Alone Now" was not the first single off
    Tiffany's debut album. The first single was "Danny", but radio
    started picking up "I Think We're Alone Now", another track on
    the album. It became a runaway number-one hit and was the
    eighteenth highest selling single for 1987 and the
    thirty-second highest selling single in Australia for 1988.</p>
      <p>This version is referenced in the alternative group Weezer's
    song "Heart Songs" on the band's 2008 
    <i>Red Album</i>but in the song it is mentioned that it was
    sung by Debbie Gibson, another teen idol who was around at the
    same time as Tiffany. When Rivers Cuomo wrote the song, he had
    noticed the oversight on his part and that he knew that the
    song was recorded by Tiffany but he left the part in the song
    where he mentions Debbie Gibson singing the song.</p>
      <p>In 2006, the British all-female pop group Girls Aloud
    covered "I Think We're Alone Now", produced by Brian Higgins
    and his production team Xenomania for their greatest hits album
    
    <i>The Sound of Girls Aloud</i>. The track was released on 18
    December 2006, to contend for the Christmas number one. The
    song also served as the official theme of the movie 
    <i>It's a Boy Girl Thing</i>, which was released in UK cinemas
    on 29 December 2006.</p>
      <p>Until three days before the greatest hits was manufactured,
    a cover of Irene Cara's "What A Feeling" was going to be in
    place of "I Think We're Alone Now". Girls Aloud had called
    their record label on a Friday afternoon to say they'd rather
    record "I Think We're Alone Now" — the group recorded the song
    the following morning and the album was mastered on Monday,
    three days afterwards.</p>
      <p>The album version was drastically reworked for the single
    release, due to the initial version being hasilty recorded;
    Higgins said that "Xenomania used the only idea they could
    think of, which was to make the song sound like 'Something
    Kinda Ooooh'". The single features an alternative vocal
    arrangement and an entirely new backing track. The song was
    also given a big band reworking for the Sound of Girls Aloud
    Tour.</p>
      <p>Girls Aloud's cover of the song was widely slated by music
    critics. It was called "cheap, obnoxious, totally pointless and
    destined to be loved only by people too out of their heads on
    Christmas spirit to know any better."</p>
      <p>The single debuted at number 50 on the UK Singles Chart a
    week prior to its physical release, due to download sales. The
    single was released in order to compete for the coveted
    Christmas number one single spot. It eventually peaked at
    number four, being beaten by Leona Lewis' "A Moment Like This".
    It spent a further five weeks in the top 75. The song also
    peaked at number eleven on the Irish Singles Chart and spent
    six weeks in Ireland's top 50.</p>
      <p>The video, directed by Alex Hemming and Nick Collett,
    features the girls trying to rob an Los Angeles casino. The
    video is based on films like 
    <i>Ocean's 11</i>and 
    <i>Casino</i>.</p>
      <p>Three different endings to the video were shot. The first
    shows the girls getting caught after opening a box full of
    money in the casino's safe, the second features Kimberley Walsh
    removing her clothes in front of casino owners, causing them to
    faint, and the third features the girls playing with the money.
    3 Mobile customers were allowed to vote on their favourite
    ending from November 8 to November 15, 2006. The latter ending
    won the vote, despite a version of the video with Kimberley
    stripping being uploaded to the internet. Since March 2007, all
    versions of the video have been made available to download on
    iTunes.</p>
      <p>The band performed the song at the following events:</p>
      <p>The song has been covered by a number of artists including
    Annakiya, '70s power pop band The Rubinoos, eurodance artist
    Playhouse, The Spinto Band, The Turtles, Lene Lovich, Pascal
    featuring Karen Parry, Annakiya, The Click Five, The Birthday
    Massacre, Comadre, The Pipettes, Snuff, Screeching Weasel, The
    Monkees, The Crimea and Me First and the Gimme Gimmes. The song
    has also been covered by Bel's Boys on their debut album 
    <i>People Let's Go</i>. The latest cover of the song was
    recently released by The Birthday Massacre on their Looking
    Glass EP.</p>
      <p>The song was spoofed by "Weird Al" Yankovic on his 1988
    album, 
    <i>Even Worse</i>, as "I Think I'm a Clone Now". Dave Garr, who
    wrote a good deal of song parodies about computers, covered
    this as "I Think We're a Clone Now". The parody dealt with the
    licensing of the Macintosh from Apple Computer to other
    companies during the short period in which Macintosh clones
    were made. The video was recorded in 1995 at Apple's
    headquarters and features the building and its landmarks of the
    day, references to former Apple CEOs Mike Spindler and John
    Sculley, and some vintage Macintosh computers including a
    Macintosh Classic and an Apple Lisa.</p>
      <p>Also, as part of RadioShack's new "TheShack" commercial
    campaign, one commercial features a man in an office cubicle
    with headphones on, singing part of the bridge and chorus in a
    falsetto range.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
