<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No_Scrubs 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No_Scrubs</songId>
   <title>No Scrubs</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TLC_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>TLC</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1999-04-10</week>
      <week>1999-04-17</week>
      <week>1999-04-24</week>
      <week>1999-05-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/ae/Tlc-noscubs2.jpg/200px-Tlc-noscubs2.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/TLC+No-Scrubs.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>FanMail</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 23, 1999</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD Single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1998 , D.A.R.P. Studios , ( Atlanta , Georgia )</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:34 (album version)</length>
      <length>4:00 (main mix w/ rap)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>LaFace</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Kevin "She'kspere" Briggs</writer>
      <writer>Kandi Burruss</writer>
      <writer>Tameka Cottle</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Kevin "She'kspere" Briggs</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"No Scrubs" is a 1999 song recorded by R&amp;B girl group
    TLC for their album 
    <i>FanMail</i>. Released as the album's first single, "No
    Scrubs" eventually became TLC's smash single. It also earned
    them their second Grammy nomination for Record of the Year, but
    lost to Santana's "Smooth". The single is generally considered
    to be one of the group's signature songs and was the 2nd
    biggest Hot 100 single of 1999, according to Billboard's Year
    End Charts. The single was certified platinum in the UK.</p>
      <p>Written by producer Kevin "She'kspere" Briggs along with
    Tameka Cottle and Kandi Burruss (both from the group Xscape),
    the track lyrically explains "scrubs" as reference to a slang
    term for a man who is (for the most part) jobless, lacking a
    car, lacking money, and otherwise described to have virtually
    no ambition or class. "No Scrubs" was the first single for TLC
    to feature lead vocals by group member Rozonda "Chilli" Thomas
    rather than Tionne "T-Boz" Watkins. There were two versions of
    the song: the album version (which was released to radio), and
    a "Main Mix" with a rap by Lisa "Left Eye" Lopes. The latter
    mix was featured in the music video for the song.</p>
      <p>Prior to the release of 
    <i>FanMail</i>, the track "Silly Ho" received some radio
    airplay, prompting a peak of number 59 in the U.S., although it
    was never released by LaFace as a lead single. "No Scrubs"
    climbed into the U.S. top ten as an airplay only song and
    jumped to number one upon the single release. The single stayed
    in the Top Ten of the Billboard Hot 100 for 17 consecutive
    weeks.No Scrubs is listed at number 123 on the All Time Singles
    Chart Worldwide with points of over 6,000,000.</p>
      <p>The futuristic music video directed by Hype Williams also
    received massive airplay on MTV, and won the group the 1999 MTV
    Video Music Award for Best Group Video, beating out favorites
    'N Sync and the Backstreet Boys. Each member had a set in the
    video. The video also has a dance sequence where the girls
    dance in front of the "TLC" logo. The Main Mix is used in the
    video instead of the album version. The video features the
    girls in three different outfits: Chilli is in white, Left Eye
    in black and T-Boz in white and red. When there are shots of
    the girls together they have two different outfits: black and
    silver. T-Boz's hair is fuchsia in the video. The set up of the
    video is similar to the Michael Jackson and Janet Jackson's
    video, "Scream" and IMx's video Stay the Night.</p>
      <p>"No Scrubs" also draws parallels with Destiny's Child's
    single "Bills, Bills, Bills", which was written and produced by
    the same production crew. Both songs drew minor controversy as
    the members were accused of being gold diggers, women who only
    like men for their wealth, in their respective songs. In
    response, the New York-based hip hop trio Sporty Thievz
    recorded what would become, respectively, their second and
    biggest hit, a parody entitled "No Pigeons", and a follow-up
    "No Billz Billz Billz (Why, Why, Why?)", released
    independently.</p>
      <p>This is their first and only single wherein Chilli sings
    lead for the full track. T-Boz does not appear on this track,
    instead it's Debra Killings, Kandi Burruss, and Tameka "Tiny"
    Cottle singing background vocals along with Chilli, though it
    sounds distinctly similar to T-Boz.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
