<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unpretty 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unpretty</songId>
   <title>Unpretty</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TLC_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>TLC</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1999-09-18</week>
      <week>1999-09-25</week>
      <week>1999-10-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/ea/Tlc-unpretty.jpg/200px-Tlc-unpretty.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/TLC+Unpretty.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>FanMail</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 10, 1999  (1999-08-10)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1998</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:01 (radio version)</length>
      <length>4:38 (album version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>LaFace</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Corey Glover</writer>
      <writer>Michael Cirincione</writer>
      <writer>Dallas Austin</writer>
      <writer>Tionne Watkins</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Dallas Austin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Unpretty" is a 1999 (see 1999 in music) single recorded by
    R&amp;B girl group TLC. Produced by Dallas Austin and
    co-written by Austin and TLC group member Tionne "T-Boz"
    Watkins, "Unpretty" was the second single released from 
    <i>Fanmail</i>. It became the group's fourth and final U.S.
    smash hit on the Billboard Hot 100 and their second Billboard
    smash in a row, following "No Scrubs". It was also nominated
    for song of the year at 1999 Grammy Awards.</p>
      <p>"Unpretty" originated from a poem of the same name written
    by Watkins, which dealt with a woman's struggle with her
    self-image. The poem also addressed the comparisons many
    females make between themselves and the sometimes unrealistic
    concepts of beauty, as it is commonly portrayed in the media.
    Upon reading the poem, TLC producer Dallas Austin helped
    Watkins adapt the poem into a song, which TLC recorded as an
    empowering song for their mostly female fan base to overcome
    feelings of physical inadequacy. Watkins and Rozonda "Chilli"
    Thomas sing lead on the song, with backing vocals by Watkins
    and Debra Killings. A remixed version, sampling Dennis Edwards
    &amp; Siedah Garrett's "Don't Look Any Further", was produced
    by Con?one. Some versions of the remix feature a rap by TLC
    member Lisa "Left-Eye" Lopes. "Unpretty" was later covered by
    La Musique Populaire for their 2004 boxed set 
    <i>A Century of Song</i>.</p>
      <p>Paul Hunter directed the music video for "Unpretty" in
    August 1999, which tied together vignettes of several different
    stories relating to the song's lyrics. The main set of
    vignettes features a young woman (portrayed by Thomas) whose
    boyfriend convinces her to get breast implants to augment her
    small bust. However, after she sees another patient in the
    hospital (cameo by Jade Valerie) getting her implants painfully
    removed, the woman flees the hospital in fear.</p>
      <p>Another prominent set of vignettes features Lopes as an
    inner-city woman who witnesses a gang fight and a murder.
    Several of Lopes' scenes are set to her verse from "I'm Good At
    Being Bad" (another track on 
    <i>FanMail</i>) instead of "Unpretty" (Lopes appears in the
    "Unpretty" performance shots reciting the song lyrics in sign
    language).</p>
      <p>Other vignettes feature a full-figured teenager worried
    about fitting the "ideal" image of the petite supermodel and
    struggling with a bulimia as a result. Near the end of the
    video, however, she tears down the unrealistic images of models
    that she has tacked on her wall, a sign that she may be
    starting to embrace her own natural body shape. One last set of
    vignettes features Watkins as a high school student who is
    harassed by two white males because she is black.</p>
      <p>The video has become a fan favorite because it is the last
    video released in the US featuring all three members of TLC
    before the death of Lisa "Left-Eye" Lopes. The music video for
    this song cost over $1.6 million making it one of the most
    expensive music videos ever made.</p>
      <p>"Unpretty" spent three weeks at the top of the U.S. pop
    chart and was TLC's final number-one single. In the UK, it was
    TLC's final top 30 hit.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
