<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creep_(TLC_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creep_(TLC_song)</songId>
   <title>Creep</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TLC_(music)</artistId>
      <artistName>TLC</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1995-01-28</week>
      <week>1995-02-04</week>
      <week>1995-02-11</week>
      <week>1995-02-18</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/1c/Creep1994.PNG/200px-Creep1994.PNG</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/TLC+Creep.PNG</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>CrazySexyCool</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 31, 1994</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>12-inch single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1994</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Contemporary R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:28</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>LaFace , 24088</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Dallas Austin</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Dallas Austin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Creep" is the first single by American R&amp;B group TLC
    from their second studio album 
    <i>CrazySexyCool</i>, released on October 31, 1994 by LaFace
    Records. The single became their first smash hit on the
    Billboard Hot 100, and remained at number one on the chart for
    four weeks, eventually becoming the second best-selling single
    of 1995, behind Madonna's "Take a Bow". TLC won the Grammy
    Award for Best R&amp;B Performance by a Duo or Group with
    Vocals, and Dallas Austin was nominated for Best R&amp;B Song.
    It was the 3rd most successful Hot 100 Single of 1995,
    according to Billboard's Year End Charts. "Creep" was ranked
    third on Spin's Top 20 Singles of the '90's.</p>
      <p>The lyrics are taken from the perspective of a woman who is
    aware of her boyfriend's infidelity and in turn cheats on him
    in an effort to appease her need for affection. A cover version
    of the song was released by alternative rock band The Afghan
    Whigs.</p>
      <p>In the documentary "The Last Days of Left Eye", TLC member
    Lisa "Left Eye" Lopes said she was 100% against the release of
    Creep as a single, and threatned to wear black tape over her
    mouth in the music video.</p>
      <p>There were three music videos made for this song, but only
    the final one was released. The video features each girl
    individually in front of a color background wearing silky
    pajamas matching the color of that background. There are other
    scenes featuring T-Boz singing into a microphone with Omar
    Lopez, a previous dancer for Janet Jackson, with an open shirt,
    playing trumpet behind her and flirting with her. There are
    also, black and white shots of them rehearsing dance moves,
    being silly and hanging out. Most of the fashions in the video
    represent early 90's fashion, such as flannel shirts, baggy
    pants and sweatshirts tied around the waist. This video shows
    TLC becoming more mature compared to their prior album.</p>
      <p>* - includes a rap by Left Eye.</p>
      <p>The second version of the single released in 1996 contained
    three versions of the song, the original, the Maxx Remix and
    the Tin Tin Out Remix. It also contains the single version of
    "Waterfalls".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
