<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It%27s_All_in_the_Game 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It%27s_All_in_the_Game</songId>
   <title>It's All in the Game</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tommy_Edwards</artistId>
      <artistName>Tommy Edwards</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1958-09-29</week>
      <week>1958-10-06</week>
      <week>1958-10-13</week>
      <week>1958-10-20</week>
      <week>1958-10-27</week>
      <week>1958-11-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1958</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:36</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>MGM</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Carl Sigman</writer>
      <writer>Charles Dawes</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"It's All in the Game" was a 1958 hit for Tommy Edwards.
    Carl Sigman composed the lyrics in 1951 to a wordless 1911
    composition entitled "Melody in A Major," written by Charles
    Dawes, later Vice President of the United States under Calvin
    Coolidge. It is the only #1 pop single to have been cowritten
    by a U.S. Vice President.</p>
      <p>The song has become a pop standard, with cover versions by
    dozens of artists, some of which have been minor hit
    singles.</p>
      <p>Edwards' song ranked at #38 on 
    <i>Billboard's All Time Top 100</i>.</p>
      <p>Dawes, a Chicago bank president and amateur pianist and
    flautist, composed the tune in 1911 in a single sitting at his
    lakeshore home in Evanston. He played it for a friend, the
    violinist Francis MacMillen, who took Dawes's sheet music to a
    publisher. Dawes, known for his federal appointments and a
    United States Senate candidacy, was surprised to find a
    portrait of himself in a State Street shop window with copies
    of the tune for sale. Dawes quipped, "I know that I will be the
    target of my punster friends. They will say that if all the
    notes in my bank are as bad as my musical ones, they are not
    worth the paper they were written on."</p>
      <p>The tune, often dubbed "Dawes's Melody," followed him into
    politics, and he grew to detest hearing it wherever he
    appeared. It was a favorite of violinist Fritz Kreisler, who
    used it as his closing number, and in the 1940s it was picked
    up by musicians such as Tommy Dorsey.</p>
      <p>In summer 1951, the songwriter Carl Sigman had an idea for a
    song, and Dawes's "Melody" struck him as suitable for his
    sentimental lyrics. Dawes had died in April of that year. It
    was recorded that year by Dinah Shore, Sammy Kaye, Carmen
    Cavallaro, and Edwards. The Edwards version had most success,
    reaching #18 on the Billboard Best Sellers In Stores survey.
    The range of the melody would have been "difficult to sing", so
    required rearrangement. A jazz arrangement was recorded by
    Louis Armstrong (vocals) and arranger Gordon Jenkins, with
    "some of Armstrong's most honey-tinged singing." Jenkins would
    in 1956 produce a version with Nat King Cole along the same
    lines.</p>
      <p>In 1958, Edwards had only one session left on his MGM
    contract. Stereo recording was becoming viable and it was
    decided to cut a stereo version of "Game" with a rock and roll
    arrangement. The single was a hit, reaching number one for six
    weeks beginning September 29, 1958, and would br the last song
    to hit number on the R&amp;B Best Seller lists. In November,
    the song hit #1 in Britain. The single helped Edwards revive
    his career for another two years.</p>
      <p>In 1999, the stereo Edwards version featured in the movie
    October Sky, based on the book "Rocket Boys" by Homer Hickam
    Jr. Hickam said it was his favorite song in high school, and
    insisted it be used in the picture.</p>
      <p>"It's All in the Game" has been recorded by different
    artists. Other notable versions include:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
