<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanky_Panky_(The_Raindrops_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanky_Panky_(The_Raindrops_song)</songId>
   <title>Hanky Panky</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tommy_James_and_the_Shondells</artistId>
      <artistName>Tommy James and the Shondells</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1966-07-16</week>
      <week>1966-07-23</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1963</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Vinyl record (7")</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Garage Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:59</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Snap! , Roulette</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jeff Barry</writer>
      <writer>Ellie Greenwich</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Henry Glover</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Hanky Panky" is a song written by Jeff Barry and Ellie
    Greenwich for their group, The Raindrops. It was famously
    remade by rock group Tommy James and the Shondells in 1966, who
    took it to number one in the United States.</p>
      <p>Donald A. Guarisco at Allmusic wrote:</p>
      <p>Barry and Greenwich authored the song in 1963. They were in
    the middle of a recording session, and realized they needed a
    "B" side to a single. (It appeared on the flip of The
    Raindrops' hit "That Boy John.") The duo then went into the
    hall and penned the song in 20 minutes. Barry and Greenwich
    weren't particularly pleased with the song, and deemed it
    inferior to the rest of their work. "I was surprised when
    [Tommy James version] was released," Barry commented to
    Billboard's Fred Bronson, "As far as I was concerned it was a
    terrible song. In my mind it wasn't written to be a song, just
    a B-side.Hanky Panky Summits (earliest version) 1963 Harmon
    1017/Rust 5072 Raindrops (11-63), Tommy James &amp; Shondells
    (2-64)</p>
      <p>Although only a "B" side, "Hanky Panky" became popular with
    garage rock bands, and many started including it in their act.
    James heard it being performed by one such group in a club in
    South Bend, Indiana. "I really only remembered a few lines from
    the song, so when we went to record it, I had to make up the
    rest of the song," he told Bronson, "I just pieced it back
    together from what I remembered."</p>
      <p>James' version was recorded at a local radio station, WNIL
    in Niles, Michigan, and released on the local label, Snap
    Records and sold well in the tri-state area of Michigan,
    Indiana and Illinois. However, lacking national distribution,
    the song quickly disappeared. James moved on, breaking up the
    Shondells, and finishing high school.</p>
      <p>In 1965, unemployed James was contacted by Pittsburgh "Mad
    Mike" Metro, who had started playing "Hanky Panky", and it had
    become popular in that area. Tommy then decided to re-release
    the song, travelling to Pittsburgh where he hired the first
    decent local band he ran into, The Raconteurs, to be the new
    Shondells (the original members declined to re-form).</p>
      <p>After making appearances on TV and clubs in the city, he
    took a master of "Hanky Panky" to New York, where he sold it to
    Roulette Records. "The amazing thing is we did not re-record
    the song," James told Bronson, "I don't think anybody can
    record a song that bad and make it sound good. It had to sound
    amateurish like that. I think if we'd fooled with it too much
    we'd have fouled it up." It was released promptly and took the
    top position of the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 for two weeks in
    July 1966.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
