<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Un-Break_My_Heart 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Un-Break_My_Heart</songId>
   <title>Un-Break My Heart</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toni_Braxton</artistId>
      <artistName>Toni Braxton</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1997-01-04</week>
      <week>1997-01-11</week>
      <week>1997-01-18</week>
      <week>1997-01-25</week>
      <week>1997-02-01</week>
      <week>1997-02-08</week>
      <week>1997-02-15</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/c/c1/ToniBraxtonUnBreakMyHeartCDSingleCover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Toni-Braxton+Un-Break-My-Heart.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Secrets</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 21, 1996 (UK) , November 12, 1996 (U.S.)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1995</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:32</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>LaFace</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Diane Warren</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>David Foster</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Un-Break My Heart" is the second single from Toni Braxton's
    second studio album, 
    <i>Secrets</i>(1996). The ballad was written by music
    impresario Diane Warren and produced by David Foster. The song
    ranked at number ten on The 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 All-Time Top Songs and number three on
    the Top 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs.</p>
      <p>The song became Braxton's second consecutive number-one
    single on the Hot 100 chart. It stayed at number one for eleven
    weeks in a row during late 1996 and early 1997, becoming
    Braxton's biggest hit to date. It also rose to number two on
    the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs. Background vocals
    were performed by R&amp;B singer Shanice Wilson. In the United
    Kingdom, the single was held off the number-one spot by the
    charity band Dunblane's "Knockin' on Heaven's Door"/"Throw
    These Guns Away", who were raising money in the light of the
    Dunblane massacre. After falling before peaking again at number
    two it was held off by the Spice Girls' "2 Become 1". In total
    "Un-Break My Heart" spent twelve weeks inside the UK top
    ten.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by Billie Woodruff and featured
    Braxton mourning the death of her lover, played by model Tyson
    Beckford.</p>
      <p>Several remixes were created; one of which was Hex Hector's
    and Soul Solution's Club Mix, which reached number one on the
    Hot Dance Club Play in the first quarter of 1997.. The remix by
    Frankie Knuckles was also very popular in clubs in the UK and
    was also the version played on BBC Radio 1 and various
    Commercial Radio Station's A-List at the time.</p>
      <p>The song was recorded by Braxton in Spanish as "Regresa a
    Mi" (translating into "Come Back to Me"). "Regresa a Mi" was
    first released as an additional track to the 1996 single
    release of "Un-Break My Heart". Il Divo (with whom Braxton
    would later record the duet "The Time of Our Lives") also
    covered this version in 2004 for their self-titled debut album 
    <i>Il Divo</i>. Mexican singer Yuridia, known for her
    Spanish-language versions of famous English-language ballads,
    also included a version of the song on her album 
    <i>Habla El Corazón</i>. A cover version in Russian was also
    recorded in 1998 by pop singer Alla Gorbacheva, called "Сердце
    не плачь" (transliteration: "Serdtse ne plach"; translation:
    "Heart, Don't Cry"). Others have covered this, including Johnny
    Mathis. Alexander O'Neal covered the song on his 2008 album, 
    <i>Alex Loves</i>. A Hungarian version was recorded by Viktória
    Pintácsi, called "Széttört egy szív" ("A Heart Has Been
    Broken"). Filipino singer Nina also recorded her own version of
    the song for her 2008 album 
    <i>Nina Sings the Hits of Diane Warren</i>. British band
    Serpentine also recorded a hard rock version.</p>
      <p>Braxton won a Grammy Award for Best Female Pop Vocal
    Performance in 1997. She also won Best Female R&amp;B Vocal
    Performance in the same year for the song "You're Makin' Me
    High".</p>
      <p>In a 2006 poll for Channel Five's program "Britain's
    Favourite Break-up Songs", "Un-Break My Heart" was voted
    twenty-seventh.</p>
      <p>The song also appeared as one of the official songs for the
    2006 FIFA World Cup in Germany on the 
    <i>Voices from the FIFA World Cup</i>album.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
