<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cold,_Cold_Heart 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cold,_Cold_Heart</songId>
   <title>Cold, Cold Heart</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tony_Bennett</artistId>
      <artistName>Tony Bennett</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1951-11-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <released>1951</released>
   <recorded>1951</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Country</genre>
      <genre>Honky Tonk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:46</length>
   </lengths>
   <writers>
      <writer>Hank Williams</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Come Away with Me</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Cold, Cold Heart" is a country music and popular music
    song, written by Hank Williams. This blues ballad is both a
    classic of honky tonk and an entry in the Great American
    Songbook.</p>
      <p>Williams first recorded and released the song in 1951, where
    it reached #1 on the country music singles chart. The song
    achingly and artfully describes frustration that the singer's
    love and trust is unreciprocated due to a prior bad experience
    in the other's past.</p>
      <p>That same year it was recorded in a pop version by Tony
    Bennett with a light orchestral arrangement from Percy Faith.
    This recording was released by Columbia Records as catalog
    number 39449. It first reached the Billboard magazine charts on
    July 20, 1951 and lasted 27 weeks on the chart, peaking at
    #1.</p>
      <p>The popularity of Bennett's version has been credited with
    helping to expose both Williams and country music to a wider
    national audience. 
    <i>Allmusic</i>writer Bill Janovitz discusses this unlikely
    combination:</p>
      <p>Williams subsequently telephoned Bennett to say, "Tony, why
    did you ruin my song?" But that was a prank – in fact, Williams
    liked Bennett's version and played it on jukeboxes whenever he
    could. This story is often related with mirth by Bennett in
    interviews and on stage; he still performs the song in concert
    as of 2005.</p>
      <p>In his autobiography 
    <i>The Good Life</i>, Bennett described playing "Cold, Cold
    Heart" at the Grand Ole Opry later in the 1950s. He had brought
    his usual arrangement charts to give to the house musicians who
    would be backing him, but their instrumentation was different
    and they declined the charts. "You sing and we'll follow you,"
    they said, and Bennett says they did so beautifully, once again
    recreating an unlikely artistic merger.</p>
      <p>"Cold, Cold Heart" has since been recorded by countless
    other artists, including Petula Clark, Johnny Cash, Louis
    Armstrong (Decca Records catalog number 27816, recorded
    September 17, 1951), Nat King Cole, Aretha Franklin,Bill Haley
    &amp; His Comets, Rosemary Clooney, Dinah Washington, Norah
    Jones, Lucinda Williams,and Ronnie Hawkins. Freddy Fender had a
    Spanish-language hit with his own translation under the title
    "Tu Frio Corazon".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
