<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Africa_(Toto_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Africa_(Toto_song)</songId>
   <title>Africa</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toto_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Toto</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1983-02-05</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/1/1f/Toto_-_Africa.jpg/200px-Toto_-_Africa.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Toto+Africa.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Toto IV</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1982</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1982</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
      <genre>Progressive Rock</genre>
      <genre>Worldbeat</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:58</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia Records</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Toto</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Africa" is a song by rock band Toto. The song was included
    on their 1982 album 
    <i>Toto IV</i>, and scored number one on the Billboard Hot 100
    chart in February 1983 and number three on the UK Singles Chart
    the same month. The song was written by the band's keyboardist
    David Paich and drummer Jeff Porcaro. David Paich sings both
    verses of the song. Bobby Kimball, Steve Lukather and Paich
    sing the choruses.</p>
      <p>One of Toto's most recognisable songs, "Africa" was almost
    omitted from the 
    <i>Toto IV</i>record prior to its release. Having spent a great
    amount of time producing the tune, the band became so tired of
    the song that they didn’t want it on the album. The song itself
    was very different from anything the band had done before, and
    some members felt that it didn’t sound like Toto.</p>
      <p>“I didn’t think it was very good,” said Steve Lukather
    (Classic Rock Revisited, 2003). “That tells you what can happen
    when we pick our own singles!”</p>
      <p>David Paich, who co-wrote the song with Jeff Porcaro, said
    that it “could have been the beginning of a solo project [for
    me] because it was so different. I thought I’d save
    it…[because] world music wasn’t around then.”</p>
      <p>The initial idea for the song came from David Paich, playing
    on his piano. Jeff explains the idea behind the song: "... a
    white boy is trying to write a song on Africa, but since he's
    never been there, he can only tell what he's seen on TV or
    remembers in the past."</p>
      <p>David Paich says the following: "At the beginning of the
    '80s I watched a late night documentary on TV about all the
    terrible death and suffering of the people in Africa. It both
    moved and appalled me and the pictures just wouldn't leave my
    head. I tried to imagine how I'd feel about if I was there and
    what I'd do."</p>
      <p>Musically the song took quite some time to assemble, as
    David and Jeff explain:</p>
      <p>"On 'Africa' you hear a combination of marimba with GS 1.
    The kalimba is all done with the GS 1; it's six tracks of GS 1
    playing different rhythms. I wrote the song on CS-80, so that
    plays the main part of the entire tune."</p>
      <p>Jeff Porcaro reminisces about how the song's drum track took
    shape:</p>
      <p>"I was about 11 when the New York's World Fair took place,
    and I went to the African pavilion with my family. I saw the
    real thing; I don't know what tribe, but there were these
    drummers playing, and my mind was blown. The thing that blew my
    mind was everybody was playing one part. As a little kid in
    Connecticut, I would see these Puerto Rican and Cuban cats
    jamming in the park. It was the first time I witnessed someone
    playing one beat and not straying from it, like a religious
    experience, where it gets loud, and everyone goes into a
    trance. I have always dug those kind of orchestras, whether it
    be a band or all drummers. But I just love a band of guys
    saying one thing. That's why I loved marching band, and I said,
    'Gee, someday there's going to be a little drum orchestra where
    everybody plays one thing, and you don't stray from it. You do
    it until you drop. You're banished from that land if you move
    from that one part.'</p>
      <p>"So when we were doing 'Africa', I set up a bass drum, snare
    drum and a hi-hat, and Lenny Castro set up right in front of me
    with a conga. We looked at each other and just started playing
    the basic groove.... The backbeat is on 3, so it's a half-time
    feel, and it's 16th notes on the hi-hat. Lenny started playing
    a conga pattern. We played for five minutes on tape, no click,
    no nothing. We just played. And I was singing the bass line for
    'Africa' in my mind, so we had a relative tempo. Lenny and I
    went into the booth and listened back to the five minutes of
    that same boring pattern. We picked out the best two bars that
    we thought were grooving, and we marked those two bars on tape.
    We made another mark four bars before those two bars. Lenny and
    I went back out; I had a cowbell, Lenny had a shaker. They gave
    us two new tracks, and they gave us the cue when they saw the
    first mark go by. Lenny and I started playing to get into the
    groove, so by the time the that fifth bar came – which was the
    first bar of the two bars we marked as the cool bars we liked –
    we were locked, and we overdubbed shaker and cowbell.</p>
      <p>"So there was bass drum, snare drum, hi-hat, two congas, a
    cowbell, and a shaker. We went back in, cut the tape, and made
    a one-bar tape loop that went 'round and 'round and 'round. The
    Linn machine was available to us. Maybe it would have taken two
    minutes to program that in the Linn, and it took about half an
    hour to do this. But a Linn machine doesn't feel like that! So
    we had an analog groove. We took that tape, transferred it onto
    another 24-track for six minutes, and David Paich and I went
    out in the studio. The song started, and I was sitting there
    with a complete drumset, and Paich was playing. When he got to
    the fill before the chorus, I started playing the chorus, and
    when the verse or the intro came back, I stopped playing. Then
    we had piano and drums on tape. You have to realize that there
    are some odd bars in 'Africa', so when you have a one-bar loop
    going, all of a sudden, sometimes Lenny's figure would turn
    around. So Lenny went in and played the song again, but this
    time he changed his pattern a little for the turn-arounds, for
    the fills, for the bridge, for the solo. We kept the original
    part and the new one. Then we had to do bongos, jingle sticks,
    and big shakers doing quarter notes, maybe stacking two tracks
    of sleigh bells, two tracks of big jingle sticks, and two
    tracks of tambourine all down to one track. I was trying to get
    the sounds I would hear Milt Holland or Emil Richards have, or
    the sounds I would hear in a 'National Geographic' special, or
    the ones I heard at the New York World's Fair."</p>
      <p>"Africa" was played on all of Toto's tours from its release
    until the band's breakup in 2008. It was sung by David Paich at
    the 2009 Millennium Development Goals Awards Ceremony.</p>
      <p>The music video was directed by Steve Barron. The story is
    of a researcher in a library (portrayed by band member David
    Paich), looking for clues to a book called 
    <i>Africa</i>. Many scenes include the band performing atop a
    stack of hardcover books.</p>
      <p>The song has been covered in 1982 by Key of Dreams,
    Italo-disco style.</p>
      <p>Singer-songwriters Howie Day and Virginia Coalition and
    Umphrey's McGee perform versions of "Africa" in their live
    shows, and the song has been a popular cover for a cappella
    groups. Tukuleur, a group from Africa, recorded a
    French-language hip hop version of the song titled Afrika.</p>
      <p>SubAudible Hum covered this song for Triple J's Like a
    Version.</p>
      <p>Belgian-born Canadian singer Lara Fabian used this song on
    her Nue Tour in 2001 as an interlude performance to her Nue
    album track "Rio" with one of her backup singers singing lead
    on the verses.</p>
      <p>German band Pyogenesis covered their song in their full
    length album, Mono, ... or will it ever be.</p>
      <p>American guitarist Andy McKee has recorded an instrumental
    version of the song on his 
    <i>Dreamcatcher</i>album.</p>
      <p>Phonte Coleman, member of the rap group Little Brother
    covered the song for his 80's cover album, Zo and Tigallo Love
    the 80's.</p>
      <p>Chris de Burgh covered it on his 2008 covers album 
    <i>Footsteps</i>.</p>
      <p>Lowry recorded a cover of the song for Engine Room
    Recordings' compilation album Guilt by Association Vol. 2,
    which was released in November of 2008.</p>
      <p>Wellington International Ukulele Orchestra recorded a cover
    the song on their 2009 release, The Dreaming EP.</p>
      <p>Olivia Lufkin did a slow cover of the song on her Sea Me
    single.</p>
      <p>Straight No Chaser did an A Capella cover of the song in the
    late 1990's for a bonus track on their album, "Holiday
    Spirits."</p>
      <p>Slovenian a cappella choir Perpetuum Jazzile performed
    Africa on many public appearances.</p>
      <p>"Africa" has been used as a sample in several songs. These
    include:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
