<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Still_Haven%27t_Found_What_I%27m_Looking_For 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Still_Haven%27t_Found_What_I%27m_Looking_For</songId>
   <title>I Still Haven't Found What I'm Looking For</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/U2</artistId>
      <artistName>U2</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-08-08</week>
      <week>1987-08-15</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/3f/Still_havent_found_cover.jpg/200px-Still_havent_found_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/U2+I-Still-Haven-t-Found-What-I-m-Looking-For.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Joshua Tree</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 1987</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
      <format>12" vinyl</format>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>cassette</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Danesmoate in Dublin , Ireland , 1986</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
      <genre>Gospel</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:37</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Island</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>U2 ( music )</writer>
      <writer>Bono ( lyrics )</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Brian Eno</producer>
      <producer>Daniel Lanois</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Still Haven't Found What I'm Looking For" is a song by
    rock band U2. It is the second track from their 1987 album 
    <i>The Joshua Tree</i>and was released as the album's second
    single in May 1987. The song was a hit, becoming the band's
    second consecutive number-one single on the US Hot 100 after
    "With or Without You", while peaking at number six on the UK
    Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>Like much of 
    <i>The Joshua Tree</i>, the song was inspired by the group's
    interest in American music. "I Still Haven't Found What I'm
    Looking For" exhibits influences from gospel music and its
    lyrics describe spiritual yearning. Lead vocalist Bono's vocals
    are in high register and guitarist The Edge plays a chiming
    arpeggio. The song originated from a demo the group used to
    develop a unique drum pattern played by drummer Larry Mullen,
    Jr.</p>
      <p>"I Still Haven't Found What I'm Looking For" was
    well-received by critics. It has subsequently become one of the
    group's most well-known songs and has been performed on many of
    their concert tours. The track has appeared on several of their
    compilations and concert films. In 2004, it was named the 93rd
    greatest song by 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>on their list of "The 500 Greatest Songs of
    All Time".</p>
      <p>"I Still Haven't Found What I'm Looking For" originated from
    a demo variously titled "The Weather Girls" and "Under the
    Weather" that the band recorded in a jam session. Bassist Adam
    Clayton called the demo's melody "a bit of a one-note groove",
    while an unconvinced The Edge, the band's guitarist, compared
    it to "'Eye of the Tiger' played by a reggae band". However,
    the band liked the drum part played by drummer Larry Mullen,
    Jr. Co-producer Daniel Lanois said, "It was a very original
    beat from Larry. We always look for those beats that would
    qualify as a signature for the song. And that certainly was one
    of those. It had this tom-tom thing that he does and nobody
    ever understands. And we just didn't want to let go of that
    beat, it was so unique." Lanois encouraged Mullen to continue
    developing the weird drum pattern beyond the demo. Mullen said
    the beat became even more unusual, and although Lanois
    eventually mixed most of the pattern out to just keep the
    basics, the rhythm became the root of "I Still Haven't Found
    What I'm Looking For".</p>
      <p>"I've always liked gospel music and I encouraged Bono to
    take it to that place...It was a very non-U2 thing to do at the
    time, to go up the street of gospel. I think it opened a door
    for them, to experiment with that territory...[Bono]'s singing
    at the top of his range and there is something very compelling
    about somebody pushing themselves. It's like hearing Aretha
    Franklin almost. It jumps on you and you can't help but feel
    the feeling."</p>
      <p>The group worked on the track at the studio they had set up
    at Georgian mansion Danesmoate in Dublin. Lanois compared the
    creation of the song to constructing a building, first laying
    down the drums as the foundation, then adding additional layers
    piece by piece, before finally "putting in furniture". After
    The Edge wrote a chord sequence and played it on acoustic
    guitar "with a lot of power in the strumming", the group
    attempted to compose a suitable vocal melody, trying out a
    variety of ideas. During a jam session, Bono began singing a
    "classic soul" melody, and it was this addition that made The
    Edge hear the song's potential. At that point, he remembered a
    phrase he had written in a notebook that morning as a possible
    song title, "I still haven't found what I'm looking for". He
    suggests it was influenced by a line from the Bob Dylan song
    "Idiot Wind": "
    <i>You'll find out when you reach the top you're on the
    bottom</i>". He wrote the phrase on a piece of paper and handed
    it to Bono while he was singing. The Edge called the phrase's
    fit with the song "like hand in glove". It became the song's
    refrain and title. From that point on, the song was the first
    piece played to visitors during the recording sessions.</p>
      <p>As recording continued, a number of guitar overdubs were
    added, including an auto-pan effect and a chiming arpeggio to
    modernise the old-style "gospel song". While The Edge was
    improvising guitar parts one day, Bono spotted a "chrome bells"
    guitar hook that he liked. It was added as a counter-melody to
    the song's "muddy shoes" guitar part, and it is this hook that
    The Edge plays during live performances of the song. Bono sang
    in the upper register of his range to add to the feeling of
    spiritual yearning; in the verses he hits a B note, and an A in
    the chorus. Background vocals were provided by The Edge,
    Lanois, and co-producer Brian Eno, their voices being
    multi-tracked. Lanois suggests that his and Eno's involvement
    in the track's creation aided in their background vocals. He
    stated, "You're not going to get that sound of, 'Oh they
    brought in some soul singers' if you know what I mean. Our
    hearts and souls are already there. If we sing it'll sound more
    real." The song's writing was completed relatively early during
    the band's time at Danesmoate. The mix was worked on for a
    while, though, with most of the production team contributing.
    The final mix was completed by Lanois and The Edge in a home
    studio set up at Melbeach, a house purchased by The Edge. They
    mixed it on top of a previous Steve Lillywhite mix, which gave
    the song a phasing sound.</p>
      <p>Lanois says he is very attached to "I Still Haven't Found
    What I'm Looking For" and has, on occasion, joined U2 on stage
    to perform it. The original "Weather Girls" demo, re-titled
    "Desert of Our Love", was included with the 2007 remastered
    version of 
    <i>The Joshua Tree</i>on a bonus disc of outtakes and
    B-sides.</p>
      <p>"Spanish Eyes" was created early during 
    <i>The Joshua Tree</i>sessions. It began as a recording made in
    Adam Clayton's house of Clayton, The Edge, and Larry Mullen Jr.
    playing around with several different elements. The piece
    evolved substantially over the course of an afternoon, but the
    casette and its recording was subsequently lost and forgotten.
    The Edge found the cassette towards the end of the album
    sessions and played it to the rest of the group. The band
    realised that it was a good track, but did not have enough time
    to complete it prior to 
    <i>The Joshua Tree</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s release.</p>
      <p>"Deep in the Heart" stemmed from a three-chord piano piece
    Bono composed on the piano about the last time he had been in
    the family home on Cedarwood Road in Dublin, which his father
    had just sold. The memories of his time living there gave rise
    to many of the lyrical ideas on the song. The Edge and Adam
    Clayton reworked the piece extensively, with Bono later
    describing the finished result as "an almost jazz-like
    improvisation on three chords", also noting that "the rhythm
    section turned it into a very special piece of music." The song
    was recorded in a similar manner to the song "4th of July" from
    U2's 1984 album, 
    <i>The Unforgettable Fire</i>; The Edge and Clayton were
    playing together in a room and unaware that they were being
    recorded on a 4-track cassette machine by the band's assistant,
    Marc Coleman.</p>
      <p>Initially, "Red Hill Mining Town" was planned for release as
    the second single. However, Bono was unable to sing the song
    during pre-tour rehearsals and the band were reportedly unhappy
    with the video shot by Neil Jordan, so "I Still Haven't Found
    What I'm Looking For" became a late choice for the second
    single.</p>
      <p>The music video for the song was filmed on Fremont Street in
    Las Vegas on 12 April 1987. It features the band members
    wandering around while The Edge played an acoustic guitar. The
    music video was later re-released on the 
    <i>U218 Videos</i>compilation DVD.</p>
      <p>Island Records commissioned New York choir director, Dennis
    Bell, to a record a gospel version of the song, and Island
    intended to release it after U2's single. However, Island boss
    Chris Blackwell vetoed the plan saying that a second single
    would look like a money grab. Bell subsequently formed his own
    label and found a distributor for the song. While in Glasgow in
    late July 1987 during The Joshua Tree Tour, Rob Partridge of
    Island Records played the demo put together by Bell of The New
    Voices of Freedom singing the song. In late September, U2
    rehearsed with Bell's choir in Greater Calvary Baptist Church
    in Harlem, and a few days later they performed the song
    together at U2's Madison Square Garden concert. Footage of the
    rehearsal is featured in the 
    <i>Rattle and Hum</i>motion picture, while the Madison Square
    Garden performance appears on the accompanying album.</p>
      <p>A live performance of the song appears in the concert films 
    <i>PopMart: Live from Mexico City</i>and 
    <i>Vertigo 05: Live from Milan</i>. Digital live versions were
    released through iTunes on the 
    <i>Love: Live from the Point Depot</i>and 
    <i>U2.COMmunication</i>albums.</p>
      <p>"I Still Haven't Found What I'm Looking For" received praise
    from many critics. 
    <i>Hot Press</i>journalist Bill Graham described the song as on
    the one-hand as a "smart job of pop handwork, pretty standard
    American radio rock-ballad fare" but that "the band's rhythms
    are far more supple and cultivated than your average bouffant
    HM band of that period". The 
    <i>Sunday Independent</i>suggested that the song was proof the
    band could be commercially accessible, yet not resort to rock
    clichés. 
    <i>NME</i>remarked that the song showed that the band cared
    about something, which made them "special". 
    <i>The Rocket</i>noted that Bono's lyrics about needing
    personal spirituality resulted in a "unique marriage of
    American gospel and Gaelic soul" and that the "human
    perspective he brings to this sentiment rings far truer than
    the rantings of, say, the born-again Bob Dylan". Several
    publications, including 
    <i>The Bergen Record</i>and 
    <i>The Boston Globe</i>, called the track "hypnotic" and
    interpreted it as depicting the band on a spiritual quest.</p>
      <p>In 2004, 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine placed the song at #93 of its list
    of "The 500 Greatest Songs of All Time". In the same year, 
    <i>Los Angeles Times</i>critic Robert Hilburn said it was U2's
    "Let It Be". The staff of the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame
    selected "I Still Haven't Found What I'm Looking For" as one of
    500 Songs that Shaped Rock and Roll.</p>
      <p>"I Still Haven't Found What I'm Looking For" appeared in the
    1999 film 
    <i>Runaway Bride</i>, and it is also heard several times in the
    1994 film 
    <i>Blown Away</i>.</p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Where the Streets Have No
      Name" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"
      <strong class="selflink">
I Still Haven't Found What I'm Looking For
</strong>" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"With or Without
      You" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Bullet the Blue
      Sky" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Running to Stand
      Still" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Red Hill Mining
      Town" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"In God's
      Country" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Trip Through Your
      Wires" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"One Tree
      Hill" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Exit" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Mothers of the
      Disappeared"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Helter
      Skelter" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Van Diemen's
      Land" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Desire" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Hawkmoon 269" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"All Along the
      Watchtower" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"
      <strong class="selflink">
I Still Haven't Found What I'm Looking For
</strong>" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Freedom for My
      People" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Silver and
      Gold" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Pride (In the Name of
      Love)" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Angel of
      Harlem" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Love Rescue
      Me" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"When Love Comes to
      Town" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Heartland" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"God Part II" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"The Star Spangled
      Banner" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Bullet the Blue
      Sky" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"All I Want Is You"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1980: "Another
      Day" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"11 O'Clock Tick
      Tock" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"A Day Without
      Me" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Will
      Follow" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1981: "Fire" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Gloria" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1982: "A
      Celebration" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1983: "New Year's
      Day" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Two Hearts Beat as
      One" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Sunday Bloody
      Sunday" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1984: "Pride (In the Name of
      Love)" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1985: "The Unforgettable
      Fire" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1987: "With or Without
      You" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"
      <strong class="selflink">
I Still Haven't Found What I'm Looking For
</strong>" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Where the Streets Have No
      Name" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"In God's
      Country" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1988: "One Tree
      Hill" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Desire" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Angel of
      Harlem" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1989: "When Love Comes to
      Town" (with B.B. King) •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"All I Want Is You"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1991: "The
      Fly" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Mysterious
      Ways" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1992: "One" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Even Better Than the Real
      Thing" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Who's Gonna Ride Your Wild
      Horses" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1993: "Numb" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Lemon" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Stay (Faraway, So
      Close!)" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1995: "Hold Me, Thrill Me,
      Kiss Me, Kill Me" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Miss Sarajevo" (as
      Passengers) 1997: "Discothèque" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Staring at the
      Sun" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Last Night on
      Earth" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Please" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"If God Will Send His
      Angels" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Mofo" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1998: "Sweetest
      Thing"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2000: "Beautiful
      Day" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2001: "Stuck in a Moment You
      Can't Get Out Of" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Elevation" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Walk On" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2002: "Electrical
      Storm" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2004: "Take Me to the Clouds
      Above" (LMC vs. U2) •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Vertigo" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2005: "All Because of
      You" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Sometimes You Can't Make It
      on Your Own" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"City of Blinding
      Lights" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts
      Club Band" (live, with Paul McCartney) •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2006: "One" (with Mary J.
      Blige) •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"The Saints Are Coming"
      (with Green Day) •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2007: "Window in the
      Skies" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2008: "The Ballad of Ronnie
      Drew" (with The Dubliners, Kíla, and A Band of
      Bowsies) •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2009: "Get on Your
      Boots" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Magnificent" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I'll Go Crazy If I Don't Go
      Crazy Tonight"</span>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
