<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/With_or_Without_You 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/With_or_Without_You</songId>
   <title>With or Without You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/U2</artistId>
      <artistName>U2</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-05-16</week>
      <week>1987-05-23</week>
      <week>1987-05-30</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/d6/Withorwithoutyoucover.jpg/200px-Withorwithoutyoucover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/U2+With-or-Without-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>The Joshua Tree</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>21 March 1987</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
      <format>12" vinyl</format>
      <format>cassette</format>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Danesmoate in Dublin , Ireland , 1986</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:56</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Island</label>
   <producers>
      <producer>Brian Eno</producer>
      <producer>Daniel Lanois</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"With or Without You" is a song by rock band U2. The third
    track from their 1987 album, 
    <i>The Joshua Tree</i>, it was released as the album's first
    single on 21 March 1987. The song was the group's most
    successful single at the time, becoming their first number-one
    hit in the United States by topping the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 for three weeks.</p>
      <p>"With or Without You" features sustained guitar parts played
    by guitarist The Edge with a prototype of the Infinite Guitar,
    along with impassioned vocals by lead singer Bono and a driving
    bassline by bassist Adam Clayton. The song originated from a
    demo recorded in late 1985 that the group continued to work on
    throughout 
    <i>The Joshua Tree</i>sessions. Ostensibly a troubled love
    song, the track's lyrics were inspired by Bono's conflicting
    feelings about the lives he led as a musician and domesticated
    man.</p>
      <p>Critics praised the song upon its release. It is frequently
    performed on the band's tours, and it has appeared on a number
    of their compilation albums and concert films. "With or Without
    You" is U2's second most frequently covered song. In 2004, 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine placed the song at number 131 on
    their list of "The 500 Greatest Songs of All Time".</p>
      <p>In late 1985, U2 convened at a house that drummer Larry
    Mullen, Jr. bought at the time to review material the group had
    written during The Unforgettable Fire Tour. During this time, a
    rough demo of "With or Without You" was written, with lead
    vocalist Bono composing the song's chord sequence. The band
    continued to work on the song at STS Studios, creating many
    different permutations of the track, but not making any
    progress. Guitarist The Edge considered the song at that point
    to be "awful". The track consisted of a Yamaha drum machine
    beat and a bass part played by bassist Adam Clayton using an
    Ibanez bass guitar with a short scale. According to Clayton,
    these early versions of the song sounded too sentimental and
    "very traditional because the chords just went round and round
    and round".</p>
      <p>The sessions for 
    <i>The Joshua Tree</i>started in earnest in 1986, and U2 were
    recording at the Georgian mansion Danesmoate in Dublin in
    August. The group attempted to take the song in a different
    direction and "fuck it up", although Bono was reluctant. Under
    the direction of co-producers Brian Eno and Daniel Lanois, The
    Edge pursued more ambient guitar playing, Clayton turned up the
    volume on his bass, and Mullen experimented with an
    electronically enhanced drum kit. Despite the work they
    continued to put it on the track, the group were considering
    abandoning the song, as they could not find an arrangement they
    liked.</p>
      <p>Bono and his friend Gavin Friday continued to work on the
    song after Lanois and Eno declined to do so. Bono credits
    Friday with rescuing the song and rearranging it, believing it
    could be a hit. Eno added a keyboard arpeggio, similar to the
    one from "Bad". The song's fate was still in doubt when The
    Edge was sent a prototype of the Infinite Guitar by Canadian
    musician Michael Brook, with whom he had collaborated for the
    soundtrack. The instrument allowed sustained notes to be
    played, producing "a similar effect to the E-Bow", but with the
    ability to provide all the "mid-points between no sustain and
    infinite sustain" that the E-Bow cannot provide. The prototype
    included elaborate assembly instructions and as The Edge
    recollects, "one wrongly placed wire and you could get a nasty
    belt of electricity. This piece of gear would have failed even
    the most basic of safety regulations." On subsequent tours, his
    guitar technician occasionally received electric shocks from
    the instrument when preparing it for performances.</p>
      <p>Listening to the backing track to "With or Without You" in
    the control room, Bono and Friday heard the sustained effect
    that The Edge was creating with the Infinite Guitar in the
    other room. The combination of the guitar effect and the
    backing track being played together made an immediate
    impression on those listening. According to Lanois, "I said,
    'That sounded pretty cool,' so we listened back and I said,
    'Jesus it's better than I thought.'" The Edge immediately
    recorded an Infinite Guitar part in two takes. The band
    considers the song's recording to be one of the album sessions'
    breakthrough moments, as it was recorded amidst concerns that
    they had run out of ideas.</p>
      <p>Bono wrote the lyrics while struggling to reconcile his
    responsibilities as both a married man and a musician. His
    attraction to the wanderlust aspects of a musical group was
    often at odds with his domestic life. While writing the lyrics,
    he realized that neither facet of his life defined him, but
    rather the tension between the two did. He explains that the
    final lyric is about "torment" and how repressing desires only
    makes them stronger.</p>
      <p>"With or Without You" is written in the key of D major and
    is played at a tempo of 110 beats per minute. Although certain
    stanzas of lyrics are repeated, the song does not follow a
    traditional verse-chorus form. Lanois says of it, "It has
    tension and builds like one of those great Roy Orbison songs,
    where every section is unique and never repeats. I like that
    kind of sophistication[...]."</p>
      <p>The song begins with a minimal drum beat by Mullen playing
    eighth notes, while a backing track, Eno's synthesiser, plays a
    "rippling" triplet arpeggio of the chord D major. A high
    sustained guitar part (played by The Edge's Infinite Guitar)
    enters, played "dry" in the left channel before reverberating
    on the right. At 0:09, Clayton's bass guitar begins to play
    eighth notes in time with the kick drum, and the song's
    four-bar sequence of the chord progression D-A-Bm-G, begins.
    This chord progression is never explicitly played but is
    "implied" by the root notes played by Clayton and the guitar
    parts of The Edge.</p>
      <p>"Notes actually 
    <i>do</i>mean something. They have power. I think of notes as
    being expensive. You don't just throw them around. I find the
    ones that do the best job and that's what I use. I suppose I'm
    a minimalist instinctively. I don't like to be inefficient if I
    can get away with it. Like on the end of 'With or Without You'.
    My instinct was to go with something very simple... I still
    think it's sort of brave, because the end of "With or Without
    You" could have been so much bigger, so much more of a climax,
    but there's this power to it which I think is even more potent
    because it's held back."</p>
      <p>Bono's vocals enter at 0:28, and they are in a lower
    register than most of his past vocals. He stays below the
    middle C for the first two and a half stanzas, centering his
    melody on the mediant F. At the end of each of the first two
    stanzas, his vocals drop an octave, from A to A. At 0:58, an
    additional sustained guitar part joins the mix. The drums
    increase in intensity at 1:45, before The Edge begins playing
    the song's signature guitar riff at 1:53. The riff, a perfect
    fifth opening to a sixth, features a prominent use of delay.
    When the riff is played, it is answered by Bono singing "And
    you give yourself away", a line on which backing vocals appear
    at 2:06 and 2:32.</p>
      <p>A stanza begins in which Bono sings the song's title in a
    high, passionate voice as the drums get heavier. At 3:03, the
    song bursts out in emotion as Bono begins open-throated
    "Oh-oh-oh-ohh" vocals, which are double-tracked, and the rhythm
    increases to play sixteenth notes on the guitar, cymbals, and
    tambourine. After another stanza of Bono repeating the song's
    title, the music dies down at 3:38 to a similar state as it was
    at the beginning of the song. Ten seconds later, Bono sings in
    a falsetto while a bass synthesiser doubles the bass guitar.
    After the vocals complete, The Edge begins a simple guitar
    figure. He explained that its understated nature was meant to
    oppose the temptation to play an intricate guitar solo as an
    ending. The second time the figure is played, the signature
    guitar riff from earlier re-appears and the song regains some
    of its intensity. The song concludes with a fade-out.</p>
      <p>The lyrics ostensibly describe a troubled relationship
    between two lovers. The 
    <i>Washington Post</i>interpreted the song as both an acerbic
    love song and a tune lamenting the moral contradictions one
    faces with their religious faith. Although the lyrics have been
    interpreted in religious contexts, Bono explained that the
    lyrics had romantic intentions, saying, "[..] There's nothing
    more revolutionary than two people loving each other. One,
    'cause it's so uncommon these days, and two, 'cause it's so
    difficult to do." In 1987, Bono explained that "And you give
    yourself away" lyric refers to how he sometimes feels exposed
    being in U2, and that his openness, both to the public and
    music press, can do damage to the group. Author Niall Stokes
    interpreted the line as encompassing the theme of "surrendering
    the ego" to one's love and spiritual faith.</p>
      <p>According to Bono, the song was heavily influenced by Scott
    Walker's album 
    <i>Climate of Hunter.</i>Clayton referred to the song's nature
    as a challenge to radio, saying, "You don't expect it there [on
    radio]. In church perhaps."</p>
      <p>United States radio stations were allowed to play the song
    at 11:30 a.m. on 4 March 1987, with strong warnings by Island
    Records against playing it earlier. It was released as 
    <i>The Joshua Tree</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s first single was on
    21 March 1987, two and half weeks after the album was released.
    It was their first single to be widely issued on CD.</p>
      <p>"With or Without You" was a huge commercial success,
    becoming the group's first single to top the US 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 chart. The song spent three weeks atop
    the chart, beginning on 16 May 1987. The song also topped 
    <i>Billboard</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s Album Rock Tracks
    chart, Canada's Top 100, and the Irish Singles Chart. According
    to 
    <i>Billboard</i>, the song was the group's breakthrough with
    American audiences. The single peaked at number four in the UK,
    and number two on the Dutch MegaCharts Top 40. In addition, the
    song spent eleven weeks in the top 75 of the UK Singles Chart.
    In 2009, the song re-entered the UK Singles Chart at number 43
    on the week ending 31 May, based on download sales due to Shaun
    Smith's performance of the song in the semi-final of 
    <i>Britain's Got Talent</i>.</p>
      <p>The video was shot in Dublin in February 1987 and was
    co-directed by Meiert Avis and Matt Mahurin. It includes
    abstracts shots of dancer Morleigh Steinberg edited in between
    shots of the band playing the song.</p>
      <p>"With or Without You" was first played live at the second
    show on the Joshua Tree Tour on 4 April 1987, and was a regular
    for the rest of that tour. It was played at most shows on
    1989's Lovetown Tour. During these tours, two extensions to the
    song not present on the studio version were played: an extra
    verse with lyrics that typically read "We'll shine like stars
    in the summer night/We'll shine like stars in the winter
    light/One heart, one hope, one love" or modifications thereof,
    which appears on the 
    <i>Rattle and Hum</i>movie; and a snippet of Joy Division's
    "Love Will Tear Us Apart" (along with the "shine like stars"
    lyrics) which can be heard in the live album and concert film 
    <i>Live from Paris</i>. Since the PopMart Tour, it has been
    more common for Bono to repeat the "Ohh" at the climax of the
    song, with the "shine like stars" verse sung rarely.</p>
      <p>"With or Without You" was played at most Zoo TV Tour
    concerts and every concert on the PopMart Tour. It was dropped
    from the setlist during the third leg of the Elevation Tour. It
    was initially a rare inclusion during the Vertigo Tour - over
    the two months of the tour's first leg, it was only played four
    times. It became a regular concert inclusion during stadium
    concerts on the second leg in Europe and remained in the
    setlist for the third leg. It has been played on every night of
    the U2 360° Tour, occasionally with the "shine like stars"
    coda.</p>
      <p>Live performances of the song also appear in the group's
    concert films 
    <i>Zoo TV: Live from Sydney</i>, 
    <i>PopMart: Live from Mexico City</i>, 
    <i>Elevation 2001: Live from Boston</i>, 
    <i>U2 Go Home: Live from Slane Castle</i>, 
    <i>Vertigo 05: Live from Milan</i>, and 
    <i>U2 3D</i>.</p>
      <p>"With or Without You" received critical praise upon the
    release of 
    <i>The Joshua Tree</i>. 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>called it an "inventively arranged tune...
    that builds from a soothing beginning to a resounding climax".
    Bill Graham of 
    <i>Hot Press</i>praised the song, suggesting it may be Bono's
    "most controlled vocal, building from an almost conversational
    first verse over a bare rhythm section to a soul-baring
    confession". Graham suggested the lyric "And you give yourself
    away" was essential to U2's message. The 
    <i>Sunday Independent</i>suggested that the song was proof the
    band could be commercially accessible, yet not resort to rock
    clichés. 
    <i>NME</i>called it "some kind of love song" and found musical
    and lyrical symmetry between the song and the group's 1981
    album 
    <i>October</i>. Readers of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>voted "With or Without You" the "Best
    Single" in a 1987 end-of-year poll.</p>
      <p>"With or Without You" has become one of U2's most well-known
    songs, and it often appears in music critics' rankings of the
    best songs of all-time. In 2000, the song appeared at number
    eight on 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s list of "100
    Greatest Pop Songs", compiled by 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>and MTV music critics to rank songs
    released since The Beatles' breakthrough. In 2004, 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>magazine placed the song at number 131 on
    its list of "The 500 Greatest Songs of All Time". The song
    subsequently appeared as one of seven U2 songs in the 2006
    music reference book 
    <i>1001 Songs: The Great Songs of All Time and the Artists,
    Stories, and Secrets</i>. U2 have included the song on two of
    their compilation albums, 
    <i>The Best of 1980–1990</i>and 
    <i>U218 Singles</i>.</p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Where the Streets Have No
      Name" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Still Haven't Found What
      I'm Looking For" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"
      <strong class="selflink">
With or Without You
</strong>" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Bullet the Blue
      Sky" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Running to Stand
      Still" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Red Hill Mining
      Town" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"In God's
      Country" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Trip Through Your
      Wires" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"One Tree
      Hill" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Exit" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Mothers of the
      Disappeared"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1980: "Another
      Day" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"11 O'Clock Tick
      Tock" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"A Day Without
      Me" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Will
      Follow" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1981: "Fire" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Gloria" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1982: "A
      Celebration" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1983: "New Year's
      Day" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Two Hearts Beat as
      One" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Sunday Bloody
      Sunday" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1984: "Pride (In the Name of
      Love)" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1985: "The Unforgettable
      Fire" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1987: "
      <strong class="selflink">
With or Without You
</strong>" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Still Haven't Found What
      I'm Looking For" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Where the Streets Have No
      Name" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"In God's
      Country" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1988: "One Tree
      Hill" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Desire" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Angel of
      Harlem" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1989: "When Love Comes to
      Town" (with B.B. King) •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"All I Want Is You"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1991: "The
      Fly" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Mysterious
      Ways" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1992: "One" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Even Better Than the Real
      Thing" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Who's Gonna Ride Your Wild
      Horses" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1993: "Numb" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Lemon" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Stay (Faraway, So
      Close!)" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1995: "Hold Me, Thrill Me,
      Kiss Me, Kill Me" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Miss Sarajevo" (as
      Passengers) 1997: "Discothèque" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Staring at the
      Sun" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Last Night on
      Earth" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Please" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"If God Will Send His
      Angels" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Mofo" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">1998: "Sweetest
      Thing"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2000: "Beautiful
      Day" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2001: "Stuck in a Moment You
      Can't Get Out Of" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Elevation" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Walk On" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2002: "Electrical
      Storm" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2004: "Take Me to the Clouds
      Above" (LMC vs. U2) •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Vertigo" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2005: "All Because of
      You" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Sometimes You Can't Make It
      on Your Own" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"City of Blinding
      Lights" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts
      Club Band" (live, with Paul McCartney) •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2006: "One" (with Mary J.
      Blige) •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"The Saints Are Coming"
      (with Green Day) •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2007: "Window in the
      Skies" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2008: "The Ballad of Ronnie
      Drew" (with The Dubliners, Kíla, and A Band of
      Bowsies) •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">2009: "Get on Your
      Boots" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Magnificent" •</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I'll Go Crazy If I Don't Go
      Crazy Tonight"</span>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
