<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_Red_Wine 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_Red_Wine</songId>
   <title>Red Red Wine</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UB40</artistId>
      <artistName>UB40</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1988-10-15</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Just for You</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 13, 1968  (1968-04-13)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <label>Bang</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Neil Diamond</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jeff Barry</producer>
      <producer>Ellie Greenwich</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Red Red Wine" is a song written and originally recorded by
    Neil Diamond, that was then covered by Tony Tribe and more
    famously by UB40. In the song, the singer finds drinking red
    wine is the only way to forget a lost love.</p>
      <p>Diamond's version reached number sixty-three on the
    Billboard Hot 100 chart in 1968. The single version of his
    recording includes a backing choir not found in any other
    version. It was also remixed for the compilation album, 
    <i>Classics: The Early Years</i>. That same year, Jimmy James
    and The Vagabonds released a cover version for the UK market.
    It charted at number thirty-six.</p>
      <p>Tony Tribe, a Jamaican rocksteady singer, recorded a
    reggae-influenced version in 1969 which reached number
    forty-six in the UK Singles Chart. Also in 1969 the song was
    covered by swamp rock/pop artist Charles Mann. In 1970, a
    remake by Vic Dana became a minor Billboard Hot 100 hit. In
    early 1972, country singer Roy Drusky enjoyed a Top 20 hit with
    his cover version.</p>
      <p>UB40 made their rendition for their cover versions album 
    <i>Labour of Love</i>. According to the band, they were only
    familiar with Tony Tribe's version, and their version featured
    a lighter, reggae-style flavor compared to Diamond's somber,
    acoustic ballad. This version reached number one in the UK
    chart in August 1983, and number thirty-four in the U.S. in
    March 1984. This cover version adds a toasted verse by UB40
    member Astro, opening: "Red Red Wine, you make me feel so
    fine/You keep me rocking all of the time".</p>
      <p>The song received a second life in the US in 1988 when DJ
    Bobby Stark started playing it at a dance club in Atlanta
    called Scenario. UB40's label, A&amp;M Records, re-released the
    song as a single, and it reached number one on the Billboard
    Hot 100 that October.</p>
      <p>Diamond later performed a UB40-inspired version of the song
    on tour. In it, Diamond makes a slight complaint about UB40
    misunderstanding the lyrics because of the happy tone to their
    version. This version was released on Diamond's 
    <i>The Greatest Hits (1966-1992)</i>.</p>
      <p>The Hobos did a cover of this song on their 2004 double
    album 
    <i>Radio Jah Jah</i>. "Red Red Wine" was also performed by
    Peter Tetteroo, former singer of Tee Set, a Dutch band, in
    1968. The song has also been performed by Cas Haley along with
    UB40 on the last episode of the season 2 show 
    <i>America's Got Talent</i>.</p>
      <p>In 2001, singer Elan released a dancehall version on the 
    <i>Buy Out Riddim</i>instrumental, best known performed by Sean
    Paul, with the song entitled, "Like Glue". This was the first
    time the song was performed on a totally different instrumental
    tracking. The lyrics were also re-written. In 2007, Sean
    Kingston sampled part of this instrumental for his second
    single, "Me Love".Me Love is actually sampled from a Led
    Zepplin Song Dyer Maker. In 2008, Sizzla also released a
    dancehall single ("No Time To Gaze") based on the UB40
    version.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
