<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Can%27t_Help_Falling_in_Love 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Can%27t_Help_Falling_in_Love</songId>
   <title>Can't Help Falling in Love</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UB40</artistId>
      <artistName>UB40</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1993-07-24</week>
      <week>1993-07-31</week>
      <week>1993-08-07</week>
      <week>1993-08-14</week>
      <week>1993-08-21</week>
      <week>1993-08-28</week>
      <week>1993-09-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/3d/Elvis_-_Rock_a_Hula.jpg/200px-Elvis_-_Rock_a_Hula.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/UB40+Can-t-Help-Falling-in-Love.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Blue Hawaii</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>October 1, 1961</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Blue Eyed Soul</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:59</length>
   </lengths>
   <writers>
      <writer>George David Weiss</writer>
      <writer>Hugo E. Peretti</writer>
      <writer>Luigi Creatore</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Can't Help Falling in Love", by George Weiss, Hugo Peretti
    and Luigi Creatore, is a pop song based on "Plaisir d'amour" by
    Jean Paul Egide Martini. It was adapted for inclusion in the
    1961 film 
    <i>Blue Hawaii</i>, starring Elvis Presley.</p>
      <p>Presley's version of the song, which topped the British
    charts in 1962, has appeared in numerous other films, including
    
    <i>Coyote Ugly</i>and Walt Disney's 
    <i>Lilo and Stitch</i>. According to the RIAA, the single is
    certified Platinum, for US sales in excess of one million
    copies.</p>
      <p>During Presley's late sixties and 1970s live performances,
    the song was performed invariably as the show's finale. Most
    notably, it was also sung in the live segment of his 1968 NBC
    television special, and as the closer for his 1973 Global
    telecast, "Aloha from Hawaii".</p>
      <p>During the following four decades, it went on to be covered
    by numerous artists, most notably by the UK group UB40, whose
    1993 version also topped the UK singles charts.</p>
      <p>It was the first single from their 1993 album 
    <i>Promises and Lies</i>. The song was released on May 10,
    1993, in the majority of countries worldwide. It was a great
    success, reaching number one in Austria, the Netherlands,
    Sweden, UK, the US, Australia, and New Zealand. The single
    version of the song has a slightly different backing rhythm and
    melody.</p>
      <p>The song appears on the soundtrack to the movie 
    <i>Sliver</i>.</p>
      <p>The song was the A*Teens's first single from their third
    album 
    <i>Pop 'til You Drop!</i>, as well as for the 
    <i>Lilo &amp; Stitch</i>movie soundtrack, which was originally
    scheduled to include several Presley tracks, the A*Teens
    picking it for inclusion in the soundtrack. The video had thus
    tremendous exposure on several television channels, with the
    A*Teens eventually including the song in their third album. As
    a result, the song had two music videos, one to promote the
    Disney movie, the other for the album.</p>
      <p>The song was a radio hit in the United States, and reached
    #12 in Sweden, #16 in Argentina and #41 in Australia. Despite
    the success of the song overseas, it failed to attract the rest
    of the Latin American public, due to the fact that there was a
    Spanish version of the song, performed by the Argentine group,
    Bandana. In addition, the A*Teens' version of the song was
    overshadowed by the promotion of Bandana's version.</p>
      <p>The video was directed by Gregory Dark and filmed in Los
    Angeles, California. It had two different versions. The "Disney
    Version", as the fans named it, features scenes of the movie,
    and also new scenes of the A*Teens with beach costumes. The
    "A*Teens Version" of the video, features the A*Teens on the
    white background with different close-ups and choreography, and
    scenes with puppies and different costumes.</p>
      <p>Tracks marked + are not A*Teens tracks.</p>
      <p>European 2-Track CD Single</p>
      <p>European/Australian CD Maxi</p>
      <p>Montgomery Clift play and sing the song in the film The
    Heiress (1949, directed by William Wyler) A*teens - Lilo and
    Stitch</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
