<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/We_Are_the_World 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/We_Are_the_World</songId>
   <title>We Are the World</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/USA_for_Africa</artistId>
      <artistName>USA for Africa</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1985-04-13</week>
      <week>1985-04-20</week>
      <week>1985-04-27</week>
      <week>1985-05-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/81/We_Are_the_World_alternative_cover.jpg/200px-We_Are_the_World_alternative_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/USA-for-Africa+We-Are-the-World.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>We Are the World</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 7, 1985</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>January 28, 1985</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>7:02</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Michael Jackson</writer>
      <writer>Lionel Richie</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Quincy Jones</producer>
      <producer>Michael Omartian</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>
         <i>This article is about the original 1985 song. See We Are
      the World 25 for Haiti for the 2010 celebrity remake and We
      Are The World 25 for Haiti (YouTube Edition) for the 2010
      YouTube collaboration.</i>
      </p>
      <p>"We Are the World" is a song and charity single originally
    recorded by the supergroup USA for Africa in 1985. It was
    written by Michael Jackson and Lionel Richie, and co-produced
    by Quincy Jones and Michael Omartian for the album 
    <i>We Are the World</i>. Following Band Aid's "Do They Know
    It's Christmas?" project in the UK, an idea for the creation of
    an American benefit single for African famine relief came from
    activist Harry Belafonte, who, along with fundraiser Ken
    Kragen, was instrumental in bringing the vision to reality.
    Several musicians were contacted by the pair, before Jackson
    and Richie were assigned the task of writing the song.
    Following several months of working together, the duo completed
    the writing of "We Are the World" one night before the song's
    first recording session, in early 1985. The last recording
    session for the song was held on February 28, 1985. The
    historic event brought together some of the most famous artists
    in the music industry at the time.</p>
      <p>The song was released on March 7, 1985, as the only single
    from the album. A worldwide commercial success, it topped music
    charts throughout the world and became the fastest-selling
    American pop single in history. The first ever single to be
    certified multi-platinum, "We Are the World" received a 4×
    certification by the Recording Industry Association of America.
    However, the song garnered mixed reviews from journalists,
    music critics and the public. Fans enjoyed hearing racially and
    musically diverse recording artists singing together on one
    track, and felt satisfied in buying "We Are the World", knowing
    that the money was going to charity. Other individuals,
    including many commentators in the rock press, were
    disappointed that the song did not challenge listeners as to
    why famines occur in the first place, and felt that the lyrics
    were self-aggrandizing.</p>
      <p>Awarded numerous honors—including three Grammy Awards, one
    American Music Award and a People's Choice Award—the song was
    promoted with a critically received music video, a home video,
    a special edition magazine, a simulcast, and several books,
    posters and shirts. The promotion and merchandise aided the
    success of "We Are the World", which was eventually named the
    biggest-selling single of all time. As of 2009, it has sold
    more than 20 million units and raised over
    $63 million for humanitarian aid in Africa and the US.</p>
      <p>Following the devastation caused by the magnitude 7.0 M
    earthquake in Haiti on January 12, 2010, a remake of the song
    by another all-star cast of singers was recorded on February 1,
    2010. Entitled "We Are the World 25 for Haiti", it was released
    as a single on February 12, 2010, and proceeds from the record
    will aid survivors in the impoverished country. "We Are the
    World" has demonstrated that diverse musicians can productively
    work together, and has further influenced the movement within
    pop music to create songs that address humane concerns.</p>
      <p>Before the writing of "We Are the World", American
    entertainer and social activist Harry Belafonte had sought for
    some time to have a song recorded by the most famous artists in
    the music industry at the time. He planned to have the proceeds
    donated to a new organization called United Support of Artists
    for Africa (USA for Africa). The non-profit foundation would
    then feed and relieve starving people in Africa, specifically
    Ethiopia, where around one million people died during the
    country's 1984–1985 famine. The idea followed Band Aid's "Do
    They Know It's Christmas" project in the UK, which Belafonte
    had heard about. In the activist's plans, money would also be
    set aside to help eliminate hunger in the United States of
    America. Entertainment manager and fellow fundraiser Ken Kragen
    was contacted by Belafonte, who asked for singers Lionel Richie
    and Kenny Rogers—Kragen's clients—to participate in Belafonte's
    musical endeavor. Kragen and the two musicians agreed to help
    with Belafonte's mission, and in turn, enlisted the cooperation
    of Stevie Wonder, to add more "name value" to their project.
    Quincy Jones was drafted to co-produce the song, taking time
    out from his work on 
    <i>The Color Purple</i>. Richie also telephoned Michael
    Jackson, who had just released the commercially successful 
    <i>Thriller</i>album and had concluded a tour with his
    brothers.</p>
      <p>Jackson revealed to Richie that he not only wanted to sing
    the song, but to participate in its writing as well. To begin
    with, "We Are the World" was to be written by Jackson, Richie
    and Wonder. As Wonder had limited time to work on the project,
    Jackson and Richie proceeded to write "We Are the World"
    themselves. They began work on the song's creation at
    Hayvenhurst, the Encino home of Jackson and his family. For a
    week, the two spent every night working on lyrics and melodies
    in the singer's bedroom. They knew that they wanted a song
    which would be easy to sing and memorable. The pair wanted to
    create an anthem. Jackson's older sister, La Toya, watched
    the two work on the song, and later contended that Richie only
    wrote a few lines for the track. She stated that her younger
    brother wrote 99 percent of the lyrics, "but he's never
    felt it necessary to say that". La Toya further commented
    on the song's creation in an interview with the American
    celebrity news magazine 
    <i>People</i>. "I'd go into the room while they were writing
    and it would be very quiet, which is odd, since Michael's
    usually very cheery when he works. It was very emotional for
    them."</p>
      <p>Richie had recorded two melodies for "We Are the World",
    which Jackson took, adding music and words to the song in the
    same day. Jackson stated, "I love working quickly. I went ahead
    without even Lionel knowing, I couldn't wait. I went in and
    came out the same night with the song completed—drums, piano,
    strings, and words to the chorus." Jackson then presented his
    demo to Richie and Jones, who were both shocked; they did not
    expect the pop star to see the structure of the song so
    quickly. The next meetings between Jackson and Richie were
    unfruitful; the pair did not produce any additional vocals and
    got no work done. It was not until the night of January 21,
    1985, that Richie and Jackson completed the lyrics and melody
    of "We Are the World" within two and a half hours, one night
    before the song's first recording session.</p>
      <p>The first night of recording, January 22, 1985, had tight
    security on hand, as Richie, Jackson, Wonder and Jones started
    work on "We Are the World" at Kenny Rogers' Lion Share
    Recording Studio. The studio, on Beverly Boulevard in
    California, was filled with musicians, technicians, video
    crews, retinues, assistants and organizers as the four
    musicians entered. To begin the night, a "vocal guide" of "We
    Are the World" was recorded by Richie and Jackson and
    duplicated on tape for each of the invited performers. The
    guide was recorded on the sixth take, as Quincy Jones felt that
    there was too much "thought" in the previous versions.</p>
      <p>Following their work on the vocal guide, Jackson and Jones
    began thinking of alternatives for the line "There's a chance
    we're taking, we're taking our own lives": the pair were
    concerned that the latter part of the line would be considered
    a reference to suicide. As the group listened to a playback of
    the chorus, Richie declared that the last part of the line
    should be changed to "We're 'saving' our own lives", which his
    fellow musicians agreed with. Producer Jones also suggested
    altering the former part of the line. "One thing we don't want
    to do, especially with this group, is look like we're patting
    ourselves on the back. So it's really, 'There's a 
    <i>choice</i>we're making.'" At around 1:30 am, the four
    musicians ended the night by finishing a chorus of melodic
    vocalizations, including the sound "sha-lum sha-lin-gay". Jones
    told the group that they were not to add anything else to the
    tape. "If we get too good, someone's gonna start playing it on
    the radio", he announced.</p>
      <p>On January 24, 1985, after a day of rest, Jones shipped
    Richie and Jackson's vocal guide to all of the artists who
    would be involved in "We Are the World"'s recording. Enclosed
    in the package was a letter from Jones, addressed to "My Fellow
    Artists":</p>
      <p>The cassettes are numbered, and I can't express how
    important it is not to let this material out of your hands.
    Please do not make copies, and return this cassette the night
    of the 28th. In the years to come, when your children ask,
    'What did mommy and daddy do for the war against world
    famine?', you can say proudly, 
    <i>this</i>was your contribution.</p>
      <p>Ken Kragen chaired a production meeting at a bungalow off
    Sunset Boulevard on January 25, 1985. There, Kragen and his
    team addressed where the song would be completed by the
    supergroup of musicians. He stated, "The single most damaging
    piece of information is where we're doing this. If that shows
    up anywhere, we've got a chaotic situation that could totally
    destroy the project. The moment a Prince, a Michael Jackson, a
    Bob Dylan—I guarantee you!—drives up and sees a mob around that
    studio, he will never come in." On the same night, Quincy
    Jones' associate producer and vocal arranger, Tom Bahler, was
    given the task of matching each solo line with the right voice.
    Bahler stated, "It's like vocal arranging in a perfect world".
    Jones disagreed, stating that the task was like "putting a
    watermelon in a Coke bottle". The following evening, Lionel
    Richie held a "choreography" session at his home, where it was
    decided who would stand where.</p>
      <p>The final night of recording was held on January 28, 1985,
    at A&amp;M Recording Studios in Hollywood, California. Michael
    Jackson arrived at 9 pm, earlier than the other artists,
    to record his solo section and record a vocal chorus by
    himself. He was subsequently joined in the recording studio by
    the remaining USA for Africa artists, which included Ray
    Charles, Billy Joel, Diana Ross, Cyndi Lauper, Bruce
    Springsteen and Smokey Robinson. Also in attendance were five
    of Jackson's siblings: Jackie, La Toya, Marlon, Randy and
    Tito. Many of the participants came straight from an American
    Music Award ceremony, which had been held that same night.
    Invited musician Prince, who would have had a part in which he
    and Michael Jackson sang to each other, did not attend the
    recording session. The reason given for his absence has varied.
    One newspaper claimed that the singer did not want to record
    with other acts. Another report, from the time of "We Are the
    World"'s recording, suggested that the musician did not want to
    partake in the session because organizer Bob Geldof called him
    a "creep". Prince did, however, donate an exclusive track, "4
    The Tears In Your Eyes", for the 
    <i>We Are the World</i>album. In all, more than 45 of America's
    top musicians participated in the recording, and another 50 had
    to be turned away. Upon entering the recording studio, the
    musicians were greeted by a sign pinned to the door which read,
    "Please check your egos at the door". They were also greeted by
    Stevie Wonder, who proclaimed that if the recording was not
    completed in one take, he and Ray Charles, two blind men, would
    drive everybody home.</p>
      <p>I think what's happening in Africa is a crime of historic
    proportions ... You walk into one of the corrugated iron
    huts and you see meningitis and malaria and typhoid buzzing
    around the air. And you see dead bodies lying side by side with
    the live ones. In some of the camps you see 15 bags of
    flour for 27,000 people. And I assume that's why we're all
    here tonight.</p>
      <p>Each of the performers took his or her position at around
    10.30 pm and began to sing. Several hours passed before
    Stevie Wonder announced that he would like to substitute the
    "sha-lum sha-lin-gay" sound for a line in Swahili. At this
    point, Waylon Jennings left the recording studio and never
    returned; he allegedly felt that no "good ole boy" ever sang in
    Swahili. A heated debate ensued, in which several artists
    rejected the suggestion. The "sha-lum sha-lin-gay" sound ran
    into opposition as well and was subsequently removed from the
    song. The participants eventually decided to sing something
    meaningful in English. They chose to sing the new line "One
    world, Our children", which most of the participants
    enjoyed.</p>
      <p>In the early hours of the morning, two Ethiopian women,
    guests of Stevie Wonder, were brought into the recording
    studio—it had been decided that a portion of the proceeds
    raised would be used to bring aid to those affected by the
    recent famine in Ethiopia. They thanked the singers on behalf
    of their country, bringing several artists to tears, before
    being led from the room. Wonder attempted to lighten the mood,
    by joking that the recording session gave him a chance to "see"
    fellow blind musician Ray Charles. "We just sort of bumped into
    each other!" The solo parts of the song were recorded without
    any problems. The final version of "We Are the World" was
    completed at 8 am.</p>
      <p>"We Are the World" is sung from a first person viewpoint,
    allowing the audience to "internalize" the message by singing
    the word 
    <i>we</i>together. It has been described as "an appeal to human
    compassion". The first lines in the song's repetitive chorus
    proclaim, "We are the world, we are the children, we are the
    ones who make a brighter day, so let's start giving". "We Are
    the World" opens with Lionel Richie, Stevie Wonder, Paul Simon,
    Kenny Rogers, James Ingram, Tina Turner and Billy Joel singing
    the first verse. Michael Jackson and Diana Ross follow,
    completing the first chorus together. Dionne Warwick, Willie
    Nelson and Al Jarreau sing the second verse, before Bruce
    Springsteen, Kenny Loggins, Steve Perry and Daryl Hall go
    through the second chorus. Co-writer Jackson, Huey Lewis, Cyndi
    Lauper and Kim Carnes follow with the song's bridge. This
    structuring of the song is said to "create a sense of
    continuous surprise and emotional buildup". "We Are the World"
    concludes with Bob Dylan and Ray Charles singing a full chorus,
    Wonder and Springsteen duetting, and ad libs from Charles and
    Ingram.</p>
      <p>On March 7, 1985, "We Are the World" was released as a
    single, in both 7" and 12" format. The song was the only one
    released from the 
    <i>We Are the World</i>album and became a chart success around
    the world. In the US, it was a number one hit on the R&amp;B
    singles chart, the Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks chart and the
    Hot 100, where it remained for a month. The single had
    initially debuted at number 21 on the Hot 100, the highest
    entry since Michael Jackson's "Thriller" entered the charts at
    number 21 the year before. It took four weeks for the song to
    claim the number one spot—half the time a single would normally
    have taken to reach its charting peak. "We Are the World" might
    have reached the top of the Hot 100 chart sooner, if it were
    not for the success of Phil Collins' "One More Night", which
    received a significant level of support from both pop and rock
    listeners. "We Are the World" also entered 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Top Rock Tracks and Hot Country Singles
    charts, where it peaked at numbers 27 and 76 respectively. The
    song became the first single since The Beatles' "Let It Be" to
    enter 
    <i>Billboard</i>
         <span style="padding-left:0.1em;">'</span>s Top 5 within two
    weeks of release. Outside of the US, the single reached number
    one in France, New Zealand, The Netherlands, Norway, Sweden,
    Switzerland and the UK. The song peaked at number 2 in Austria,
    number 12 in Italy and number 18 in Denmark.</p>
      <p>The single was also a commercial success; the initial
    shipment of 800,000 "We Are the World" records sold out within
    three days of release. The record became the fastest-selling
    American pop single in history. At one Tower Records store on
    Sunset Boulevard in West Hollywood, 1,000 copies of the
    song were sold in two days. Store worker Richard Petitpas
    commented, "A number one single sells about 100 to
    125 copies a week. This is absolutely unheard of." By the
    end of 1985, "We Are the World" had become the best selling
    single of the year. Five years later it was revealed that the
    song had become the biggest single of the 1980s. "We Are the
    World" was eventually cited as the biggest selling single in
    both US and pop music history. The song became the first ever
    single to be certified multi-platinum; it received a 4×
    certification by the Recording Industry Association of America.
    The estimated global sales of "We Are the World" are said to be
    20 million.</p>
      <p>Following its release, "We Are the World" received mixed
    reviews from journalists, music critics and the public.
    American journalist Greil Marcus felt that the song sounded
    like a Pepsi jingle. He wrote, "... the constant repetition of
    'There's a choice we're making' conflates with Pepsi's
    trademarked 'The choice of a new generation' in a way that, on
    the part of Pepsi-contracted song writers Michael Jackson and
    Lionel Richie, is certainly not intentional, and even more
    certainly beyond the realm of serendipity." Marcus added, "In
    the realm of contextualization, 'We Are the World' says less
    about Ethiopia than it does about Pepsi—and the true result
    will likely be less that certain Ethiopian individuals will
    live, or anyway live a bit longer than they otherwise would
    have, than that Pepsi will get the catch phrase of its
    advertising campaign sung for free by Ray Charles, Stevie
    Wonder, Bruce Springsteen, and all the rest." Author Reebee
    Garofalo agreed, and expressed the opinion that the line "We're
    saving our own lives" was a "distasteful element of
    self-indulgence". He asserted that the artists of USA for
    Africa were proclaiming "their own salvation for singing about
    an issue they will never experience on behalf of a people most
    of them will never encounter".</p>
      <p>In contrast, Stephen Holden of 
    <i>The New York Times</i>praised the phrase "There's a choice
    we're making, We're saving our own lives". He commented that
    the line assumed "an extra emotional dimension when sung by
    people with superstar mystiques". Holden expressed that the
    song was "an artistic triumph that transcends its official
    nature". He noted that unlike Band Aid's "Do They Know It's
    Christmas", the vocals on "We Are the World" were "artfully
    interwoven" and emphasized the individuality of each singer.
    Holden concluded that "We Are the World" was "a simple,
    eloquent ballad" and a "fully-realized pop statement that would
    sound outstanding even if it weren't recorded by stars".</p>
      <p>In "We Are the World", Bruce gave Cyndi Lauper and Tina
    Turner a run for their money for worst performance.
    Springsteen's amazing, up-all-night, three-packs-a-day
    rendition with Stevie Wonder rivalled Tina Turner's
    self-conscious moaning and Lauper's putting three syllables in
    'change'., The argument was this: "He's trying so hard, he
    really 
    <i>feels</i>the lyrics." Yeah, just like any Holiday Inn lounge
    lizard feels the lyrics to "Feelings".</p>
      <p>The song proved popular with both young and old listeners.
    The public enjoyed hearing a supergroup of musicians singing
    together on one track, and felt satisfied in buying the record,
    knowing that the money would go towards a good cause. People
    reported they bought more than one copy of the single, some
    buying up to five copies of the record. One mother from
    Columbia, Missouri purchased two copies of "We Are the World",
    stating, "The record is excellent whether it's for a cause or
    not. It's fun trying to identify the different artists. It was
    a good feeling knowing that I was helping someone in need."</p>
      <p>According to music critic and Bruce Springsteen biographer
    Dave Marsh, "We Are the World" was not widely accepted within
    the rock music community. The author revealed that the song was
    "despised" for what it was not: "a rock record, a critique of
    the political policies that created the famine, a way of
    finding out how and why famines occur, an all-inclusive
    representation of the entire worldwide spectrum of post-Presley
    popular music". Marsh revealed that he felt some of the
    criticisms were right, while others were silly. He claimed that
    despite the sentimentality of the song, "We Are the World" was
    a large scale pop event with serious political overtones.</p>
      <p>"We Are the World" was recognized with several awards
    following its release. At the 1986 Grammy Awards, the song and
    its accompanying music video won four awards: Record of the
    Year, Song of the Year, Best Pop Performance by a Duo or Group
    with Vocal and Best Music Video, Short Form. The music video
    was awarded two honors at the 1985 MTV Video Music Awards. It
    collected the awards for Best Group Video and Viewer's Choice.
    People's Choice Awards recognized "We Are the World" with the
    Favorite New Song award in 1986. In the same year, the American
    Music Awards named "We Are the World" "Song of the Year", and
    honored organizer Harry Belafonte with the Award of
    Appreciation. Collecting his award, Belafonte thanked Ken
    Kragen, Quincy Jones, and "the two artists who, without their
    great gift would not have inspired us in quite the same way as
    we were inspired, Mr. Lionel Richie and Mr. Michael Jackson".
    Following the speech, the majority of USA for Africa reunited
    on stage, closing the ceremony with "We Are the World".</p>
      <p>"We Are the World" was promoted with a music video, a video
    cassette, and several other items made available to the public,
    including books, posters, shirts and buttons. All proceeds from
    the sale of official USA for Africa merchandise went directly
    to the famine relief fund. All of the merchandise sold well;
    the video cassette—entitled 
    <i>We Are the World: The Video Event</i>—documented the making
    of the song, and became the ninth best-selling home video of
    1985.</p>
      <p>The music video showed the recording of "We Are the World",
    and drew criticism from some. They felt that Michael Jackson
    was "unable to leave his ego at the door" in the video because
    he wore sequined socks, a single glove and sunglasses. The
    singer claimed he had wanted to wear his signature socks so
    that the audience would be able to identify him; in the clip,
    the camera moves up his body, before resting on his face. The
    musician joked before filming, "People will know it's me as
    soon as they see the socks. Try taking footage of Bruce
    Springsteen's socks and see if anyone knows who they belong
    to." Jackson was also criticized for filming and recording his
    solo piece privately, away from the other artists. The singer's
    supporters reasoned that Jackson was a perfectionist; recording
    in front of other big name artists would leave him awestruck
    and unable to perform at his best. His detractors suggested
    that Jackson liked to feel different from everybody else, and
    that he had wanted to emphasize the difference by erecting
    barriers around himself.</p>
      <p>The song was also promoted with a special edition of the
    American magazine 
    <i>Life</i>. The publication had been the only media outlet
    permitted inside A&amp;M Recording Studios on the night of
    January 28, 1985. All other press organizations were barred
    from reporting the events leading up to and during "We Are the
    World"'s recording. 
    <i>Life</i>ran a cover story of the recording session in its
    April 1985 edition of the monthly magazine. Seven members of
    USA for Africa were pictured on the cover: Bob Dylan, Bruce
    Springsteen, Cyndi Lauper, Lionel Richie, Michael Jackson, Tina
    Turner and Willie Nelson. Inside the magazine were photographs
    of the "We Are the World" participants working and taking
    breaks.</p>
      <p>On the morning of April 5, 1985 (Good Friday of that year),
    "We Are the World" received worldwide coverage. At
    10:25 am, over 8000 radio stations simultaneously
    broadcast the song around the world. They played it to show
    their support for the relief of famine in Ethiopia. The song
    was also broadcast by Muzak, a company which pipes background
    music into 110,000 stores and businesses in the US. It was the
    second time Muzak had played the sound of "human voice", the
    first being an announcement on the release of American hostages
    in Iran in 1981. As the song was broadcast, hundreds of people
    sang along on the steps of St. Patrick's Cathedral in New York.
    The simultaneous radio broadcast of "We Are the World" was
    repeated again the following Good Friday.</p>
      <p>"We Are the World" gained further promotion and coverage on
    May 25, 1986, when it was played during a major benefit event
    held throughout the US. Hands Across America—USA for Africa's
    follow-up project—was an event in which millions of people
    formed a human chain across the US. The event was held to draw
    attention to hunger and homelessness in the United States. "We
    Are the World"'s co-writer, Michael Jackson, had wanted his
    song to be the official theme for the event. The other board
    members of USA for Africa outvoted the singer, and it was
    instead decided that a new song would be created and released
    for the event, titled "Hands Across America". When released,
    the new song did not achieve the level of success that "We Are
    the World" did, and the decision to use it as the official
    theme for the event led to Jackson—who co-owned the publishing
    rights to "We Are the World"—resigning from the board of
    directors of USA for Africa.</p>
      <p>Four months after the release of "We Are the World", USA for
    Africa had taken in almost $10.8 million. The majority of
    the money came from record sales within the US. Members of the
    public also donated money—almost $1.3 million within the
    same time period. In May 1985, USA for Africa officials
    estimated that they had sold between $45 million and
    $47 million worth of official merchandise around the
    world. Organizer Ken Kragen announced that they would not be
    distributing all of the money at once. Instead, he revealed
    that the foundation would be looking into finding a long-term
    solution for Africa's problems. "We could go out and spend it
    all in one shot. Maybe we'd save some lives in the short term
    but it would be like putting a Band-Aid over a serious wound."
    Kragen noted that experts had predicted that it would take at
    least 10 to 20 years to make a slight difference to
    Africa's long-term problems.</p>
      <p>In June 1985, the first USA for Africa cargo jet carrying
    food, medicine and clothing departed for Ethiopia and the
    Sudan. It stopped 
    <i>en route</i>in New York, where 15,000 T-shirts were
    added to the cargo. Included in the supplies were high-protein
    biscuits, high-protein vitamins, medicine, tents, blankets and
    refrigeration equipment. Harry Belafonte, representing the USA
    for Africa musicians, visited Sudan in the same month. The trip
    was his last stop on a four nation tour of Africa. In Africa,
    Belafonte was greeted and praised by Prime Minister Salim Ahmed
    Salim. Salim told the musician, "I personally and the people of
    Tanzania are moved by this tremendous example of human
    solidarity."</p>
      <p>One year after the release of "We Are the World", organizers
    noted that $44.5 million had been raised for USA for
    Africa's humanitarian fund. They stated that they were
    confident that they would reach an initial set target of
    $50 million. By October 1986, it was revealed that their
    $50 million target had been met and exceeded; CBS Records
    gave USA for Africa a check for $2.5 million, drawing the
    total amount of money to $51.2 million. USA for Africa's
    Hands Across America event had also raised a significant amount
    of money—approximately $24.5 million for the hungry in the
    US.</p>
      <p>Since its release, "We Are the World" has raised over
    $63 million for humanitarian causes. Ninety percent of the
    money was pledged to African relief, both long and short term.
    The long term initiative included efforts in birth control and
    food production. The remaining 10 percent of funds was
    earmarked for domestic hunger and homeless programs in the US.
    From the African fund, over 70 recovery and development
    projects were launched in seven African nations. Such projects
    included aid in agriculture, fishing, water management,
    manufacturing and reforestation. Training programs were also
    developed in the African countries of Mozambique, Senegal,
    Chad, Mauritania, Burkina Faso, Mali and Niger.</p>
      <p>"We Are the World" has been performed live by members of USA
    for Africa on several occasions both together and individually.
    One of the earliest such performances came in 1985, during the
    rock music concert Live Aid, which ended with more than
    100 musicians singing the song on stage. Harry Belafonte
    and Lionel Richie made surprise appearances for the live
    rendition of the song. Michael Jackson would have joined the
    artists, but was "working around the clock in the studio on a
    project that he's made a major commitment to", according to his
    press agent, Norman Winter.</p>
      <p>An inaugural celebration was held for US President-elect
    Bill Clinton in January 1993. The event was staged by Clinton's
    Hollywood friends at the Lincoln Memorial and drew hundreds of
    thousands of people. Aretha Franklin, LL Cool J, Michael Bolton
    and Tony Bennett were among some of the musicians in
    attendance. The celebration included a performance of "We Are
    the World", which involved Clinton, his daughter Chelsea, and
    his wife Hillary singing the song along with USA for Africa's
    Kenny Rogers, Diana Ross and Michael Jackson. 
    <i>The New York Times'</i>Edward Rothstein commented on the
    event, stating, "The most enduring image may be of Mr. Clinton
    singing along in 'We Are the World', the first President to
    aspire, however futilely, to hipness."</p>
      <p>Michael Jackson died in June 2009, after suffering a cardiac
    arrest. His memorial service was held several days later on
    July 7, and was reported to have been viewed by more than one
    billion people. The finale of the event featured group
    renditions of the Jackson anthems "We Are the World" and "Heal
    the World". The singalong of "We Are the World" was led by
    Darryl Phinnessee, who had worked with Jackson since the late
    1980s. It also featured co-writer Lionel Richie, Jackson's
    family and the late singer's children. Following the
    performance, "We Are the World" re-entered the US charts for
    the first time since its 1985 release. The song debuted at
    number 50 on 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s Hot Digital Songs chart.</p>
      <p>On January 12, 2010, Haiti was struck by a magnitude-7.0
    earthquake, the country's most severe earthquake in over 200
    years. The epicenter of the quake was just outside the Haitian
    capital Port-au-Prince. Over 230,000 civilians have been
    confirmed dead by the Haitian government because of the
    disaster and around 300,000 have been injured. Approximately
    1.2 million people are homeless and it has been reported that
    the lack of temporary shelter may lead to the outbreak of
    disease.</p>
      <p>As a result of the devastation, a new version of "We Are the
    World" was recorded on February 1, 2010. Over 75 musicians were
    involved in the recording, which was held in the same studio as
    the original. The new version features revised lyrics as well
    as a rap segment pertaining to Haiti. Michael Jackson's younger
    sister Janet duets with her late brother on the track, as per a
    request from their mother Katherine. In the video and on the
    track, archive material of Michael Jackson is used from the
    original 1985 recording.</p>
      <p>"We Are the World" has been recognized as a politically
    important song, which "affected an international focus on
    Africa that was simply unprecedented". It has been credited
    with creating a climate in which musicians from around the
    world felt inclined to follow. According to 
    <i>The New York Times'</i>Stephen Holden, since the release of
    "We Are the World", it has been noted that movement has been
    made within popular music to create songs that address
    humanitarian concerns. "We Are the World" was also influential
    in subverting the way music and meaning were produced, showing
    that musically and racially diverse musicians could work
    together both productively and creatively. 
    <i>Ebony</i>described the January 28 recording session, in
    which Quincy Jones brought together a multi-racial group, as
    being "a major moment in world music that showed we can change
    the world". "We Are the World", along with Live Aid and Farm
    Aid, demonstrated that rock music had become more than
    entertainment, but a political and social movement. Journalist
    Robert Palmer noted that such songs and events had the ability
    to reach people around the world, send them a message, and then
    get results.</p>
      <p>Since the release of "We Are the World", numerous songs have
    been recorded in a similar fashion, with the intent to aid
    famine victims throughout the world. One such example involved
    a supergroup of Latin musicians billed as "Hermanos del Tercer
    Mundo", or "Brothers of the Third World". Among the supergroup
    of 62 recording artists were Julio Iglesias, Jose
    Feliciano and Sergio Mendes. Their famine relief song was
    recorded in the same studio as "We Are the World". Half of the
    profits raised from the charity single was pledged to USA for
    Africa. The rest of the money was to be used for impoverished
    Latin American countries.</p>
      <p>The 20th anniversary of "We Are the World" was celebrated in
    2005. Radio stations around the world paid homage to Michael
    Jackson, Lionel Richie and USA for Africa's creation by
    simultaneously broadcasting the charity song. In addition to
    the simulcast, the milestone was marked by the release of a
    two-disc DVD called 
    <i>We Are the World: The Story Behind the Song</i>. Ken Kragen
    asserted that the reason behind the simulcast and DVD release
    was not for USA for Africa to praise themselves for doing a
    good job, but to "use it to do some more good [for the original
    charity]. That's all we care about accomplishing." Harry
    Belafonte also commented on the 20th anniversary of the
    song. The entertainer acknowledged that "We Are the World" had
    "stood the test of time"; anyone old enough to remember it can
    still at least hum along.</p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>The Jazz Soul of Little Stevie ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Tribute to Uncle Ray ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>With a Song in My Heart ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Stevie at the Beach ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Up-Tight ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Down to Earth ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>I Was Made to Love Her ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Someday at Christmas ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Eivets Rednow ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>For Once in My Life ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>My Cherie Amour ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Signed, Sealed &amp; Delivered ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Where I'm Coming From ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Music of My Mind ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Talking Book ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Innervisions ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Fulfillingness' First Finale ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Songs in the Key of Life ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Hotter than July ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>In Square Circle ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Characters ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Conversation Peace ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>A Time to Love</i>
         </span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Recorded Live: The 12 Year Old Genius ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Stevie Wonder Live ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Natural Wonder</i>
         </span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Journey through the Secret Life of Plants ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>The Woman in Red ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Jungle Fever</i>
         </span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Looking Back ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>Stevie Wonder's Original Musiquarium ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>At the Close of a Century ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>The Definitive Collection ·</i>
         </span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
            <i>The Complete Stevie Wonder</i>
         </span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Fingertips - Part
      2" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Uptight (Everything's
      Alright)" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Blowin' in the
      Wind" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"A Place in the
      Sun" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Was Made to Love
      Her" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"For Once in My
      Life" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
      "Shoo-Be-Doo-Be-Doo-Da-Day" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"My Cherie
      Amour" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Yester-Me, Yester-You,
      Yesterday" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Never Had a Dream Come
      True" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Signed, Sealed, Delivered
      I'm Yours" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Heaven Help Us
      All" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"If You Really Love
      Me" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Superstition" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"You Are the Sunshine of My
      Life" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Higher
      Ground" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Living for the
      City" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"He's Misstra Know it
      All" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"You Haven't Done
      Nothin'" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Boogie On Reggae
      Woman" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Wish" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Sir Duke" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Send One Your
      Love" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Master Blaster
      (Jammin')" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Ain't Gonna Stand for
      It" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Lately" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Happy
      Birthday" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"That Girl" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Do I Do" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Ebony and
      Ivory" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Ribbon in the
      Sky" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Just Called to Say I Love
      You" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Part-Time
      Lover" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"That's What Friends Are
      For" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Go Home"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Discography ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Syreeta Wright ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">KJLH ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Motown ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">Soul music</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Nel blu dipinto di blu
      (Volare)" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Mack the
      Knife" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Theme from A Summer
      Place" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Moon River" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Left My Heart in San
      Francisco" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Days of Wine and
      Roses" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"The Girl from
      Ipanema" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"A Taste of
      Honey" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Strangers in the
      Night" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Up, Up and
      Away" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Mrs. Robinson"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Aquarius/Let the Sunshine
      In" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Bridge over Troubled
      Water" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"It's Too
      Late" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"The First Time Ever I Saw
      Your Face" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Killing Me Softly with His
      Song" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Honestly Love
      You" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Love Will Keep Us
      Together" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"This
      Masquerade" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Hotel
      California" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Just the Way You
      Are"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"What a Fool
      Believes" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Sailing" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Bette Davis
      Eyes" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Rosanna" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Beat It" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"What's Love Got to Do with
      It" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"
      <strong class="selflink">
We Are the World
</strong>" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Higher Love" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Graceland" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Don't Worry, Be
      Happy"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Wind Beneath My
      Wings" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Another Day in
      Paradise" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
      "Unforgettable" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Tears in
      Heaven" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Will Always Love
      You" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"All I Wanna
      Do" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Kiss from a
      Rose" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Change the
      World" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Sunny Came
      Home" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"My Heart Will Go On"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Smooth" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Beautiful
      Day" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Walk On" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Don't Know
      Why" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Clocks" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Here We Go
      Again" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Boulevard of Broken
      Dreams" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Not Ready to Make
      Nice" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Rehab" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Please Read the
      Letter"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Use Somebody"</span>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
