<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_in_This_Club 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_in_This_Club</songId>
   <title>Love in This Club</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usher_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Usher featuring Young Jeezy</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2008-03-15</week>
      <week>2008-03-22</week>
      <week>2008-03-29</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/5a/Love_In_This_Club.jpg/200px-Love_In_This_Club.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Usher-featuring-Young-Jeezy+Love-in-This-Club.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Here I Stand</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 25, 2008</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>maxi single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Fall 2007</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
      <genre>Electropop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:23 (Album Version)</length>
      <length>3:46 (Radio Edit w/o Rap)</length>
      <length>4:50 (Video Version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>LaFace</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Usher Raymond</writer>
      <writer>Jamal Jones</writer>
      <writer>Lamar Taylor</writer>
      <writer>Jay Jenkins</writer>
      <writer>Ryon Lovett</writer>
      <writer>Keith Thomas</writer>
      <writer>Darnell Dalton</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Polow da Don</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Love in This Club" is a song by American R&amp;B singer
    Usher nominated for 2008 MTV Video Music Awards. The song was
    released as the first single from his 2008 album, 
    <i>Here I Stand</i>. It features rapper Young Jeezy, and was
    produced by Atlanta-based producer Polow da Don. This was also
    the opening performance for the 2008 Black Entertainment
    Television (BET) Awards. A mixtape series was named after this
    song. So far it has produced five volumes, including one
    covered by T-Pain, Ciara, and Rihanna. The song was digitally
    released on January 25, 2008 in the U.S., and peaked at number
    one on the Hot 100.</p>
      <p>Atlanta-based music producer Polow da Don was inspired to
    create a beat during his weekend stay in Las Vegas, Nevada for
    the MTV Video Music Awards, which later became "Love in This
    Club". When he finished working on the material, da Don felt it
    fit for Usher and played it for him.</p>
      <p>Usher left the studio during one of his sessions for the
    album. Young Jeezy went in after Usher had gone. He heard the
    song and he wanted to contribute to it. Da Don was skeptical,
    but allowed Young Jeezy to make his verse. He played the new
    version to Usher, who loved the new version, allowing Young
    Jeezy's verse to stay. Ironically, Jeezy's rival, rapper Gucci
    Mane, recently confirmed in an interview that he was originally
    supposed to be on the song.</p>
      <p>"Love in This Club" is a mid-tempo song that contains loops
    taking from (Euro Hero Synths) to Apple's GarageBand software,
    however denied by Polow da Don. The song features guest vocals
    from Young Jeezy. According to Polow da Don, the lyrics are not
    about sex, they're about having the urge. Polow da Don wanted
    to call the song "Lust at first sight". When the song was first
    released, there was also controversy due to how similar the
    song is to the Kill Paradise song, "Brake Your Bones," with
    both using a similar bass progression, and stuttering intro, as
    well as sharing a similar chorus.</p>
      <p>Early in 2008, several songs for Usher's fifth studio album
    leaked into the Internet, including "Love in This Club". Usher
    called the incident an "internal conspiracy" because it was
    unofficially released beyond his awareness. This also happened
    to the lead single "Yeah!" off his 2004 album 
    <i>Confessions</i>, which was intentionally leaked by its
    producer Lil Jon, to street DJs late in 2003. Polow da Don
    confessed that he had leaked "Love in This Club", following
    what Lil Jon did. He felt the song would be a hit, but that "it
    was so much back-and-forth between Usher and his record label"
    and he was tired of waiting on "label politics".</p>
      <p>"Love in This Club" received mixed reviews from critics.
    Sophia Baratta of 
    <i>Billboard</i>magazine gave the track a positive review,
    noting the "slow ballad tempo and smooth vocals transition to
    an upbeat hip-hop twist." She called the song evident enough of
    an "evolved sound", summing it up as "a catchy tune with enough
    fuel to return Usher to the top of R&amp;B." Bill Lamb of
    About.com found that the vocals in the song sound like a "close
    cousin" of Akon. Lamb, however, noted that it failed to equal
    the "sheer beauty of Akon's best vocals or any particular
    soulfulness." He complimented da Don for producing an
    "atmospheric synth groove" and Young Jeezy's "reliably gritty"
    rap, but Lamb expected more after a "four year wait." 
    <i>Blender</i>gave the track a lukewarm response, awarding it 2
    and 1/2 out of 5 stars, saying it was reminiscent to one of
    Usher's previous hits, "Lovers &amp; Friends". They called the
    track "too safe" and that it was "strictly PG". They felt that
    one of the other leaked songs, "Dat Girl Right There", would
    have made a more adventurous first single choice. 
    <i>Digital Spy</i>awarded the song three stars out of five,
    contending that it was "hardly the most original of comeback
    singles", but sounded "very, very now".</p>
      <p>This single ranked at number 1 on the "10 Best Singles of
    2008" list by American magazine 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>.</p>
      <p>"Love in This Club" began receiving airplay on urban and
    rhythmic radio stations across the U.S. upon the song's leak
    and debuted on the Hot 100 at number eighty-three on the issue
    date of March 1, 2008. In the song's third week on the Hot 100
    it jumped from number fifty-one to number one, becoming Usher's
    eighth chart-topping single and the first for Young Jeezy. It
    was at the time the sixth highest jump to number one in the
    history of the Hot 100. It is Usher's fifteenth top ten hit on
    the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs chart, where it has reached
    number one, also making it his ninth number one on the
    chart.</p>
      <p>Internationally, the single debuted at number twenty-seven
    on the Sweden Singles Top 60, number eleven on the Canadian Hot
    100, number seven on the New Zealand RIANZ Singles Chart,
    number forty-nine on the Australian ARIA Singles Chart, number
    19 on the UK Singles Chart and number thirty-six on the Swiss
    Singles Top 100. So far, Love In This Club has peaked at number
    8 on the Canadian Hot 100 and Sweden Top 60, number one in New
    Zealand as of the week ending May 10, 2008. It debuted at
    number 19 on the UK Singles Chart and in its fourth charting
    week, it reached number six. After falling down to number
    seven, it jumped back up the chart to number four upon its
    physical release. On the week ending April 19, "Love In This
    Club" moved back into the Top 10 on the Canadian Hot 100, by
    making a 2-point jump from 12-10, and then the following week
    reached a new peak position of number six. In Australia, it has
    become a huge hit peaking at number eight, rising 13 spots from
    number 21. To date, this is Young Jeezy's biggest hit (his
    biggest hit as a solo artist would be Soul Survivor).</p>
      <p>On December 28, 2008, the UK Singles Chart landed this at
    #33 for the chart end show.</p>
      <p>Usher was concerned with the premature public exposure of
    the song because "everything has to be set up on their end." He
    noted the necessity of its accompanying music video as soon as
    it would have released properly. However, the song received
    favorable responses from radio industries, similar to "Yeah!"'s
    early reception. Eventually, the video was released on April 7,
    2008. It features cameos by Keri Hilson (as Usher's love
    interest), Diddy, Rick Ross, One Chance, Robin Thicke, Nelly
    and Kanye West. It also has cameos from adult film stars Havana
    Ginger and Savannah Stern. Polow da Don, the producer of the
    track, also appears in the video as the DJ for the club. The
    music video contains an extended dance sequence which is not
    part of the album version of the song.</p>
      <p>The music video starts with Usher waking up inside of an
    empty club. He calls out to see if anyone is there and a girl
    comes out. The music video is spent with Usher escaping the
    temptation of women while trying to escape from the club at the
    same time. At the end of the video, Usher finally escapes from
    the club but it is seen all burned down. It is a cliffhanger
    leading in to his next video, "Moving Mountains".</p>
      <p>The video features a slightly remixed version of the song,
    compared to the radio edit, with added sound effects.</p>
      <p>Some music channels have cut out the beginning scene where
    Usher first meets his love interest and the ending scene where
    he finds the club is destroyed, namely on the music channel
    Bubble Hits Ireland. The music video has received over 39
    million views on YouTube.</p>
      <p>Three official remixes have been released so far. The first
    features T.I. in addition to Young Jeezy, and the second
    features R. Kelly in addition to Young Jeezy.</p>
      <p>The main official remix titled "Love in This Club, Part II"
    features American singer Beyoncé Knowles and rapper Lil
    Wayne,was serviced to urban stations. Due to strong airplay and
    digital downloads, "Love in This Club, Part II" has peaked at
    number 18 on the Hot 100 and number 10 on 's Hot
    R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs chart. It was released on iTunes as a
    pre-order track.</p>
      <p>MSTRKRFT also produced an official remix of the track and
    have been using it in their live DJ sets.</p>
      <p>Also, the song was mashed up with the popular internet meme
    Keyboard Cat by The Hood Internet.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
