<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yeah!_(Usher_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yeah!_(Usher_song)</songId>
   <title>Yeah!</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usher_(entertainer)</artistId>
      <artistName>Usher featuring Lil Jon and Ludacris</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2004-02-28</week>
      <week>2004-03-06</week>
      <week>2004-03-13</week>
      <week>2004-03-20</week>
      <week>2004-03-27</week>
      <week>2004-04-03</week>
      <week>2004-04-10</week>
      <week>2004-04-17</week>
      <week>2004-04-24</week>
      <week>2004-05-01</week>
      <week>2004-05-08</week>
      <week>2004-05-15</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/2e/Usher-yeah.jpg/200px-Usher-yeah.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Usher-featuring-Lil-Jon-and-Ludacris+Yeah.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Confessions</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>February 3, 2004</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>CD maxi single</format>
      <format>digital download</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2003-2004</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
      <genre>Crunk</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:10</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Arista</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Lil Jon</writer>
      <writer>Sean Garrett</writer>
      <writer>Patrick J. Que Smith</writer>
      <writer>Ludacris</writer>
      <writer>Robert McDowell</writer>
      <writer>James Phillips</writer>
      <writer>LaMarquis Jefferson</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Lil Jon</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Yeah!" is a hip hop song by American singer Usher, written
    by American songwriters and producers Lil Jon, Sean Garrett,
    Patrick J. Que Smith, Ludacris, Robert McDowell and James
    Elbert "LRoc" Phillips. It was released as the lead single from
    Usher's hit fourth studio album, 
    <i>Confessions</i>(2004). The track was produced by Lil Jon,
    who combined crunk and R&amp;B in the song's beat. The song
    features vocals from Lil Jon and a rap verse from rapper
    Ludacris. This song could arguably be one of Usher
    (entertainer)'s most famous songs.</p>
      <p>The song was remixed with Tego Calderón. It features a
    three-note beat that continues throughout the track. The song
    reached number 1 on twenty different charts in fifteen
    countries, and gained several platinum certifications,
    including by the RIAA and RIANZ. The single topped the U.S. Hot
    100 for a record twelve weeks, the longest-running of 2004, and
    its huge success added to Usher's hit success that year. Usher
    was the longest-running number 1 artist in 2004 with four
    number 1 singles, and the most successful artist of 2004. With
    over two million worldwide sales in one year, it is one of the
    fastest selling hip hop songs ever. The song ranks 2nd on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade. Usher performed
    "Yeah!" at the Victoria's Secret Fashion Show 2008 as runway
    soundtrack. The song won Best Rap/Sung Collaboration at the
    47th Grammy Awards.</p>
      <p>In 2003, Usher submitted his fourth studio album, 
    <i>Confessions</i>, to his label Arista Records, thinking it
    was already completed. However, when Usher and the company's
    then-president Antonio "LA" Reid listened to the songs, they
    felt the album needed a lead single. Although they had "Burn",
    the first song created early in the making of the album, as
    waiting list, Usher had to record a few more tracks.</p>
      <p>Usher went back to the studio and enlisted fellow Atlantians
    rapper-producer Lil Jon, alongside rapper-actor Ludacris, to
    produce songs for him. Lil Jon recalled: "He needed a single.
    They had 'Burn,' 'Burn' was hot, but they needed that first
    powerful monster. That's when I came in."</p>
      <p>Several months before Lil Jon came into the production of 
    <i>Confessions</i>, he was commissioned by Jive Records to
    produce fifteen beats for rapper Mystikal. The rapper would
    only choose two tracks, which would give Lil Jon the chance to
    peddle the leftovers to other record labels. Without Lil Jon's
    knowledge, Jive Records gave one of the tracks that Mystikal
    passed on to hip hop artist Petey Pablo, who also records for
    the label. Lil Jon went to Pablo, who had already recorded the
    song, which later became "Freak-a-Leek". Lil Jon tried to
    settle it with Jive by making another beat for Pablo; however,
    Pablo did not give up the track, in light of the fact that it
    was already recorded and had been getting responses from South
    radio. Lil Jon comments, "With so much invested, Jive wouldn't
    give up the cut." Lil Jon reworked the track and a new
    instrumental was used, from which "Yeah!" was based. The song
    was co-written by Sean Garrett, Patrick J. Que Smith, Ludacris,
    Robert McDowell and James Elbert "LRoc" Phillips.</p>
      <p>Though "Yeah!" had been created, the label was not ready to
    decide whether it would be released as the lead single,
    considering they had "Burn" on queue. Usher's friend and former
    A&amp;R rep Kawan "KP" Prather commented: "'Burn' being a great
    song is one thing, but it's one of them things where people
    said, 'It's strong, but can we make history with that?' At the
    end of the day, you want an event." Usher was also skeptical if
    "Yeah!" was the right choice.</p>
      <p>After Lil Jon leaked "Yeah!" to street DJs across the United
    States, Usher opted "Burn" as the lead single of the album and
    was already planning for its music video. The song was not
    intended to be a proper single and only a teaser for Usher's
    fans after waiting for years. However, the responses of "Yeah!"
    were overwhelmingly favorable, and "Yeah!" was released as the
    first single instead of "Burn", which became the second single
    from the album. The single was released in the United States on
    January 27, 2004 as a CD single and 12" single. In the United
    Kingdom, it was released as a CD single, containing the album
    and instrumental version of the song, and two unreleased tracks
    from the album, "Red Light" and "Sweet Lies".</p>
      <p>"Yeah!" was lauded by contemporary critics for its
    production. Jem Aswad of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>called it "irresistibly
    crunked-out", adding, "ensuing track glides smoothly between
    club-friendly hip-hop soul and ballads." Laura Sinagra 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>commented that the song "creates sensual
    panic by combining Usher's jumpy attacks with Jon's sublime,
    frayed beats." Jon Caramanica of 
    <i>Blender</i>noted that "Yeah!" is the first song to mix
    "mainstream R&amp;B and menacing Southern crunk." Sal
    Cinquemani of Slant Magazine said that the song has brought
    Usher to a "whole new level of crunk." Andy Kellman of Allmusic
    described the song as a "crunk-meets-R&amp;B foundation" which
    features an "instantly addictive eight-note keyboard vamp". He
    added that because it is "absorbing", Ludacris' voice cannot be
    noticed that much. Matt Cibula of Popmatters characterized the
    song as a "full-fledged club über-crunk salacious" but he added
    that it fails to be a "club banger". Steve Jones of 
    <i>USA Today</i>referred to "Yeah!" as a "club-rattling" song
    from a combination of "Atlanta's vibrant music scene", Lil
    Jon's "insistent beats" and Ludacris' "racy rhymes".</p>
      <p>Critics complimented Usher for the song. Aswad called it the
    "grittiest song" Usher had sung for revealing his "newfound
    maturity". Caramanica said that it is "probably the scariest
    record — in a good way — he's ever made" and Usher "smartly
    shares the spotlight." Cibula stated that Usher's "smoove-ass"
    singing and Ludacris' presence contributes to the success of
    the single.</p>
      <p>"Yeah!" was nominated at the 2005 Grammy Awards for Record
    of the Year, and won the Best Rap/Sung Collaboration award. At
    the 2005 Soul Train Music Awards, "Yeah!" was nominated for
    best R&amp;B/Soul or Rap Dance Cut.</p>
      <p>"Yeah!" charted well on various charts worldwide. The single
    debuted on the U.S. Hot 100 at number fifty-three on January
    13, 2004, prior to its physical release. Seven weeks later, it
    peaked on the chart at number one on March 2, staying there for
    twelve consecutive weeks. "Yeah!" became Usher's fourth
    number-one single; Lil Jon's first; and Ludacris' second. The
    single remained on the Hot 100 for forty-five weeks. "Yeah!"
    became the most-played song in 2004. Nielsen Broadcast Data
    Systems placed the song on the top for getting 496,805 total
    plays, above Hoobastank's single "The Reason" with 489,976
    spins. The single was certified platinum by the Recording
    Industry Association of America on June 11, 2006 for reaching
    one million shipments. "Yeah!" became the 2004's
    best-performing single in the United States. The single ranks
    at number 11 on The Billboard Hot 100 All-Time Top Songs.</p>
      <p>Internationally, "Yeah!" received similar responses, topping
    many charts. The single reached number 1 in the Australia
    Singles Top 50, Austria Singles Top 75, Canadian Singles Chart,
    Denmark Singles Top 40, Dutch Top 40, France Singles Top 100,
    Germany Singles Top 100, Ireland Singles Top 50, New Zealand
    Top 40, Norway Singles Top 20, Swiss Singles Top 100, and the
    UK Singles Top 75. Overall, the single charted to different
    charts worldwide for a year, early in 2004 to early in 2005.
    The single was certified platinum by the Australian Recording
    Industry Association for selling 70,000 units. At the 2004 Year
    Ender charts, "Yeah!" became the twenty-eighth best-selling
    single in Australia. It was certified double platinum by the
    Recording Industry Association of New Zealand.</p>
      <p>Mr. X, formerly Little X, had previously directed videos for
    Usher's singles "U Don't Have to Call" and "U Got It Bad". Mr.
    X said that the song reminded him of laser beams . He felt the
    sound was a laser beam for him, referring to the beat as
    "distinctive". Usher and Mr. X combined ideas to create a dance
    video for "Yeah!". The treatment was accompanied of how Usher
    wanted to be portrayed in the video, particularly showcasing
    his dance moves.</p>
      <p>The music video was filmed in a vacant art gallery in Los
    Angeles over two days. When the shooting started, Mr. X
    recalled Michael Jackson's "low-tech" and "laser-flashing" 1979
    "Rock With You" video, and used it as a reference. Forty extras
    were commissioned to dance with Usher, and two ladies to tempt
    him in different scenes. They went through photo browsing and
    phone calling, opting for Destiny, a friend of Mr. X, who
    seduces Usher in the club ala Marilyn Monroe wardrobe to
    complement the lyrics. Usher's other would-be seductress is
    portrayed by model Melyssa Ford. Lil Jon acted as an assistant
    director during the sessions. Usher took charge of his ideas on
    his wardrobe and choreography, with additional routines,
    specifically the Rockaway and the thunderclap, which Mr. X
    learned from Jamaica. The Rockaway influenced Fat Joe and
    Terror Squad's "Lean Back" video.</p>
      <p>Usher's dancing in front of the green and blue laser beams
    is prominently featured throughout the video. Lil Jon and
    Ludacris appeared on the video as well. Ludacris protégé Chingy
    also appears near the end of the video, holding up his chain
    which shows his name. Sean "Diddy" Combs' former assistant,
    Farnsworth Bentley, made a cameo at the end of the video as
    well, when he was in Los Angeles and Mr. X begged him to dance
    in the video with his violin.</p>
      <p>The music video debuted on MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>at number ten on February 19, 2004.
    "Yeah!" topped the countdown, and retired on May 3 at number
    six after appearing on the countdown for fifty days. "Yeah!"
    became one of the most successful music videos by Usher,
    alongside "Confessions Part II", which also remained for fifty
    days. At the 2005 Soul Train Music Awards, the video was
    nominated for Michael Jackson Award for best R&amp;B/Soul or
    Rap Music Video.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
