<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burn_(Usher_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burn_(Usher_song)</songId>
   <title>Burn</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>Usher</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>2004-05-22</week>
      <week>2004-05-29</week>
      <week>2004-06-05</week>
      <week>2004-06-12</week>
      <week>2004-06-19</week>
      <week>2004-06-26</week>
      <week>2004-07-03</week>
      <week>2004-07-17</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f9/Usher_-_Burn_-_CD_cover.jpg/200px-Usher_-_Burn_-_CD_cover.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Usher+Burn.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Confessions</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 13, 2004</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>2003</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:15</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Arista</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Usher Raymond</writer>
      <writer>Jermaine Dupri</writer>
      <writer>Bryan-Michael Cox</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Jermaine Dupri</producer>
      <producer>Bryan Michael Cox</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Burn" is a song by American R&amp;B singer Usher, which he
    wrote with American songwriters Jermaine Dupri, Bryan-Michael
    Cox. The song was produced by Dupri and Cox for Usher's fourth
    studio album, 
    <i>Confessions</i>(2004). "Burn" is about breakup in a
    relationship, and the public referred to it as an allusion to
    Usher's personal struggles.</p>
      <p>Originally planned as the album's lead single, "Burn" was
    pushed back after favorable responses for the song "Yeah!". The
    song was released as the second single from the album in July
    2004. The single topped various charts around the world,
    including the Hot 100 for eight non-consecutive weeks. The song
    succeeded "Yeah!" at the #1 position. Both singles gave Usher
    nineteen consecutive weeks with a song in the top spot, longer
    than any solo artist of the Hot 100 era. "Burn" was certified
    platinum in Australia and gold in New Zealand and United
    States. The song was well-received by critics and has garnered
    award nominations. In 2009 it was named the 21st most
    successful song of the 2000s, on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Songs of the Decade.</p>
      <p>When Usher planned to make a new record after his third
    album, 
    <i>8701</i>, he decided to not branch out that much with
    musical collaborators and continue building music with his
    previous producers. Usher again enlisted record-producer
    Jermaine Dupri, who had collaborated on his two previous
    albums, along with The Neptunes, R. Kelly, among others to work
    on his fourth studio album 
    <i>Confessions</i>. Dupri contacted his frequent collaborator
    Bryan-Michael Cox, who had also made hits like the 2001 single
    "U Got It Bad" for Usher. During the early session for the
    album, Dupri and Cox talked about a situation which later
    became "Burn". At that time, Usher's two-year relationship with
    TLC's Chilli was flaming out. They said, "Yo, you gotta let
    that burn ... That's a song right there", and started
    writing.</p>
      <p>"Burn" is a slow jam, combining R&amp;B and ballad genres.
    The song is performed with a moderate groove. It is composed in
    the key of B minor. The melody line of the song has influences
    from "Ignition (Remix)" by R.Kelly and "How to Deal" by Frankie
    J. "Burn" has a combination of robotic noises, synthesized
    strings and guitar lines.</p>
      <p>The lyrics are constructed in the traditional verse-chorus
    form. The song starts a spoken intro, giving way to the first
    verse. It continues to the chorus, following the second verse
    and chorus. The bridge follows, leading to a break and
    finalizing in the chorus.</p>
      <p>"Burn" was considered a "window to Usher's inner thoughts",
    along with the controversial track "Confessions" and
    "Confessions Part II". The song is about breakups and ending
    relationships. According to Matt Cibula of Popmatters, "Burn"
    is constructed from "two-step concept". In the lyrics "You know
    that it's over / You know that it was through / Let it burn /
    Got to let it burn", Usher breaks up with his woman but found
    her sad about feeling bad about what happened to their
    relationship. However, Usher says that she must deal with it
    before she can accept the truth. For the lines "It's been
    fifty-eleven days / Umpteen hours / I'm gonna be burnin' / Till
    you return", the direction changes after Usher realized that
    breaking up with her was a huge mistake and that he wanted her
    back to him.</p>
      <p>Usher submitted the album to his label Arista Records after
    he felt it was already completed. After he and the company's
    then-president Antonio "LA" Reid listened to the songs, they
    felt the album needed a first single and that they needed one
    or two more songs to create, which caused the postponement of
    the album's release. Usher went back to the studio and
    collaborated with Lil Jon who said, "He needed a single. They
    had 'Burn,' 'Burn' was hot, but they needed that first powerful
    monster. That's when I came in." They worked for few more
    tracks, including "Red Light", which was not included in the
    first release of the album, and "Yeah!", which features
    Ludacris and Lil Jon.</p>
      <p>However, everybody in the label was scared to decide what to
    consider as the lead single. Reid was choosing whether "Yeah!"
    would be released then, considering that they had "Burn". Usher
    was also doubtful if the former was the right choice, after he
    wanted for R&amp;B record. Until "Yeah!" was leaked, "Burn" was
    chosen as the official first single from 
    <i>Confessions</i>. "Yeah!", which was also intended as a
    promotional song and a teaser for Usher's fans, was released to
    street DJs and mixtapes. However, the song's favorable
    responses led to another direction; "Yeah!" was pursued to be
    the lead single and "Burn" was set as its follow-up. "Burn" was
    released in the United States on July 6, 2004 as a CD single
    and 7" single.</p>
      <p>"Burn" was featured in the episode "Tom, Sarah and Usher" of
    the Cartoon Network series 
    <i>The Boondocks</i>. In the episode, Tom does his own redition
    of a typical Usher music video.</p>
      <p>Usher decided about the new material "to let it all hang out
    by singing about some of his own little secrets, as well as a
    few bones from his homies' skeleton-filled closets." The public
    speculated that the material in the new album he was referring
    to was his recent personal struggles in which he promised a
    "real talk" on it. In early 2004, Usher broke up with Chilli
    due to "irreconcilable differences and because they found it
    almost impossible to make compromises." Usher said in an
    interview: "It's unfortunate when you have to let a situation
    go because it's not working", which added reference to the
    break up. Dupri, however, confessed that his personal life is
    the real story of the album. Usher said he took inspirations
    collectively by looking at his friends' personal situations
    that they gone through.</p>
      <p>"Burn" was lauded by contemporary music critics. Jem Aswad
    of 
    <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>complimented Dupri and Cox for
    producing what he called the "best song" from the album, along
    with "Confessions Part II" which they also produced. Aswad
    found the songs feature "mellifluous melodies". Laura Sinagra
    of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>found Usher's singing a "sweet falsetto on
    the weepy breakup song ", adding, it "convincingly marries
    resolve and regret, but when it comes to rough stuff, there's
    still no 'u' in p-i-m-p." Cibula called the song brilliant and
    considers its step one and step two technique a hit. Jon
    Caramanica of 
    <i>Blender</i>complimented the song for living up as the only
    "serviceable" among all ballad-influenced songs in the album
    which "often drown in their own inanity." Ande Kellman of
    Allmusic considered "Burn" as one of the Usher's best moments
    in the album, together with "Caught Up", the final single from 
    <i>Confessions</i>. Steve Jones of 
    <i>USA Today</i>stated that Usher is singing about a
    relationship that cannot be saved because of the "flame has
    simply died".</p>
      <p>"Burn" was nominated at the 47th Grammy Awards for Best Male
    R&amp;B Vocal Performance and Best R&amp;B Song. The song
    earned British record company EMI the "Publisher of the Year"
    at the American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers
    2005 Pop Music Awards.</p>
      <p>"Burn" was another commercial success for Usher, but not on
    such a wide scale as "Yeah!". In the United States, the single
    debuted on the Hot 100 at number sixty-five, months prior to
    its physical release. It reached the top spot on May 29, 2004,
    replacing "Yeah!"'s twelve-week run at number one. The single
    was beaten by Fantasia's 2004 single "I Believe", which
    propelled on the chart on its debut. It returned to number one
    for one last week, before it was finally knocked off by the
    album's third single "Confessions Part II". The single failed
    to remain on the top spot as "Yeah!" achieved, staying only for
    eight non-consecutive weeks. "Burn" was the fifth most-played
    song in 2004 for earning 355,228 total plays, alongside "Yeah!"
    which topped the tally for 496,805 spins. The single was
    certified platinum by the Recording Industry Association of
    America for selling 1,000,000 units. It became the second
    best-selling single in the United States, behind Usher's single
    "Yeah!". Like "Yeah!", "Burn" helped 
    <i>Confessions</i>remain on the top spot position.</p>
      <p>Internationally, several music markets responded equally
    well. In the United Kingdom, the single debuted at number one
    and stayed for two weeks. Across European countries, the single
    performed well, reaching the top ten in Denmark, Ireland,
    Norway, The Netherlands and Switzerland. It entered the top
    twenty in Austria, Belgium, Germany and Sweden. In Australia,
    the single debuted at number three and peaked at number two.
    The single was certified platinum by the Australian Recording
    Industry Association for selling 70,000 units. At the 2004 Year
    Ender charts, "Burn" became the thirty-first best-selling
    single in Australia. In the New Zealand, it peaked at number
    one for three weeks, and remained on the chart for twenty-three
    weeks. The single was certified gold by the Recording Industry
    Association of New Zealand.</p>
      <p>The music video for "Burn" was directed by Jake Nava, who
    had produced a wide array of videos for Atomic Kitten, Beyoncé
    Knowles, among others. It was shot at the former Hollywood
    house of American popular singer Frank Sinatra. The video
    features model Jessica Clarke.</p>
      <p>The video starts with Usher sitting on a sofa with a
    backdrop of his girlfriend. When the verse starts, Usher went
    to a wide glass window pane, looking at his girlfriend swimming
    in the pool. The surface aflame after she immersed in the
    water. The next scene continues to Usher with his mistress
    having sex. While sitting on the edge of the bed, Usher
    reminisces the moments he and his girlfriend having intimate
    moment in the same bed. The bedsheets burns, following to Usher
    riding a silver car. The video cuts with the backdrop also
    burning. Continuing to the car scene, Usher stops as he sees
    his imaginary girl again. He went out and dances, executing
    various hand routines. Video intercuts follow and the video
    ends with Usher standing with his back.</p>
      <p>The music video debuted on MTV's 
    <i>Total Request Live</i>at number six on May 4, 2004, the same
    debut with "Confessions Part II". The video reached the top
    spot and remained on the countdown for thirty-three days.
    "Burn" topped MuchMusic's 
    <i>Countdown</i>on July 24, 2004, and remained on the chart for
    fifteen weeks.</p>
      <p>In the July 2008 issue of 
    <i>Vibe</i>magazine, Usher told writer Mitzi Miller, "Women
    have started to become lovers of each other as a result of not
    having enough men." On June 26, 2008, AfterEllen.com writer
    Sarah Warn revealed that Jessica Clark, the lead in Usher's
    "Burn" music video, was in fact an openly gay model. In the
    article, Warn writes, "Maybe it's not a lack of men that's
    turning women gay, Usher--maybe it's you!"</p>
      <p>Besides from Usher, Cox has benefited for co-creating 
    <i>Confessions</i>, as well as from the success of "Burn". He
    has been doing records for Alicia Keys, B2K, Mariah Carey and
    Destiny's Child, but he felt 2004 introduced him to another
    landscape in the music industry. His contribution to the song
    has elevated him to fame, as well as people looking back to his
    past records. "Burn" earned him two Grammy nominations. Cox
    stated, "Everybody who does this for a [
    <i>sic</i>] living dreams about being nominated. It's the
    ultimate accomplishment. I've always been the silent guy — I
    come in, do my job and head out. I like to leave all the glory
    and shine to others, but this is the validation that means the
    most to me. It also makes me want to work harder to get that
    same recognition again."</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
