<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chariots_of_Fire_(song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chariots_of_Fire_(song)</songId>
   <title>Chariots of Fire</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vangelis</artistId>
      <artistName>Vangelis</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1982-05-08</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a2/Chariots-of-fire-album.jpg/200px-Chariots-of-fire-album.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Vangelis+Chariots-of-Fire.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Chariots of Fire</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1981</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>New Age</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:33</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Polydor</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Vangelis</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Vangelis</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Chariots of Fire" is an instrumental theme written and
    recorded by Vangelis for the soundtrack of the 1981 film of the
    same name. The recording has since been covered by numerous
    performers and used as theme music for various television
    programmes and sporting events.</p>
      <p>On the film's soundtrack album, the piece is called "Titles"
    because of its use in the movie's opening titles sequence, but
    it widely became known as "Chariots of Fire". According to
    Allmusic, the track title was listed as "Chariots of Fire -
    Titles" on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 chart, and simply as
    "Chariots of Fire" on the Adult Contemporary chart.</p>
      <p>A 1989 CD single release also gave the title of the piece
    simply as "Chariots of Fire". When the single debuted at #94 on
    the Billboard Hot 100 during the week ending Dec. 12, 1981, it
    was known simply as "Titles." Seven weeks later, when it moved
    to #68, the Hot 100 chart dated Jan. 30, 1982, the single was
    now listed as "Chariots of Fire" and stayed with that name for
    the remainder of its chart run. Radio listeners and radio DJs
    could now better identify with the song.</p>
      <p>Vangelis was accused of plagiarising "Chariots of Fire" from
    a song by fellow Greek composer Stavros Logarides called "City
    of Violets". Vangelis won in court by convincing the judge to
    allow him to bring his setup to the court and demonstrate his
    method of composing by improvising new music.</p>
      <p>"Chariots of Fire" enjoyed one week at number-one on the
    Billboard Hot 100 in May 1982, after climbing steadily for five
    months (it made #1 in its 22nd week on the chart), and to date
    remains the only song by a Greek artist to top the U.S. Charts.
    It was Polydor's first-ever #1 single in the U.S. in the
    1980s—Gloria Gaynor's "I Will Survive" and Peaches and Herb's
    "Reunited" were also #1 songs on Polydor in 1979.</p>
      <p>The single spent 64 weeks on the Australian charts, although
    it only peaked at #21. In Japan, "Chariots of Fire" was the
    biggest-selling single of 1981. The track proved moderately
    successful in the UK, where it reached #12, but its parent
    album peaked at #5 and spent 107 weeks on the album chart.</p>
      <p>A video clip was made of Vangelis playing "Chariots of Fire"
    on acoustic piano in front of a projection of the film. He is
    smoking a cigarette in the first minute of the video.</p>
      <p>Innumerable cover versions of "Chariots of Fire" have been
    recorded in all styles by all manners of artists, including the
    orchestral sounds of John Williams and the Boston Pops, the
    electric guitars of The Shadows, the acoustic guitar of Bronn
    Journey, the 150-bpm house by Trance Opera, the soft piano of
    Richard Clayderman, the pan flute of Zamfir, and the jazz of
    The Bad Plus. Ween also plays a portion of this song at the end
    of Japanese Cowboy live.</p>
      <p>Vocal recordings of "Chariots of Fire" have been made by
    Jane Olivor, Mireille Mathieu, Demis Roussos, and Italian
    soprano Gioaria — all with lyrics provided by Jon Anderson.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
