<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ice_Ice_Baby 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ice_Ice_Baby</songId>
   <title>Ice Ice Baby</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vanilla_Ice</artistId>
      <artistName>Vanilla Ice</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1990-11-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/3/3f/Vanilla_Ice_-_Ice_Ice_Baby.jpg/200px-Vanilla_Ice_-_Ice_Ice_Baby.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Vanilla-Ice+Ice-Ice-Baby.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>To the Extreme</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 1990</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>CD</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1989</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:32</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>SBK Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Vanilla Ice</writer>
      <writer>Earthquake</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Vanilla Ice</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Ice Ice Baby" is a hip hop song written by American rapper
    Vanilla Ice and DJ Earthquake. The song samples the bassline of
    "Under Pressure" by Queen and David Bowie, who did not
    initially receive songwriting credit or royalties until after
    it had become a hit. Originally released on Van Winkle's 1989
    debut album 
    <i>Hooked</i>and later on his 1990 national debut 
    <i>To the Extreme</i>, it is his most famous and popular song.
    It has appeared in remixed form on 
    <i>Platinum Underground</i>and 
    <i>Vanilla Ice Is Back!</i>A live version appears on the album 
    <i>Extremely Live</i>, while a rap rock version appears on the
    album 
    <i>Hard to Swallow</i>, under the title "Too Cold".</p>
      <p>"Ice Ice Baby" was initially released as the B-side to Van
    Winkle's cover of "Play That Funky Music", but the single was
    not initially successful. When a disc jockey played "Ice Ice
    Baby" instead, it began to gain success. "Ice Ice Baby" was the
    first hip hop single to top the 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts. Topping the Australian, Dutch, Irish,
    Italian and UK charts, the song helped diversify hip hop by
    introducing it to a mainstream audience.</p>
      <p>Robert Van Winkle, better known by his stage name Vanilla
    Ice, wrote "Ice Ice Baby" at the age of 16, basing its lyrics
    upon his experiences in South Florida. The lyrics describe a
    drive-by shooting and Van Winkle's rhyming skills. The chorus
    of "Ice Ice Baby" originates from the signature chant of the
    national African American fraternity Alpha Phi Alpha. Of the
    song's lyrics, Van Winkle states that "If you released 'Ice Ice
    Baby' today, it would fit in today's lyrical respect among
    peers, you know what I'm sayin'? [...] My lyrics aren't, 'Pump
    it up, go! Go!' At least I'm sayin' somethin'."</p>
      <p>The song's hook samples the bassline of the 1981 song "Under
    Pressure" by Queen and David Bowie. Freddie Mercury and David
    Bowie did not receive credit or royalties for the sample. In a
    1990 interview, Van Winkle said the two melodies were slightly
    different because he had added an additional note. In later
    interviews, Van Winkle readily admitted he sampled the song and
    claimed his 1990 statement was a joke; others, however,
    suggested he had been serious. Van Winkle later paid Mercury
    and Bowie, who have since been given songwriting credit for the
    sample. In December 1990, Van Winkle told 
    <i>Smash Hits</i>magazine where he came up with the idea of
    sampling "Under Pressure":</p>
      <p>Van Winkle described himself as the first rapper to cross
    into the pop market, and said as a result he "had to take the
    heat for a lot of people" for his music's use of samples, but
    the criticism he received over sample use allowed sampling to
    become acceptable in mainstream hip hop.</p>
      <p>"Ice Ice Baby" was initially released by Ichiban Records as
    the B-side to Van Winkle's cover of "Play That Funky Music".
    The 12-inch single featured the radio, instrumental and a
    cappella versions of "Play That Funky Music" and the radio
    version and "Miami Drop" remix of "Ice Ice Baby". When a disc
    jockey played "Ice Ice Baby" instead of the single's A-side,
    the song gained more success than "Play That Funky Music". A
    music video for "Ice Ice Baby" was produced for $8000. The
    video was financed by Van Winkle's manager, Tommy Quon, and
    shot on the roof of a warehouse in Dallas, Texas. In the video,
    Van Winkle is shown rapping the lyrics while he and others
    dance to the song. Heavy airplay of the video by The Box while
    Van Winkle was still unknown increased public interest in the
    song. "Ice Ice Baby" was given its own single, released in 1990
    by SBK Records in the United States, and EMI Records in the
    United Kingdom. The SBK single contained the "Miami Drop",
    instrumental and radio mixes of "Ice Ice Baby" and the album
    version of "It's A Party". The EMI single contained the club
    and radio mixes of the song, and the shortened radio edit. The
    single was quickly pulled from the American market soon after
    the song reached number one, in a successful attempt to drive
    consumers to buy the album instead.</p>
      <p>"Ice Ice Baby" was the first hip hop single to top the 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts. It has been credited for helping
    diversify hip hop by introducing it to a mainstream (not
    exclusively black) audience.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Entertainment Weekly</i>reviewer Mim Udovitch wrote that
    "[Vanilla Ice] probably would have scored with his hit rap
    single 'Ice Ice Baby' even if he hadn't been white. There's
    just something about the way its hook — a sample from Queen and
    David Bowie's 'Under Pressure' — grabs you and flings you out
    onto the dance floor."</p>
      <p>Following the song's success, California rapper Mario
    "Chocolate" Johnson, an associate of record producer Suge
    Knight, claimed that he had written and produced the song, and
    had not received credit or royalties for the song. Knight and
    two bodyguards arrived at The Palm in West Hollywood, where Van
    Winkle was eating. After shoving Van Winkle's bodyguards aside,
    Knight and his own bodyguards sat down in front of Van Winkle,
    staring at him before finally asking "How you doin'?" Similar
    incidents were repeated on several occasions before Knight
    showed up at Van Winkle's hotel suite on the fifteenth floor of
    the Bel Age Hotel, accompanied by Johnson and a member of the
    Los Angeles Raiders. According to Van Winkle, Knight took him
    out on the balcony by himself, and implied that he would throw
    Van Winkle off unless he signed the rights to the song over to
    Knight.</p>
      <p>After audiences began to view Van Winkle as a novelty act
    and a pop star rather than a legitimate rapper, his popularity
    began to decline. Eminem states that when he first heard "Ice
    Ice Baby", "I felt like I didn't want to rap anymore. I was so
    mad, because he was making it real hard for me." Van Winkle
    lost some credibility among hip hop fans, but later began to
    regain some success, attracting a new audience outside of the
    mainstream audience that had formerly accepted him, and then
    rejected him. "Ice Ice Baby" continues to be the song that Van
    Winkle is best known for internationally, although Van Winkle
    states that his American fans like his newer music better.</p>
      <p>A live version appeared on the album 
    <i>Extremely Live</i>. "Ice Ice Baby" was rerecorded in a rap
    rock version titled "Too Cold". Originally intended to be
    released as a hidden track or B-side, "Too Cold" was featured
    on Van Winkle's 1998 album 
    <i>Hard to Swallow</i>, and became a radio hit in some markets.
    In 2000, a remix titled "Ice Ice Baby 2001" was released in
    Europe as a single, with a newly-produced music video. The
    remix generated new international interest in Van Winkle's
    music. In 2006, singer Richard Cheese released a comedic cover
    of the song, performed in a lounge style, on his album 
    <i>Silent Nightclub</i>.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Blender</i>ranked "Ice Ice Baby" fifth on its list of the
    "50 Worst Songs Ever". In 1999, the song's music video was
    "retired" on the MTV special 
    <i>25 Lame</i>, in which Van Winkle himself appeared to destroy
    the video's master tape. Given a baseball bat, Van Winkle ended
    up destroying the show's set.</p>
      <p>In 2010, Irish singing duo Jedward recorded a mashup of
    "Under Pressure" and "Ice Ice Baby" as their debut single.
    "Under Pressure (Ice Ice Baby)" was released in the United
    Kingdom on January 31, 2010 via download and as a physical
    single on February 15, 2010. Vanilla Ice will rap a part on his
    own and also with Jedward in the song.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
