<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Let_It_Snow 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Let_It_Snow</songId>
   <title>Let It Snow! Let It Snow! Let It Snow!</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vaughn_Monroe</artistId>
      <artistName>Vaughn Monroe</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1946-01-26</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Let It Snow! Let It Snow! Let It Snow!", also known as "Let
    It Snow", is a song written by lyricist Sammy Cahn and composer
    Jule Styne in 1945. It was written in July 1945 in Hollywood,
    California during one of the hottest days on record.</p>
      <p>First recorded by Vaughn Monroe on October 31, 1945, it
    became a popular hit, reaching number one on the music chart
    the following year. One of the best-selling songs of all time,
    "Let It Snow!" has been covered countless times. Due to its
    seasonal lyrics, it is commonly regarded as a Christmas song in
    the Northern Hemisphere. Yet despite its cheery, holiday feel,
    it is a love song that never mentions Christmas and both the
    composer and lyricist were Jewish.</p>
      <p>Popular cover versions during the song's original popularity
    (late 1945-early '46) included the jazz bands of Woody Herman
    and Bob Crosby. This song was included on Ella Fitzgerald's
    1960 Verve Records release: "Ella Wishes You a Swinging
    Christmas". Bing Crosby recorded a version in 1962. Dean Martin
    also recorded different versions in 1959 and 1966.</p>
      <p>The 1945 recording by Monroe was featured in the first two 
    <i>Die Hard</i>movies, set during Christmas Eve in (assumedly)
    successive years.</p>
      <p>Jessica Simpson's version, recorded for her 
    <i>Rejoyce: The Christmas Album</i>in 2004 (see 2004 in music)
    and produced by Billy Mann, was the album's first single, and
    made the top twenty of the Adult Contemporary chart. The
    Italian singer Irene Grandi recorded in 2008 a personal
    version, sung in English. Connie Talbot recorded the song on
    her 2008 Christmas Album.</p>
      <p>The song was also covered by Vonda Shepard in 2000 for 
    <i>Ally McBeal</i>, on the album 
    <i>A Very Ally Christmas</i>and Celtic Woman in the 2006 album 
    <i>A Christmas Celebration</i>.</p>
      <p>This song can also be found on Martina McBride's 
    <i>White Christmas</i>album which was released in 1999.</p>
      <p>A heavy metal version of this song was recorded by Twisted
    Sister for their 2006 album 
    <i>A Twisted Christmas</i>.</p>
      <p>Japanese-American pop star Hikaru Utada and pop star Mika
    covered a version of the song at Studio Coast, Tokyo on
    November 30, 2009.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
