<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Everything_She_Wants 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Everything_She_Wants</songId>
   <title>Everything She Wants</title>
   <artist>
      <artistName>Wham!</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1985-05-25</week>
      <week>1985-06-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/05/Everything_She_Wants.jpg/200px-Everything_She_Wants.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Wham+Everything-She-Wants.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Make It Big</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 27, 1984 (UK) , April 17, 1985 (US)</released>
   <formats>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1984</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Music</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:01</length>
      <length>6:29 (Remix)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>CBS</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>George Michael</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Michael</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Everything She Wants" was a song by British pop duo Wham!,
    released in 1984 on Epic Records on a double A-side with "Last
    Christmas". It was written by George Michael, one half of the
    duo.</p>
      <p>Upon release, "Last Christmas" took the majority of the
    attention and airplay as it was appropriate in early December
    as Christmas approached. However, the presence of an
    equally-billed flip side meant that radio stations had
    something else to play once "Last Christmas" had lost its
    topicality.</p>
      <p>A five-minute song (there also exists a
    six-and-a-half-minutes-long version with an added bridge),
    "Everything She Wants" is written from the angle of a man
    rapidly approaching desperation at the material demands of his
    partner which seem to be coming to a head, despite the amount
    of work he does to keep them happy. In a twist, the second
    verse takes the story a step further by revealing that the
    woman is pregnant but the man cannot find any happiness in the
    announcement because of the extra pressure a baby will put upon
    him.</p>
      <p>The presence of the Band Aid project meant that the double
    A-side peaked at number two in the UK singles chart, although
    in the process it became the biggest selling record not to get
    to number one. However, in the USA, the song did reach the
    summit of the Billboard Hot 100, and became the third
    number-one song in a row from 1984's 
    <i>Make It Big</i>album.</p>
      <p>Wham! would go on to have two more number-one hits in the UK
    before splitting at their height in 1986.</p>
      <p>Although Michael bemoaned much of Wham!'s material as he
    began his solo career, "Everything She Wants" remained a song
    of which he was proud, and he continued to perform it in his
    shows. Furthermore, Michael remarked in an interview (to
    promote 25 Live tour) that "Everything She Wants" is his
    favourite Wham! song.</p>
      <p>The song was remixed and re-released as "Everything She
    Wants '97" for the greatest hits album 
    <i>If You Were There</i>in 1997.</p>
      <p>The song was also mentioned in a landmark 1998 sampling
    copyright decision in the case of 
    <i>Santrayll v. Burrell</i>. Federal Court Judge Peter K.
    Leisure concluded that MC Hammer had sampled music by another
    rap group (The Legend). The Legend admitted to sampling Wham!'s
    "Everything She Wants" (among other songs) and not disclosing
    the sampled works when filing for copyright registration. In
    essence, Hammer argued that because The Legend admitted to
    sampling (i.e. "Everything She Wants"), this constituted a
    knowing failure to advise the Copyright Office of facts that
    might have led to the rejection of the copyright application.
    Meaning: no copyright protection, no lawsuit for infringement
    against Hammer. The court disagreed and found that: (1) it was
    possible that a jury might find that the failure to disclose
    the samples was not deliberate and (2) the samples played such
    a minor role in The Legend's song that the unauthorized use of
    samples "could not possibly have led the Copyright Office to
    reject the copyright applications."</p>
      <p>The popular Canadian teen drama Degrassi: The Next
    Generation, which named each episode after an 80s hit song,
    named an episode after this song.</p>
      <p>Rapper Foxy Brown sampled "Everything She Wants" on the
    single "I Can't" from her number one album 
    <i>Chyna Doll</i>.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
