<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wake_Me_Up_Before_You_Go-Go 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wake_Me_Up_Before_You_Go-Go</songId>
   <title>Wake Me Up Before You Go-Go</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wham!</artistId>
      <artistName>Wham!</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1984-11-17</week>
      <week>1984-11-24</week>
      <week>1984-12-01</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/9/9d/WakeMeUpBeforeYouGoGo.jpg/200px-WakeMeUpBeforeYouGoGo.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Wham+Wake-Me-Up-Before-You-Go-Go.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Make It Big</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 5, 1984</released>
   <formats>
      <format>12"</format>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1984</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:50</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>CBS Records (US/Canada) , Epic Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>George Michael</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Michael</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Wake Me Up Before You Go-Go" is a song by English pop duo
    Wham! which was released in 1984 and became their first UK
    number one hit. It was written and produced by George Michael,
    one half of the duo.</p>
      <p>Michael's inspiration for the song was a scribbled note left
    by his Wham! partner Andrew Ridgeley for Andrew's parents,
    originally intended to read "wake me up before you go" but with
    "up" accidentally written twice, so Ridgeley wrote "go" twice
    on purpose. Released in May 1984, it heralded the beginning of
    a softer, sunnier image for Wham!, who had spent the previous
    year as a moodier, more politically themed duo, with songs
    about unemployment, young marriage, and battles of will between
    parents and their children. With the release of "Wake Me Up
    Before You Go-Go", they re-emerged with wider smiles, more
    colourful clothing, and a more positive disposition in
    interviews.</p>
      <p>The song entered the UK singles chart at number four — after
    much hype from the duo claiming they would go straight in at
    number one, which was a rare occurrence then — and climbed to
    the top seven days later, staying there for three weeks.</p>
      <p>The song also went to the top of the Hot 100 in the USA and
    Michael followed it up with a solo single, "Careless Whisper"
    and another Wham! hit, "Freedom", both of which were also UK
    number-one hits. The album, 
    <i>Make It Big</i>, was an unqualified success. Wham! had three
    more UK number one singles and split at their height in
    1986.</p>
      <p>Another band, 
    <i>Babs &amp; The Bopettes</i>, sang phonetically by Tress
    MacNeille as Babs Bunny along with her friends, Gail Matthius
    as Shirley the Loon, Kath Soucie as Fifi Le Fume and Cree
    Summer as Mary Melody. The "Jitterbug!" part is by Charles
    Adler as Buster Bunny, Joe Alaskey as Plucky Duck and Don
    Messick as Hamton J. Pig. The chorus is when Babs Bunny
    lectures Gogo Dodo to wake Babs up before Gogo does. At the
    end, she laughs and says, "Well c'mon, do you want me to see
    Buster, or 
    <i>not</i>?".</p>
      <p>The music video, essentially the duo performing (it also
    introduced Ridgeley as a guitar player for the band) to a
    teenage audience, was memorable for the clothes, which became a
    lasting sartorial image for the 1980s as a decade. Michael and
    Ridgeley, plus backing singers Pepsi and Shirlie, along with
    motor trade Guru Peter (Froudy) Froud, were wearing Katharine
    Hamnett T-shirt designs which said "CHOOSE LIFE" (originally a
    slogan targeted at drug abuse and suicide) and "GO GO", which
    became much sought-after fashion items of the year. Michael was
    also seen in luminous gloves, which he later bemoaned as the
    clip of him always picked out by advertisers whenever "Wake Me
    Up Before You Go-Go" went on to a compilation album. The video
    was filmed at the Carling Academy Brixton in London.</p>
      <p>The video was barely "spared retirement" from rotation on
    MTV when it was voted #11 on the network's worst videos
    countdown in 1999. During the video's commentary, co-host Denis
    Leary joked that he knew George Michael was gay when he first
    caught a glimpse of Michael's shorts.</p>
      <p>On the other hand, Blink-182 listed the video as their
    all-time favorite.</p>
      <p>The US 7" single (Columbia 04552) had the same track
    listing.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
