<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Here_I_Go_Again 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Here_I_Go_Again</songId>
   <title>Here I Go Again</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whitesnake</artistId>
      <artistName>Whitesnake</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-10-10</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/2/25/Hereigoagain.jpg/200px-Hereigoagain.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Whitesnake+Here-I-Go-Again.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Whitesnake</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1987</released>
   <formats>
      <format>Cassette</format>
      <format>CD</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>September 1985–October 1986</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hard Rock</genre>
      <genre>Heavy Metal</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:36</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Geffen</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>David Coverdale</writer>
      <writer>Bernie Marsden</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Mike Stone &amp; Keith Olsen</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Here I Go Again" is a song recorded by Whitesnake.
    Originally released on their 1982 album, 
    <i>Saints &amp; Sinners</i>, the song was re-recorded for their
    eponymous 1987 album 
    <i>Whitesnake</i>. The 1987 version hit number one on the
    Billboard Hot 100 chart on October 10, 1987, and number nine on
    the UK Singles Chart on November 28, 1987. The 1987 version
    also hit number one on the Canadian Singles Chart on October
    24, 1987. In 2006, the 1987 version was named the 17th Greatest
    Song of the 1980s by VH1. The song was re-recorded yet another
    time in a new "Radio Version" for the band's 
    <i>Greatest Hits</i>album in 1994.</p>
      <p>The song was written by lead singer, David Coverdale, and
    former Whitesnake guitarist, Bernie Marsden. The most notable
    differences between the original and revamped version are the
    style of the music (blues-rock versus hard rock) and a slight
    change in the lyrics. The chorus of the original version
    features the lines:</p>
      <p>Whereas the newer version is:</p>
      <p>The change was made because even before finishing writing
    and recording the 1987 album, Coverdale had decided to release
    a new version of "Here I Go Again" as one of the singles. He
    was afraid an American audience might think he was singing
    "Like a homo, I was born to walk alone" so he changed the
    lyrics.</p>
      <p>The guitar on the 1993 remix version was played by session
    guitarist Dann Huff.</p>
      <p>The music video for the song was directed by Marty Callner
    who directed most of Whitesnake's videos in the 1980s. It
    became memorable due to actress Tawny Kitaen's appearance
    wearing white lingerie. In the video she is seen prancing on
    the hood of Whitesnake lead singer David Coverdale's Jaguar and
    massaging him while he is trying in vain to concentrate on
    driving. Kitaen would later become Coverdale's wife for a brief
    period.</p>
      <p>The music video was parodied in an 
    <i>American Dad!</i>episode, as well as the films 
    <i>Talladega Nights: The Ballad of Ricky Bobby</i>and 
    <i>Death Proof</i>. It was also featured a number of times in
    the Frat Pack film 
    <i>Old School</i>. It was featured being sung by Nicholas
    D'Agosto and Eric Christian Olsen during the credits of "Fired
    Up!" It was also parodied in Bowling for Soup's "1985" music
    video. Originally recorded by SR-71, the song itself contains
    further references with the lyrics "She was gonna shake her
    ass/On the hood of Whitesnake's car".</p>
      <p>There are several different versions of the song, all
    recorded officially by Whitesnake. They are:</p>
      <p>In 1987, EMI released a limited Collectors Poster Edition
    'USA Single Remix' 7" vinyl [EMP 35], the B-side of which
    consists of an engraved signature version, and the sleeve of
    which unfolds into a poster of the band.</p>
      <p>While the 1987 album version and the "Radio" version
    (released on the 
    <i>Greatest Hits</i>album) of the tune are fairly similar,
    there are several significant differences. The original 1987
    version has a long and slow keyboard and vocal intro, whereas
    the other kicks straight in with the band. One was recorded for
    the album 1987, the other for a U.S single release. They
    contain two very different guitar solos, Adrian Vandenberg
    plays the album and video solo, and Dan Huff plays on the radio
    edit version. Of the two versions, the one most widely referred
    to is the remastered version released in 1987, although both
    receive significant airplay today.</p>
      <p>The song appeared in the 1998 film I Still Know What You Did
    Last Summer.</p>
      <p>The song appeared prominently in the 2003 comedy Old
    School.</p>
      <p>The song appeared in the 2008 film Adventureland.</p>
      <p>The song appeared in the credits of the 2009 film Fired
    Up.</p>
      <p>"Here I Go Again" was rendered anew as the debut single by
    Polish dance/pop singer Mandaryna. Remixed by Groove Coverage,
    the song was a smash hit in Poland, Europe and Asia, peaking at
    #2 on the Polish Singles Chart.</p>
      <p>Christian rock parody band, ApologetiX, released a parody of
    the song titled "Here I Go (Against All I've Known)" on their
    2006 studio album, 
    <i>Wordplay</i>.</p>
      <p>The song appears as a cover in the game 
    <i>Karaoke Revolution Party</i>.</p>
      <p>Eurotrance group Topmodelz covered the song on their 2008
    album, 
    <i>Time 2 Rock</i>, and released two remixes of their
    cover.</p>
      <p>The song was featured in the Broadway musical Rock of Ages,
    which opened on 7 April 2009 at the Brooks Atkinson
    Theatre.</p>
      <p>Uncle Kracker released his new album, Happy Hour in 2009
    with the track Livin' The Dream featuring the chorus of Here I
    Go Again in the song.</p>
      <p>The song is played during the final cutscene of the
    real-time strategy video game World in Conflict.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
