<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Wanna_Dance_with_Somebody_(Who_Loves_Me) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Wanna_Dance_with_Somebody_(Who_Loves_Me)</songId>
   <title>I Wanna Dance with Somebody (Who Loves Me)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whitney_Houston</artistId>
      <artistName>Whitney Houston</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-06-27</week>
      <week>1987-07-04</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/69/WhitneyHouston_IWannaDance.jpg/200px-WhitneyHouston_IWannaDance.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Whitney-Houston+I-Wanna-Dance-with-Somebody-Who-Loves-Me.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Whitney</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 28, 1987</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>November 1986</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:52</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Arista</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>George Merrill</writer>
      <writer>Shannon Rubicam</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Narada Michael Walden</producer>
      <producer>Whitney Houston</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Wanna Dance with Somebody (Who Loves Me)" is the first
    single from Whitney Houston's second studio album 
    <i>Whitney</i>. It was produced by Narada Michael Walden, and
    written by George Merrill and Shannon Rubicam of the band Boy
    Meets Girl, who had previously written the number-one Whitney
    Houston hit "How Will I Know". The original arrangement was
    more of a country tune but was transformed to make it a dance
    song by Walden.</p>
      <p>The song reached number one on the Billboard Hot 100 on June
    27, 1987 (the same day that Houston's album 
    <i>Whitney</i>debuted at number one, the first time ever by a
    female artist), and remained there for two weeks. It remained
    in the top forty of the Hot 100 for fourteen weeks, and was
    ranked fourth on the Year-End Chart.</p>
      <p>The song reached number one on the Hot 100 Single Sales
    chart for two weeks, and on the Hot 100 Airplay chart for three
    weeks, Houston's longest run at that time. It was also a
    milestone in Houston's career, as it sold enough units to be
    certified platinum, her first single to achieve this. It was
    also number one on the Adult Contemporary chart for three
    weeks, and reached number two on the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop
    Singles &amp; Tracks. It became Houston's first number-one on
    the Hot Dance Club Play chart.</p>
      <p>Internationally, Houston made the song a global smash, as it
    became her biggest hit at that point. It reached number one in
    over a dozen other countries, including the United Kingdom,
    West Germany, Australia, and Switzerland, propelling the parent
    album 
    <i>Whitney</i>to number one in all of those countries as well.
    At 4.2 million sold globally, it is Houston's second
    best-selling single after "I Will Always Love You".</p>
      <p>
         <i>Slant Magazine</i>ranked the song at #88 in their 100
    Greatest Dance Songs</p>
      <p>
         <i>Blender Magazine</i>ranked the song #275 in their Top 500
    songs since 1980 List.</p>
      <p>The song also won "Best Music Video" at the First Annual
    Garden State (New Jersey) Music Awards. In 1988, Whitney
    Houston opened the night of the 30th Annual Grammy Awards
    singing "I Wanna Dance with Somebody (Who Loves Me)".</p>
      <p>The video for "I Wanna Dance with Somebody" (directed by
    Brian Grant) is one of Houston's best recognized music videos.
    In the intro of this video, Houston just finishes a performance
    onstage. She walks backstage, and the scene is intercut with
    more vivid, colorful images of her. The song then explodes into
    its beginning, with myriad locations and various outfits by
    Houston, as dancers trying to impress her as she dances around,
    just having a good time. The music video was in heavy rotation
    on music channels MTV, VH1, and BET during the song's run.</p>
      <p>"I Wanna Dance with Somebody (Who Loves Me)" was ranked
    fourth on The Billboard Hot 100 Year End Charts (1987), and
    remained in The Billboard Hot 100 for nineteen weeks.</p>
      <p>It was Houston's fourth number-one single on The Billboard
    Hot 100, her third on The Billboard Hot 100 Airplay, fourth on
    The Billboard Hot 100 Single Sales, her fourth on The Billboard
    Adult Contemporary, and her fifth overall Billboard Top Ten
    hit.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
