<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_Will_I_Know 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_Will_I_Know</songId>
   <title>How Will I Know</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whitney_Houston</artistId>
      <artistName>Whitney Houston</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-02-15</week>
      <week>1986-02-22</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/88/Whitney_Houston_HowWill_IKnow.jpg/200px-Whitney_Houston_HowWill_IKnow.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Whitney-Houston+How-Will-I-Know.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Whitney Houston</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>November 1985</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>Cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1984</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Dance Pop</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:36</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Arista</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>George Merrill</writer>
      <writer>Shannon Rubicam</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Narada Michael Walden</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"How Will I Know" is the third hit single from Whitney
    Houston's self-titled first album. The single was released in
    November 1985 and was written by George Merrill and Shannon
    Rubicam of Boy Meets Girl fame, who wrote it for Janet Jackson.
    The song is an electric dance tune about the singer wondering
    if a guy she likes feels the same way about her. Houston became
    a staple on MTV with the release of this hit single.</p>
      <p>On the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 singles chart, "How Will I
    Know" reached the #1 spot on February 15, 1986, becoming
    Houston's second number-one single and third top five single
    from the same album. The single displaced "That's What Friends
    Are For" by Houston's cousin Dionne Warwick, thus becoming just
    the third time (and first time by female artists) in history
    for relatives to replace each other at number one on the Hot
    100. It remained at number one for two weeks, and spent fifteen
    weeks in the top forty. It was ranked #6 on Billboard's top
    year end pop charts. The song performed extremely well on other
    Billboard charts as well, climbing to number one on the Adult
    Contemporary, Hot Black Singles, and Hot Dance Club Play
    charts, showing Houston's success was not limited to any single
    genre. Internationally, the single made Houston a noticeable
    star, reaching number five in the United Kingdom. The song may
    be heard in its original version, or in an extended percussion
    intro version (such as in the music video). Later copies of
    Houston's debut album contain the latter version.</p>
      <p>The music video for "How Will I Know" was directed by Brian
    Grant and is set against a fantasy, vividly colored background,
    with dancers in black outfits and wearing French-style makeup.
    The video is recognized for the animated paint dripping down
    the screen. In the video, when Houston sings "I'm asking you
    'cause you know about these things", there's a brief screencap
    of singer, close family friend, and godmother Aretha Franklin.
    Notable, too, is that the melody of "How Will I Know" closely
    samples the chorus melody of Aretha's earlier 1985 hit, "Who's
    Zoomin' Who", which was a relatively popular hit and also
    produced by Narada Michael Walden, hence her paying homage to
    her as well.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
