<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Didn%27t_We_Almost_Have_It_All 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Didn%27t_We_Almost_Have_It_All</songId>
   <title>Didn't We Almost Have It All</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whitney_Houston</artistId>
      <artistName>Whitney Houston</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1987-09-26</week>
      <week>1987-10-03</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/6e/Whitney_Houston_Didnt_We_Almost.jpg/200px-Whitney_Houston_Didnt_We_Almost.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Whitney-Houston+Didn-t-We-Almost-Have-It-All.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Whitney</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>August 13, 1987</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>Cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1986</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Soul</genre>
      <genre>R&amp;B</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>5:07</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Arista</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Michael Masser</writer>
      <writer>Will Jennings</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Michael Masser</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Didn't We Almost Have It All" is the second single from
    Whitney Houston's second album Whitney, and was nominated for
    Song of the Year at the 1988 Grammy Awards. The song was
    written by Michael Masser and Will Jennings and was released in
    August 1987. Originally, another song was to be released as the
    second single, "For The Love Of You", but Arista Records
    decided to release "Didn't We Almost Have It All" instead.</p>
      <p>The single was number one on the US Billboard Hot 100 even
    though there was not a video for the song. A live performance
    of the song recorded during Houston's successful 1987–1988
    Moment of Truth World Tour was played on MTV, VH1, and BET. The
    performance is from a Saratoga Springs, New York date.</p>
      <p>"Didn't We Almost Have It All" reached number one on the
    Billboard Hot 100 for two weeks, from September 26 to October
    9, 1987, where the song became her fifth consecutive number
    one. The song also topped both component charts, the Hot 100
    Single Sales and Hot 100 Airplay, Houston's fourth song (and
    fourth consecutive release) to do so.</p>
      <p>The single stayed in the Top 40 for thirteen weeks, and
    topped the Billboard Adult Contemporary Charts for three
    weeks.</p>
      <p>Internationally, the song hit the top ten in several
    markets, and reached the Top Twenty in the United Kingdom
    (#14); Switzerland (#18); and Germany (#20).</p>
      <p>"Didn't We Almost Have It All" was ranked twenty-second on
    the Billboard Hot 100 year-end charts (1987), and remained in
    the Billboard Hot 100 for seventeen weeks. It was her fifth
    number one single on the Billboard Hot 100, her fourth on the
    Billboard Hot 100 Single Sales, her fourth on the Billboard Hot
    100 Airplay, and her fifth on the Billboard Adult Contemporary
    Charts.</p>
      <p>The season 3 finale of 
    <i>Grey's Anatomy</i>and an episode of the eighth season of 
    <i>Degrassi: The Next Generation</i>are named after this
    song.</p>
      <p>It is widely speculated the song is about Houston's
    relationship with then NFL star Randall Cunningham.</p>
      <p>The Austrian singer Lia Weller performed the song in the
    fourth season of the talent show Starmania. Although it was
    generally considered one of the best performances of the
    evening, she was voted off. A week later, she released the Song
    on iTunes.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
