<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greatest_Love_of_All 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greatest_Love_of_All</songId>
   <title>Greatest Love of All</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whitney_Houston</artistId>
      <artistName>Whitney Houston</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1986-05-17</week>
      <week>1986-05-24</week>
      <week>1986-05-31</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/66/Whitney_Houston_GreatestLove.jpg/200px-Whitney_Houston_GreatestLove.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Whitney-Houston+Greatest-Love-of-All.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Whitney Houston</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>March 1986</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
      <format>Cassette single</format>
      <format>7" single</format>
      <format>12" single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1984</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
      <genre>Gospel</genre>
      <genre>Soul Ballad</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:52</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Arista Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Michael Masser</writer>
      <writer>Linda Creed</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Narada Michael Walden</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Greatest Love of All" is an inspirational song written by
    Michael Masser and Linda Creed and performed by Whitney
    Houston. Creed wrote the lyrics in the midst of her struggle
    with breast cancer. The words describe her feelings about
    coping with a terminal illness and being a young mother. Creed
    eventually succumbed to the disease in April 1986 (at the age
    of 37).</p>
      <p>The song was the seventh single released from Houston's
    self-titled multi-platinum debut studio album, 
    <i>Whitney Houston</i>. The single, released in April 1986,
    spent three weeks at #1 on the Hot 100 chart in May of that
    year. Clive Davis, founder of Houston's label Arista Records,
    was initially against Houston recording the song, but he
    eventually gave in after persuasion from Houston and Masser.
    The song was first included as the B-side to the single "You
    Give Good Love", another Top 5 hit by Houston.</p>
      <p>Houston's original album version features a piano intro,
    while the single version begins with a keyboard intro. After
    the single became a success, it replaced the album version on
    subsequent copies of the album. The original album version was
    restored for the 2010 Deluxe Anniversary Edition reissue of the
    album.</p>
      <p>The song had originally been recorded by George Benson for
    the 1977 Muhammad Ali film 
    <i>The Greatest</i>. Benson's version was a great hit, reaching
    #2 on the R&amp;B chart and making the top 40 on the 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100.</p>
      <p>Houston's single reached number one on the Hot 100 chart for
    three weeks in 1986. The single was the fourth hit (and third
    #1) from her debut album. To date, this song was her second
    longest stay atop this chart, behind 1992's 
    <i>I Will Always Love You</i>. The song also reached number one
    on both component charts, the Hot 100 Singles Sales and the Hot
    100 Airplay, her second consecutive release to do so, and
    stayed for fourteen weeks in the top forty. On other 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts, Houston also performed well, reaching
    number three on the R&amp;B chart. The song topped the adult
    contemporary chart for five weeks, Houston's longest stay at
    the top of the chart at the time. The song ranked #11 on
    Billboard's year end pop singles chart. Houston's single fared
    well internationally as well, reaching #8 in the United Kingdom
    and the top ten or #1 in several other European countries. It
    became her first #1 single in Australia. Houston won the
    American Music Award for Favorite Soul/R&amp;B Video, and was
    nominated for a Grammy Award for Record of the Year and a Soul
    Train Music Award for Single of the Year.</p>
      <p>Many critics called the single the centerpiece of Houston's
    debut album. Stephen Holden of 
    <i>The New York Times</i>wrote that "Houston sings it with a
    forceful directness that gives its message of self-worth an
    astounding resonance and conviction" and called the song a
    compelling assertion of spiritual devotion, black pride, and
    family loyalty, all at once. Don Shewey of 
    <i>Rolling Stone</i>wrote that as the song builds, Houston
    "slowly pours on the soul, slips in some churchy phrasing,
    holds notes a little longer and shows off her glorious
    voice."</p>
      <p>Houston's music video was filmed at Harlem's Apollo Theater
    in New York City. In the video, she is a successful singer
    about to perform in from of an audience at the Apollo Theater.
    She reminisces about the time when she was a child performing
    in a talent competition at the very same theater. The video
    features Houston's mother Cissy Houston playing herself,
    encouraging and supporting a young Whitney.</p>
      <p>US Vinyl, 7", Single</p>
      <p>An alternate version of the song, featuring just the piano
    and the vocal, appeared on 200,000 limited copies of the album 
    <i>Whitney Houston</i>.</p>
      <p>Among the many such references in the popular culture
    are:</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
