<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Will_Always_Love_You#Whitney_Houston 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Will_Always_Love_You#Whitney_Houston</songId>
   <title>I Will Always Love You</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whitney_Houston</artistId>
      <artistName>Whitney Houston</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1993-01-02</week>
      <week>1993-01-09</week>
      <week>1993-01-16</week>
      <week>1993-01-23</week>
      <week>1993-01-30</week>
      <week>1993-02-06</week>
      <week>1993-02-13</week>
      <week>1993-02-20</week>
      <week>1993-02-27</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/72/Dolly_Parton_I_will.jpg/200px-Dolly_Parton_I_will.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Whitney-Houston+I-Will-Always-Love-You.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Jolene</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>April 4, 1974 (U.S.) , July 23, 1982 (re-recording) , 1995 (re-recording w/ Vince Gill )</released>
   <formats>
      <format>45 rpm single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>RCA Studio "B", Nashville ; June 17, 1973 (original)</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Country</genre>
      <genre>Soft Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:55</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Dolly Parton</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Bob Ferguson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"I Will Always Love You" is a song written by American
    singer-songwriter Dolly Parton in 1973, who first released the
    song as a single in 1974. American singer Whitney Houston's
    (1992) version of the song became one of the best-selling
    singles of all time.</p>
      <p>Dolly Parton wrote the song in 1973 and it was released a
    year later, having been produced by Bob Ferguson. She has told
    numerous interviewers over the years that she wrote it for her
    one-time partner and mentor Porter Wagoner, with whom she was
    having a business splitting at the time. Recorded on June 17,
    1973 in RCA's Studio "B" in Nashville, the song was included on
    Parton's album 
    <i>Jolene</i>, and was released as a follow-up single, after
    the country chart-topping success of the title track, in April
    1974. The single reached number 1 on the 
    <i>Billboard'</i>Hot Country Songs a month later, but had just
    modest success on the pop charts. The lyrics express a
    bittersweet and poignant ode to an ex-lover, and are delivered
    with Parton's distinctive twang.</p>
      <p>Parton re-recorded the song in 1982 to include it on the
    soundtrack of 
    <i>The Best Little Whorehouse in Texas</i>, the film version of
    the Broadway musical of the same name. Her 1982 version also
    reached number 1 on the U.S. Hot Country Songs, marking the
    first time the same song reached number 1 on the country charts
    twice by the same artist. The 1982 version also saw limited
    crossover pop success, reaching number 53 on the Billboard Hot
    100 and number 17 on the Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks.</p>
      <p>Parton had success with the song again in 1995 in a duet
    with Vince Gill. This time the song peaked at number 15 in
    December of that year, making it the third time the song was a
    hit for Parton, albeit in duet form this time. In 2003, CMT
    ranked it number 16 on their 
    <i>100 Greatest Songs in Country Music</i>. A year later, CMT
    ranked it number 1 on their 
    <i>100 Greatest Country Love Songs</i>.</p>
      <p>The most recent release of the song appears on Parton's 2008
    album 
    <i>Backwoods Barbie</i>, which features a live version - an
    exclusive iTunes bonus track.</p>
      <p>In 1992, singer Whitney Houston recorded the song for the
    soundtrack to 
    <i>The Bodyguard</i>, her film debut. Houston was originally to
    record Jimmy Ruffin's "What Becomes of the Brokenhearted" as
    the lead single from 
    <i>The Bodyguard</i>. However, when it was discovered the song
    was to be used for 
    <i>Fried Green Tomatoes</i>, Houston requested a different song
    and her co-star Kevin Costner brought her Linda Ronstadt's 1975
    version of "I Will Always Love You" from her album 
    <i>Prisoner in Disguise</i>. Houston and producer David Foster
    re-arranged the song as a soul ballad. Her record company did
    not feel a song with an a cappella introduction would be as
    successful; however, Houston and Costner insisted to maintain
    an a cappella intro. Whitney Houston's recording is not the
    only version of the song featured in the movie. In a scene
    where she dances with Kevin Costner, a version by John Doe can
    be heard playing on a jukebox.</p>
      <p>Houston's version was a massive worldwide success, selling
    over 15 million copies worldwide. It became a regular on
    countdown lists: appearing at number 8 on VH1's 
    <i>100 Greatest Songs of the Past 25 Years</i>; number 4 on
    VH1's 
    <i>100 Greatest Songs of the 90s</i>and number 1 on VH1's 
    <i>100 Greatest Love Songs</i>. The song also lists at number
    68 on 
    <i>Billboard's Greatest Songs of all time.</i>
      </p>
      <p>The single's music video, credited to Alan Smithee, begins
    with the performance of the song Houston gives at the end of 
    <i>The Bodyguard</i>. The video then cuts to Houston in a dark
    blue suit sitting in an empty theater with the spotlight
    shining on her, singing of her love. The video is intercut with
    scenes from 
    <i>The Bodyguard</i>and gives the viewer the experience of
    reliving the moments with the singer.</p>
      <p>The single spent fourteen weeks at the top of the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100, which at the time was a record. The single
    became Houston's longest run at number 1, beating her previous
    record of three weeks with 1986's, "Greatest Love of All." It
    is also the longest running number 1 single from a soundtrack
    album.</p>
      <p>The single debuted at number 40 on the Billboard Hot 100 and
    became Houston's tenth number 1 hit a mere two weeks later. It
    also dominated various other 
    <i>Billboard</i>charts, spending fourteen weeks at the top of 
    <i>Billboard</i>Hot 100 Single Sales (the most for a solo
    female artist &amp; later tied by Mariah Carey's 
    <i>We Belong Together</i>), and eleven weeks at number 1 on its
    Hot 100 Airplay. The song also stayed at number 1 for five
    weeks on the Hot Adult Contemporary Tracks and for eleven weeks
    on the Hot R&amp;B/Hip-Hop Songs becoming the longest running
    number 1 on the R&amp;B charts at the time, and remained in the
    top 40 for twenty-four weeks. It became Arista Records' biggest
    hit. The song was number 1 on the Hot 100, Adult Contemporary,
    and R&amp;B chart simulateously for a record five weeks.</p>
      <p>Houston's single sold approximately 400,000 copies in its
    second week of release, making it the best-selling song in a
    single week (taking the record from Bryan Adams' "(Everything I
    Do) I Do It for You"). It broke its own record in the following
    three weeks, peaking at 632,000 copies in the week ending
    December 19, 1992 (the week it broke its own record for most
    copies sold in a single week for any song). It was certified
    4xPlatinum in the U.S. for shipments of over 4 million copies.
    and another six million worldwide, making it the third
    best-selling single in the world. It remains the biggest
    selling single by a female artist and the biggest selling
    non-charity single.</p>
      <p>Houston's single became a massive international success,
    hitting number 1 in the United Kingdom for ten weeks, and
    Australia for ten weeks. It also hit pole position in Austria
    for 5 weeks, Belgium, Ireland, Sweden for 3 weeks, Norway for 9
    weeks, Switzerland for 8 weeks, Germany for 6 weeks, France for
    8 weeks, Denmark, Netherlands for 6 weeks, and New Zealand for
    11 weeks. It is the only single to have ever topped both the
    U.S. and Australian charts for at least ten weeks.</p>
      <p>The song stayed at number 1 in the United States throughout
    January and February in 1993, making it the first time 
    <i>Billboard</i>didn't rank a new number one single until March
    of the new year. Houston's "I Will Always Love You" was also
    the year-end single of 1993 in the U.S. Similarly, in the UK,
    Houston's version was ranked the number 1 single of 1992, and
    then made the countdown again in 1993 where it was ranked
    number 9, marking the first time any artist or group had the
    same single ranked in the top 10 of the year-end review two
    years in a row. Houston's soundtrack album for 
    <i>The Bodyguard</i>was number 1 for twenty weeks, and it
    became the best-selling soundtrack of all time. The album has
    been certified diamond in the U.S. for sales of over 17
    million, and has sold 42 million copies total worldwide to
    date.</p>
      <p>CD single</p>
      <p>CD maxi-single</p>
      <p>After Whitney Houston's cover of the song became a hit, the
    tabloid press began reporting on a 'feud' between the two
    performers, stemming from Parton's allegedly reneging on an
    agreement that she would not perform the song for a number of
    months while Houston's version was on the charts, so as not to
    compete with the more recent cover. However, both Houston and
    Parton have dispelled any rumors, speaking glowingly of one
    another in interviews, Houston praising Parton for writing a
    beautiful song, and Parton thanking Houston for bringing her
    song to a wider audience, and in the process making her a great
    deal of money in royalties. Dolly Parton also gave a live
    interview, confirming this.</p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Nel blu dipinto di blu
      (Volare)" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Mack the
      Knife" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Theme from A Summer
      Place" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Moon River" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Left My Heart in San
      Francisco" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Days of Wine and
      Roses" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"The Girl from
      Ipanema" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"A Taste of
      Honey" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Strangers in the
      Night" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Up, Up and
      Away" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Mrs. Robinson"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Aquarius/Let the Sunshine
      In" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Bridge over Troubled
      Water" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"It's Too
      Late" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"The First Time Ever I Saw
      Your Face" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Killing Me Softly with His
      Song" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"I Honestly Love
      You" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Love Will Keep Us
      Together" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"This
      Masquerade" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Hotel
      California" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Just the Way You
      Are"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"What a Fool
      Believes" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Sailing" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Bette Davis
      Eyes" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Rosanna" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Beat It" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"What's Love Got to Do with
      It" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"We Are the
      World" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Higher Love" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Graceland" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Don't Worry, Be
      Happy"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Wind Beneath My
      Wings" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Another Day in
      Paradise" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">
      "Unforgettable" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Tears in
      Heaven" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"
      <strong class="selflink">
I Will Always Love You
</strong>" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"All I Wanna
      Do" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Kiss from a
      Rose" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Change the
      World" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Sunny Came
      Home" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"My Heart Will Go On"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Smooth" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Beautiful
      Day" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Walk On" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Don't Know
      Why" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Clocks" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Here We Go
      Again" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Boulevard of Broken
      Dreams" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Not Ready to Make
      Nice" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Rehab" ·</span>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Please Read the
      Letter"</span>
      </p>
      <p>
         <span style="white-space:nowrap">"Use Somebody"</span>
      </p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
