<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kansas_City_(R%26B_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kansas_City_(R%26B_song)</songId>
   <title>Kansas City</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wilbert_Harrison</artistId>
      <artistName>Wilbert Harrison</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1959-05-18</week>
      <week>1959-05-25</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumName>Beatles for Sale</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>December 4, 1964</released>
   <recorded>October 18, 1964</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Rock And Roll</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>2:33 (mono version)</length>
      <length>2:38 (stereo version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Parlophone</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Jerry Leiber and Mike Stoller / Richard Penniman</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>George Martin</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>from the album 
    <i>Beatles for Sale</i>
      </p>
      <p>"Kansas City" is the title of a rhythm and blues song
    written by Jerry Leiber and Mike Stoller in 1952. The song, a
    12-bar blues, was first recorded by Little Willie Littlefield
    that same year, under the title, "KC Lovin' ". (Ralph Bass of
    Federal Records, Littlefield's label, thought "K.C." sounded
    much "hipper" than "Kansas City," and so changed Leiber &amp;
    Stoller's original title.) Littlefield's record was a regional
    hit in and around Los Angeles, where Federal was located.</p>
      <p>The best known version of "Kansas City" was recorded in 1959
    by Wilbert Harrison. It hit number one on both the R&amp;B
    chart and the Billboard Hot 100, and also restored the song's
    proper title. Since Harrison's record, the song has been
    covered by hundreds of performers, including Jimmy Witherspoon,
    Little Richard, Wanda Jackson, The Beatles, Herman's Hermits,
    Albert King, Joe Williams, Little Milton, Peggy Lee, Bill Haley
    &amp; His Comets, Gene Summers &amp; Sonny Fisher (duet) and
    Fats Domino. Many other artists found some degree of success on
    the Hot 100 with this song, including Rocky Olson, Hank Ballard
    and The Midnighters, Trini Lopez, and James Brown. Ten versions
    of the song are featured on the 1994 CD, 
    <i>The Best Of Kansas City</i>.</p>
      <p>The Beatles' version combined Little Richard's version into
    a medley with Little Richard's song, "Hey, Hey, Hey, Hey." This
    version differs considerably from the original, adding lyrics
    such as "Ah, Kansas City; coming to get my baby back home;
    yeah, yeah..." and removing most of the original lyrics (such
    as: "I'm goin' to Kansas City, Kansas City here I come...").
    Several different versions of Haley's "Kansas City" exist, some
    featuring vocals by Haley himself and others sung by his
    saxophone player, Rudy Pompilli; lyrically, however, all
    versions by Haley adhere to the Leiber &amp; Stoller
    original.</p>
      <p>In 2005, Kansas City adopted "Kansas City" as its official
    song, dedicating "Goin' To Kansas City Plaza" in the historic
    18th and Vine Jazz district. The Beatles' version of Kansas
    City is played over Kauffman Stadium's sound system after each
    Kansas City Royals win, while the Wilbert Harrison version is
    played after each loss.</p>
      <p>The lyrics of the song mention the intersection of "12th
    Street and Vine", a location now marked in a park.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
