<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Play_That_Funky_Music 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Play_That_Funky_Music</songId>
   <title>Play That Funky Music</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wild_Cherry_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Wild Cherry</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1976-09-18</week>
      <week>1976-09-25</week>
      <week>1976-10-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/c/c8/Play_That_Funky_Music_Wild_Cherry.jpg/200px-Play_That_Funky_Music_Wild_Cherry.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Wild-Cherry+Play-That-Funky-Music.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Wild Cherry</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1976</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7"</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1975</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Disco</genre>
      <genre>Funk Rock</genre>
      <genre>Pop</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:12</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Epic Records</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Robert Parissi</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Play That Funky Music" is a funk rock song written by lead
    vocalist and guitarist Robert Parissi and recorded by the rock
    band Wild Cherry. The performers on the classic recording
    included the members of the band at the time, guitarist Bryan
    Bassett, bassist Allen Wentz, and drummer Ron Beitle, with
    session horn players Chuck Berginc, Jack Brandiar, Joe Eckert,
    and Rick Singer hired to play the horn riff that runs
    throughout the track's verses. The single hit number one on the
    Billboard Hot 100 on September 18, 1976 and was also number one
    on the Hot Soul Singles chart. The single was certified
    platinum by the Recording Industry Association of America for
    shipments of over two million records. The song was also the
    basis of a top five U.S. hit for Vanilla Ice in 1990.</p>
      <p>The autobiographical song was inspired by the times, and the
    song's unforgettable title (and chorus) came from drummer Ron
    Beitle's observation during a break between sets at the 2001
    Club in Pittsburgh. The group was mostly a hard rock outfit,
    but the Disco era was really gaining steam and many of the
    group's loyal followers were asking for more dance songs. While
    taking a break between sets, Ron uttered the now classic line
    "play some funky music, white boy". Lead singer Robert Parissi
    decided they should, and wrote down the phrase on a bar order
    pad. They later recorded it in Cleveland with a Disco
    sound.</p>
      <p>Originally, it was planned that the song should be released
    on the B-side of Wild Cherry's cover of the Commodores' "I Feel
    Sanctified"; however, when the owners of Sweet City Records
    heard the song, they suggested that the B-side become the
    A-side. (Epic Records picked up the record for worldwide
    distribution.) The song sold over two million copies, but was
    Wild Cherry's only hit.</p>
      <p>The song listed at #73 on 
    <i>Billboard's Greatest Songs of All Time</i>.</p>
      <p>Parissi said he often wrote songs in a similar style as a
    song he'd pick out from each new week of the Top 40. After
    writing songs in this manner for some time, one of the songs he
    wrote was Funky Music. The song that served as inspiration for
    the hit was Fire by Ohio Players, which features a similar bass
    line and rhythm guitar part.</p>
      <p>Part of the song's popularity stemmed from the controversy
    surrounding its lyrics. A few listeners thought the lyrics were
    "play that fucking music, white boy". At the time, Parissi and
    the record label vehemently denied that there was any profanity
    in the vocals, though on the full version of the song's fade
    out the phrase "play that funky music, honky " is used. The
    group did, however, re-record the chorus just for the city of
    Boston, which apparently was having some racial tension at the
    time. Hence, a version was released in which the chorus is
    "Play that funky music right, boy".</p>
      <p>Vanilla Ice later released a song featuring an
    interpretation of "Play That Funky Music". Songwriter Robert
    Parissi was not credited, and was later awarded $500,000 in a
    copyright infringement lawsuit.</p>
      <p>Although it did not initially catch on, its B-side, "Ice Ice
    Baby", gained more success when a disc jockey played that track
    instead of the single's A-side.</p>
      <p>Following the success of "Ice Ice Baby", "Play That Funky
    Music" was reissued as its own single (with new lyrics), and
    peaked at #4 on the U.S. Hot 100 and #10 in the UK.</p>
      <p>This song has been used in the films, 
    <i>Evolution</i>(2001) and 
    <i>The New Guy</i>(2002). A rap version is played in the film 
    <i>Malibu's Most Wanted</i>(2003), while an instrumental
    version of the song is played on bagpipes by Matt Stifler in
    the direct-to-video movie, 
    <i>American Pie: Band Camp</i>(2005).</p>
      <p>The song appears in the video games 
    <i>Guitar Hero 5</i>and 
    <i>DJ Hero</i>(as a playable track), 
    <i>Dance Dance Revolution Extreme 2</i>(a cover version), and 
    <i>Shaun White Snowboarding</i>.</p>
      <p>It also appeared on an episode of King of the Hill entitled
    Patch Boomhauer.</p>
      <p>Robin Williams has used the song title, delivered in a bad
    Lawrence Welk impression, as a one-liner</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
