<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gettin%27_Jiggy_Wit_It 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gettin%27_Jiggy_Wit_It</songId>
   <title>Gettin' Jiggy Wit It”</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Will_Smith</artistId>
      <artistName>Will Smith</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1998-03-14</week>
      <week>1998-03-21</week>
      <week>1998-03-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/08/JiggyWitIt.png/200px-JiggyWitIt.png</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Will-Smith+Gettin-Jiggy-Wit-It.png</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Big Willie Style</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>January 16, 1998</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1997</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Hip Hop</genre>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:48</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Sony</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Nasir " Nas " Jones</writer>
      <writer>Samuel Barnes</writer>
      <writer>Bernard Edwards</writer>
      <writer>Joe Robinson</writer>
      <writer>Nile Rodgers</writer>
      <writer>Will Smith</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Poke &amp; Tone</producer>
      <producer>L.E.S. (co-prod.)</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Gettin' Jiggy wit It" is a single by Will Smith from his
    album 
    <i>Big Willie Style</i>. Released in early 1998 and co-written
    by Nas, it was Smith's first hit produced by Poke &amp; Tone,
    who replaced his long-time partner Jazzy Jeff, though the
    record-scratching techniques of Jazzy Jeff can be heard in the
    song. It sampled the Sister Sledge song "He's the Greatest
    Dancer" and The Bar-Kays song "Sang and Dance". The record
    spent three weeks at the top of the Hot 100 chart from March
    14, 1998. This song also won a Grammy Award in 1999 for the
    Best Rap Solo Performance.</p>
      <p>It was ranked the 68th greatest song of the 1990s by VH1.
    The connotations associated with the word jiggy were heavily
    influenced by this single. The term went from being used to
    acclaim one's fashion or style towards being synonymous with
    dancing, and eventually back to the original association with
    sexual connotations. Will Smith has attested in an interview
    that his inspiration to alter the meaning for the purpose of
    the song came from his association of the term "jiggy" with
    "jigaboo", a derogatory term for African-Americans, which made
    the literal meaning of the title "getting African-American with
    it" and which was meant to reference the popular folk-myth of
    an innate sense of rhythm in black folks. The co-opting of a
    once offensive word also was racially empowering.</p>
      <p>Two remixes produced by Jermaine Dupri surfaced. The first
    version uses the same lyrics from the album and features a
    female chorus (available on a CD Single). The second version
    contains brand new lyrics by Will Smith with guest raps by Big
    Pun, R.O.C. &amp; Cam'ron, with additional vocals by Jermaine
    Dupri. The second version was deemed a bit hardcore for Will,
    and ended up being unreleased. Version 2 is now available only
    at the iTunes Music Store.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Gettin' Jiggy wit It</i>win a 1998 MTV Video Music Award for
    
    <i>Best Rap Video</i>. It was also nominated for four another
    awards, including 
    <i>Best Choreography</i>, 
    <i>Viewer's Choice</i>, 
    <i>Best Dance Video</i>, and 
    <i>Video of the Year</i>. However, another nominations was lost
    for Madonna and her song 
    <i>Ray of Light</i>.</p>
      <p>The song is featured in Backyard Football '08.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
