<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wild_Wild_West_(Will_Smith_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wild_Wild_West_(Will_Smith_song)</songId>
   <title>Wild Wild West</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Will_Smith</artistId>
      <artistName>Will Smith featuring Dru Hill and Kool Moe Dee</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1999-07-24</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/c/c0/Will_smith_west.jpg/200px-Will_smith_west.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Will-Smith-featuring-Dru-Hill-and-Kool-Moe-Dee+Wild-Wild-West.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>Wild Wild WestWillennium</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>May 4, 1999</released>
   <formats>
      <format>CD Single</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>Spring 1999</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Pop Rap</genre>
      <genre>Funk</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:34 (Album version)</length>
      <length>4:07 (Single version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Overbrook / Interscope / Columbia</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Moe Dewese</writer>
      <writer>Rob Fusari</writer>
      <writer>Will Smith</writer>
      <writer>and Stevie Wonder</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Rob Fusari &amp; Mark Wilson</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Wild Wild West" is the title of a hip hop song written by
    Will Smith as the theme song for Smith's film of the same name.
    The song also appears on Smith's 1999 album, 
    <i>Willenium</i>. Will Smith's 1999 release was recorded
    specifically for Smith's planned summer blockbuster movie, 
    <i>Wild Wild West</i>. Smith's song became a number-one pop hit
    on the Billboard Hot 100, and its extended music video,
    directed by Paul Hunter, was a hit on MTV. Will Smith's "Wild
    Wild West" single samples Stevie Wonder's song "I Wish", with
    parts of the chorus from Kool Moe Dee's song of the same name
    as well. Kool Moe Dee re-performs that chorus for the song,
    with additional guest vocals from R&amp;B group Dru Hill. The
    album version of the song also features, as an introduction, a
    brief spoken word conversation between Will Smith and his son
    Jaden Smith in which Will asks his son what song he should
    perform next, and Jaden suggests this one.</p>
      <p>The high-profile music video for the single, running seven
    minutes and including several dialog sequences, featured Smith,
    Kool Moe Dee, Dru Hill, and guest appearances from Stevie
    Wonder, and, as their 
    <i>Wild Wild West</i>characters Kevin Kline, Salma Hayek and
    Kenneth Branagh. Fellow popstar Enrique Iglesias also appeared
    in the video playing a Prince. Moreoever, 
    <i>The Fresh Prince of Bel-Air</i>co-star and tap dancer
    Alfonso Ribeiro appeared in the music video as one of the
    dancers. Other cameos include actor Larenz Tate, Shari Headley,
    singer/writer/producer Babyface, and female rapper MC Lyte. The
    "Wild Wild West" video notably was a star-making vehicle for
    Dru Hill lead singer Sisqó, while relegating the other three
    members of the quartet to the background. Dru Hill member James
    "Woody" Green quit the group on the set of the video, feeling a
    need to return to his gospel music roots.</p>
      <p>Despite its pop success, the song was criticized for both
    sampling Wonder's song and for its incongruity with the western
    for which it serves as the theme. It won the Golden Raspberry
    Award for Worst "Original" Song of 1999. An "unreleased" remix
    of this song, said to be remixed by Jason Nevins, is available
    through file-sharing programs. In an episode of 
    <i>South Park</i>, Eric Cartman sings a parody of "Wild Wild
    West".</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
