<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blues_in_the_Night 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blues_in_the_Night</songId>
   <title>Blues in the Night (My Mama Done Tol' Me)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woody_Herman</artistId>
      <artistName>Woody Herman</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1942-02-14</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Blues in the Night" is a popular song which has become a
    pop standard and can certainly be considered part of the Great
    American Songbook. The music was written by Harold Arlen, the
    lyrics by Johnny Mercer, for a 1941 film begun with the working
    title 
    <i>Hot Nocturne</i>, but finally released as 
    <i>Blues in the Night</i>. The song is sung in the film by
    William Gillespie.</p>
      <p>Arlen and Mercer wrote the entire score for the 1941 film 
    <i>Blues in the Night</i>. One requirement was for a blues song
    to be sung in a jail cell. As usual with Mercer, the composer
    wrote the music first, then Mercer wrote the words. Arlen
    said,</p>
      <p>The whole thing just poured out. And I knew in my guts,
    without even thinking what Johnny would write for a lyric, that
    this was strong, strong, strong! When Mercer wrote "Blues in
    the Night", I went over his lyric and I started to hum it over
    his desk. It sounded marvelous once I got to the second stanza
    but that first twelve was weak tea. On the third or fourth page
    of his work sheets I saw some lines—one of them was "My momma
    done tol' me, when I was in knee pants." I said, "Why don't you
    try that?" It was one of the very few times I've ever suggested
    anything like that to John.</p>
      <p>When they finished writing the song, Mercer called a friend,
    singer Margaret Whiting, and asked if they could come over and
    play it for her. She suggested they come later because she had
    dinner guests—Mickey Rooney, Judy Garland, Mel Tormé, and
    Martha Raye. Instead, Arlen and Mercer went right over.
    Margaret Whiting remembered what happened then:</p>
      <p>They came in the back door, sat down at the piano and played
    the score of "Blues in the Night". I remember forever the
    reaction. Mel got up and said, "I can't believe it." Martha
    couldn't say a word. Mickey Rooney said, "That's the greatest
    thing I've ever heard." Judy Garland said, "Play it again." We
    had them play it seven times. Judy and I ran to the piano to
    see who was going to learn it first. It was a lovely
    night..</p>
      <p>In 1941 "Blues in the Night" was one of nine songs nominated
    for the Academy Award for Best Original Song. Observers
    expected that either "Blues in the Night" or "Chattanooga Choo
    Choo" would win, so that when "The Last Time I Saw Paris"
    actually won, neither its composer, Jerome Kern, nor lyricist,
    Oscar Hammerstein II, was present at the ceremony. Kern was so
    upset at winning with a song that had not been specifically
    written for a motion picture and that had been published and
    recorded before the film came out that he petitioned the Motion
    Picture Academy to change the rules. Since then, a nominated
    song has to have been written specifically for the motion
    picture in which it is performed..</p>
      <p>Alec Wilder said of this song, "'Blues in the Night' is
    certainly a landmark in the evolution of American popular
    music, lyrically as well as musically." Mercer, being from the
    South, realized "that Arlen's notes were meant to be sung as a
    blues slide and that individual syllables would have made the
    song too formal, too racially white."</p>
      <p>The first two lines have been sung in several ways: "My
    momma done tol' me / when I was in knee pants"; "My momma done
    tol' me / when I was in blue jeans"; "My momma done tol' me /
    when I was in pigtails."</p>
      <p>Recorded versions that charted in the United States were by
    Woody Herman, Dinah Shore, Jimmie Lunceford, Cab Calloway,
    Artie Shaw, and Rosemary Clooney. Recorded versions in the
    United Kingdom were by Shirley Bassey and Helen Shapiro.</p>
      <p>The Woody Herman recording was released by Decca Records as
    catalog number 4030. The record first reached the Billboard
    magazine charts on January 2, 1942 and lasted 11 weeks on the
    chart, peaking at #1.</p>
      <p>The Dinah Shore recording was released by RCA Bluebird
    Records as catalog number 11436. The record first reached the
    Billboard magazine charts on February 13, 1942 and lasted 7
    weeks on the chart, peaking at #4.</p>
      <p>The Jimmie Lunceford recording was released by Decca Records
    as catalog number 4125. The record first reached the Billboard
    magazine charts on January 30, 1942 and lasted 5 weeks on the
    chart, peaking at #4.</p>
      <p>The Cab Calloway recording was released by OKeh Records as
    catalog number 6422. The record first reached the Billboard
    magazine charts on March 6, 1942 and lasted 1 week on the
    chart, at #8.</p>
      <p>The Artie Shaw recording was released by RCA Victor Records
    as catalog number 27609. The record first reached the Billboard
    magazine charts on November 21, 1941 and lasted 1 week on the
    chart, at #10.</p>
      <p>The Rosemary Clooney recording was released by Columbia
    Records as catalog number 39813. The record first reached the
    Billboard magazine charts on September 26, 1952 and lasted 2
    weeks on the chart, peaking at #29.</p>
      <p>In addition, the song has been recorded at least three times
    by Jo Stafford. On October 15, 1943, she recorded it with
    Johnny Mercer, the Pied Pipers, and Paul Weston's Orchestra, in
    a version released as a single (catalog number 10001) and on an
    album (
    <i>Songs by Johnny Mercer,</i>catalog number CD1) by Capitol
    Records. On February 20, 1959, she recorded it with The
    Starlighters in a version released on an album (
    <i>The Ballad of the Blues,</i>catalog number CL-1332) by
    Columbia Records. Finally, she recorded it for the July 25,
    1995, release of "Songs That Won The War: Hollywood
    Canteen".</p>
      <p>More recently, the rock group Chicago included the song on
    their "Night and Day" album in 1995. The arrangement by
    vocalist Bill Champlin features a guitar solo by Aerosmith's
    Joe Perry.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
