<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Owner_of_a_Lonely_Heart 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Owner_of_a_Lonely_Heart</songId>
   <title>Owner of a Lonely Heart</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yes_(band)</artistId>
      <artistName>Yes</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1984-01-21</week>
      <week>1984-01-28</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/58/Owner45.jpg/200px-Owner45.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Yes+Owner-of-a-Lonely-Heart.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>90125</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>5 November 1983</released>
   <formats>
      <format>7" vinyl</format>
      <format>12" vinyl</format>
   </formats>
   <recorded>1983</recorded>
   <genres>
      <genre>Progressive Rock</genre>
      <genre>Pop Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>4:29 (album version)</length>
      <length>3:50 (single version)</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>Atco</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Trevor Rabin</writer>
      <writer>Jon Anderson</writer>
      <writer>Chris Squire</writer>
      <writer>Trevor Horn</writer>
   </writers>
   <producers>
      <producer>Trevor Horn</producer>
   </producers>
   <descr>
      <p>"Owner of a Lonely Heart" is a song by the progressive rock
    band Yes. It is the opening track of their 1983 album 
    <i>90125</i>. Written primarily by Trevor Rabin (who was new to
    the band at the time), the song reached number one on the U.S.
    Billboard Hot 100 — to date Yes' biggest chart success by far.
    Since then, it has seen many releases; the original release had
    "Our Song" as the b-side, while others had various b-sides such
    as "Leave It", "Make It Easy", and remixes of this song.</p>
      <p>Standout features of the song include the catchy, heavily
    distorted introductory guitar riff, which establishes a motif
    for the song; producer Trevor Horn's innovative use of jarring,
    heavily syncopated orchestra hits and other high-tech sound
    effects; Rabin's disorienting, schizophrenic guitar solo, which
    was played through an MXR Pitch Transposer, which mixed the
    original note with one a perfect fifth higher.</p>
      <p>The song's falsetto titular refrain is actually sung by
    producer Trevor Horn as well as (lead singer) Jon Anderson.
    Rabin also ably performed this song during his 1989-90 solo
    tour, with a bit of difficulty on the higher vocal range.
    Invariably, the Rabin-era band performed this song, preceded by
    a truncated "Make it Easy" intro. Jon Anderson has also
    performed "Owner", even though Yes guitarist Steve Howe has
    repeatedly expressed dislike for the song.</p>
      <p>The song's music video, directed by Peter Christopherson,
    received a great deal of airplay on MTV, introducing the
    revamped Yes lineup and sound to a new generation of fans
    largely unfamiliar with the band's very different earlier work,
    which had helped to define the genre of progressive rock. The
    video begins with a bird flying over different areas and then
    cuts to an archetypal Everyman as he tries to make it through a
    day whilst being shocked by pseudo-psychotic flashes of being
    menaced by the various animals. He is brought to court by
    government-looking toughs, summarily thrown out of court and
    into a boiler room where he fights a bruiser, then runs onto
    the roof of the building. There, he is confronted by the
    various band members, shifting back and forth between human and
    animal guises, which drives him to leap from the building. The
    video then ends with the same man in the same crowd as at the
    beginning of the video, but instead he turns back, presumably
    to go home and avoid the day.</p>
      <p>Another possible interpretation of the video is that this
    was the year 1983 and many people were looking ahead to the
    following year 1984. George Orwell's novel Nineteen Eighty-Four
    cast a dark vision of the future, including an oppressive,
    intrusive government who used the Thought Police to monitor and
    maintain control of the population. The video brings the
    audience into that Orwellian nightmare through the life of an
    ordinary citizen, a man, arrested and brought to "Justice". All
    the characters waiting in line show resignation in their
    expressions, suggesting that they've been imprisoned at the
    Ministry of Love at one time or another and no longer have a
    free will of their own. The man may be a free thinker thus
    making, and marking, him as an enemy of Big Brother. The
    flashbacks and visions of the animals may indicate that he was
    previously mind wiped and these are side effects of the
    process. The thought of having to go back to The Ministry of
    Love and it's tortures is enough to send him into a state of
    panic and suicide. He wakes up, only to find he's been
    daydreaming ( or was he ), the impact is enough to turn him
    around, avoiding what may lay ahead.</p>
      <p>Notably, keyboardist Tony Kaye does not appear in the video.
    At the time of the video shoot, Eddie Jobson was standing in as
    the band's keyboardist. He can be seen briefly in a few quick
    shots, but he was not part of the video's "animal
    transformation" scene in which the other four band members take
    part. Ultimately, Kaye returned to the lineup, and it is not
    believed that Jobson ever recorded any material with the
    band.</p>
      <p>The biggest major legacy of the track is arguably the
    beginnings of ZTT Records and the electronic group The Art Of
    Noise; as well as being a former member of Yes, Trevor Horn
    served the role of one of the band's producers during the
    recording of 
    <i>90125</i>and "Owner of a Lonely Heart". With him were Gary
    Langan, J.J. Jeczalik and Anne Dudley, all working with Horn as
    his production team, in the roles of engineers and arrangers.
    Taking samples and loops directly from these Yes recording
    sessions (as well as work done on Malcolm McLaren's 
    <i>Duck Rock</i>), the team subsequently formed the Art Of
    Noise under the auspice of Trevor Horn, becoming the first
    signed act of his ZTT Records label. The crunching stabs,
    orchestral samples and thunderous drums of "Owner of a Lonely
    Heart" can be heard in the Art Of Noise's initial
    recordings.</p>
      <p>"Owner of a Lonely Heart" has been remixed several times,
    most notably by Max Graham in April 2005; his version reached
    number nine in the UK Singles Chart and the music video is
    still popular. 808 State also did remixes ('2 Close To the Edge
    Mix' and 'Not Fragile Mix'). and Kyper used riffs of the song
    in his own song "Tic-Tac-Toe". The song is also covered by
    Colin Blunstone, backed by an orchestra. Yet another remix was
    done in 2004 by Deep Dish. The track had also been sampled by
    the group Dubstar; a sample of the drum fill can be heard at
    the beginning of "No More Talk" (on their 
    <i>Goodbye</i>album). Turkish electronic music singer Hande
    Yener has sampled "Owner of a Lonely Heart"s melody throughout
    her song Hipnoz.</p>
      <p>Venezuelan rock band Caramelos de Cianuro quotes the main
    guitar riff of the song throughout their song "Baby Cohete" of
    their 2006 album Flor De Fuego.</p>
      <p>Frank Zappa also incorporated parts of the song into the
    guitar solo of one of his own songs, "Bamboozled by Love" on
    his 1984 and 1988 tours (see 
    <i>You Can't Do That on Stage Anymore, Vol. 3</i>).</p>
      <p>On Yes' 35th Anniversary tour, "Owner of a Lonely Heart" was
    frequently played acoustically.</p>
      <p>"Owner of a Lonely Heart" was featured on Flash FM, a radio
    station in video game 
    <i>Grand Theft Auto: Vice City</i>. The song was also featured
    in a D-TV music video on The Disney Channel, set entirely to
    clips from the 1936 cartoon 
    <i>Elmer Elephant</i>.</p>
      <p>An excerpt of "Owner of a Lonely Heart" is featured in
    Michael Jackson's "D.S." from his 1995 album, 
    <i>HIStory</i>. The album focuses on Jackson's isolation after
    the then-recent child abuse allegations.</p>
      <p>In an Episode of 
    <i>The Simpsons</i>entitled "The DeBarted" Homer does his own
    version of the song, singing "Driver of a loaner car," while
    driving a car on loan from a body shop.</p>
      <p>Both hit shows 
    <i>Grey's Anatomy</i>and 
    <i>Degrassi: The Next Generation</i>named an episode after this
    song. Both shows are known to name their episodes after hit
    songs.</p>
      <p>"Weird Al" Yankovic used a section of the song in his polka
    medley "Hooked on Polkas".</p>
      <p>The song also appears in an episode of 
    <i>Knight Rider</i>, starring David Hasselhoff.</p>
      <p>
         <i>Mystery Science Theater 3000</i>parodied the song, with Tom
    Servo pondering the implications of the song (Tom: "How does
    the (singing) "Owner of a lonely heart" (normal voice) compare
    to, say, the (singing) "Owner of a broken gas fireplace?"
    (Normal voice) Or for that matter, to the (singing) "Owner of a
    perfectly functional cheese slicer?" (Normal voice) As the
    (singing) "Owner of a lonely heart" (normal voice) how do I
    stack up against the (singing) "Owner of a pencil?" I mean,
    come on, Yes!"), then Mike and the bots were constantly
    assaulted by the orchestral hit.</p>
      <p>Cover versions include a soft jazz one by Icelandic duo
    Kristjana &amp; Agnar on their album 
    <i>Ég um þig</i>(Me for you) and Brooklyn indie band Grizzly
    Bear on their EP 
    <i>Sorry for the Delay</i>.</p>
      <p>The Atlanta-based rapper E-Dubb's debut single "Whooty
    (White Girl with a Booty)" has a riff that mimicks the Yes
    song, but later re-released with a similar sounding riff.</p>
      <p>The "Class President" episode of 
    <i>Everybody Hates Chris</i>features this song.</p>
      <p>"Owner of a Lonely Heart" was, according to a radio
    interview with Yes in 1991 (with the 
    <i>Union</i>tour), originally written as a ballad, not as the
    rock song that became famous. Jon Anderson convinced producer
    Trevor Horn to speed it up and add some guitar riffs to make it
    stand out and be more "upbeat". However, as the next paragraph
    states, Trevor Rabin had already recorded an upbeat demo
    version of this song before Jon Anderson and Trevor Horn joined
    the 90125 project, so this story is probably not true.</p>
      <p>An extremely raw demo version of the song can be found on
    Rabin's album 
    <i>90124</i>, with a different pre-chorus verse and a jazz
    fusion keyboard solo reminiscent of Chick Corea.</p>
      <p>The orchestra and drum samples were lifted from Funk, Inc.'s
    "Kool is Back."</p>
      <p>Two characters in the movie 
    <i>The Break-Up</i>sing the song at a dinner. The song is
    included on an album of music from the movie.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
