<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Young_Love_(1956_song) 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Young_Love_(1956_song)</songId>
   <title>Young Love " Tab Hunter</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tab_Hunter</artistId>
      <artistName>"Young Love" Tab Hunter</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1957-03-02</week>
   </weeks>
   <descr>
      <p>"Young Love" is a popular song, written by Ric Cartey and
    Carole Joyner and published in 1956.</p>
      <p>The original version was recorded by Ric Cartey With The
    Jiva-Tones on November 24, 1956. It was originally released in
    1956 by Stars Records as catalog number 539 and one month later
    by RCA Records as catalog number 47-6751. Cartey's version
    never charted, but better-known versions were released by Sonny
    James, Tab Hunter (in a version that did even better on the
    charts) and The Crew-Cuts.</p>
      <p>The recording by Tab Hunter was released by Dot Records as
    catalog number 15533. It first reached the Billboard magazine
    charts on January 19, 1957. On the Disk Jockey chart, it peaked
    at #1; on the Best Seller chart, at #1; on the Juke Box chart,
    at #1; on the composite chart of the top 100 songs, it reached
    #1. The success of this record led Warner Bros., where Hunter
    was a contract player, to form Warner Bros. Records.</p>
      <p>The recording by Sonny James was released by Capitol Records
    as catalog number 3602. It first reached the Billboard magazine
    charts on January 5, 1957. On the Disk Jockey chart, it peaked
    at #1; on the Best Seller chart, at #2; on the Juke Box chart,
    at #4; on the composite chart of the top 100 songs, it reached
    #2. On 
    <i>Billboard'</i>s country music charts, it was a No. 1 hit for
    nine weeks, and remained the longest-reigning of James' 23
    chart-topping songs on the chart.</p>
      <p>The flip side of James' version was a song called "You're
    the Reason I'm In Love." That song was a Top 10 hit on the
    Billboard country charts in early 1957. In 1971 – 14 years
    after the original — James re-recorded that song in a
    faster-tempoed, horn-heavy rendition as "That's Why I Love You
    Like I Do" (the original slower-tempoed song featured an
    electric guitar solo); the newly recorded, re-titled version
    was released as a single and reached No. 1 in June 1972.</p>
      <p>The recording by The Crew-Cuts was released by Mercury
    Records as catalog number 71022. It first reached the Billboard
    magazine charts on January 26, 1957. On the Disk Jockey chart,
    it peaked at #17; on the Juke Box chart, at #17; on the
    composite chart of the top 100 songs, it reached #24.</p>
      <p>In 1964 the song was recorded by The Rolling Stones, and was
    issued as a single under the name "Bo and Peep" [1]</p>
      <p>In 1966 the song was covered by Lesley Gore, her version
    reached number 50.</p>
      <p>In 1969 the song was covered by Mary Hopkin, and included on
    her LP "Post Card", which was produced by Paul McCartney.</p>
      <p>In 1969 a duet version of the song was made by country music
    singers Connie Smith and Nat Stuckey. Their version reached #20
    on the Country Music charts.</p>
      <p>In 1973 the song was revived by teen hearthrob Donny Osmond.
    The Mike Curb and Don Costa produced version became a hit on
    both sides of the Atlantic, reaching #25 on the Billboard Hot
    100 and #1 on the UK singles chart, spending four weeks at the
    top in August 1973.</p>
      <p>In 1976, Ray Stevens had a minor country and pop hit with
    the song.</p>
      <p>In 1993 country band Twister Alley covered this song on
    their self-titled album and released it as a single. It peaked
    at #70 on the US Country singles chart.</p>
      <p>Celtic Thunder performed the song. It was released on their
    album Celtic Thunder: Act II.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
