<topSong><!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is included in the section 
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License." Content derived from 
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_the_Year_2525 

Modified in February 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
GNU Free Documentation License.--><songId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_the_Year_2525</songId>
   <title>In the Year 2525 (Exordium and Terminus)</title>
   <artist>
      <artistId>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zager_and_Evans</artistId>
      <artistName>Zager and Evans</artistName>
   </artist>
   <weeks>
      <week>1969-07-12</week>
      <week>1969-07-19</week>
      <week>1969-07-26</week>
      <week>1969-08-02</week>
      <week>1969-08-09</week>
      <week>1969-08-16</week>
   </weeks>
   <album>
      <albumImageId>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/0/09/In_the_Year_2525_Single.jpg/200px-In_the_Year_2525_Single.jpg</albumImageId>
      <albumImageUri>/images/Zager-and-Evans+In-the-Year-2525-Exordium-and-Terminus.jpg</albumImageUri>
      <albumName>2525 (Exodium &amp; Terminus)</albumName>
   </album>
   <released>1969  (1969)</released>
   <genres>
      <genre>Psychedelic Rock</genre>
   </genres>
   <lengths>
      <length>3:15</length>
   </lengths>
   <label>RCA</label>
   <writers>
      <writer>Rick Evans</writer>
   </writers>
   <descr>
      <p>"In the Year 2525 (Exordium and Terminus)" is a hit song
    from 1969 by the Lincoln, Nebraska duo Zager and Evans which
    reached number one on the Billboard Hot 100 for the six weeks
    commencing July 12. The song was written by Rick Evans in 1964
    and originally released on a small regional record label (Truth
    Records) in 1968. A year later, an Odessa, Texas radio station
    popularized the disc, which RCA Records quickly picked up for
    nationwide distribution.</p>
      <p>"In the Year 2525 (Exordium and Terminus)" opens with the
    words "In the year 2525, If man is still alive, If woman can
    survive, They may find...". Subsequent verses pick up the story
    at 1010-year intervals from 2525 to 6565. Disturbing
    predictions are given for each selected year. In the year 3535,
    for example, all of a person's actions, words and thoughts will
    be preprogrammed into a daily pill. Then the pattern as well as
    the music changes, going up a half step in the key of the song,
    after two stanzas, first from A flat minor, to A minor, and,
    then, finally, to B flat minor, and verses for the years 7510,
    8510 and 9595 follow.</p>
      <p>The song has no chorus. Amid ominous-sounding orchestral
    music, the final dated chronological verse is, 
    <i>In the year 9595, I'm kinda wonderin' if Man is gonna be
    alive. He's taken everything this old Earth can give, and he
    ain't put back nothing, whoa-whoa...</i>, The summary verse
    concludes: 
    <i>Now it's been 10,000 years, Man has cried a billion tears,
    For what, he never knew. Now man's reign is through. But
    through eternal night, The twinkling of starlight. So very far
    away, Maybe it's only yesterday.</i>, before the song
    effectively "starts over" with the first verse again and then
    fades out, leaving open the possibility that "we went through
    this before," and life is now at the start of another
    cycle.</p>
      <p>The overriding theme, of a world doomed by its passive
    acquiescence to and overdependence on its own overdone
    technologies, struck a resonant chord in millions of people
    around the world in the late 1960s.</p>
      <p>The song describes a nightmarish vision of the future as
    man's technological inventions gradually dehumanize him. It
    includes a colloquial reference to the Second Coming (
    <i>In the year 7510, if God's a-coming, He ought to make it by
    then.</i>), which echoed the zeitgeist of the Jesus Movement.
    The song also references examples of technologies that were not
    fully developed but were known to the public in 1969, such as
    robots, as well as future technology that would come into
    existence long before their prediction in the song, the science
    of test tube babies and genetic selection by parents of their
    future children. Such a concept had been explored in a few
    science fiction novels but had not yet, for the most part, been
    mentioned in the mainstream media until "In The Year 2525" was
    released in 1969.</p>
      <p>In one of the daily newscast to the crew of Apollo 11
    capsule communicator Ronald Evans told the returning crew that
    "In the Year 2525" was currently number one in the billboard
    charts after also informing the crew about the large number of
    Moon based songs that had just been written following the
    successful Moon Landing.</p>
      <p>It is unusual for a recording artist to have a number one
    hit and then never have another chart single for the rest of
    their career. "In the Year 2525" actually gave Zager and Evans
    this status 
    <i>twice</i>: they remain the only act to do this in both the
    U.S. 
    <i>and</i>UK singles charts. The duo also recorded and released
    the song in Italian under the title of "Nell'Anno Due Mila
    Trenta Tre" ("In The Year 2033"). Their follow up single on
    RCA-Victor, "Mr. Turnkey" (a song about a rapist who nails his
    own wrist to the wall as punishment for his crime), failed to
    hit the main music charts on either side of the Atlantic
    (although it did manage to make the Bubbling Under Hot 100
    chart, peaking at #106).</p>
      <p>The song has been covered many times. A notable version is
    sung by the italo-french pop icon Dalida, another one by the UK
    new romantic group Visage; another version was used as the
    theme song for the short-lived science fiction series 
    <i>Cleopatra 2525</i>. It is also featured in both parts of the
    two-part second season finale of 
    <i>Millennium</i>where a man-made virus is threatening to wipe
    out humanity. The Slovenian industrial group Laibach edited the
    lyrics in their cover version to make it appropriate for 1994's
    album. There was also a dance cover of this song by The Act
    featuring Clinton III in 1993. More recently, it was covered by
    the gothic rock band Fields of the Nephilim, by the electronic
    body music band Project Pitchfork (album 
    <i>Dhyani</i>), 1991, by the German electronic band Strauss
    &amp; Roggenbuck, and most recently by Ian Brown on his 2009
    album "My Way".</p>
      <p>In the 1992 movie 
    <i>Alien 3</i>, a prisoner is heard singing a line or two of
    the song while scraping the inside of a ventilator shaft,
    shortly before he is attacked by a juvenile Xenomorph and
    subsequently diced by a large ventilation fan. The movie takes
    place a few hundred years after the 20th century.</p>
      <p>The song appeared on the list of songs deemed inappropriate
    by Clear Channel following the September 11, 2001 attacks.</p>
      <p>The song still receives regular airplay on many radio
    stations. It was often featured as bumper music on 
    <i>Coast to Coast AM</i>with Art Bell (before Bell retired).
    "In The Year 2525" was one of the 10 biggest singles of the
    1960s in the United States, although it didn't neatly fit into
    any of the main categories of rock music. Upon release by RCA
    in 1969, it quickly became a multi-million-seller.</p>
      <p>According to Jimmy Guterman and Owen O'Donnell, authors of 
    <i>The Worst Rock and Roll Records of All Time</i>(1991), who
    place the song at number six on their list of the 50 worst
    rock-and-roll singles, "science fiction and rock and roll don't
    mix any better than Zsa Zsa Gabor and reality". Others differ,
    calling the one-hit wonder "prophetic" .</p>
      <p>The White Stripes refer to "the year 2525" in the song
    "You're Pretty Good Looking (For a Girl)" on their album
    (2000).</p>
      <p>The song was prominently featured in the 2009 comedy
    Gentlemen Broncos starring Michael Angarano, Sam Rockwell and
    Jermaine Clement.</p>
   </descr>
</topSong>
